<movie id="10" title="Abyss The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty knots? No way, Barnes... the reds don't have anything that fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the signal onto a speaker and everyone in the attack room listens to the intruder's acoustic signature, a strange THRUMMING. The captain studies the electronic position board, a graphic representation of the contours of the steep-walled canyon, a symbol for the Montana, and converging with it, an amorphous trace, representing the bogey.</context>
      <utterance>Checked it twice, skipper. It's a real unique signature. No cavitation, no reactor noise... doesn't even sound like screws.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what it's not, it's not one of ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir! Contact changing heading to two-one-four, diving. Speed eighty knots! Eighty knots!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty knots...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>clearance to cliff wall, one hundred fifty feet.</context>
      <utterance>Still diving, depth nine hundred feet. Port</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting tight in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can still give him a haircut. Helm, come right to oh six niner, down five degrees.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming right to oh six niner, sir. Down five degrees.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAVIGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Port side clearance one hundred twenty feet narrowing to seventy-five. Sir, we have a proximity warning light.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too damn close! We've gotta back off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Range to contact, two hundred. Contact junked to bearing two six oh and accelerated to... one hundred thirty knots, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the control room lights dim almost to blackness.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing goes one thirty!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIRENS. Everyone shouting at once. The power flickers low.</context>
      <utterance>Turbulence! We're in its wake!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helm, all stop! Full right rudder!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Power returns in time for the sonarman to get a glimpse at the side-scan display... AS THE SHEER CLIFF WALL LOOM BEFORE THEM.</context>
      <utterance>All stop. Full right rudder. Hydraulic failure. Planes are not responding, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hydraulics restored, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Collision alarm! Collision alarm! Lighten her up, Charlie!</utterance>
   <speaker>NAVIGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The torpedo room is flooded, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blow all tanks! Blow everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Passing twelve hundred feet...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blowing main tanks!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve hundred fifty feet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Main forward tanks ruptured!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Passing thirteen hundred feet...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too deep to pump auxiliaries!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All back full! All back full!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answering all back full. Passing thirteen hundred fifty feet... fourteen hundred... fourteen fifty... The Captain locks eyes with the Exec amid the din...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Exec opens the door to a small box and punches a button. A red light comes on. The Captains takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>We're losing her. Launch the buoy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON VIDEO SCREEN (MINUTES LATER) showing divers working in total blackness around some sort of installation on the bottom of the ocean. They move through the harsh floodlights in dreamlike slow motion, looking like space-suited figures with their helmets and umbilical hoses.</context>
      <utterance>Does not look good at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No light from the surface. How deep are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>WIDER, showing the Navy contingent crowding the control room. DeMarco is hardcore military, brusque and efficient. Kirkhill is a small man with pinched features, wearing a shirt and tie, which on a drill ship means company man and/or dickhead.</context>
      <utterance>Seventeen hundred feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need them to go to over two thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can do it.  Get Brigman on the line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud! Hippy's on the bitch-box. It's a call from topside. That new company man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the roustabouts, a wiry Texan, turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Kirkhill? That guy doesn't know his butt from a rathole. Hey, Perry!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perry chuckles and sets to the task cheerfully. Bud EXITS, ducking his head through a low watertight hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor and square away the mud hose and those cable slings. This place is starting to look like my apartment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He enters his office, a tiny cubicle with stacks of paperwork, dust- gathering tech manuals and waterstained Penthouse fold-outs. He picks up the phone... punches down a line.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming. Keep your pantyhose on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD ON Bud's expression, darkening, as he listens.</context>
      <utterance>Brigman here. Kirkhill? What's going on?  I am calm. I'm a calm person. Is there some reason why I shouldn't be calm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks a chair out of the way and slams his palm down on a switch marked DIVER RECALL. A SIREN, blasting through the water from a big hydrophone loudspeaker.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All divers. Drop what you're doing. Everybody out of the pool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go, hon'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They react to Bud's recall, looking toward him up in the control module.</context>
      <utterance>Just in time, sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit, we just got out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Night makes a grab for his butt with the manipulator claw, which he narrowly avoids.</context>
      <utterance>There was a time when I would have asked why.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FINLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on? How come we got recalled?</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Night jumps 'ashore' from Flatbed's broad deck and joins them. Catfish is unzipping his bulky dry-suit.</context>
      <utterance>Hell is I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just follow standard procedure, will ya... flog the dog till somebody tells us what's happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Catfish, I'll sell you my October Penthouse for twenty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save you money, darlin'... the pages are all stuck together by now. Bud enters, approaching the group.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on, Boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks, I've just been told to shut down the hole and prepare to move the rig.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She-hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're being asked to cooperate in a matter of national security. Now you know exactly as much as I do. So just get your gear off and get up to control. There's some kind of briefing in ten minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAN AROUND the reactions of the various drill crew members... shocked, hushed, curious.</context>
      <utterance>At 09:22 local time this morning, an American nuclear submarine, the USS Montana, with 156 men aboard, went down 22 miles from here. There has been no contact with the sub since then. The cause of the incident is not known.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your company has authorized the Navy's use of this facility for a rescue operation. The code name is Operation Salvor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want us to search for the sub?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud's scowl has been deepening since DeMarco started to talk.</context>
      <utterance>No. We know where it is. But she's in 2000 feet of water and we can't reach her. We need divers to enter the sub and search for survivors, if any.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you guys have your own stuff for this type of thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hippy, born suspicious and recently graduated to paranoid, leans forward...</context>
      <utterance>By the time we get our rescue submersible here the storm front will be right on us. But you can get your rig in under the storm and be on- site in fifteen hours. That makes you our best option right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should we risk our butts on a job like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been authorized to offer you all special- duty bonuses equivalent to three times normal dive pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, for triple time I'd crawl through razor blades and shower off with lime juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here to tell ya', you could set me on fire and call me names.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't know what kind of a deal you guys worked out with the company, but my people are not qualified for this... they're oil workers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A four-man SEAL team will transfer down to you to supervise the operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can send down whoever you like, but I'm the toolpusher on this rig, and when it comes to the safety of these people, there's me... then there's God. Understand? If things get dicey, I'm pulling the plug.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brigman. Now let's get the wellhead uncoupled, shall we?</context>
      <utterance>I think we're all on the same wavelength,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Lindsey finds out about this, it's not gonna be a pretty sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to have to shoot her with a tranquilizer gun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you let them do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Lins. I thought you were in Houston.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was, but I managed to bum a ride on the last flight out here. Only here isn't where I left it, is it, Bud?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't up to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were that close to proving a submersible drilling platform could work. We had over seven thousand feet of hole down for Chrissake. I can't believe you let them grab my rig!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your rig?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My rig. I designed the damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup, a Benthic Petroleum paid for it. So as long as they're hold the pink slip, I go where they tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>bought you... more like least rented you cheap--</context>
      <utterance>You wimp. I had a lot riding on this. They</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm switching off now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgil, you wiener! You never could stand up to fight. You-- Bud hits the switch and the screen goes dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hippy looks over him, trying very hard not to crack up.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgil?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I hate that bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well you never should have married her then. Bud nods fatalistically.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey looks up in surprise as she nimbly climbs the side of Cab Three and grabs the lifting shackle, circling her raised hand to signal the crane man.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, gentlemen! We either launch now or we don't launch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cab Three, with Lindsey riding its back, is pulled up out its cradle and starts to swing violently as Explorer pitches. The submersible is then swung out to the center of the launch well. It sways and gyrates above the furious water below. Lindsey drops into the upper hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Take her up, Byron!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little sub is swinging like a pendulum on the cable, and the SEALs, jammed in with their equipment in the tiny space, are getting slammed into the walls. Lindsey is calmly flipping switches as she talks.</context>
      <utterance>Bates is sick. Besides I've got more hours in this thing than he does.  A little change of plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady, we better fish or cut bait.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So Kirkhill, we gonna do this or we gonna talk about it?</context>
      <utterance>Just hold your water, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care who drives the damn thing. Just get my team in the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestured dismissively to McBride.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright. Christ Almighty!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab Three, you are clear to launch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's only one way it's going to happen... She pulls the lever hard. CLUNK-CLANG! The shackle-release drops the sub. It freefalls ten feet to the water with an enormous splash and keeps right on going after Lindsey floods the trim tanks. Coffey et al have been slammed hard.</context>
      <utterance>Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey cuts on the floodlights and maneuvers the descending submersible so that the umbilical cable is a few feet ahead on her front port. Moving up through her lights, it will guide her down to the rig. Cab Three free-falls into increasing darkness. Soon it is a candle below us in the indigo.</context>
      <utterance>Touchdown. The crowd goes wild. Explorer... Cab Three. We are styling. MCBRIDE  Roger, Cab Three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deepcore, Deepcore... this is Cab Three on final approach.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha, Cab Three. Who is that? That You, Lindsey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bud's expression is nothing less than stricken.</context>
      <utterance>None other.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no... you gotta be kidding me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy, y'all. Hey, Lindsey! I'll be damned! You shouldn't be down here sweet thing, ya'll might run ya stockings.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't stay away. You running mixture for us? Good. Couldn't ask for better.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HISSSS of inrushing compressed gas. The pressure in the chamber rises. The breathing mixture is composed of helium, oxygen and nitrogen. Catfish monitors it carefully from a station outside the chamber, watching the gauges with a practiced eye. Lindsey and the SEALs all grab their noses and start making funny faces... popping their ears with the familiar diver's 'equalization' technique. They continue as:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, here we go. Start equalizing, y'all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get comfortable. The bad news is we got six hours in this can, blowing down. The worse news is it's gonna take us three weeks to decompress back to the surface later.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been fully briefed, Mrs. Brigman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me that, okay... I hate that. Alright, from now on we watch each other closely for signs of HPNS...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good. About one person in twenty just can't handle it. They go buggo. They're no way to predict who's susceptible, so stay alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we've all made chamber runs to this depth. We're checked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ignore her. Start going over some diagrams of the Montana's interior. It's going to be a long six hours.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... chamber runs. Uh huh, that's good.  Well, hey... you guys know any songs?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those guys ain't so tough. I fought plenty of guys tougher'n them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catfish hold up one calloused fist up in front of Hippy's face.</context>
      <utterance>Now we get to hear about how he used to be a contender.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see this? They used to call this the Hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hippy wasn't born then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, was there a wall here before? I don't remember a wall here. Oh, Jammer! Hi. The 'wall' grins down to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey emerges behind them and, ignoring Lindsey, faces Jammer.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy, there, little lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those guys are about a much fun as a tax audit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDER, as Hippy and Bud to see Lindsey leaning in the doorway. She and Bud size each other up. He opts for a jovial approach, his eyes wary.</context>
      <utterance>Hippy, you're going to give that rat a disease.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, well. Mrs. Brigman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey crossed past him, her eyes scanning the banks of equipment, almost unconsciously checking, checking... getting the pulse of her big iron baby.</context>
      <utterance>Not for long.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never did like being called that, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even when it meant something.  Is that One Night up in Flatbed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey leans past Bud to the gooseneck mike on the console.</context>
      <utterance>Who else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, One Night, it's Lindsey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you were dumb enough to come down. Now you're stuck here for the storm... dumb, hot-rod... dumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses past Bud and exits into the corridor. Bud bolts out of the chair to follow her and Hippy scrambles in to take over.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I didn't come down here to fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops abruptly to look at a leaky pipe. He almost slams into her. She moves on, climbing down the ladder to the lower level.</context>
      <utterance>Then why'd you come down?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need me. Nobody knows the systems on this rig better than I do. What is something was to go wrong after the Explorer clears off? What would have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the lower level landing, Lindsey opens a hatch into one of the machine rooms. ROAR OF PUMPS AND COMPRESSORS.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, you're right! Us poor dumb ol' boys might've had to think for ourselves. Coulda been a disaster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna know what I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scowls at a pressure gauge and turn a valve minutely.</context>
      <utterance>Not particularly. Jeez, look where this is set! Morons.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you were worried about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey's on the move again, and Bud scrambles through the pipes to keep up.</context>
      <utterance>That must be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think you were. Come on, admit it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was worried about the rig. I've got over four years invested in this project.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, right... and you only had three years with me. She looks up at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to have priorities.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you still wearing that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud stays in the doorway. Lindsey takes a heaps of Bud's cloths off the narrow bunk. Start unconsciously straightening the room.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Divorce ain't final. Forgot to take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't worn mine in months.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what's-his-name wouldn't like it. The Suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you always have to call him that? The Suit? It makes you sound like such a hick. His name is Michael. Lindsey takes off her borrowed tennies and socks. Bud eyes her, sounding too causal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what about "Michael" then... Mr. Brooks Brothers... Mr. BMW. You still seeing him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't seen him in a few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud, why are you doing this? It's not part of you life any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what happened... you woke up one day and realized the guy never made you laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the watertight door, forcing him out. Locks it. She turns and throws her shoe hard against the far wall.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Bud. It was just that simple. Aren't you clever? You should get your own show... Ask Dr. Bud, advice to the lovelorn from three hundred fathoms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CUT WIDE, showing the rig crew gathered around a worktable in the sub-bay. The divers, Bud, Catfish, Sonny, Finler, Jammer, and the four SEALs have their dry-suits on. The pre-dive briefing. Lindsey, One Night, and Hippy will crew the submersibles. Wilhite is going around clipping DOSIMETER BADGES on everybody.</context>
      <utterance>This is us. We're just on the edge of the Cayman Trough. The Montana is here, on its side, 300 meters away and 70 meters below us. We think she slid down the wall, and lodged against this outcropping.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This tells us how much radiation we get?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, whoah... I can't handle no radiation, man. Forget it! Include me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hippy, you pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good's the money if your dick drops off in six months?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take reading as we go. If the reactor's breached or the warheads have released radioactive debris, we'll back away. Simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud pats the top of a small ROV, sitting next to its larger brother, Big Geek.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... Hippy's not going... McWhirter, you can run Little Geek.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way! No way! He can't fly an ROV worth shit. I'll go. Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's three AM. These guys are running on bad coffee and four hours sleep. You better start cutting them some slack.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't afford slack, Brigman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you come on my rig, you don't talk to me, you start ordering my guys around. It won't work. You gotta know how to handle these people... we have a certain way of doing things here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>End of discussion. Coffey is walking away. Burning, Bud crosses to his gear locker. Picks up his helmet. Finler is suiting out next to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in your way of doing things. Just get your team ready to dive.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you know your hand is blue?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NEARBY, Monk comes over to pick his helmet up off the worktable. Hippy points to the heavy equipment case that says F.B.S. DEEP SUIT/MARK IV.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and get your gear on.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mink opens the case and shows them an unfamiliar diving suit, what looks like a space helmet, and a large backpack.</context>
      <utterance>I've been meaning to ask you what this thing is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fluid breathing system. We just got them. We use it if we need to go really deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How deep?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catfish is grappling with the concept.</context>
      <utterance>Deep.  It's classified... you know. Anyway, you breathe liquid, so you can't be compressed. Pressure doesn't get to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're saying you get liquid in your lungs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monk take a clear plastic box full of O-rings off the shelf and dumps them out. He opens a valve on the backpack and allows some of the fluid inside it to drain into the box. Then he take Beany by the tail off Hippy's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oxygenated fluorocarbon emulsion.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops Beany in the box and, before Hippy can protest, closes the lid. Beany is forced under the surface. He struggled for a second, and bubbles come out of his mouth. Then he casually swims around in there, completely submerged... breathing liquid. Catfish and the others stare into the box, amazed.</context>
      <utterance>Check this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monk takes Beany out and hold him by the tail for a few seconds to drain his lungs. Then hands him back to Hippy. The rat is annoyed, but otherwise alright.</context>
      <utterance>See? He's diggin' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is no bullshit hands down the goddamnedest thing I ever saw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Com-check, everybody. Flatbed, you on line?</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-four, Lindsey, read you loud and clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab Three?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab Three, check. Right behind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's you depth, Cab Three?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going over the wall. Coming to bearing 065. Everybody stay tight and in sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starting out descent. Divers, how're you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How deep's the drop-off here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This here's the bottomless pit, baby. Two and a half miles straight down.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock off the chatter. Cab One, you getting anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab One, do you see it yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spotlight flares back from the great brass screw of the Montana. It dwarfs Cab One, FILLING FRAME.</context>
      <utterance>The magnetometer is pegged. Side-scan is showing a big return, but I don't see anything yet. Are you sure you got the depth right on this? BUD  You should be almost to it, ace. She turns the submersible and...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah, roger that... uh, found it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cab One, radiation readings?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neutron counter's not showing very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilhite, anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative. Nominal.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just continue forward along the hull.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy that, continuing forward. You just want me to get shots of everything, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, document as much as you can, but keep moving. We're on a tight timeline.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The great black hull of the Montana recedes into the darkness beyond the puny beams of their lights. It seems bigger than the Titanic and just as eerie in its final resting place. On it side, the sub's top deck becomes a wall along which the tiny submersibles are moving. Ahead, in the lights, is a white painted circle.</context>
      <utterance>Copy that.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the midship hatch. You see it, Cab Three?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, I see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get around so your lights are on the hatch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check. Then I just hang with these guys, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you want me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhite, Schoenick, and Monk unhook their short whip-umbilicals from the central manifold and roll off the side of Flatbed. They maneuver down toward the sub's hatch. Hippy guides Cab Three in closer to the hatch area.</context>
      <utterance>Just hold above it. Alright, A team.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand by on the ROV.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hippy nods and Perry drops Little Geek through the hatch into the water and feed out a length of tether. Hippy picks up the control box and watches the video screen, guiding the ROV toward the Montana's hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Perry, stand by on the ROV.  Sorry about this, little buddy. Better you than me, know what I mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Radiation is nominal. The warheads must still be intact.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many are there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>24 Trident missiles. Eight MIRVs per missile.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's 192 warheads... And how powerful are they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ... this is World War Three in a can.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's knock off the chatter, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting a reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's twitching but it's below the line you said was safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhite and Schoenick follow him through the escape trunk, into the dark corridor beyond.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Let's get in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go in through that large breach.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud's team leaves Flatbed, swimming forward. The opening is a black mouth in their lights. Coffey moves inside. Bud attaches one end of an orange nylon line to a piece of pipe and moves into the wreck behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jammer, Catfish, Finler, and Sonny follow him inside.</context>
      <utterance>Take it slow, stay on the line, and stay in sight. Watch for hatches that could close on you, or any loose equipment that could fall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jammer and Bud squeeze in around Coffey. Together they wrench the door open on its squealing hinges. It give way suddenly, flying open. The suction pulls SOMETHING THROUGH. It slams Bud's shoulder. He turns. A FACE... RIGHT IN FRONT OF HIM! He jerks back, gasping. Face to face with Barnes, the sonarman. The ensign seems unmarked, merely dismayed at his own mortality, judging from his wide eyes and mouth. Coffey reaches past Bud and pushes the ensign's body out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>It's jammed. Give me a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the control room. Their lights play over the high-tech wreckage. Floating debris and bodies make shifting shadows on the walls as they swirl in the currents. A languid, weightless waltz. They move through the carnage. Their lights pick out tableaux... the planesman still strapped in his chair, someone jammed into the ceiling pipes, hanging down. Dead faces, pale in the lights. Still. We see only glimpses. Coffey locates the captain's body and rolls it over. Removes the missile arming key which hangs on a chain around the dead man's neck. Moves on. All business. Bud turns back to his guys. Checking them. He notices Jammer is breathing so rapidly he's fogging his helmet. Catfish, Finler, and Sonny aren't much better. A wave a panic seems imminent.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, let's keep moving. We knew we were going to see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you guys doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm alright, I'm dealing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Triple time sounds like a lotta money, Bud. It ain't. I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Bud working, calming them, talking them through it. He's sweating rivers in his helmet, not looking too steady. His projection of calm to the others is his own salvation. Coffey pauses in the doorway to the communications room.</context>
      <utterance>We're here now. Let's get her done.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This part I do alone. Brigman, take you men and continue aft. Split up into two teams of two. Let's get moving... we head back in fourteen minutes. Bud leads his team into a narrow corridor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sweep their lights around the chamber. Jammer turns... his beam illuminating a body just beyond the door. A coveralled seaman turning slowly in the eddying current. Small albino crabs crawl slowly over the man's face. One scuttles out of his gaping mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Missile compartment. Those are the launch tubes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Almighty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud goes to him. Gets up close to his face. Sees that he's not. That he's hyperventilating. Fighting nausea. Bud grabs him by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deep and slow, big guy. Deep and slow. Just breathe easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... they're all dead, Bud. They're all dead. I thought... some of them... you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking you back out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud sees that the big diver's breathing has stabilized. He looks at his watch. Checker Jammer's pressure gauges.</context>
      <utterance>No! I'm okay now. I just don't... I can't go any further in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Jammer. No problem. You stay right here. I have to go there to the end... you'll see my lights. We'll stay in voice contact. Just hold onto the rope. Five more minutes. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves off through the center aisle of the gallery swimming between the huge cylinders. He pays out the lifeline as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, okay. Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUD, at the same moment, is fiddling with the connector cables on his helmet lights, which are dimming and flickering. He hears nothing from his helmet transceiver. JAMMER, smacks the side of his helmet. Shakes the transceiver on his belt. Nothing... just static. Then even the static dies. Panic time. He grabs the safety line and pulls twice. Hard. It is snagged on a sharp metal edge ten feet from him. He pulls twice more, harder, hauling the thing. The line severs. Jammer stared at the frayed and floating toward him. His eyes bug. He looks all around in the darkness. Can't see Bud. Can't decide what to do. We can see hysteria revving up inside him like a flywheel. Then he becomes aware of a faint radiance flickering over the walls. It is a cold and ethereal light, unlike the warm-white of their dive lights. It grows brighter. He turns slowly toward it. The glow is moving beneath the steel grill of the deck, sending shafts of cold light flickering upward hypnotically, coming toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Bud? BUD?! You readin' me? BUD?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C.U. JAMMER, shielding his eyes, staring into the radiant source. Guess what, Jammer? It's not Bud. In the brightest center of the glow, SOMETHING is moving, a figure casting strange inhuman shadow across the walls. Jammer blinks against the glare, his face registering total, outright astonishment melting into terror. The glare pulses subtly, hypnotically. The shifting shadow falls across Jammer. He finally snaps out of his fixity... Screaming and gulping air he spins away and starts clawing hand over hand through the treacherous wreckage. His harness catches on a twisted pipe. He struggles, totally out of control... the big man reduced to a blind panic. Jammer heaves forward with all his adrenalized strength. He tears free of the entangling debris. Launches like a torpedo... slamming his backpack full force into the top sill of the hatchway. His tri-mix regulator takes the full brunt of the impact. ON BUD, swimming furiously back toward Jammer's position. The strange radiance is gone. His dive light flare back to full brightness.</context>
      <utterance>Bud? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches Jammer only to find him thrashing violently in place. A seizure. Bud grapples with him.</context>
      <utterance>Jammer? Answer me, buddy, JAMMER?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catfish, Sonny, and Finler arrive from the corridor a moment later. They leap into the fray.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, big guy. Hand on!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's convulsing!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they're all yelling at once, grappling with the big man, struggling with the valves on his breathing gear.</context>
      <utterance>It's his mixture! Too much oxygen!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crank it down, man! We're gonna losing him...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHIT, it's stuck... goddamnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it?! You got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jammer's convulsion ends. He goes limp.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah... yeah. It's turning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drag Jammer's slack form into the corridor, hauling their way rapidly back along the lifeline.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta get him out of here. Come on!  Hang on, buddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She has a hard time focusing on what he's saying. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>CAB ONE! CAB ONE! Meet me at Flatbed! This is a diver emergency!! Do you copy? Lindsey?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy you, Bud. On my way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whattya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud, torn by guilt, gazes at the big man lying pathetically on the cot.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a medic, which is mostly about patching holes. This type of thing... there's not much I can do. The coma could last hours or days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative. But there was definitely a Russian bogey. The Brigman woman saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CINCLANTFLT's gonna go apeshit. Two Russian attack subs, a Tango and Victor, have been tracked within fifty miles of here... and now we don't know what the hell they are. Okay, I don't have any choice. I'm confirming you to go to Phase Two. Wilhite and Schoenick glance uneasily at each other. Coffey is silent. He is vibrating with tension... his fists clenched to prevent the shaking. He is wrestling with the moment, knowing it is, in a way, a point of no return.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey takes a deep breath. Lets it out. Phase Two is clearly a big deal.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I mean no. Negative, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get anything on the cameras. Video or anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Look, forget it. I don't want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Be that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what I saw. Okay? Coffey wants to call it a Russian submersible, fine. It's a Russian submersible. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you think it's something else. What? One of ours?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey is wrestling with a feeling which is somehow also certain knowledge.</context>
      <utterance>Whose then? Lindsey? Talk to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jammer saw something in there, something that scared the hell out him--</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His mixture got screwed up. He panicked and pranged his regulator.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what did he see that made him panic?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think he saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hippy comes pounding up, sticks his head in, gesturing animatedly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I DON'T KNOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow him into the corridor, trotting down to the mess hall.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you guys... hurry up, check this out! They're announcing it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet! Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn it up, bozo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>involvement in the sinking of the Trident sub USS Montana. The Navy has not released the names of the 156 crewmembers, who are all presumed dead at this time. Civilian employees of a Benthic Petroleum offshore drilling rig--</context>
      <utterance>... the Kremlin continues to deny Russian</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey that's us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--are apparently participating in the recovery operation but we have little information about their involvement. On the scene now is--</utterance>
   <speaker>FINLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BOOOOH! We want names!</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LONG LENSE VIDEO SHOT of the Benthic Explorer and the other vessels in a stormy sea CUTS TO a shot of BILL TYLER, the on-scene reporter, in rain gear, clutching his microphone. He is on the deck of a Navy support ship, being used as a staging area from the press, well away from the center of the operation.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey! There's the Explorer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With Cuba only 80 miles away, the massive buildup of US ships and aircraft in the area has drawn official protest from Havana and Moscow and has led to a redirection of Soviet warships into the Caribbean theater.</context>
      <utterance>--there is a tremendous amount of activity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you describe the mood there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mood is one of suspicion, even confrontation. A number of Russian and Cuban trawlers, undoubtedly surveillance vessels, have been circling within a few miles throughout the day, and Soviet aircraft have repeatedly been warned away from the area...</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we're right in the middle of this big-time international incident. Like the Cuban Missile Crisis or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figured that out for yourself, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got Russian subs creeping around. Shit! Something goes wrong they could say anything happened down here, man. Give our folks medals, know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hippy, just relax. You're making the women nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cute, Virgil.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean it. Those SEALs aren't telling us diddly. Something's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hippy, you think everything's a conspiracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Night is pounding down the corridor from the sub bay.</context>
      <utterance>Everything is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up! Coffey's splitting with Flatbed! He got me to show him the controls, then his guys suited up and they're rolling. Bud breaks into a run, passing her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit! D'you tell him we need it right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him we had to get the umbilical unhooked</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to get unhooked and get out of here... and your boys go sightseeing!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be back in two hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>De Marco's expression is infuriatingly calm... icy. McBride looks at his watch and swears under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Two hours?! We're gonna be getting the shit kicked out of us by our friend Fred in two hours!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEWS ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>VARIOUS CUTS of men in life jackets among huge waves... Rescue helicopters hovering. Shaky camera work. Wind blasting. INTERCUT WITH REACTIONS of the rig crew watching.</context>
      <utterance>Little is known at this hour about the events leading up to the collision. The US Navy guided missile cruiser Appleton apparently struck the Soviet 'Udaloy' class destroyer in low visibility conditions...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>SHOT OF AMERICAN CRUISER, burning, listing to one side in heavy seas. Replaced by SHOT OF NETWORK ANCHORMAN.</context>
      <utterance>In violent seas little hope remains for over a hundred Russian crewmen still missing after the sinking an hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It continues. Bud looks at Lindsey. She turns to him, expression grim.</context>
      <utterance>Soviet military spokesmen have claimed that the collision constituted an unprovoked attack. This was denied--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud, this is big time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch that. Just step away. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excusez moi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffey, we're a little pressed for time.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two SEALs unlash the object in the black bag. Bud an Lindsey exchange a glance. He glares at Coffey as they pass each other. One Night nimbly climbs the hatch-tower and drops in. Bud swings the heavy hatch up, balancing it, and grins down at One Night.</context>
      <utterance>Monk, Schoenick... secure the package.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't no drill, slick. Make me proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings the hatch closed with a CLANG.</context>
      <utterance>Piece of cake, baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud! We've lost the crane!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Say again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the signal over the speakers and the room fills with eerie PINGING. Bud shouts over the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Got it! It's dropping straight to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VARIOUS ANGLES, QUICK CUTS, as everyone runs to comply: The rig crew pounding down the narrow corridors. Diving through low hatchways. Hatches are closed and the wheels spun down. Hippy puts into a ZIP-LOK BAG and seals it.</context>
      <utterance>Rig for impact! Seal all exterior hatches. Move it! Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benthic Explorer, Benthic Explorer. Do you read, over? This is Deepcore--</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Sonny. They're gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you find Wilhite?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Bud lock eyes. Bud bites back on his recriminations, but his gaze blames Coffey. He turns away.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I was under orders. I had no choice. Coffey's manner is subdued, contrite. A marked contrast to his previous brusque arrogance. He's wrestling with his own loss, a sever blow to the tight brotherhood of a SEAL unit. Bud's anger is not dispelled. But he can't address it now. He moves on. PAST THE INFIRMARY, where Sonny Dawson is rigging a sling over his own broken arm. He cries out in pain, cursing at himself. LOOKING DOWN THE CENTRAL WELL as Bud crosses. Down through the grill decking we can see the bottom level of the module is flooded. Catfish is down there welding, sending shivering reflections through the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Brigman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the scoop, ace?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rather than trigger anger and invective, the disaster seems to have affected her in a different way. She's accepted the situation, now that's it's done, and is immersing herself in technical tasks, which are for her therapeutic.</context>
      <utterance>I can get power to this module and sub-bay if I remote these busses. I've gotta get past the mains, which are a total melt-down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need some help?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>won't be enough to run the heaters. In a couple hours this place is going to be as cold as a meat locker.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. No, I can handle it. Bud... there</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about O-2?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brace yourself. We've got about 12 hours worth if we close off the sections we're not using.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The storm's gonna last longer than 12 hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes back to her task, working efficiently with a socket wrench.</context>
      <utterance>I can extend that. There's some storage tanks outboard on the wrecked module. I'll have to go outside to tie onto them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lins...  I'm glad your here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well I'm not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right through the brainpan. Deader'n dogshit, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where're you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quarters. Level two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Perry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we just leave him there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, for now. Our first priority's to get something to breathe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cat, you tie onto this manifold. There's some tanks on the other side; I'm gonna go check them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to attach one end of a coiled-up high-pressure hose to a manifold. She takes the other end of the hose and moves off into the darkness. Little Geek goes with her faithfully.</context>
      <utterance>You watch yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a three-eighths socket on a long extension.  So there you were--</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There we were, side by side, on the same ship, for two months. I'm tool-pusher and we're testing this automated derrick of hers. So, we get back on the beach and... we're living together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't mean you had to marry her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were due to go back out on the same ship. Six months of tests. If you were married you got a state-room. Otherwise it was bunks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, good reason. Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was alright for a while, you know. But then she got promoted to project engineer on this thing, couple years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She went front-office on you. Tighten that for me, right there. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's jammed his fingers with a wrench torquing down a bolt. Whips his hand out.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know Lindsey, too damn aggressive-- Son of a--!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her arm around his shoulders, somehow managing to be fraternal, maternal and suggestive all at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>She didn't leave me... she just left me behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ACROSS THE CHAMBER, Hippy scowls as Little Geek's screen starts to go haywire with interference.</context>
      <utterance>Bud, let me tell you something. She ain't half as smart as she thinks she is. She smiles and pretends to kink Lindsey's air-hose.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lindsey, you reading me? Over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is the little vehicle she almost collided with at the Montana wreck. It comes right up behind her. She doesn't know it's there. It hovers sideways like a hummingbird, as if curious, trying to get a better look. She becomes aware of the pulsing glow on the ground around her. She turns slowly. We see her react as the glowing, pulsing apparition is reflected in her faceplate. A more powerful glow washes up onto her from below. Her eyes go down. She gasps, absolutely stunned... Above the edge of the wall, AN ENORMOUS SHAPE RISES SILENTLY OUT OF THE DEPTHS. Over sixty feet across. It looks like a blown glass manta ray, its transparent outer hull housing interior structures of great delicacy and complexity, pulsing with a blue-violet glow. Lindsey stand before it, unable to move. Absolutely rapt. Captivated by its ethereal beauty. It begins to turn, majestically, one rounded wing passing only a few feet above her. She reaches up. Touches it as it passes over her. Lindsey is without fear, completely mesmerized. The thing completes its turn and dives gracefully down along the wall. She is gently lifted by a backwash of turbulent water. About that time, Lindsey remembers she has a still camera, a little Nikonos. She fumbles to set focus and exposure with her bulky gloves as the beautiful machine glides into the depths. Gets all set for a shot and... WOOSH! The little 'scoutschip' whizzes past her from behind, startling her. She completely misses the shot of the 'manta ship'. She pivots, trying to get a shot of the little one as it zig-zags down along the wall, fast as a meteor. CLICK. She get a shot a second before it disappears. From around the flank of the rig module, Catfish appears. Their com-sets come backs to life, along with their lights.</context>
      <utterance>Catfish... I got a problem here. You there? Catfish? Behind her, SOMETHING rises from the depths.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better not say you missed that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Missed what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice shot, Lins.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDER, SHOWING THE GROUP huddled around Lindsey who has her freshly-processed slide roll laid out on the pinball machine, using it as a light table.</context>
      <utterance>What is that? You drop your dive light?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you guys... look, this is the little one right here. You can see how it's kind of zigging around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say so. It could be anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. Sees a lot of skepticism in the eyes around her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you what is there. You're just not hearing. The impulses somehow aren't getting from you ears to your brainpan. There's something down there. Something not... us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all could be more specific.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not us. Not human. Get it? Something non- human, but intelligent...</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey is reddening. Despite her conviction, this is really hard.</context>
      <utterance>You mean like Coffey?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A non-terrestrial intelligence.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hippy is not really mocking her. He's actually into it. But it has that effect. Catfish is eyeing Lindsey like he's never seen her before.</context>
      <utterance>Non-Terrestrial Intelligence. NTIs. Yeah, I like that better then UFOs. Although that works too... Underwater Flying Objects.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we talkin' little space friend here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on! Hot rods of the Gods. Right, Lins? Hey, no really! It could be NTIs. The CIA has known about them for years. They abduct people all the time. There was this woman I knew in Albuquerque who--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud takes her firmly by the arm. Heads her out into the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Hippy, do me a favor... stay off my side.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lindsey, will you step into my office for a minute...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Lindsey--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud, something really important is happening here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. I'm just trying to hold this situation together. I can't allow you to cause this kind of hysteria--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're talking across each other, not connecting. Bud weary and frustrated. Lindsey is cranked up with the afterglow of her encounter.</context>
      <utterance>Who's hysterical? Nobody's hysterical!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is when you're hanging on by your fingernails, you don't go waving you arms around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw something! I'm not going to go back there and say I didn't see it when I did. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you are the most stubborn woman I ever knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to believe me, Bud. Look at me. Do I seem stressed out? Any of the symptoms of pressure sickness, any tremors, slurred speech?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud is stilled by her intensity. She moves close to him. Eyes alive and luminous.</context>
      <utterance>Bud, this is me, Lindsey. Okay? You know me better than anybody in the world. Now watch my lips... I saw these things. I touched one of them. And it wasn't some clunky steel can like we would build... it glided. It was the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a machine, but it seems almost alive. Like a... dance of light. Bud, you have to trust me... please. I don't think they mean us harm. I don't know how I know that, it's just a feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I go on a feeling? You think Coffey's going to go on you 'feeling'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud has been taking this all in. His eyes tracking her face. He closes his eyes, taking a deep breath. It's so hard for him to do this, but...</context>
      <utterance>We all see what we want to see... Coffey looks and he sees Russians, he sees hate and fear. Bud, you have to look with better eyes than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't, Lindsey. I'm sorry. How can I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>warning if the Soviet craft try another incursion.</context>
      <utterance>I want 'round-the-clock manning of the sonar shack and the exterior cameras. We need early</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why haven't you finished repairs on the hydrophone transmitter yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey is sweating, despite the chill. Keeps his hands clenched in fists so they won't see how bad the tremors have gotten.</context>
      <utterance>I was having my nails done.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get something straight. You people are under my authority--</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey's eyes are straight razors. He slashes them from face to face. You can see him tightening up like a clockspring, losing control of the situation in front of his own men. Bud defuses it.</context>
      <utterance>Look, podner... we don't work for you, we don't take orders from you, and we don't much like you. In addition to which your momma dresses you funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fish'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>handle the exterior surveillance. One Night, see if you can get that transmitter working for me, okay?</context>
      <utterance>Take the first watch in sonar. Hippy, you</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD ON COFFEY as everyone leaves. Winding tighter.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a couple of hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE SCREEN, Geek's POV. Coffey is blocking Hippy's view of whatever it is they're working on. Abruptly, be moves. The warhead is lying there in plain sight, detonator wires hooked up. Hippy's eyes bug out. He knows exactly what it is.</context>
      <utterance>Come on... move to the left... just a little more... come on, A.J. Squared Away... that's it--</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries to the VCR and puts it into RECORD.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty radical, guys. Pretty radical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bud has his face right up to screen. He frowns, skeptical.</context>
      <utterance>Say hello to MIRV.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, man. What else could it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why bring it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud whips around. Lindsey, standing quietly in the doorway. It's apparent from expression she's been watching them for some time. She looks ready to kill somebody. Then she's gone.</context>
      <utterance>It's gotta be, like, an emergency plan to keep it away from the Russians... Hotwire one of the nukes with some kinda detonator, put it back in the sub, and fry the whole thing, slicker'n snot. Oh, uh... hi, Lins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, goddamnit, if you won't do something about it, I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches the watertight door to Maintenance Room B. It's locked. Before Bud can stop her she grabs a fire-extinguisher off the wall and pounds on the steel door like a big gong. BOOM! BOOM! BOOM! Needless to say, it opens. She pushes past Schoenick, see the bomb lying there naked.</context>
      <utterance>Lindsey! Wait a second--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>thing... into my rig! With everything that's been going on up in the world, you bring a nuclear weapon in here? Does this strike anyone as particularly psychotic, or is it just me?</context>
      <utterance>You've got some huevos bringing this...</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to know the details of this mission... you're better off if you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right... I don't. I just need to know that this thing is out of here! You hear me, Roger Ramjet?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Brigman, you're becoming a serious impediment to this mission. I believe the stress is affecting you.  Escort her to quarters and have Monk prepare a tranquilizer. Schoenick takes her arm in a tight grip.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey goes bananas, trying to get Schoenick's big hands off her arms. Bud slams his hand down on the intercom button.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit, you can't do that. Oww... goddamnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the fire alarm for good measure and spins on Coffey... warning him with a look that is not to be messed with. Coffey is braced back against the worktable... an odd stance, with one arm behind his back. Suddenly there's a crowd outside the door as Catfish, Hippy, One Night, and Sonny come running up. Confrontation time. Sirens going. About a million volts of electricity in the air. Bud braces Schoenick.</context>
      <utterance>Emergency! Maintenance room B. Emergency!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does. Lindsey jerks away. Rubs her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Let her go. Do it... right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dumb jarhead motherf--</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill out, Lindsey!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is frozen in place. Bud a Coffey... snake and mongoose, glaring. Bud pulls Lindsey back into the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE FROM BEHIND COFFEY, as Bud's group moves out of sight up the corridor. Hands behind his back. In his hand, cocked, finger on the trigger, is the .45. He turns and sets it on the table, steadying himself as if in the wind. he seems to sag. When he looks at Schoenick, his eyes are wounds. A hunted animal. Voice shaky.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. We were just leaving.  Weren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't be trusted. They're turning against us. We may have to take... steps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lins, stay away from that guy. I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. The dude's in bad shape... you see his hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the shakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, the guy's operating on his own, cut off from chain of command. He's exhibiting symptoms of pressure-induced psychosis. And he's got a nuclear weapon. So, as a personal favor to me... will you put your tongue in neutral for a while?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, I give this a sphincter-factor of about nine point five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you can just punch into his little chip where you want him to go, and he goes, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, but the tether off it ain't gonna be fancy. When he gets down there he'll just sit, like a dumb-shit. Unless something wanders through view of the camera, you'll get nada.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go for it. We could get lucky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I really oughta talk to Bud about this. E.C.U. COFFEY. Watching them in the dark. Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just you and me. We get some proof, then tell them. Hippy, look... if was can prove to Coffey it's not Russians, maybe he'll ease off the button a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta tell you, that guy scares me a lot more than whatever's down there. A.J. Squared Away goddamn jarhead robot. Okay, gimme a couple hours on this. Coffey watches, his jaw clenched.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey sips hers, staring. Her thoughts are far away... in the bottomless pit. She is leaning up against the table where Bud is sleeping. His soft snoring downshifts into a loud rasp. Lindsey touches him gently on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud grunts and turns without waking, an automatic response. The snoring stops. It is a quiet, intimate moment, a reminder of the mileage these two have logged together.</context>
      <utterance>Virgil, turn on your side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her liquid face suddenly transforms into a likeness of Bud's. She reaches out her hand slowly. Gingerly, her fingers touch the surface. Ripples extend outward from the contact, across Bud's features. Her fingertips break effortlessly through the surface, just like she's dipping her hand into a bowl of water, except sideways. She draws her wet fingers out and studies them, amazed. Touches one fingertip to her tongue.</context>
      <utterance>It's trying to communicate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pseudopod pulls back from her. It loops in the air dramatically, full circle... and ties itself into a knot. As the knot tightens down, it melts back into the body. The 'disappearing knot' trick. Lindsey laughs, grinning with the open wonder and delight of a child at a magic show. She is transported.</context>
      <utterance>Seawater.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Bud. He grins broadly. He's with her now. The stunned group watches as the thing moves on across the room. Out to the corridor</context>
      <utterance>Show off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey is looking out from under his eyebrows like Nicholson in "The Shining". Bud give her a warning look. Don't poke at the rattler.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, raise your hand if you think that was a Russian water-tentacle. Lieutenant? No? Well, a breakthrough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You done impressing yourself, ace?</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way that could just be seawater.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must've learned how to control water... I mean at a molecular level. They can plasticize it, polymerize it... whatever. Put it under intelligent control.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey is hunched over, elbows on his knees. His hands are out of sight. His arm is moving in a slow rhythm. We can't see what he's doing.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe their whole technology is based on that. Controlling water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing was probably their version of Big Geek... like an ROV.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE UNDER THE TABLE, showing what Coffey is doing. He has his K-BAR KNIFE gripped white-knuckle in one hand. He is drawing it slowly and repeatedly across the skin of the other forearm. Neat chevrons of blood from wrist to elbow. C.U. COFFEY -- He doesn't flinch. His eyes are hard and bright as diamond drills. No one notices. He's keeping the edge.</context>
      <utterance>Just checking is out, huh? How come?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're curious, maybe. We could be the first people they've seen up close.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope they don't judge the whole race offa us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey stands abruptly, snags Schoenick with his eyes, and leaves, walking through the group as if they were smoke. This cold behavior brings the mood down a notch.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I oughta shave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It went straight for the warhead. And they think it's cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOENICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffey walks away without hearing him. Schoenick catches up.</context>
      <utterance>You need to get some sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schoenick doesn't know. He hopes Coffey knows. Because he's a fearless man who's discovering what it is to be afraid. Coffey inserts the magazine with a CLACK! Snaps the bolt. Tosses the rifle to Schoenick.</context>
      <utterance>We have no way of warning the surface. Do you know what that means?</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means... whatever happens is up to us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they're from down there originally? Or from... you know. She jerks her thumb toward the ceiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they're from 'you know'. Some place that has similar conditions... cold, intense pressure. No light.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy as hogs in a waller down there, prob'ly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands his gun to Monk, with the assumption of absolute loyalty from a team member. Monk's eyes move between Coffey and the pistol. We can't tell what he's thinking. Coffey grabs Hippy and shoves him onto a chair.</context>
      <utterance>FREEZE! Don't move. That's it.  Here, hold this a second. We're going to phase three.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey looks stricken. Her plan is betraying them all.</context>
      <utterance>They're using Big Geek to take the bomb to the NTIs! We set it up to go right to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning he grabs her by the hair and hurls her against the Coke machine, pinning her there with one hand. Bud leaps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... Oh no...  Please, you can't. Coffey, think about what you're doing... for God's sake-- Coffey lets her approach him, his eyes glittering.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand reaches down, OUT OF FRAME. We hear something RIP. His hand comes back up... holding a piece of gaffer's tape. He slaps it over her mouth. Then pushes her down into a chair. Hippy looks at Monk and Schoenick.</context>
      <utterance>This is something I've wanted to do since I first met you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boss is having a full-on meltdown. Guy's fixing to pull the pin on fifty kilotons and we're all ringside!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the timer set for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHOENICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Don't talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't get to minimum-safe-distance in three hours. The shockwave will kill us. It'll crush this rig like a semi driving over a beer can.</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody is twitching a hyper. Schoenick is white-knuckling his assault rifle... looking from Monk to Coffey to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! SHUT UP! What's the matter with you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stay calm. The situation is under control. Coffey backs out quickly with Schoenick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schoenick... your Lieutenant is about to make a real bad career move...</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy's crazier'n a shithouse rat!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pound on the door. Schoenick turns and hangs his cap over the tiny window.</context>
      <utterance>We have to stop him! Schoenick!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... he's about to declare war on an alien species, Schoenick, just when they're trying to make contact with us.  I think I'm reaching him. There is a CLUNK-CLATTER and the door unlatches.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. Jammer is standing there. Schoenick is in a heap against the far wall, moaning. Jammer hands the rifle to Hippy as he walks in. Hippy turns to cover the other SEAL. Monk puts his hands up, passively.</context>
      <utterance>See?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud appraises Jammer, who seems a little weak and dazed but basically okay.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the least of your problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. How you feeling, big guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figured I was dead, there, when I seen that angel comin' toward me. They all look at him for a second. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, okay, right. You can tell us about it later. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's jammed the mechanism.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're locked in trimodule-C. No other doors give access to the sub-bay corridor. Bud's mind is racing. He drops down the ladder to Level One, into about two feet of water. He reaches down and open the emergency lockout hatch. Takes off his boots.</context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm gonna free-swim to hatch six... get inside, get the door open from the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud, that water's only a couple degrees above freezing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I guess you better wish me luck, huh? Catfish is pulling his boots off as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud clasps him on the shoulder and starts hyperventilating. He drops into the water.</context>
      <utterance>Wish us luck.  'Case I don't die. Okay, Bud... let's go, podner, I ain't got all day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hafta... go on to... the moonpool. Only way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud looks at Catfish, shivering and heaving, wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>I can't... make it... podner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud hyperventilates rapidly and pikes over diving back out through the hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Cat. You head back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't get to the door... I think he's going to try and take him himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE SCREEN, Bud picks up a piece of pipe. Hefts it. Moves forward, crouched... stalking. Lindsey yells at the screen in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>He couldn't be that dumb. The guy's a trained killer. Bud's idea of a fight is arm-wrestling One Night over laundry duty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catfish is right behind him. Dripping wet. A trail of water goes back to the moonpool a few feet away. CRACK! Catfish's 'Hammer' punch comes in so hard and so fast, Coffey is knocked right on his ass. He doesn't get up. Just sort of flops around. Catfish helps Bud to his feet. They advance on Coffey, who crab-scuttles sideways, his eyes rabid. He picks up a helium tank and hurls it at them. As they duck he sprints to Flatbed and drops through the hatch and slams it down.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud leaps across the water to land on Flatbed. The hatch is already sealed. He grapples with Geek/MIRV, trying to free it from the steel claw.</context>
      <utterance>Get the door!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs it out of Hippy's hands and aims it at the sub. He racks the water with a long burst. BENEATH THE SURFACE, the rounds nip nasty contrails through the water. They barely scar the front port.</context>
      <utterance>Give me that!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catfish rakes the descending sub with more bursts, trying to hit the shimmering shape of the ROV on its back. UNDERWATER we see the rounds arcing wild, a few hitting the ROV but causing little damage. Coffey complete his descent to just above the seafloor. ABOVE, Catfish empties the weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Forget that... go for Big Geek!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn. Bud is fumbling into his wetsuit like a madman. The others rush over to help him.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catfish slams a backpack onto Bud's shoulders, grappling with the straps and hose connections. Hippy and Sonny (with one hand) are clipping, zipping and buckling all over him. This is a world-record suit-up time. Bud pulls the rubber neck-dam of the helmet's lower ring down over his face.</context>
      <utterance>Get the rest of my gear. Grab that hat there... let's go guys! Come on, come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helmet... helmet! Work fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me one, Virgil.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points. Through the front port, they can see the ROV still straining at its leash. Lindsey dives toward it, simultaneously working the controls to open her own small manipulator claws.</context>
      <utterance>Can we negotiate later? There's Big Geek.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did okay, back there. I was fairly impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not good enough. We still gotta catch Big Geek.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey is flipping switches. Nothing works.</context>
      <utterance>Not in this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You totaled it, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud looks down. There's already about a foot of water sloshing around the floor at their feet.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. So sue me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's flooding like a son of the bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up and hand-mike of the underwater telephone.</context>
      <utterance>You noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deepcore, Deepcore, this is Cab One, over. She waits. No response.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a SEARING CRACKLE or arc-light, a power panel shorts out and everything goes black.</context>
      <utterance>Deepcore, this is Cab One. We need assistance, over. Deepcore, this--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A faint illumination, dimmer than moonlight, washes in through the front port. Lindsey scrunches up against the acrylic and scans the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful.  There's some light from somewhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A glow, beyond a rock promontory... like the lights of a town just over the hill in the desert.</context>
      <utterance>Over there. It's the rig.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good hundred yards, I'd say.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll come out after us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his helmet and clicks on the light. Using the thing like a bulky flashlight. The water is really pouring in, spraying them like a shower... almost two feet deep already.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it's gonna take them a while to find us. We better get this flooding stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see where it's coming in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the light and he tries to reach the burst weld, which is blocked by a steel switch panel and a bunch of conduit.</context>
      <utterance>Somewhere behind this panel. Hold this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't get to it. Have to pull this panel off. You go any tools?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud scans the cramped interior, feels around under the water. It's past his knees.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, look around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the panel in both hands and starts torquing on it, trying to wrench it off the wall. Heaves on it repeatedly. Finally stops, panting. He's breathing hard now, and it's not just effort.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Son of a bitch. All I need's a goddamn crescent wrench.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nervous edge in her voice now. Bud's turning all around, looking around for anything, trying to think fast. Water up to their waists. The sea closing in.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... okay. We gotta get you out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how!</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've only got one suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know! I know! But we better come up with something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs up on the pilots seat, scrunching right up against the ceiling, keeping as much of herself as possible out of the frigid water. She's shaking all over with the cold, and getting drenched from above by water pouring in.</context>
      <utterance>Aaargh!! I'm freezing!</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, look, you swim to the rig and come back with another suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That stops the conversation for a second. About two feet of airspace left. Bud can't believe what this is coming down to. They both stare at each other for a long moment. He makes a decision. Starts pulling off his backpack.</context>
      <utterance>Seven, eight minute swim each way... not enough time. Look at this...  Time I get back you'll be--</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, put this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you growing gills all of a sudden? You got it on, keep it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't argue, goddamnit, just--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud has his pack off uncoupling it. She keeps fighting his hands, stopping him, hooking it back up. The desperation of the situation fuel the struggle.</context>
      <utterance>No way! Forget it. Not an option.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lindsey, just put the thing on and shut up--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO!! Now be logical, Bud, you're--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen... will you listen to me for a second!? You're for the suit on and you're a better swimmer than me. Right? So I got a plan...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drown, you tow me back to the rig--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud stops moving and looks into her face, inches from him. The water is up to their necks. He knows that, as always, infuriatingly, Lindsey is right.</context>
      <utterance>Look, this water is only a couple degrees above freezing. I drown. I go into deep hypothermia... my blood like icewater. I can maybe be revived after ten, fifteen minutes. You got all the stuff to do it on the rig.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a deep breath. Before her nerve fails she busies her hands on his suit, rehooking everything.</context>
      <utterance>It's the only way, Bud. Now trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raise his helmet. Water up to their chins. They lock eyes, inches apart. He can feel her breath on his face... maybe for the last time.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I don't believe this is happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Lins... I--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her head in both hands and pulls her mouth to his. They lock together in a fierce kiss, fueled by passion and terror... the naked realization of love hanging over the abyss of death. She breaks away at the last possible second and quickly pulls his helmet over his head. Seats is down over the neck ring. Lock the bail-out handle, sealing it. Even with her head press up into the highest point of the ceiling, Lindsey's mouth is barely above water. She give a scared little laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is half-paralyzed with the cold, shaking pathetically. Puts her face to the glass of his helmet. Seconds to go.</context>
      <utterance>This is maybe not such a great plan, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't hear her, but he read her lips. They clutch each other desperately. The embrace last while the water rises over her mouth and nose. She starts to choke. Her hands grip his shoulders like claws. She bucks and thrashes. Bud holds her, and a scream tears loose from him, a pure agony of the soul.</context>
      <utterance>Hold me. Hold me, Bud... I'm so scared...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Bud. Oh my God... that's Lindsey! BUD  Deepcore, Deepcore, do you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read you, Bud. We're here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to the infirmary... get the cart .. oxygen... de-fib kit... adrenaline in a... ten cc syringe... and some... heating blankets. You got all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me in the moonpool. Move fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jammer and Sonny leap into the freezing water, waist deep on the submerged diving platform. Bud bursts to the surface. Together they haul Lindsey across the platform, out of the water, and onto the deck. Her skin is blue- white, her chest still. Bud rips his helmet off in a near-frenzy, like a man possessed, a man with a mission. The others are galvanized by his energy even though they all see Lindsey as dead, a corpse... cold and inert. Water flows from her mouth and nose and her lips are blue, her limbs completely limp. Hippy peels back one eyelid, to find the pupil fixed and dilated. But when Bud shouts for them to move, they move.</context>
      <utterance>Here he comes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They flip his wife's body over. He straddles her, pushing down with both hands in the middle of her back. Seawater gushes from her slack lips. He does it again until the flow stops, then flips her onto her back.</context>
      <utterance>Turn her over!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Night and Catfish are fumbling with the emergency cart equipment. They've all been trained in CPR and use of the gear but that was years ago, and is a friend they're working on. They're all thumbs. Catfish drops the electrodes, picks them up quickly, hands them to Bud...</context>
      <utterance>Come on, hurry! Gimme the de-fib...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud rips into her clothing, opening her jumpsuit, literally tearing away her T-shirt, revealing her bare chest... bony and still.</context>
      <utterance>Here, here, here... no, you got to have bare skin, or it won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps the things into Lindsey's bare skin, one on the sternum and one on the side of the rib cage.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Gimme those, come on. Catfish, move it, man! Come on... come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that it? Is this right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! I mean, I don't know... it looks right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Night hits the switch and Lindsey's body convulses. It is a pure muscle reflex, and when it is over, there is not a hint of life. Hippy pushes him back and puts a black rubber oxygen mask over her mouth. He opens the valve on the cylinder and starts pumping the squeeze bag. They start packing electronic blankets around her to fight the intense hypothermia</context>
      <utterance>All right. Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The current hits Lindsey again and her back arches. Bud doesn't wait for a result... he's in his own reality now, driven. He's doing it all at once, somehow, in a senseless frenzy... pumping on her chest with his hands, squeezing the oxygen bag, placing the electrodes.</context>
      <utterance>Do it again, One Night. Zap her again!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey's back arches. Her body relaxes, inert.</context>
      <utterance>Aw. Christ... come on, baby. Again! Do it again!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hush seems to have fallen over the group. They know instinctively that it's over. But Bud can't accept it. He looks at them, beseechingly, like they are somehow intentionally holding out on him. One Night starts to cry, quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, One Night... what are you waiting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do. And Bud works, feverishly. He lock his lips over hers and starts mouth-to-mouth. It is frantic, passionate... the kiss of life.</context>
      <utterance>No! NO! She's not... her heart is strong, she wants to live... can't you see that? Come on, Lins. Come on, baby! Zap her again! Do it... DO IT!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps her face, hard. Her head lolls. He smacks her the other way.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, breath! Goddamn it, you bitch, you never backed down from anything in life... now fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LINDSEY's POV, from the bottom of the great well. The circles of faces and light rockets toward us in the blackness, as we soar upward from the pit. We see Bud yelling, but his voice is distant, windlike.</context>
      <utterance>Fight, Goddamnit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look on in wonder as Bud wills this woman back. She starts to cough, weakly at first... then more violently as she draws air into her lungs. Bud crouches over her, rubbing her limbs... trying to re- establish circulation. It is like a difficult birth. Lindsey comes hacking and howling back into the world, wet and naked and fighting for breath. Bud puts the oxygen mask over her face and she draws breath after agonized breath. He pushes her wet hair back from her face with his trembling hands, and watches her breathe. Color is returning to her skin as she lies there, gasping weakly. ONE THE GROUP... Catfish, Hippy, One Night, Jammer, the others... they're all grinning, crying, beaming... gazing at the miracle of her rebirth. ON BUD... tears are streaming down his face.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Lins. You can do it... fight your way back, baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did it, ace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... big boys don't cry, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, tough guy. I guess it worked, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Course is worked. You're never wrong, are you? How d'you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been better. Next time it's your turn, okay? Bud's expression turn inexplicably grim.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you got that right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Bud, no... not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around at the others. Sees their eyes. The fear. Has her answer. He lowers the helmet over his head. Catfish clamps it down. We see what's driving him... his sense of responsibility for these people, for not being able to prevent this situation. He touches her cheek, one last time. She sees his fingers are trembling. Then he puts on the gloves. Catifsh is strapping a KEYPAD UNIT onto Bud's forearm. Lindsey wants to scream... to stop this madness. BUD (muffled) So I'll hear you, but I can't talk?</context>
      <utterance>Who then?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His breathing is shallow and tense. He looks at Lindsey. The eyes of a condemned man. She squeezes his hand. He takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>The fluid prevents your larynx from making sound. It'll feel a little strange. BUD  Warning you now, folks, I'm a lousy typist.  The moment of truth, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monk gently cracks a valve on the suit's feed line. The breathing fluid (3M fluorocarbon emulsion FX-80) swirls into the helmet. Bud reflexively raises his chin. The liquid fills toward his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's rock and roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, there's nothing in there to breathe but liquid. His eyes go wide, instant panic. He starts to thrash. Chest heaving.</context>
      <utterance>Relax now, Bud. Just keep breathing as it fills... don't fight it. Take it in. Just let yourself take it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey grabs Bud's shoulders, steadying him. He finds her eyes, the look calming him. He's passed into a realm from which she has already returned. His spasms subside. He begins to "breathe" normally. He gets a goofy look of wonder on his face, not really believing what he's experiencing. He is alive, alert and quite completely drowned inside the FBS helmet. He grins. Gives a big thumbs up. Lindsey picks up a microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Hold him. Hold him. This is normal... it'll pass in a second. You're gonna be okay. We all breathe liquid for nine months, Bud. Your body will remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bud taps out a brief message. FEELS WEIRD - YOU SHOULD TRY THIS prints out on their portable monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Can you hear me okay?  Try your keypad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They help Bud to the edge of the dive platform. Jammer and Hippy lower Little Geek into the water and Bud grabs onto it. Hippy yells right up next to his helmet.</context>
      <utterance>I already have, moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a few seconds, she can't see him. Her chin quivers, minutely.</context>
      <utterance>I redid Little Geek's chip the same as Big Geek! He should take you right to it. All you gotta do is hang on! Lindsey crouches at the edge to watch Bud submerge. He looks up at her as he drops away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4800 feet. It's official.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud, according to Monk here, you just set a record for the deepest suit dive. Bet you didn't think you'd be doing this when you got up this morning. The screen print out: CALL GUINESS. They laugh. So far so good. Seconds later...</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One mile down and still grinnin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>8500 feet, Bud. Everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him a pressure effects. Tremors, vision problems, euphoria.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE SCREEN, printing out: COLD.</context>
      <utterance>Ensign Monk want to know how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then: HANDS SHAKING. HHARD TO TYPE.</context>
      <utterance>Big baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's starting. It hits the nervous system first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep talking, Lindsey. Just let him hear your voice. It doesn't matter what about.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey has somehow tuned out the others in the room. In her mind she is with Bud, out in the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget Bud, you're being graded on spelling as well as sentence structure, so concentrate, okay?  Bud, I... uh, there's some things I want to say. It's hard for me. I'm not of those softy, gooey- center-type people. It's not easy, you know, being a cast-iron bitch. It takes discipline and years of training. A lot of people don't appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>remember that bike trip... we rode the Honda up through Oregon? It took me a week to get my hair untangled, but I've never been happier. It was the most... free... I've ever felt. I'm sorry I can't tell you these things to your face.</context>
      <utterance>But is wasn't all bad. I know that. You</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two miles down and still grinnin' Comin' up on the big ten thou'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bottom's still a mile and a half down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>12000 feet. Jesus, I don't believe he's doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Hippy. Bud, how you doing? He types: SE LUMINUS THINNGS Everyone snaps suddenly alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of luminous things, Bud?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen prints out: ITS OK. SQUID. GLOWING SQUID.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's... you know... them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's losing it. Talk to him. Keep him with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Concentrate on my voice. Just listen to my voice.</context>
      <utterance>Bud, it's the pressure. Try to concentrate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going away, Bud. I'm right here, right here with you. This is Lindsey, Bud. I'm right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Signal's fading.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone hustles to comply. The room is plunged into darkness, the faces of the group lit only by the ghostly CRT screen.</context>
      <utterance>We're losing juice... kill everything we don't need. Catfish, knock out those lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run it through the digital processor, cook it as much as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen thousand feet. Good Christ Almighty, this is insane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little Geek just folded.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, little buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can still make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey seems not to be in the room, but to be with him, seeing what he sees. She is oblivious to the others.</context>
      <utterance>I know how alone you feel... alone in all that cold blackness... but I'm there in the dark with you, Bud you're not alone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing. Hippy and One Night start checking the equipment. Lindsey tried unsuccessfully to keep the terror our of here voice.</context>
      <utterance>How you doin', podner? Still with us, come-back? Talk to us, Buddy boy. They watch the screen, expectantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an agonizing pause, then the letters appear slowly: SHAKING STOPED.</context>
      <utterance>Bud? You hangin' in there? Talk to me, Bud. Are you okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Bud, we'll go step by step. Take the cover plate off the firing box. A long pause. Then... PLATE OFF</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Bud, you have to cut the ground wire, not the lead wire...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bud is staring. Blinking. The two wire look big as sewer pipes, and they're miles away... way down there where his hands are. The only light he has left is a CYALUME STICK. He pulls out the little plastic tube. Breaks and shakes. It starts to glow, a tiny wand of green light. He fumbles with his tool pouch, takes out a pair of side-cutters. CUTING NNOW he types to them. He reaches into the detonator. DETAIL, THE WIRES... in the green Cyalume glow, the look identical. The cutters go over on wire. A long beat. They withdraw, then go over the other wire... He cuts--</context>
      <utterance>It's the blue wire with the white stripe, not... I repeat... NOT the black wire with the yellow stripe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would we see the flash?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're holding their breaths. Then... STILL HERE A cheer goes up. Rebel yells.</context>
      <utterance>Through three miles of water? I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet, quiet! Save you air, goddamnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bud, give me a reading off you liquid oxygen gauge. TEN MINUTES WORTH ID SAY. Lindsey does white.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's hopeless. Lindsey grabs the headset from Monk.</context>
      <utterance>It took him over an hour to get down there--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop you weights and start back now! The gauge could be wrong...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey's voice has twisted into a sob. She begins to weep, quietly.</context>
      <utterance>No! You can make it! You hear me? Drop your weights... you... can breathe shallow... you... it could be wrong--</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Virgil, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONT CRY BABY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pause. Then the words...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOVE YOU WIFE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She stares at the printout.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no reply.</context>
      <utterance>Love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice echoes metallically in the strange chamber. Soft laps of water from the 'walls'. In the air a pattern of glowing lines appears, a series of what appears to be circuit diagrams. Bud staggers back from this strange 'screen' hanging in mid-air. The image is about twenty feet across. There is a rolling jumble of static and interference which resolves into... the face of Dan Rather, doing the evening news. STATIC, then another newscast. And another. Fragments of the same story. The world on the brink of war.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Uuuh... how you guys doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time, we're allowed to focus on the story. An on-the-scene interview outside a high-tech seismology lab. There is an air of hysteria about the scene... technicians running across the background of the shot, people shouting, the reporter jamming his mike at the harried-looking scientist.</context>
      <utterance>You watch out TV? That what you're trying to say? That you know what's been going on up there? The NTIs are impassive. Static... then another newscast.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Berg is edgy and distracted. People keeps handing him pieces of paper, computer hardcopy. The biggest thing in his life is happening...</context>
      <utterance>... a Caltech scientist who is among those reporting an unprecedented disturbance in the world's oceans. Dr. Breg, can you give us a clearer explanation then we're getting?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An assistant runs up, face shiny with fear, beckoning. We see that Berg is running scared. The impossible bringing the greatest terror to the rational mind.</context>
      <utterance>They're acoustic shockwaves, like tsunamis, but with no seismological source. The waves are propagating toward the shorelines of every continent--</utterance>
   <speaker>BERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image dissolves into static, fades out. Bud turns to the NTIs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'll be right there... I have to go. Look, we don't know what it is! Okay? Not the slightest goddamn idea!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Static again, then a brilliant flash. Grainy stock film of a hydrogen bomb test in the Pacific. The film repeats, and then again, faster, and again until is merges into an unbroken white glare. Bud gets the message.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing it! Right? That's what you're telling me. Yeah, you can control water... that's your technology. But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen exploded into a staccato series of searing images, stark moments from recent history... US soldiers fighting in Vietnam, street warfare in Beirut, a car bomb in Belfast, a suspect shot in the head in the streets of Saigon, burned and bleeding children, grainy footage of corpses bulldozed into mass graves at Auschwitz, Wermacht soldiers marching in goose-step review, a 13-year-old contra with an AK-47... Just glimpses, strobing... a few frames of each. But enough. The images continue. HOLD ON BUD, as the lights flicker on his face, the ongoing indictment of humanity.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you don't know they're really gonna do it. Where do you get off passing judgment on us, when you can't be sure? How do you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen darkens. Then letters appears on it, slowly printing out, as if someone was clumsily typing them.</context>
      <utterance>Why? You could've done it. Why didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WE KNEW THIS WAS...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we've seen this before so we know the rest...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deepcore, do you read? This is Benthic Explorer, over.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yes, we read! Good of you to join us. How's that storm doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>itself out all of the sudden. We're up here in a flat sea with no wind. But then a lot of weird things've been happening.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's strange... it just kind've blew</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LATER, Hippy, Catfish, and Monk are conferring B.G. on how to get a new umbilical hooked on. One Night is talking to McBride on the hydrophone.</context>
      <utterance>Well, hell, son. You better get us a line down here, we're in moderately poor shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They figure is was over a half mile high.</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances down at the telemetry screen, seeing movement.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could have seen it--</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hey! HEY!! Look... it's Bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey bolts to the screen. Stares at the message printing out. A huge grin wraps around her face.</context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lindsey take the mike and sits before the screen. During the message, her voice will go through an emotional spectrum from confusion to wonder, to a childlike joy.</context>
      <utterance>What's it say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCBRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you boys might by out of business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENDIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bendix is hunched over the sonar, and we can see the screens lit up like a Wurlitzer.</context>
      <utterance>Something's going on down there. I'm getting some big readings....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENDIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Active is pinging back something big... it's enormous! Coming up right under us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENDIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? EVERYWHERE!!  Over there! Port bow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BENDIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAT THEY SEE -- Fifty yards away, between them and the Albany, sits Deepcore Two. It looks like a particularly ugly and unwanted toy, sitting on the glistening plain of the NTI Ark's hull. CLOSER, ON TRIMODULE C, as the hatch at the bottom opens. Catfish's feet appear, bicycling. He swings down to the pearlescent 'deck'. Stands there blinking in the sunlight, mole-like. Jammer plonks down behind him. He turns, lifts Lindsey down. Hippy, Sonny, and the rest, emerge into the light of the sun. A deliverance from the blackest night they will ever know.</context>
      <utterance>Look...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should be dead. We didn't decompress.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATFISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out blood oughta be fizzin' like a warm, shook- up Coke.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindsey has tears streaming down her cheeks... for the sun, for life, for their deliverance and the larger one she knows has happened, an epiphany for the whole human race.</context>
      <utterance>They must've done something to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blinks. Seeing something not far away. She gives a little laugh, or something between laughing and crying. REVERSE, as Bud walks up the curving incline of one of the mouth-like enterances to the NTI structure. His suit is casually unzipped and the FBS helmet dangles from one hand jauntily. She starts toward him. Breaks into a run. Then stops a few feet from him. Watching him come to her. His smile, his eyes illuminating her. He stops and she touches him, lightly. Is this real? The look at each other, wonderingly a moment. Then laugh. She sniffs loudly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. I think you could say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Brigman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their lips meet.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mrs. Brigman.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
