<movie id="265" title="Hebrew Hammer The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GENTILE BOY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gentile Girl next to him holds up a bag of bagels.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Mordechai, look. I dropped a penny. He drops a penny. The other children cackle.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENTILE GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gentile Boy 1 feigns choking.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Mordechai. Want a bagel?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENTILE BOY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More laughter. Morty attempts to take it all in stride. We PUSH into GENTILE GIRL 2, a severe looking puritanically dressed child as she turns to face the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Jew nose, save some oxygen for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENTILE GIRL 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead silence. The other children exchange "Now that went a little over the line" looks. The silence is broken by the sound of the SCHOOLBELL. Morty gathers himself, and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Morty, my mom says that unless your people wise up and accept Jesus Christ as your lord and savior you're all going to burn in hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GENTILE BOY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other children take notice of Mordechai's gift and begin to laugh. Mordechai is crushed. MRS. HIGHSMITH (40's), an incredibly Waspy teacher puts down her copy of 'Modern W.A.S.P.,' and appears genuinely concerned by the teasing Mordechai has weathered. She walks over to comfort him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey everybody! Look what Mordechai got. Nice spinning top Morty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HIGHSMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, now class let's not make fun of Mordechai's spinning top. We need to all learn the importance of tolerance and understanding. Isn't that right Mordechai?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORDECHAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes Mrs. Highsmith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HIGHSMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to Mordechai for confirmation on the word.</context>
      <utterance>So class, in honor of Mordechai's special day, I'd like for all of us to wish Morty a heartfelt Merry...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HIGHSMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In unison, the class attempts to repeat the words, but all suffer various degrees of pronunciation problems.</context>
      <utterance>Cha-noo-kuh Day 7.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HIGHSMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She squeezes his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Very good class. I hope you've all learned an important lesson today. Just because Mordechai's people are different from us...just because they might appear strange to us with their furry hats, their beady eyes, and their long sideburns...not to mention their bizarre customs and unnecessarily guttural, funny sounding names...just because they control all of the worlds' money, yet are too cheap to buy their children anything better than spinning tops for presents, does not mean that we can't learn to respect and love them as our equals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HIGHSMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A reaction shot of the mortified Morty.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Chanoo-juah-kah Day 7 Morty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Macabee tears open the wrapping paper and holds up the gift - a Hebrew Hammer action figure. He beams. We cut back to the Hammer as he smiles back. From O.C., we hear Maccabee say...</context>
      <utterance>Happy Hanukkah Maccabee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACCABEE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>The Hammer smiles back and walks off frame.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks Hammer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We punch in to a CLOSE UP of a demure Miriam as the Hammer takes stock of the goods. She is an atrociously ugly girl wearing orthodontic headgear, and bespectacled with a pair oversized librarian's glasses. The Hammer shakes off his wave of nausea.</context>
      <utterance>Hammer, why don't you come eat by us for Shabat. My Miriam is all grown up now. God willing, you should settle down and marry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the invite Mrs. Kleinman, but right now G dash d's the only one for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer continues on down the street. The old woman and Miriam are framed in the BG.</context>
      <utterance>I can dig it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer stops for a second and smiles at the compliment.</context>
      <utterance>Hammer, you're the baaddest Hebe this side of Tel Aviv.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off frame.</context>
      <utterance>Shabat Shalom!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it back! Give me back my yarmulke!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GENTILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TEDDY (the non-speaking teen Gentile) throws the yarmulke, and we FOLLOW it as it spins towards another TEENAGE GENTILE. The other Teenage Gentile excitedly extends his hands to catch, but right before it reaches him another hand comes into frame and snatches it. He looks up, and we cut to his... POV as we tilt up to reveal The Hammer. He looks pretty damn big and pissed off from this angle. The Teenage Gentile begins to shake and stammer.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Teddy, throw me the frisbee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GENTILE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We...we were going to give it back. I swear to god.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just take god's name in vain?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GENTILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. It...It's not like that. We were just about...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just about to leave, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GENTILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer looks down to Shlomo. His spirit seems broken.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, that's right. We were just about to leave. C'mon Teddy. The two run off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess. Sometimes I wonder why I even bother praying to one god.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey! Be proud of who you are. You're a bad, bold, big-nosed, biblical brother. You feelin' me? The kid's morale is boosted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer pounds his fist into his chest ala the Black Panthers. The kid returns the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Aveenooh Shalom Alechem little brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer points at him as he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks Hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay Jewish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Hanukkah Tikva.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIKVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer tosses his Shtreml and we WHIP with it as lands squarely on the hat rack. We cut back to the Hammer. He's wearing a yarmulke.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Hanukkah Morty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's shakin' Yenta.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIKVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for stahters, your mother called. She said to remind you that you're having Shabat Dinner by her tomorrow, and also to remind you to bring the Manischewitz, and she wanted me to relate the following information to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what's the information?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIKVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said to remind you that you're having Shabat dinner by her tomorrow and also to remind you to bring the Manischewitz. The Hammer lets this sink in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIKVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm going to be out of the office from 1:30 to 3:00 on Sunday. I have a terrible yeast infection and I need to see my gynecologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we're not open on Sundays.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIKVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that. I just thought that you might want to know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As Santa speaks, we begin on a painting of a meek and frightened looking Santa Claus. His eyes look fearfully to his right. Below the picture frame is a plaque reading "St. Nick the Nervous. 1871-1941", we continue a slow DOLLY to the right on to the next picture. We see another Santa Claus, much more treacherous in his appearance. His eyes are fixed menacingly on the picture of Santa to his left. The plaque below his picture read, "St. Nick The Nasty 1941-1970." We continue our DOLLY to the right, finally ending on a painting of a jolly, portly Santa. Below his picture the plaque reads, "St. Nick The Nice. 1970-Christmas Present." We cut to a WIDE shot of a Conference Room. The same nice Santa Claus from the last picture addresses a handful of ELVES. Two reindeer flank Santa on either side. Their nameplates hang from their necks - "BLITZEN" and "RUDOLPH." At the other end of the table from Santa sits his son DAMIAN, quite a nasty looking man.</context>
      <utterance>I want to start by thanking all of you for pulling yourselves away from the workshop to make this emergency meeting. I know it's the busiest time of the year for all of you, so I'll try and be brief.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Damian whispers to an elf on his right hand side, and then makes the JERKING OFF motion with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>My father, often referred to as St. Nick The Nasty, was a tyrannical man. He was obsessed with making Christmas the only holiday anyone could celebrate before the New Year. Since his death, I've prided myself on ensuring that the Christmas season is one of tolerance and understanding between all races and religions. It's always been my belief that Hanukkah and Kwanzaa deserve the same respect as Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Rudolph's nose dims, so do the lights in the room. Santa picks up a remote in his hand, and turns on a SLIDE</context>
      <utterance>Lights please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We see a slide of THE HEBREW HAMMER, an African American man (Mohammed), and Santa Claus arm in arm below a banner in a mall reading "HAPPY HOLIDAYS!"</context>
      <utterance>Over the course of my career as Santa Claus, I've made it my mission to ensure that Jews, Christians, and African Americans could all observe their respective holidays in harmony.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We see another slide in which an assembly of SCHOOLCHILDREN are singing.</context>
      <utterance>I was responsible for pushing the Happy Holidays Ordinance, in which all Merry Christmas signage was replaced by the Trans-relgious and inoffensive phrase 'Happy Holidays.'</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Damian, preoccupied with the cigarette he's attempting to light, looks up in response to his name. A brown bagged bottle of booze now sits on the table in front of him. We can see Santa and the reindeer in silhouette on the slide projection screen behind him.</context>
      <utterance>It was nearly a decade ago, in conjunction with our friends in the Jewish and African American communities that I supported a bill that mandated that 'Dreidel, dreidel, dreidel' and 'I'm dreaming of a bright Kwanzaa' be taught and sung in elementary schools along with the Christmas standards 'Frosty The Snowman', and 'Deck The Halls.' Which is why upon examination of my annual naughty and nice list it shocked me to discover that my own son, Damian...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Santa addresses Damian.</context>
      <utterance>The heir to the Red Suit could be so filled with hate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We being a SLOW PUSH into Damian as he ponders the question. The cigarette dangles from his lips. Rudolph nods to Blitzen. Blitzen returns the gesture with a nod of acknowledgment. With a slow and measured pace Damian says...</context>
      <utterance>Damian, when I learned of your ludicrous scheme to wipe out Hanukkah, my first reaction was one of disgust. Now, I'm only filled with sadness and disappointment. Disappointed that I failed to teach you the true meaning of Christmas. What do you have to say for yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the slide projector screen behind Damian, we see the silhouetted images of Blitzen and Rudolph goring Santa through the chest with their antlers. Damian cringes. Blood trickles from Santa's mouth, and with his last breath he utters the words...</context>
      <utterance>Ho. Ho. Ho.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA CLAUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa falls out of frame with a thud. Standing behind him with bloodied antlers is Blitzen. Damian walks over to the newly deceased Santa, takes his bloodstained Santa's hat, and put it on his own head. From this point on in the screenplay, Damian will now be referred to as SANTA. The elves in the room, in various stages of shock, stare at their new master in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Et tu, Blitzen?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you fucking midgets looking at!? Get back to work! We have Hanukkah to destroy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His pleas for silence are ignored.</context>
      <utterance>Gentleman!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Still chaos. He flips a light switch on and off a few times as he says...</context>
      <utterance>Gentleman! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The entire hall responds in unison...</context>
      <utterance>Sheket B'vakasha! Sheket B'vakasha!</utterance>
   <speaker>HALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room falls silent. Every member of the JDL sits straight up with their hands folded in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARVEY WEINSTEIN sits before a plaque reading, "HARVEY</context>
      <utterance>The time for action is now. We predict that the St. Nick Day Massacre will put Hanukkah-Christmas relations back at least a hundred years. With this meshuggena new Santa Claus in power, Hanukkah is in jeopardy. Our first order of business is to put into motion a plan to create goodwill towards the Jewish Community. Mr. Chairman of the Worldwide Jewish Media Conspiracy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>HARVEY WEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHAIRMAN OF THE ANTI-DEFAMATION LEAGUE pipes in.</context>
      <utterance>We need your people to crank out a couple more award winning documentaries on the Holocaust, possibly a new Adam Sandler movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADL CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not another Adam Sandler movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY WEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with Adam Sandler movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADL CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to create goodwill here. I just think...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY WEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plaque reading "Anti-Defamation League" is clearly framed in this shot.</context>
      <utterance>Frankly, I don't care what you think. I think you're a putz.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADL CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't defame me. I'm against that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Focus people. Our next order of business is to assign an agent to track Santa's activities. Step in and use force if the situation calls for it. We need to put the toughest Jew we have on the case. Suggestions? Suggestions, anybody? One of the JDL MEMBERS calls out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JDL MEMBER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Steven Spielberg?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, he made ET. We need someone tough people. A SECOND MEMBER calls out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JDL MEMBER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Itzahk Perlman?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We stay on the chief while we hear offscreen...</context>
      <utterance>He's in a wheelchair for crying out loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JDL MEMBER'S 3 AND 4</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allen Greenspan? Henry Kissinger?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too old.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADL CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joe Lieberman?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Missing in action.</utterance>
   <speaker>JDL MEMBER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert Shapiro?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a lawyer. We're looking for heros people.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY WEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David Copperfield?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the back of the room, ESTHER (25), a Semitic siren, pushes her way to the front. A black skirt covers every inch of her sexy figure.</context>
      <utterance>What's he gonna do, make Santa disappear? Think people think. We need a hard hittin' Hebe on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hall fills with hushed voices as the various members of the JDL whisper to one another.</context>
      <utterance>What about Mordechai Jefferson Carver?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>interrupts. The plaque in front of him reads, "SAGE ELDERLY</context>
      <utterance>The Hebrew Hammer? No. No way. After the way he handled that situation in the West Bank? He's the only Jew in the world too extreme for the JDL. There's a reason why we kicked him out of our ranks, sweetheart. We need a man who can follow orders. A man with self-control. We need a man... The COUNCIL ELDER, a sage looking elderly Jewish man</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COUNCIL ELDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We need a man who can get the job done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief nods his head reluctantly.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, he's our only hope. And you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADL CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only problem is, ever since we kicked him out, he wants nothing to do with us. There's no way we can persuade him to come back. Esther lifts her skirt a few inches.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I can persuade him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There is knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>It was the day before Hanukkah when she strolled into my office.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The door opens to reveal a long denim skirt covering every possible inch of flesh. We tilt up the length of the skirt to reveal Esther. She is breathtakingly sexy. The Hammer quickly removes his feet from the table. Esther approaches his desk and sits.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jefferson Carver?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, call me Mordechai.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late. Traffic was a pisher, and I've been circling the block for the past half hour looking for parking. What are you listening to?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Hammer attempts to press stop on his tape recorder, but accidentally FAST FORWARDS to another part of the tape. We hear the sound of SEXUAL INTERCOURSE. The Hammer scrambles for the STOP button.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, the things I would do to her if I had the...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Client notes. Sorry.  What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Esther. Chief Bloomenbergensteinenthal from the Jewish Defense League desperately needs to speak with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is old Chief Bloomenbergensteinenthal? Is he still shtooping every girl he can get his hands on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer makes the realization.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, his days of marital infidelity have long since past. Now he just shtoops my mother exclusively.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother? Oh. Whoops.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai, Santa Claus has been rubbed out by his son Damian. The man's a demon. There's no telling what this new anti semitic psycho Santa is capable of.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer stops himself and glances over Esther's shoulder. In the doorway stands a BLONDE BOMBSHELL in a mink coat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to hear about Santa. He was a good friend, but my days...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE BOMBSHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hammer? I'd like to hire you to put a tail on my husband. I think my life might be in danger. I think he wants to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Blonde Bombshell is confused for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry Shiksa, I think you got the wrong office. I'm the Hebrew Hammer. Mike Hammer's down the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE BOMBSHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut to a shot of the Hammer's In/Out Box. Both are completely empty, and thickly coated with spiderwebs. The Hammer takes notice of her expression of skepticism.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. Esther, you seem like a nice girl, so I'm only gonna say this once. I no longer affiliate myself with that organization. The politics there were brutal. Besides, I've already got a full case load. Esther looks down at his desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Still a look of disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>That's...uh...that's all done electronically now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you being so difficult? All my father wants is to just speak with...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer grabs his overcoat from the coat rack. Esther gets up as well.</context>
      <utterance>I hate to cut you short, but in an hour the sun goes down, and then it's officially the Sabbath. I can't work on the Sabbath. This is where we're going to have to part ways boobola.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's obvious the Hammer's amused by her persistence.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving your side until I get you to agree to come speak with my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two walk towards the front door of the office.</context>
      <utterance>Be my guest. But I have to warn you, I'm going to my mother's for dinner tonight. And if you think I'm difficult, wait till you meet her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer pulls a bottle of wine out from a paper bag.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai! Shabat Shalom!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shabat Shalom mama. I brought some Manischewitz. The black label.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver forcefully grabs Esther into an embrace resembling a bear hug, and begins to plaster her with sloppy kisses. Esther is visibly overwhelmed by it all as the kissing and embracing continue for a bit too long. Mrs. Carver places her tongue into Esther's ear canal as a sign of affection, forcing Esther to break the embrace. Mrs. Carver and Esther look at one another strangely for an awkward few moments.</context>
      <utterance>I can see. And you also brought a nice girl to come eat by us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Do you have a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Esther.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the story of Purim.  Well, now that we're all acquainted, let's sit down and start the Sabbath.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oy vey, I'm stuffed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver enters the dining room through the kitchen door carrying an enormous platter loaded with serving dish after serving dish of food.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I could eat another latke if you paid me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther and the Hammer exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody ready for the main course?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver places the food on a dresser opposite the kitchen table and then sits.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, I think we've had enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver directs her piercing stare at the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Not until Mordechai finishes everything in front of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Esther coughs up some of her food. The Hammer interjects.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai!?  So, Esther, how did you and Mordechai meet. You know they call him the Hebrew Hammer for a reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom! Esther works for the JDL. They sent her to try and recruit me back to save Hanukkah for them. What she doesn't seem to understand is that nothing, not even god himself could convince me to ever work for them again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer cuts her off.</context>
      <utterance>But Hanukkah's in dan...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not my problem. If you'll excuse me now, I need to use the bathroom. He stands and leaves. Mrs. Carver stares lovingly at Esther.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like my Mordechai, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's...he's very nice.  But Mrs. Carver, the fate of Hanukkah rests solely in his hands. Please, you have to help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hanukkah, Shmanukkah. It isn't even one of the high holidays. What concerns me more is that my boychick is almost thirty, and has yet to settle down with a nice Jewish girl.  I'll make you a deal. I'll help you with your little Hanukkah problem if you help me with my Mordechai.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther begins to choke again.</context>
      <utterance>He works too much. God forbid he should have a nice Jewish girl come eat by him once in a while. Take his mind off his work. Maybe a blowjob here and there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer calls out from the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Is this something you could do for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, where do you keep the plunger?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther appears panicked.</context>
      <utterance>It's under the sink by my tampons!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In the BG, we hear the toilet FLUSH. The Hammer begins his walk back to the table.</context>
      <utterance>So, do we have a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther begins to speak, but Mrs. Carver interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>So, what did you two ladies discuss while I was gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther plays along.</context>
      <utterance>I was just telling your nice friend Esther about how I used to have such a problem with the gas.  So, once I started taking two charcoal pills before I ate, the gas cleared itself right up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver turns her attention towards her son.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. That's...good to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai. Do you love your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, stop with this already. Of course I love you. You're my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how come you won't stop this Certified Circumcised Dick nonsense and get yourself a real job.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, I have a real job. I do good things for this community. I help people.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why can't I show a picture?</context>
      <utterance>When I play bridge with all the girls, everyone has what to talk about with their sons. They show pictures. Their sons are lawyers and doctors and Rabbis.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So don't show a picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know my friend Maureen? Her son, the investment banker? He paid for her entire retirement in Boca Raton. What a mench he is. Instead of schleping to save Hanukkah, god forbid you should go back to business school and get an MBA. Maybe then you could send me to Boca, too. This puts the Hammer into a neurotic fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver throws her arms up in resignation.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh, What. So, all of a sudden my saving Hanukkah's not good enough for you? Is that what your saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to argue with you. Let's just eat in peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. We're gonna argue. And you know what mom? I'm going to save Hanukkah just to spite you. And when my face is all over the television. When your friends are opening their Hanukkah gifts next year, don't mention it to them, okay? I wouldn't want you to have to show my picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver looks at Esther and winks.</context>
      <utterance>Do what you must.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver becomes very animated.</context>
      <utterance>Such a good boy he is. The Hammer shakes his head in frustration.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>MAZEL TOV, a tabby with two paralyzed back legs wearing a diaper slides itself across the floor. With each writhing motion we hear a very distinct SWISHING NOISE. Mrs. Carver picks the cat up and places it in her lap. Mazel Tov makes a strange, UNHAPPY NOISE.</context>
      <utterance>Mazel Tov!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver pulls off Mazel Tov's diaper while it still sits in her lap. She plays with undiapered cat's two good paws.</context>
      <utterance>What's that Mazel Tov? Your diaper needs changing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's let your tuchus breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, why don't you put that cat out of its misery?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody hungry for desert?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's clearly irritated by this.</context>
      <utterance>Jew Confirmation Test initiated.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've gotta be kidding me. They're still doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please state your full Hebrew name.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vault-like gate slides open in a futuristic manner, and the Hammer steps in. The gate shuts behind him, and he finds himself in an all white room. A microphone is placed by another massive door directly in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai Baruch Netanyahoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please state the six dishes found on the Passover Seder plate in alphabetical order?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second door slides open, and Morty steps forward into the next room. Inside this room lies a single violin in a case.</context>
      <utterance>Beitzah, Charoset, Chazeret, Karpas, Maror, and Zeroa.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer picks up the violin and begins to play 'Hava Nagila.' He's pretty damn good at it. The next door slides open, and Hammer steps forward into yet another room. A drape, about four feet high off the floor, is stretched into a semi-circle against the wall of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Please demonstrate musical aptitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer steps inside the drape, and drops his pants. A panel on the wall opens, and a metal probe heads for his shmekel. He is clearly uncomfortable with this bit of testing.</context>
      <utterance>Please step forward and remove your undergarments.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh. That's cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door slides open, and the Hammer quickly pulls his pants up as he steps into the next room. The room is completely empty with the exception of a one way mirror on the front wall by the door.</context>
      <utterance>Circumcision confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nothing happens. The Hammer waits a few seconds, but quickly becomes agitated.</context>
      <utterance>Final test initiated.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut to the OTHER SIDE OF THE MIRROR. The Chief observes the Hammer as he continues to whine. Next to them, a METER with the label "WHINING SCALE" slowly grows in magnitude as the Hammer continues to rant. The meter bars go from red to yellow in color.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Can anybody hear me? I think this machine is broken or something. Hello?  This is ridiculous! I didn't even want to come here. I shlep all the way out to the middle of nowhere, for lord knows what purpose, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am so unhappy with this situation. Why Mordechai? Why do you always feel it necessary to do what other people want you to do? Why can't you be your own man...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The meter bars switch from yellow to green, finally passing the '0 - Jewish' mark.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Back inside with the Hammer, the doors slide open, revealing the Chief to the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>He's still got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome back Hammer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A minion practicing Jew-do, the deadly fighting art. Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two leave, and continue their walk down the hallway. An agent with his back to camera fiddles with some HIGH-TECH gadgetry that lines the walls.</context>
      <utterance>There's more. Follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Chief stops behind the man and taps him on the back. SAMMY DAVIS JR. JR., the spitting image of Sammy, turns to greet the two.</context>
      <utterance>We've even relaxed our centuries old admissions criteria.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai Jefferson Carver, I'd like for you to meet the Jewish Defense League's first black Jewish agent. A close personal friend of mine, agent Sammy Davis Jr. Jr.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY DAVIS JR. JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hebrew Hammer? I've heard about this cat. Your beautiful babe. Keep on keeping on. The Hammer is a bit taken back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sammy's all smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. I'll, uh, keep doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sammy, if you'll excuse us, Mordechai and I have business to attend to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY DAVIS JR. JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two cats keeps purrin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Mordechai, now that we're alone I just want to say that I'm not happy about this. I don't want a repeat of that incident in the West Bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the job done didn't I? I did what I had to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A settlement completely demolished, ten smashed army jeeps, four dead Arabs. G dash D damn it, Hammer! You think you're above the Ten Commandments? Just find Santa Claus and bring him back to us. No heroics, got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's your Bar Mitzvah. I'm just readin' the Torah portion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's good to see that you can be so nonchalant about the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I could be chalant about it, but then again I'm not even sure if that's a word. Listen Chief, we could stand around arguing all day, but I gotta case to crack.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your first move?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna pay a visit to the K.L.F. See if they've got the 411 on Santa's location. I'll check in with you when I know more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer walks out the door. The Chief calls to him.</context>
      <utterance>You be careful Hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat passes, and then the Hammer walks back in.</context>
      <utterance>The fate of Hanukkah rests squarely on your shoulders.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. You guys have seriously got to stop with that stuff. That's a lot of pressure to put on one Jew. I'm only human you know. I'm already shvitzing about the whole thing. You know, believe it or not, I'm allowed to make mistakes, too. I can only do the best that I can do, and that's just gonna have to be good enough for all of you. A reaction shot of the befuddled Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alright, I'm out of here.</context>
      <utterance>Just...just stop with that. Okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BLACK TEENAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.S., one of the BAAAD BROTHERS inquires.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, yo, we got ourselves a visitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAAAD BROTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK TEENAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men scramble for their guns, inserting clips, and removing safeties. The front doors bust open, and we DOLLY into the Hammer. All guns are trained on him. From behind the frontline of gunmen, MOHAMMED, clearly the leader of the operation, pushes his way through. He walks towards the Hammer. You can feel the tension in the room.</context>
      <utterance>It's some pimped out Hebrew dude in a caddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hebrew Hammer! My main Kike!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two embrace in a warm hug. The White Accountant looks up in shock from the card table. His nametag is clearly visible, and it reads, "WHITE ACCOUNTANT." He points at Mohammed.</context>
      <utterance>Mohammed Ali Paula Abdul Rahim. My main nigga!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE ACCOUNTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>You...you just called him a Kike.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE ACCOUNTANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer and Mohammed look to one another. They're having a hard time understanding his concern.</context>
      <utterance>And you. You just called him a Nigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The White Accountant thinks it over for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Well it's okay when we call each other that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE ACCOUNTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other Brothers put their guns down and go back to their pre-Hammer activities, and the accountant takes his place back at the card table. Mohammed puts his arm around the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Morde-chai, tell me, what brings your bad self down to the KLF?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm back on the job for the JDL. You hear about that crazy white boy who took over as Santa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer looks over at the Brothers smoking weed, making out with their girlfriends, etc. Mohammed takes notice.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, most definitely. Got the brothers here in full alert mode.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta always be cool under pressure. You know what I'm sayin.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True dat. True dat. So, what's the word on the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This clearly flies over the Hammer's yarmulke.</context>
      <utterance>Word is that papa's got a brand new bag, and it's velvety red, and it ain't gonna be overnight Fed-Exed to Jerusalem. If you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I...I don't. What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. It means that Santa's gonna fuck Hanukkah's shit up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if I can help it. You got any information for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. But I know somebody who does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jamal pulls his shades down slightly to get a better look.</context>
      <utterance>Jamal, I'd like for you to meet the Hebrew Hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Sup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like for you to tell him what you told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jamal makes the sideways gun holding gesture, and mock pulls the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>A'ight, a'ight, cool. Yo, it's like this. That nigga Santy Claus be trippin'. First that motherfucker kills his own pops, then he start talkin' 'bout bustin a cap in Hanukkah's ass. Next, the racist motherfucker kick my ass out the workshop, sayin' that there ain't no room for no little colored elves like me. Can you believe that shit? Yo, if it wasn't for the arthritis in my joints, you best believe that I'd be...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jamal thinks for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything else you can tell me? His hangouts, his next move, anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jamal pulls out a matchbbok from his pocket. The front cover reads, "DUKE'S - WHERE SKIN IS IN." He hands it to the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Well, come to think of it, there is one thing. Before I left, I was packin' up my shit and I overheard the nigga talkin' to some business pahtnah or something. Sayin that he'd meet him today at some joint called Duke's. Round five o'clock if my memory serves. When he got off the phone and jetted, I scoped the room for some jewelry, cash, whatevers. You know, a severance package. Didn't find any duckets, but I did snatch this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks little brother, you've been a big help.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit fool, ain't no thang. If it wasn't for my real brothers here at the K.L.F., I'd be shining shoes at the train station or getting my afro tossed up against a velcro wall in some redneck bar somewhere. I finally gots a place where I belong. Fuck Christmas. I'm all about smoking blunts and pimpin' bitches. I'm all about Kwanzaa nigga! Mohammed and the Hammer head towards the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's new. He's still got a long way to go before he understands the true meaning of Kwanzaa.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks again Mo, you always deliver the goods.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watch your back Hammer. Hanukkah might just be his first move. For all we know Kwanzaa could be next. There's a lot of brothers counting on you. If you fail...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, look. I'm going to work really, really hard on this one. But, please stop with the pressure. I'm already tense as it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mohammed pounds his fist against his chest and then raises it. The Hammer returns the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>It's cool. It's cool. Aveenooh Shalom Alechem, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alekem Salam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALVATION NAVY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. He's on his way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa puts the walkie-talkie down, and addresses somebody</context>
      <utterance>Excellent. Everything is going as planned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We cut to the other side to reveal whom he's speaking to. Jamal, the same black 'elf' from the Kwanzaa Liberation Front sits at the table across from Santa.</context>
      <utterance>With the Hebrew Hammer out of the picture, Hanukkah will be nothing more than a confusing and hard to pronounce word. I want to thank you very much Jamal for all of your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pfff. Shit nigga, ain't no thang. Hey, yo Santy Claus, so does this mean that you gonna make me an official elf now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa looks over to TINY TIM. Unshaven, not so tiny anymore, and still on crutches, Tiny Tim's grown up since 'A Christmas Carol.' A common street thug. C'mon, did you seriously think that Scrooge would give free handouts to the Cratchit family forever? Tiny Tim shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this guy Tiny Tim?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A shot of a couple of the same elves from the conference room slaving away on the assembly line.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look around you Jamal. Do you see any colored midgets in my workshop?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your presence would be a disruption to the utopian model of efficiency I've created here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELVES appear to be struggling with the speed at which the products move down the assembly line. The HEAD ELF steps out from the assembly line and addresses Santa.</context>
      <utterance>That's some cold shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD ELF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other elves stop working and vocalize their agreement with the Head Elf.</context>
      <utterance>Utopian model of efficiency my ass! Ever since you took charge, this place has been more like a sweatshop.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD ELF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The other elves shout out their approval. Santa takes it all in stride.</context>
      <utterance>We know our rights Santa! You're in violation of the union regulations! We're going on strike!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Head Elf is taken aback by what seems to be a glimpse of compassion on Santa's part.</context>
      <utterance>You know something, you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD ELF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. This is a sweatshop. And since you elves aren't willing to do the work, I made arrangements to have some Taiwanese children shipped over. And I might add, they're more than willing to work for peanuts. Santa performs the two fingered whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A group of FIVE TAIWANESE BOYS file past Santa towards the assembly line. As each child passes Santa, he hands them each a bag of</context>
      <utterance>Come on in boys!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's our first plan of attack Santa?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa walks over to a FED-Y truck overflowing with large brown cardboard boxes marked 'PRODUCT.'</context>
      <utterance>While I was in Taiwan negotiating the solution to our labor problems, I came across a factory that illegally manufactures the most addictive, Jewish pride weakening substance on the planet. I bought the entire plant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you and your men to target every young person in the Jewish neighborhoods of every major city of this country. I want you to flood their streets with this product.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tiny Tim's curiosity is peaked.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's the beauty of it. These are free samples.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's in the boxes? Heroin? Cocaine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa slits open one of the boxes with a large knife and pulls out a VIDEOCASSETTE generically labeled, "It's A Wonderful Life."</context>
      <utterance>Worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bootleg copies of the Frank Capra classic, 'It's A Wonderful Life.'</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's some cold shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manischewitz. Straight up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINHEAD BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manischewitz wine. The Hammer interrupts him by clearing his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Usually we don't serve your kind. But since you had the balls to walk in here, Kike, I'll pour you one last drink before we lynch you. The bartender reaches for a bottle of cherry flavored</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bartender eyeballs him, and then grabs the bottle of Black Label Manischewitz. He grabs a glass from the rack, and begins to pour.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, can I have the black label?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The bartender stops pouring and places the bottle on the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I figure if this is my last drink, you might as well leave the bottle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINHEAD BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer picks up the bottle and begins to examine it.</context>
      <utterance>Do you guys take Shekels? I just got back from a trip in Israel, and all I've got is a fistful of Shekels. He drops a fistful of Shekels on the bar. A FEW SKINHEADS slowly begin to approach the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>With one swift motion, the Hammer spins the bottle up to grab it by the neck, and thwacks the bartender on the head with it. All of the OTHER OCCUPANTS in the bar jump out of their seats, encircling the Hammer. We do a QUICK PUSH into the Hammer as he pulls out TWO SAWED OFF SHOTGUNS from underneath his coat.</context>
      <utterance>5733. That was a good year for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points his weapons, and we...</context>
      <utterance>Shabat Shalom, motherfuckers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TELEVISION SET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A JEWISH MOTHER calls to her son from O.S.</context>
      <utterance>Papa, Papa! Mommy says that every time you hear the sound of a bell ringing an angel gets his wings!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEWISH MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Maccabee looks over his shoulder in disgust, and then CRANKS UP THE VOLUME on the film until all other sounds are drowned out.</context>
      <utterance>Maccabee! It's time to light the menorah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shlomo, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy says that every time you hear the sound of a bell ringing, an angel gets his wings!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car door beeps again. The kid looks to it, and the Hammer follows his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer is baffled. He looks down at Shlomo's hand and spots the videocassette. He grabs it from him and examines at it.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy says that every time you hear the sound of a bell ringing, an angel gets his wings!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer inspects the tape a little longer, and then gives the label a huge lick.</context>
      <utterance>Bootleg 'It's A Wonderful Life' from Taiwan.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A POV shot from inside the Hammer's trunk as it opens. Hammer stands with Shlomo. Inside the trunk we see a box of videos. The three on top read, "Fiddler On The Roof," "Yentl," and "Chaim Potok's The Chosen." The Hammer grabs a copy of the Chosen and hands it to Shlomo.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty five percent pure. Damn! People could get hurt watching this shit.  Come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chaim Potok's The Chosen?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HASIDIC KID ON A BIKE with a Christmas tree in tow rides past the two. One of the ornaments makes a tinkling sound.</context>
      <utterance>Get yourself home and watch this as soon as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLOMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer slaps him out of his spell.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy says that every time you hear the sound of a bell ringing, an angel gets his wings!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, hey! You can beat this. Now get going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, it's me. Listen carefully. I need for the Worldwide Jewish Media Conspiracy to mass produce video copies of every Hollywood movie ever made featuring a positive Jewish protagonist as its lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you want us to make copies of Yentl, Fiddler On The Roof, and Chaim Potok's The Chosen?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll work. Get them out to the Jewish community stat. We got an epidemic on our hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on it Hammer. How'd you do with Santa?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a trap. I'm back at square one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then I've got good news for you. We just got word that he'll be making an appearance at the Mall Of America today. I'm sending Esther to meet you there at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thinking. We'll disguise ourselves as a Gentile couple to pass undetected. Now that he thinks I'm dead, this should be a piece of homentashen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut back to the Hammer on the payphone. He holds the receiver away from his ear. He doesn't want to hear this.</context>
      <utterance>One last thing Hammer. You take care of yourself. The...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fate of Hanukkah. Right. Right. Yeah, Got it. Will do. Okay, bye now. He hangs up and leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little BLONDE GENTILE GIRL tugs on Tony's sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing stirring here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE GENTILE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I be next? Please, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gentile Girl pulls her Power Muff Girls T-shirt down, allowing the two to get a better look at it.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get a look at you, shall we.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She twirls for the two.</context>
      <utterance>A power muff girls T. Very nice. Alright, now spin around.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A pushy, FRECKLE FACED GENTILE BOY steps out of line and approaches the two.</context>
      <utterance>Very nice! Alright. You're cool. Go on and see Santa, sunshine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRECKLE FACED GENTILE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair! How come she gets to go next? We were here first!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid begins to sob uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>Oh really! Is that a fact? Well guess what buddy? You ain't gettin' in to see Santa today, so why don't you just turn around and high tail it home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRECKLE FACED GENTILE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony apes him.</context>
      <utterance>But I've been waiting to see Santa all year.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid is a pathetic mess.</context>
      <utterance>But I've been waiting to see Santa all year.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me. Get moving punk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of Santa?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two pass a samples booth. The FREE SAMPLES WOMAN solicits the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>He must be behind that curtain. Relax. We're undercover. We need to give off the appearance of calm. You see Esther, the trick to undercover work is to try and blend in. Act as a Gentile would.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMPLES WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We get a CU of the burger followed by a CU of the Hammer. He's mortified, but he pulls it together.</context>
      <utterance>Could I interest you in a free sample bacon cheeseburger?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sample Woman looks at him strangely as the Hammer and Esther walk on.</context>
      <utterance>While I thank you, Gentile friend, for your generous offer of that deliciously unkosher snack, I sadly have to decline for I stuffed myself full of meat and milk product at a prior lunch engagement.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two take their place at the end of the line in to see Santa. Tony performs the two fingered whistle.</context>
      <utterance>You're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids all vocalize their disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have everyone's attention please. In fifteen minutes, Santa's gonna have to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The kids aren't buying it. More boos and protests of disapproval.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, don't be like that kids. We gotta lot work to do if we're gonna get all those presents out in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tony spits and grabs his crotch as he turns back around to take his place in front of the velvet ropes. Esther surveys their place in line. It's about fifteen deep.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! You want shitty ass presents for Christmas? You want Barbies with heads screwed on backwards? You want remote control cars without the batteries included. Then be my fucking guest!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do? We're at least an hour from the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two make their way up to the front of the line. They pass a man who looks eerily like ex-rapping god, MC HAMMER.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that...? No, couldn't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey! Not so fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get through. It's an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther adjusts her bust. She's incredibly sexy in her tight fitting denim jacket. She smiles flirtatiously at the Elves.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry pal, you're gonna have to wait in line just like all the other parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand on Tony's bicep and smiles once again.</context>
      <utterance>We're so sorry to have to cut, but our beautiful Gentile boy ran on ahead of us in line.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tony is putty in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>It would mean so much to Paul and I if you'd let us through to see Santa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony unhinges the rope, and the two pass. The Hammer leans over to Esther.</context>
      <utterance>Well...umm, when you put it that way. Sure go on through.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do the Jewish people do during Hanukkah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They worship the devil and sacrifice small Gentile children like me in bizarre, sadistic rituals.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bambi and Tawni escort Jimmy out, and re-enter with Esther and the Hammer. Santa's confused.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Santa can tell that you've been a very good boy this year. Run along now Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry folks, I don't do couples.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you keep your mouth shut and come with me, you won't get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer rips off his baseball hat and T-shirt. Santa gasps.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? Do I know you, friend? Take a look around you. Do you even know who I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me guess, you're the goy who stole Hanukkah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer takes out his gun and points it Santa.</context>
      <utterance>The Hebrew Hammer! You're alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your shpiel, Santa?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa snaps his fingers, and Bambi and Tawni drape themselves on either side of the Hammer, rubbing his arms erotically.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa there. C'mon Mordechai, is this any way to treat an old family friend? Let's cut out all the unpleasantness. I admit, I went way overboard with the whole Hanukkah thing. Let me make it up to you. How about a peace offering?  Girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bambi speaks with a thick Southern drawl.</context>
      <utterance>Bambi. Tawni. I'd like for you to meet world renown Semitic super stud, Mordechai Jefferson Carver.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAMBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer's enjoying the attention. He looks down at Bambi's breasts. We're talking HUGE, obviously augmented boobolas. A large crucifix chain hangs around her neck, nestled in between the mounds of silicone. We hear the requisite DING as it sparkles. The Hammer is released from the sexual spell of the Gentile Seductress.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I declare I just love Jewish men. They're so sensitive and well read. Esther is clearly jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls move away from the Hammer. Esther smiles at the Hammer's resolve.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry Santa. I like my women like my matzah. Unleavened.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Tony draws the curtain back.</context>
      <utterance>This is where you go down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees the Hammer with his gun pointed at Santa's head.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hurry it up in there. We gotta bunch of kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Esther pulls out her piece and points it at Tony.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does. The entire crowd of children can now see what's happening. Hushed, fearful whispers. MC Hammer steps out of line and pleads...</context>
      <utterance>Back it up buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MC HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer does a double take. MC Hammer gives a "Did I just say that?" expression.</context>
      <utterance>Please Hammer, don't hurt em'!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do this clean. I don't want to make a scene Santa. Santa stands up slowly with his hands raised.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a bit too late for that now, isn't it? Excuse me children, if I could have your attention for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer plays along, raising his hand to keep the children calm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just calming the kiddies.  There's no need to worry about Santa. He's just having a peaceful, adult conversation with his nice Jewish friend, The Hebrew Hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey everybody. How's it hangin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer and Esther look to one another. This riles the masses. Trouble.</context>
      <utterance>In fact, he's just informed me that he personally plans on cancelling Christmas this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we show him how that makes us feel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barely audible sound of a gospelized version of the Biblical slave song, "Let My People Go" sounds as if it's coming from within the walls of the mall.</context>
      <utterance>It's over. We're doomed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer tries to place the source.</context>
      <utterance>Shh. Shh, listen. Do you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a panel on the wall slides open to reveal a door. The other side of the door is dark, but it has a cavernous feel to it. An elderly Jewish woman, HARRIET TUBBELMAN, appears from out of the doorway. She smokes a corncob pipe.</context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIET TUBBELMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harriet escorts the two into the passageway, and the door slides shut behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Psst. Hammer, Esther. This way. Hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved our lives. Thank you. How can I ever repay you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIET TUBBELMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands each of them a ticket and then lowers the lap restraints for Hammer and Esther, testing them to make sure they're secure.</context>
      <utterance>...My name is Harriet Tubbelman, but you can call me Moses. The only payment I ask Mordechai, is that you keep Hanukkah safe for us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIET TUBBELMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She begins to walk away, but then catches herself as she turns back to face them.</context>
      <utterance>You should be safe from here on out. Just follow the river to it's conclusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIET TUBBELMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, and keep your arms and legs inside the water craft at all times.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles with great pride.</context>
      <utterance>Where are we? What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIET TUBBELMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Railroad. Just sit back, relax, and enjoy the ride. The brakes on the water craft release, and the craft makes it way from the loading dock. Wide eyed, Esther and Hammer check out their surroundings. Hasidic Animatronic puppets sing of thousands of years of Jewish oppression and persecution in an educational, yet oddly entertaining way. The Hammer puts his arm around Esther and continues to check out the attraction in wonderment. Esther secretly glances at him affectionately. It's clear she's falling for him. We cut to a wide shot as we watch the craft disappear down the river. A funkdafied version of the "Let My People Go" song FADES UP and over the gospel version from the ride.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the Underground Jewish</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That got annoying fairly quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CARNIVAL WORKER stands behind a makeshift 'Underground Jewish Railroad' booth.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARNIVAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two hand the Carnival Worker their tickets.</context>
      <utterance>Tickets please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two walk past him. Esther turns to the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, we're kosher. Thanks though.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a once over. She is stunning.</context>
      <utterance>Now we wait for Santa to make his next move.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to get a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Why not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>BANDLEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer raises his hand in acknowledgment. The entire bar cheers and applauds. Hammer escorts Esther to a table on the woman's side of the wall, and then walks around to the other side of the divider where he takes a seat opposite the wall from her. The band begins a rousing version of "Hava Nagila." A good majority of the men in the bar rush to the dance floor and begin dancing zealously with one another. Esther shouts over the wall in an attempt to overcome the din of the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! The Hebrew Hammer everybody!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer struggles to hear. He shouts back to her.</context>
      <utterance>So, do you come here often!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, do you come here often!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah, about once a week!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, yeah, about once a week!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HASIDIC BAR PATRON approaches the Hammer and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>HASIDIC BAR PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We get another shot of the men dancing together, arm in arm, on the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Patron leaves, JOSHUA, another Hasidic man standing directly behind him takes his place at the Hammer's table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay right now. Thanks though.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSHUA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Morty, wanna cut a rug?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer motions to the wall. Joshua looks as if his feelings are hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, I'm good. I'm kind of here with somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSHUA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay. Maybe next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Joshua leaves, we get a WIDER shot of the Hammer's table. A LONG LINE OF MEN leads up to it. CHAIM FEYGELE, an effeminate slick Hasidic man, chest hair spilling out of his loosely buttoned butterfly collar shirt, neck dripping with gold chains, steps up to the Hammer. He's got a huge phoney smile plastered across his face.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Maybe next time Joshua. Take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIM FEYGELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Shalom there mister!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we know each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIM FEYGELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chaim points to the dance floor. Another shot of men dancing with one another, arm in arm.</context>
      <utterance>No, but we have mutual friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIM FEYGELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This guy is clearly making the Hammer nervous.</context>
      <utterance>The name's Feygele. Chaim Feygele.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai. My friends call me Morty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIM FEYGELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mordechai is flustered.</context>
      <utterance>So Morty, I just love a man in a black suit. Care to dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut to Esther's side of the wall. The Hammer walks behind her while she checks out the band on stage.</context>
      <utterance>Uhhh. You know, I...have to go to the bathroom. I'll be right back. The Hammer gets up quickly and leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns around, pleasantly surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Hey there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would love to get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther pulls herself away from the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I'm better with men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should try a different kind of dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a TIGHT MEDIUM SHOT of Esther. Her erect nipples are clearly outlined through her blouse. Now, the Hammer's really getting it.</context>
      <utterance>You mean like disco dancing or doing the funky chicke...Oh. I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we're talking Boobola.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes Esther.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to talk dirty to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She's warming up.</context>
      <utterance>I want to have lots of children by you. Get a good paying, stable job. Settle down in Long Island somewhere. Someplace nice. Fancy. But not fancy schmancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want for our children to go to private schools and take music lessons. Little Abraham will go to Stanford for college, Batya will go Ivy League, maybe Vassar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep going.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's on fire for him.</context>
      <utterance>Afterwards they'll make the decision as to whether or not they'd like to continue their religious studies in Israel. Because, hey, after all we'll have practiced the highly effective assertive democratic style of child rearing, sprinkled with a healthy dose of liberalism.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, yes! Keep going! Don't stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also, on a daily basis, I want you to tell me what to do, where to do it, and how I should live my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs him and kisses him passionately.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss me you Semitic stud!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As the two embrace, we RACK FOCUS from the two of them in the BG to the Hanukkah candles burning brightly on the menorah in the FG. We blur out of focus.</context>
      <utterance>Shabat Shalom!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer gives her ass a smack, and then picks up a container filled with some kind of WHITE POWDER. He snorts a bit of it off of the Star Of David chain that hangs from his neck, and places the container of white powder back in its place by the menorah. Esther is mortified.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, that was amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you just snort?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Antihistamine. It's for my allergies. The capsules make me gassy. She relaxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She cuts him off.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I've been thinking about what Santa's got planned for us next. Maybe he'll...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother was right. You do work too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, she said that, did she? What else did Mommy Dearest have to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she also said that you need to find a nice girl to help take your mind off of your work. I'm just glad she thought I was good enough for you. The Hammer sits up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you guys have this conversation? When I was in the bathroom? What else did she have to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer goes into a fit.</context>
      <utterance>Relax Morty, I think your mom is wonderful. She cares so much about you. Get this, while you were gone she said she'd help me get you to work with the JDL if I'd come eat by you once in awhile. Like I needed any incentive to be with you. She's so...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You made a deal with my mother to sleep with me if I'd help you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a realization.</context>
      <utterance>What does that make you? What does that make me? And my mother. What does that make her?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god. She's become my pimp. And she's whoring her bitch-son out to the highest bidder.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks aloud.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's not like that. You're being completely neurotic. I was just playing along...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always meddling in my life. This is so typical of her.  But from you? I thought we had something good here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Esther, I just don't think we can see each other romantically anymore. The phone RINGS, and the Hammer picks it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We WIPE INTO SPLIT SCREEN. The Chief is on the other end.</context>
      <utterance>Hammer here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hammer, it's the Chief. We've got ourselves a situation. Get yourself down here, I've got something you need to see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai. Thank god you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clicks a button on a remote control, and static fills the GIANT TELECOMMUNICATIONS SCREEN, eventually fading into the image of a larger then life SANTA.</context>
      <utterance>About an hour ago, we received this transmission from the North Pole.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An image of a GIANT CLOCK in the shape of a Star Of David.</context>
      <utterance>And now my Hanukkah loving friends, I will reveal to you the true nature of my diabolical scheme.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We TILT down to reveal a BLUE GLOWING SUBSTANCE in its base. Santa comes back on screen.</context>
      <utterance>The Jewish Atomic clock, located in the outskirts of Jerusalem. Keeper of time for the Jewish Calendar. Powered by Judeum. An element so rare, it exists only inside the clock itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He struggles with this one. He looks at someone O.S. at the North Pole.</context>
      <utterance>Once I extract the Judeum from the clock, the Jewish Calendar will cease to exist, forever eradicating Hanukkah. In less than twenty four hours, which by your Jewish Calendar is approximately...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A notepad and pen are handed to him from O.S. Santa makes some written calculations on the notepad. He's clearly having trouble. The Hammer and Esther exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Can I borrow that pen and notepad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tiny Tim hobbles into frame on his crutches.</context>
      <utterance>Four years and three quarters a lunar cycle?  Well, whatever! In less than twenty four Christian hours, Hanukkah will be nothing more than a fond memory. Tiny Tim.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas everybody, and god bless us, everyone. The two laugh hysterically.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The transmission, however, doesn't end. The two abruptly stop laughing. Santa begins to talk to TINY TIM.</context>
      <utterance>End transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was good. Very chilling, but you still got all the points across that we talked about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut to more confused reactions of the Hammer and Esther.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Good, good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't too over the top?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was the perfect level.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa looks towards the camera and begins to react strangely.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Oh, did I tell you. I picked up that new KC and the Sunshine Band record that you recommended. You were right, it is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Santa approaches the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Why is the red light on the camera still on? Are you still filming me!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer turns to the Chief.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking ass... Static fills the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like I got a plane to catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take Esther with you, you'll need the backup.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, it's too dangerous. Besides, my days of hooking are over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not my bitch Mordechai. Please, you have to believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I miss something here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his attention to Esther.</context>
      <utterance>It's a long story. I'll explain when I get back from saving the clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer exits. Esther is dejected.</context>
      <utterance>Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tail him. He's gonna need the help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you speak English?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISRAELI RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ch sound she makes is accompanied by a whole lot of spittle. The Hammer wipes his face, and then returns the favor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Chello.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's unfazed. The Hammer continues.</context>
      <utterance>Chello.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She checks her rental sheet.</context>
      <utterance>I need to rent your biggest Cadillac. Preferably lowered, with white wall tires.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISRAELI RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nails him again. Seriously annoyed, he wipes his face clean once more.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry sir, but somebody just rented our last Chadillac.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what else do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISRAELI RENTAL AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer puts his hand up as a shield and cuts her off quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we do have a Ch...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever it is, I'll take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HEAD ELF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELF FLUNKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not sure. I think it was left over from an Israeli Robbie Kneivel television special. You want me to get rid of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD ELF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No time. Besides, it's not like someone's gonna jump their motorcycle into the building while we're inside. The HEAD THUG ELF points up towards the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD ELF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Thug Elves look up to the sky, and we do an OVERHEAD PUSH DOWN ON THEM as helicopter force winds blow their hats off. The carriage of SANTA'S SLEIGH touches down on the ground. Tiny Tim sits shotgun in the sleigh while Santa vomits violently over the other side. Santa finishes up, and wipes his mouth with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>There's Santa now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm airsick you asshole! Where the hell did these reindeer learn to fly?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Why don't you ask them sir. Santa takes this in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More scared reindeer faces. Comet furtively motions towards Rudolph with his antlers. Santa sees this, marches quickly up to Rudolph, and gets in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Who's the leader of this operation?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your major malfunction, dumbfuck!? Rudolph's scared shitless.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Rudolph attempts to move forward, but the harness attachments prevent him from doing so.</context>
      <utterance>Step forward son!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can feel the Robert Deniro-esque intensity boiling inside of Santa.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, he can't sir. The harnesses.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rudolph shakes his head. The bells on his harness tinkle. Santa continues to stare down the reindeer as he walks away. Rudolph is clearly broken, but continues staring back at Santa as he makes his way out of frame. The expression on Rudolph's face changes from fear to insolence as he angrily follows the O.S. Santa. Suddenly, Santa charges right back into frame, and places his drawn gun to Rudolph's temple.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna learn to guide this sled right? You gonna make sure your men follow suit? Because if I'm puking down chimneys come Christmas Eve, I'm gonna have your hide. We clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Rudolph quickly looks away. Santa puts his gun back into his belt, and then adjusts his suit and hat as if to regain his composure. Without warning, Santa throws a fake punch at Rudolph's face, forcing the reindeer to flinch.</context>
      <utterance>You eyeballin' me son!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the kind of place where a giant telescope at an observatory would be housed. The clock is breathtaking in its size. On its face, in place of the standard numerals are the names of Jewish holidays. For example, "Yom Kipur" is where the twelve should be, followed by "Passover", etc. In the center of the face, an odometer-like gauge reveals the year '5734.' At its base, the brilliant blue Judeum glows brightly. Santa barks out orders.</context>
      <utterance>The Jewish Atomic Clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>One of the thugs pushes play on a ghetto blaster and the song 'Santa Claus Is Coming To Town' begins to play. A few of the thugs insert a bicycle pump into the Judeum clock base and begin pumping.</context>
      <utterance>Get moving! We've got work to do!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still on the bike, the Hammer uses his feet to backpeddle the motorcycle to the doorway. Looks of bewilderment from Santa and his gang. The Hammer reaches the doorway and kisses his hand. A John Wooish SLO-MO shot as the Hammer touches his hand to the mezuzah nailed to the doorframe. The Hammer jumps off the bike, and we get the requisite QUICK push in on him as he pulls out two Uzi's from under his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Uh. Can you just give me one second? Santa is confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Santa draws a pistol, and with a single shot from his Uzi, the Hammer blows it out of his hand. It lands on the other side of the room. Santa looks up from his empty hand.</context>
      <utterance>Let's dance the hora!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa's Elf Thugs open a CHEST filled with LARGE SUB-MACHINE GUNS. The chest is labeled "HEAVY ARTILLERY." With great difficulty, they struggle to pull the heavy machinery out of the box. The Hammer, mildly amused, watches them. The Hammer blasts away, and the elves scramble for safety. The sound of gunfire is deafening and constant. An Elf sneaks quietly towards Santa's gun. Esther walks in through the front door and spots something O.S. that gives her cause for concern. Unbeknownst to the Hammer, the SNEAKY ELF picks up Santa's gun. He raises it at the Hammer, ready to fire.</context>
      <utterance>Get him boys!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer turns and nails the elf just in time. Esther, gun drawn, backs up into frame with the Hammer, and the two fire off rounds.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai! Behind you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai, I love you. I couldn't let you do this alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too. I'm sorry about freaking out yesterday. I was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We do another QUICK PUSH into the Hammer as he turns towards Tiny Tim. Tiny Tim, standing alone with his crutches tucked under his arms, looks like a deer caught in headlights. The Hammer grins mischievously.</context>
      <utterance>Go check on the clock. I'll finish up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer begins firing. In SLOW-MOTION, Tiny Tim hobbles as fast as he can towards an overturned table, gunfire trailing him. Like a pole vaulter with two poles, Tiny Tim plants his crutches firmly into the ground and launches himself over the table. He lands directly on top of Santa, who cowers underneath the table.</context>
      <utterance>Uh oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get off of me you cripple!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We DOLLY BACK with the Hammer as he approaches the camera, firing rounds at the table. We cut to the duct taped Hasidic Guards tied to their chairs. One of them frantically nudges the other and motions to the window. Fear fills both of their eyes. We see what they see. Through the window, the SUN is quickly setting behind the mountains. We cut back to the Hammer. The speed with which he shoots begins to slow. Esther, checking the clock for damage calls to him.</context>
      <utterance>What are we gonna do? He's got us on the ropes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut back to Santa and Tiny Tim underneath the table. We HEAR the shooting continue to slow, until finally it ceases altogether. Santa and Tiny Tim exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm feeling kind of tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on? Why'd he stop?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he ran out of ammo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tiny Tim pokes his head over the table to see... The Hammer and Esther lie together slumped up against the wall. They look exhausted. Tiny Tim drops back below the table.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's kinda just resting in the corner with his girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks for a second. An idea forms.</context>
      <utterance>Resting?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What day is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa makes the connection.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. About sundown I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blank look from Tiny Tim.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't I think of this? It's the Sabbath.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer's POV as Santa and his thugs approach him cautiously.</context>
      <utterance>The day of rest. He can't fight on the Sabbath. C'mon, get up. We've got him beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Santa turns to his thugs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, well. It looks as if the Hebrew Hammer's got a weakness after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Another blank look from Tiny Tim.</context>
      <utterance>Finish extracting the Judeum from the clock.  Tiny Tim, I want you to introduce the Hebrew Hammer to the Christmas spirit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to be nice to him for no apparent reason whatsoever, buy him clothing he'll never wear, and for just one day of the year pretend to forgive him for all the horrible things he did to me as a young boy when my mommy wasn't looking?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks about it.</context>
      <utterance>No dipshit, I want you to kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa grabs Esther and attempts to pull her up. The Hammer holds on tightly to her other hand, but isn't strong enough to resist Santa's might. Esther's hand is pulled from his firm grip, and Santa takes her into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Santa's gonna take the sled back to the North Pole and celebrate his victory with his new stocking stuffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esther!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa forces her out the front door, leaving Tiny Tim alone with the Hammer. O.S., we hear the sound of Santa's Sled taking off.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a shot of the elves pumping out the Judeum from the clock, and then tilt up to reveal its face. The dial slowly spins past 'Yom Kippur', 'Passover', 'Hanukkah,' 'Purim', and then finally the 'Macy's 50% Off Spring Sale.' Tiny Tim raises his gun point blank at the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look Hammer. The clock's already beginning to power down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We hear the sounds of a whole lot of GUNS being COCKED. Tiny Tim turns around to see the ENTIRE KWANZAA LIBERATION FRONT with their guns raised at him. Jamal, standing next to Mohammed, flashes Tiny Tim a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Ah. What's the matter? No more snappy one liners. It seems all is lost when...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Kwanzaa nigga!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mordechai, you're back. The clock?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still ticking. Thanks to the help from the Brothers at the KLF, Hanukkah's safe for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's wonderful! The Chief notices the Hammer's dejected look.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why the long face?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Esther. Santa's got her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief, overcome by sadness, slumps down into a chair.</context>
      <utterance>My Esther! Oh Mordechai.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Will you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo, standing in the BG, gives the Chief the fist/chest salute.</context>
      <utterance>I love her sir. If I don't help you, I won't be able to make her my wife. Mohammed Ali Paula Abdul Rahim has agreed to come with me to the North Pole on a rescue mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asalam Alekem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a mench. Thank you.  Mordechai, by any means necessary, you bring my Esther back to me. Even if it requires using Judaism's most powerful weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief shakes his head yes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, not the...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There won't be any need for that sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hammer, the fate of my daughter rests solely in your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer motions to Mo, and the two begin to leave. They pass by Sammy Davis Jr. Jr. The Hammer acknowledges him.</context>
      <utterance>I know sir. I won't let you down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sammy Davis Jr. Jr.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY DAVIS JR. JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo whispers into the Hammer's ear.</context>
      <utterance>You two cats are beautiful. I love you guys. You take care babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still working out some identity issues.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be tough, but the back entrance looks like our best bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to ask you, how were you able to pinpoint the exact location of Santa's workshop? We've been trying to gain that piece of surveillance for years. The Hammer puts the binoculars down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the year 5734. It's time the boys at the KLF got into the 58th century. Let me show you something. The Hammer pulls out a LAPTOP COMPUTER.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The JDL supplies all its agents with this state of the art device called a laptop computator.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. What's it do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer makes a few keystrokes and turns the screen towards Mo.</context>
      <utterance>Now this might get a bit technical, but try and stay with me. Using a highly sophisticated connection of other computators, called the Internet, I can access surveillance maps, villian biographical information, and even sports scores with a few simple keystrokes of this electronic typewriter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that's far out! Hey, the Jets won!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wait, there's more. With a few swift clicks of this hand-computer interface, commonly referred to as a mouse, I can download illicit pornographic material and even send it along to a friend via a cyber postal route known as e-mail. Mo's interest is seriously peaked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Porno? You're tellin' me that you can get porno on that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer does some computing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mo's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>For example, here's a picture of your sister Tawanda getting freaky with a German Shepard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the laptop from the Hammer and looks at the screen. A picture of TAWANDA making out with a GERMAN man decked out in lederhosen on a rural German hillside. The two are surrounded by sheep. Mo gives a sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>Gettin' freaky with a what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mo goes for the keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Oy vey, that's almost as bad. That's Tawanda getting freaky with a notorious white supremacist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We get a CU of the ENTER KEY as Mo presses it. A SOOTHING COMPUTERIZED FEMALE VOICE purrs...</context>
      <utterance>Where's the white out button on this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTERIZED FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Message sent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What just happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember that bit about the cyber postal route?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer looks at the blissfully ignorant Mo with empathy.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, forget about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rudolph, equipped with a tray around his neck holding a glass of egg nog, walks over. Santa stares at him antagonistically as he takes the glass off of the tray and takes a sip. Santa puts his cigarette back into his mouth, takes a drag and blows smoke past camera. A huge cloud of smoke blows over Rudolph's face. Santa smiles at his women as we hear Rudolph cough.</context>
      <utterance>Rudolph, more egg nog!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the two women are pushed from his lap as a SASSY BLACK PROSTITUTE rises up between his legs from underneath the table.</context>
      <utterance>Ho, ho, ho.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASSY BLACK PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen motherfucker, I already told you! I don't care how much yo ass is payin' me, if you call me that one more time there ain't gonna be no more visits down to the South Pole! You feelin' me!? His ego deflates a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tiny Tim enters the room. He has a black eye and his clothing is torn.</context>
      <utterance>Yes maam, loud and clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SASSY BLACK PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn sugar, what happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Santa, I got some really bad news.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer unwraps his leather straps, and then tosses them high over the wall. The boxes on the straps catch on a pipe. The line is pulled taut, and the boxes hold secure against the pipe. The Hammer and Mo begin to scale the wall a la the 60's Batman and Robin television show. The Hammer leads the way while Mo, directly behind him, has his arms wrapped tightly around his waist. The Hammer stops climbing for a second, and turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Just praying to god that we don't kill ourselves going over this wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mo releases his arms from the Hammer's waist. Indeed, he is tied in.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you don't have to hold on to my waist. You're tied in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo heads for the door. The Hammer calls to him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that was easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Before we enter, you need to know that my research has determined that Santa's compound is wired with the XP 2000 stereo type alarm system.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A stereo type alarm system?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer points to above the door. Sure enough, there sit</context>
      <utterance>Take a look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we bypass it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This pisses Mo off.</context>
      <utterance>The alarm will trigger if the system detects any Non-W.A.S.P. tendencies inside the building. For example, if you were to dribble a basketball, or eat watermelon, or use the word dawg...that is, spelled with an aw as opposed to the letter o...within the confines of this workshop, the alarm would sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen cat, I'll have you know that I hate the taste of watermelon and am a terrible basketball player.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two enter through the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well that's good news for us. It means the system is outdated. This should be easy. C'mon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer bends down to pick up the change.</context>
      <utterance>It's all clear. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo's eyes widen in terror.</context>
      <utterance>Mo, I think you dropped some...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer picks up the pennies, and the ear splitting alarm system is triggered. Red Lights flash, and over the loudspeakers we hear..</context>
      <utterance>Hammer, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUDSPEAKERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo and The Hammer start running down the hallway. Doors line the corridor. The Hammer kicks open one of the doors, and enters as it shuts behind him. The camera stays in the hallway with Mo, who looks around nervously. From inside the room, we can hear</context>
      <utterance>Jewdar alert! Jewdar alert!</utterance>
   <speaker>INTENSE GUNFIRE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hammer exits the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two continue on down the hall. The Hammer spots another door, violently kicks it open, and enters. Again, the door shuts behind him followed by the sound of more INTENSE</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNFIRE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hammer exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mo stops and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo shakes his head in understanding, and the two run on, making a hard right out of frame at the corridor's end. A beat passes, and then we hear MORE INTENSE GUNFIGHTING.</context>
      <utterance>Offscreen gunfire. That Jewish Atomic Clock stuff ate up a lot of our budget.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tiny Tim spots them and begins to hobble furiously away in the other direction.</context>
      <utterance>There's Tiny Tim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mo runs down the hallway after Tiny Tim. The Hammer turns towards the other direction to find... TWO ELVES on multi-colored MOPEDS comin' right for him. The Hammer stands motionless as the Elves gain ground. Right before they reach him, the Hammer quickly pulls his Talis off of his neck and holds it outstretched, clotheslining the two off of their mopeds. The elves are out cold. The Hammer admires his work. Santa, running for his life, rounds the corner. He stops dead in his tracks as he spots the Hammer. The two look at one another for a brief moment, and then Santa points at something behind the Hammer.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take Tiny Tim. You go find your woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer looks behind him. Nothing. He turns back to find Santa long gone.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's that over there? Is that a bowl of Matzah Ball soup?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off down the hall after Santa.</context>
      <utterance>Damn!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tiny Tim closes his eyes in anticipation of the worst. Mo grabs both of his crutches from under his arm and runs off. Tiny Tim wobbles a few steps and then slumps down against the wall. We PULL AWAY from Tiny Tim as he calls to Mo.</context>
      <utterance>Now I'm gonna do to you what I should have done earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINY TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My crutches. Noooo. Not my crutches.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my girlfriend Santa?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell you anything Hammer! You're gonna have to kill me before I tell you! The Hammer's confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if I kill you, then you'll be dead. Santa thinks about this for a couple seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer looks up from his interrogation and spots a sign taped to a door directly behind Santa. It reads, "THE ROOM</context>
      <utterance>Good point.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHERE THE HEBREW HAMMER'S GIRLFRIEND IS."</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hammer grins mischievously at Santa.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hammer fires a single round past camera. RED SPLATTERS his face. We cut to the other side. Santa cowers by the cart of</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry your pretty little head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We hear Esther screaming from inside the room.</context>
      <utterance>That was a warning shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Santa kicks the Hammer's gun out of his hand, and then draws a pistol from behind his belt and points it at him.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai! I'm in here! Help! The Hammer turns towards the sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More screaming from Esther behind the door.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like the tables have turned once again Hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you won't even be able to say goodbye to your Esther. So sad. So long Mordechai. Give my father my regards. Santa readies to fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer closes his eyes and puts his hands together as if in meditation. Santa looks around nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I didn't want it to come to this, but you leave me no choice. I have no other option but to use the most powerful weapon in the Jewish arsenal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer meditates for a bit more. Suddenly, his eyes open and he begins...</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shlepped all the way to the North Pole for this? I come to fight you, and you don't even put out anything to nosh on? What kind of arch nemesis are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther continues to scream for help. This makes the Hammer even more determined.</context>
      <utterance>Hah! Jewish guilt. Well, it won't work on me Hammer. I'm too strong for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's beginning to work on Santa.</context>
      <utterance>What sort of host would treat company this way? Esther is clearly uncomfortable in your guest room. I'm shvitizing from running around shooting people. And my feet. What kind of flooring is this anyway? My arches are killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santa's a wreck.</context>
      <utterance>And to top it off, you didn't even have the courtesy to give me a proper hello when I entered the room. What have I ever done to you to be treated with such disrespect?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands his piece to the Hammer and kneels on the ground, pointing to his head.</context>
      <utterance>Please, make it stop. I'll do anything. Here take my gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mo enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot me. Please, just one to the head. Put me out of misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOHAMMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hammer, you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's kosher. Watch him for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hammer kicks open the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esther!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is restrained to a chair. The Hammer quickly unties her, and the two kiss. As they continue kissing, we hear the sound of someone CLEARING THEIR THROAT. The Hammer looks towards the source of the noise to see none other than JOSEPH LIEBERMAN. Joe is tied to a chair, and wears a Gore/Lieberman 2000 campaign button.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer begins to untie Joe.</context>
      <utterance>Joseph Lieberman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPH LIEBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esther looks at the Hammer curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Mordechai! Thank god you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two know each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three step back into Santa's Conference Room. Mo continues to hold Santa at gunpoint.</context>
      <utterance>We go to the same temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Hammer turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Mo, get him out of my sight. Mo begins to take Santa away.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Santa's a broken man. He gets on his knees and inquires earnestly...</context>
      <utterance>No, wait. I need closure here.  I just wanna say one thing. You know where you messed up Santa? You underestimated the true meaning of Hanukkah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer thinks about this for a second. He's drawing a blank. He looks to Esther, and she shrugs back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Please tell me. What is the true meaning of Hanukkah?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's...that's a very good question. And I do know that it does have something to do with...dreidels, and... Esther chimes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and latkes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mo drags Santa out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>And latkes! And some miracle oil that lasted eight days. And that my friend, should've been enough for you. Take him away Mo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer turns to Esther, and gets down on one knee. He places a ring on her finger.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I see the light now. I was wrong. I'm... And Santa's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esther Bloomenbergensteinenthal, will you marry me? She glows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe pokes his head out into the Hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Of course! I'd gladly give up my last name to be with you. The two kiss in celebration.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE LIEBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to the Hammer. The Hammer shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>What happened out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE LIEBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Mordechai, you know how I detest gore.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we PULL out as the three make their way down the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Well then maybe you should have thought about that before you ran with him. C'mon, let's get you back to Washington.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Esther and the Hammer at the other end of the table. They smile and hold hands. Domestic bliss.</context>
      <utterance>Shabat Shalom everybody!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER/ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a bit of difficulty, Mrs. Carver works her large behind into her chair.</context>
      <utterance>Shabat Shalom!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer raises his glass in honor of Mun Chi. Mun Chi returns the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>And a Merry Christmas to all of our Gentile friends. Mun Chi.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Esther smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Before we start the Sabbath, I'd personally just like to thank god for all the blessings I've received over the past year. A beautiful fiancee...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver is as proud as can be...</context>
      <utterance>...a wonderful mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and the opportunity to help my brothers and sisters in the Jewish community.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squeezes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well I'm just glad you're safe Bubba Shaina, and eating by your mother for Shabos.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver begins to cut her meat.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But with all the attention the newspapers and television have given you, you'd think that you were the pope or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets himself back on track.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I did save Hanukkah mom. My children, and my children's children, and my children's children's children...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and their children will all be able to eat latkes and spin dreidels, and light the menorah with the knowl...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So you saved Hanukkah Mr. Big Shot. I mean, let's be honest Mordechai, it isn't even one of the high holidays. Mordechai looks to Esther. She shrugs her shoulders in encouragement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if you had saved Passover or Yom Kipur, then maybe you'd have what to brag about. Did I tell you that my friend Maureen's son, the Investment Banker, was responsible for a very big merger on...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We get a shot of Mrs. Carver. She's a master of the art of pleasant non-listening.</context>
      <utterance>...No, no, no, no, no. I see what you're doing here. So all of a sudden Hanukkah's not good enough for you, is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I have news for you mom. It is good enough...I'm good enough and I won't leave here until I hear you tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver picks up the paralyzed Tabby and begins Eskimo kissing it.</context>
      <utterance>Mazel Tov!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Mazel Tov! A boojee boojee boojee boo...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mun Chi, completely uninvolved in the conversation and obviously famished, scoops serving after serving onto his plate. Mrs. Carver ignores her son as she continues to play with the cat.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm not finished yet, mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Carver removes the diaper. Esther and Hammer gag from the smell of it. Mun Chi, a forkful of food inches from his mouth, gets a whiff and then places the utensil down in angry frustration.</context>
      <utterance>...A boojee boojee boojee boo. What's that Mazel Tov? Your tuchus needs some more airing out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom! We're eating!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a good poop you made in your diaper Mazel Tov! That's right! Mommy loves you! Such a good boy you are! This gets the Hammer going.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I get it. To you, the cat pooping in his diaper is somehow better than my saving a Jewish holiday.  Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what are you two planning after the wedding?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for starters, we're going to honeymoon in Boca for a week. And then, when we get back, Morty's been talking about taking a stable, good paying job as a consultant for the JDL.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From outside, we hear the sound of sleighbells ringing.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I couldn't be happier for the both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer motions for everyone to get up and follow him to the window. We cut to the outside of the window looking in on the four as they try and get a better look outside.</context>
      <utterance>I think I hear the new Santa Claus busy at work. C'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot to ask you, who'd they put in charge as the new Santa Claus?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hammer spots something up in the sky, and points it out to the rest of them.</context>
      <utterance>Since Santa will be living out the rest of his days at a home for the religionally insane and because he had no blood heirs, the Kwanzaa Liberation Front and the Jewish Defense League agreed to make the whole Santa Claus process a democratic vote. We're all very pleased with the first Santa elect.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The full moon shines brightly in the BG of the night sky as we slowly PAN past Rudolph and the rest of the reindeer, eventually reaching the cockpit. Jamal holds the reigns and waves down at Mordechai and company. From the window, Mordechai, Esther, Mrs. Carver, and Mun Chi wave back. The Hammer Jewxploitation theme music begins to fade up.</context>
      <utterance>Look, there he is now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas Jamal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We pull away from the outside window as the four continue to wave. One by one, the reindeer whip straight past camera followed by Jamal. As he clears frame we...</context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas Niggas!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
