<movie id="562" title="Time Machine The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say, this is outright rude of the man!</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridewell, filling his glass, is trying to say some- thing but is interrupted by KEMP (unscrews the cigar from his tight lips) This is such a confounded waste of time! If he's not coming, I've any number of more important things to do. All heads turn as Mrs. Watchett enters, closing the door quietly behind her. With an envelope in her hand she stands there, hesitating.</context>
      <utterance>He's undoubtedly been detained. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is taken aback for a moment, then walks over to Filby and hands him the open envelope. He takes his time in extracting the note.</context>
      <utterance>Speak up -- what is it, woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDEWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pointing to note)</context>
      <utterance>Well...are we or are we not invited to dinner? FILBY  Apparently we are.  How long has he been gone? MRS. WATCHETT  I can't rightly say, sir. - Several days...I hardly catch a glimpse of him lately. He never leaves the laboratory and comes out only to nibble at his meals...but he did tell me days ago about dinner tonight and left these instructions.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A faint, nervous smile is her acknowledgement and with that she retreats toward the door. DR. HILLYER (indicating the note) What does it say, Filby? What's wrong?</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mrs. Watchett.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kemp tears the note out of Filby's hand and reads it hurriedly. Meanwhile, Mrs. Watchett swings the door open and turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing really. - George merely says that if he is not here by eight we're to begin without him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises and starts for the dining room. The others follow.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner is served, gentlemen! BRIDEWELL  First sensible thing I've heard all evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is peculiar. He is usually very prompt, precise and punctual.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not the behavior of a gentleman.</context>
      <utterance>He's making fools of us by inviting us here and then not showing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridewell, already seated at the heavily laden dining table, pours a glass of wine for himself while the others settle down. This time the chair at the head of the table is conspicuously unoccupied. BRIDWELL (arises, lifting his glass) One thing I will say for George, he keeps the best cellar in the south of England...and Mrs. Watchett is the finest cook in the world. - I think I'll drink to that! The glass barely touches his lips as he freezes at the SOUND OF DROPPING TRAYS and a PIERCING SCREAM. All look in the direction of another door across the room.</context>
      <utterance>To say nothing of the waste of time. DR. HILLYER  To say nothing of the waste of time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching him, each seizes an elbow to support him. Bridewell throws a frantic glance at Dr. Hillyer back at the table. The Time Traveller, however, moves forward under his own power.</context>
      <utterance>Good lord! - What's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches the table and sinks into his chair. With trembling hands Bridewell tries to pour him a glass of wine, spilling most of it over the tablecloth. The Time Traveller looks up at him with a wry smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all right...just some food...a drink...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stunned Bridewell is unable to speak while the Time Traveller empties his glass. BRIDEWELL (a delayed answer) Of course. I'm...all right... Meanwhile, Mrs. Watchett hovers over the Time Traveller like a mother hen. MRS. WATCHETT (half apology, half concern) I didn't recognize you!...it was so dark... The CAMERA MOVES IN as she dishes up a bowl of soup for him, but he pushes it away.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Watchett grasps the carving knife from Dr. Hillyer and, with a single slash, cuts off a huge portion of beef and loads it onto his plate.</context>
      <utterance>Meat...I'm hungry for meat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, can't you speak, man? What happened to you? Aren't you going to tell us...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDEWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone, can't you? TIME TRAVELLER  It's all right. - I want to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will keep, George. Eat, rest a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I must tell it now... while I still remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, try to relax a bit. You've all the time in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly the CAMERA MOVES IN CLOSER while everyone listens so intensely that, aside from the Time Traveller's VOICE, only the TICKING of a pendulum CLOCK is heard.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, David.  That's exactly what I have. - All the time in the world!... ever since we were all together five days ago, the last day of Eighteen Hundred Ninety Nine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA DRAWS BACK to reveal the LIBRARY. The Time Traveller, wearing casual tweeds and smoking a pipe, sits in his favorite chair behind the Ebony Box. Across from him in another chair sits Dr. Hillyer puffing his cigar. Bridewell and Filby have glasses in their hands -- Kemp nothing. All are looking at the box.</context>
      <utterance>There in that box rests the result of two years' labor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to finish the job before the new century began. - I barely made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDEWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marvelous. DR. HILLYER  What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it has to do with time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always maintained what this nation needs is a reliable timepiece. The Navy needs one. The Army needs one. - For the artillery you know. KEMP  Couldn't do better, George. So that's why you've been in hiding. - Clever of you, indeed! FILBY  I don't believe George is referring to a new kind of timepiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A perplexed look comes over Bridewell's face. Dr. Hillyer registers concern. Kemp looks troubled. Only Filby expresses avid interest.</context>
      <utterance>When I speak of time, I'm referring to the fourth dimension.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, as you know, the difficulty in explaining the fourth dimension is that it cannot be seen or felt - it must be thought of.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind, George, would you refresh me on the first three dimensions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Filby, they must have taught you something at school! BRIDEWELL  Suppose you explain it, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly!  When I move in a straight line, forward or backward, that's one dimension. - When I move to the left or right, two dimensions. - When I move up and down, three dimensions.  For instance, this box has three dimensions: length, breadth, and height. BRIDEWELL  Well, then, what's the fourth dimension?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's...that's mere theory! No one can really say what the fourth dimension is or even that it exists.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the contrary, Doctor! The fourth dimension is as true and as real a dimension as any of the other three. In fact, they couldn't exist without it. DR. HILLYER  How do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It wouldn't exist at all, would it?</context>
      <utterance>Well, take that box. It has the first three dimensions, as you said. But what if it didn't exist in Time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So - for an object to exist at all, it must exist in the fourth dimen- sion....and that fourth dimension is duration....Time! DR. HILLYER  All right! But what's in that box?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming to that. But first, consider! Why is it that we usually ignore the fourth dimension? Because we have no freedom to move in it. We can move in the other three -- up, down, forward, backward, sideways. But when it comes to Time, we are prisoners. Do you follow me, Anthony?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George! You've given a most lucid explanation and all that! But I don't think I entirely understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look! There are a lot of things in the world you don't understand, aren't there?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! Quite a number.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't refuse to believe in them because of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if I can see the proof with my own eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to Dr. Hillyer as he eagerly rushes to the table, lifts the box with surprise at its lightness, and takes it to the Time Traveller. George opens it with great care and brings forth a mechanical device</context>
      <utterance>Good! All I'm asking you to do now is to witness a demonstration of the possibility of movement in the fourth dimension.  Philip, will you please hand me that box?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you. The larger model can carry a passenger on a journey through Time. - Not through Space, mind you, but through Time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDEWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I say George! If you start floating around in the future, aren't you likely to mess things up for the rest of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The future is already there. It's irrevocable and cannot be changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the most important question to which I hope to find an answer. Can Man control his destiny? Can he change the shape of things to come?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine that this cigar is the Time Traveller. Now, this lever in front of him controls movement. Forward pressure sends the Machine into the future, backward pressure into the past. And the harder the pressure the faster the Machine travels.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, uncertain whether he is joking or not. Bridewell stoops with difficulty to examine the table.</context>
      <utterance>This experiment can be performed only once. If it succeeds, I lose my model forever. That is why I need witnesses.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite disbelief, there is a tense silence as he puts his finger on the lever. Then he pauses.</context>
      <utterance>You're ready then?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Hillyer extends his hand hesitantly, smiling weakly.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Hillyer, would you care to lend me your hand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did it go? TIME TRAVELLER  Go? Nowhere in the usual sense. It's still here.  But it's no longer in the present. It's traveling through time - to the future, to be precise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you seriously expect us to believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you just said it hasn't really moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why can't we see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Hillyer runs his hand over the top of the table. DR. HILLYER (exasperated) If it occupies the same space, I should be able to feel it.</context>
      <utterance>Because we're in this room on December 31st, 1899, while the model you saw is perhaps a hundred years away. This room, or even this house, may no longer exist a hundred years from now. But the Time Machine is occupying the same space it did a moment before it went off on its journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must remember that the space you've just put your hand through is today's space. You can't put your hand into the space of tomorrow. DR. HILLYER  Space is space! It doesn't change! The same space that is here now should be here a hundred or even a thousand years from now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Hillyer turns away, speechless.</context>
      <utterance>No! Time changes space. This flat ground we're standing on now could have been at the bottom of the sea a million years ago. And a million years from now it could be the interior of a huge mountain.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose what you say is true. Exactly what do you suggest we do with such a contraption?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Hillyer, having controlled his fury, now exchanges significant glances with Kemp and turns back with an air of reasonableness.</context>
      <utterance>For my part, I intend to take a journey into the future. - Unless someone else prefers to volunteer. There is no response. BRIDEWELL  I say, George. Suppose you go off and get lost in the fiftieth century! How will you find your way back? TIME TRAVELLER  That's a calculated risk I'm prepared to take.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen, George! I don't know what you take us for, but we're not fools. There are a number of ways of doing a disappearing trick! But a man of your ability should not bother with such nonsense.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're being sensible. I'll take care of it first thing in the New Year.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, time to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Hillyer and Kemp head toward the door. Bridewell lingers at the table where the model of the Time Machine disappeared. BRIDEWELL (concerned) Are you all right, George?</context>
      <utterance>Yes, we all have our plans for tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly Bridewell leaves the library followed by the Time Traveller.</context>
      <utterance>Coming, Bridewell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door and they file past him, Bridewell at the rear.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>AD LIBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridewell clasps the Time Traveller's shoulder, reassuringly.</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year. - Goodbye, George - Happy Twentieth Century. - Etc.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd better stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm all right.</context>
      <utterance>You needn't have troubled yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you're not. - You've been behaving oddly for over a month now.  I'm not leaving until you tell me what's on your mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your gesture, David, but if you don't mind I'd rather you left me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Enormously.</context>
      <utterance>You have changed, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. FILBY  Will you answer me one question honestly?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why this preoccupation with Time? TIME TRAVELLER  Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go simple on me, George! TIME TRAVELLER  If you want to know the truth, I don't much care for the time I was born into. - It seems people aren't dying fast enough these days. They call upon science to invent new, more efficient weapons to depopulate the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I quite agree with you. But here we are and we have to make the best of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may have to. I don't. FILBY  All right. Take a journey on your contraption. What would you become?... A Greek? A Roman? One of the Pharaohs?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I prefer the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not seriously saying you can do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw the experiment this afternoon, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw a toy machine vanish. But I'm certain there are a number of ways of doing that trick. Any magician at the Hippodrome could probably do it. TIME TRAVELLER  It was no trick! - Would you care to see the full-scale model?</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I would not! I have no desire to tempt the laws of Providence and I don't think you should. It's not for man to trifle with.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you sound like Hillyer and Kemp.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Distant SOUNDS of NEW YEAR'S CELEBRATIONS are HEARD.</context>
      <utterance>There is something in their common sense attitude to life.  George, I speak to you as a friend. More, as a brother. If that machine can do what you say it can...destroy it. Destroy it, George, before it destroys you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have plans for New Year's Eve. Don't let me keep you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary isn't well. We decided to stay home with the baby. But why don't you come home with me. You haven't seen little Jaime for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's stopping you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>I just want to see the old century out by myself. FILBY  Have it your own way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you promise me that you won't leave the house tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Filby, a little puzzled by this strange promise, turns to go as the Time Traveller puts down the poker and steps up to him.</context>
      <utterance>I promise you, I won't walk out of the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David! Please don't think me un- friendly! - Come over to dinner - next Friday. Won't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Filby pats his arm before he leaves. The Time Traveller stands there until he hears the FRONT DOOR SHUT. Then, FOLLOWED BY THE CAMERA, he goes to the writing table and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Fine...and will you bring the others with you? FILBY  Whatever you say, George. - Happy New Year. TIME TRAVELLER  And a very happy New Year to you, David.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you be having supper in this evening, sir? TIME TRAVELLER  I don't think so, Mrs. Watchett. Why don't you take the evening off and celebrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir, but if you won't be needing me I think I'll turn in early and get some sleep...  ...it I can. - Goodnight, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to go as the Time Traveller calls after her.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mrs. Watchett!  I've invited Mr. Filby and the others to dinner next Friday.  Happy New Year, Mrs. Watchett.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Watchett exits, closing the door after her. Once again the Time Traveller is alone. He looks at the old calendar that reads: "December 3l. 1899," rips the final sheet from the pad, crumples it into a tight little ball and tosses it into the hearth where it burns. With slow and deliberate movements he replaces the old calendar with the new one. Then, he hastily scribbles a note which he puts into an envelope and places it prominently on the table. He rises and mounts the steps that lead to:</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...arc in less than a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this it has turned into night and a little SNAIL rushes across the ground beneath the plant, and then the flowers start to open again. Light begins to flood the scene. In the b.g. Mrs. Watchett leaps into the garden, pauses the briefest instant to sprinkle the flowers, then with the speed of wind streaks away.</context>
      <utterance>....to see flowers closing their eyes for the night, changes that normally took hours, occuring in seconds, was beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand shoves the lever farther over toward the future position. THE HUMMING SOUND RISES TO HIGHER PITCH. The Time Traveller lurches in his seat, clings to the controls and looks at the dials.</context>
      <utterance>And as yet I was travelling very slowly!  What if I went faster?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filby! I expected more of an enthusiastic greeting from... FILBY  I'm afraid you have me confused with my father, sir. There was a remarkable resemblance. - I'm James Filby.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you a friend of father's?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...yes...I've been away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was killed in the war...a year ago. TIME TRAVELLER  No!...it can't be...  I'm sorry to hear that.  And the gentleman who used to live across the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, him. Some inventor who disappeared around the turn of the century. - If you're interested in that house, forget it. You can't buy it or even go inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was executor of the inventor's estate and he refused to liquidate it.  I often chided him on that account, but he felt positive that the owner would return some day. - Some people hereabouts think it's haunted.  Who are you, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a stranger who once knew your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.  Have you been at the front, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front? What front?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the war, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What war?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great heavens, man, don't you know we've been at war with Germany since nineteen fourteen? I thought perhaps you had seen action in France...or maybe...  Perhaps a cup of tea would make you feel better. Won't you come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...no, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure you're alright, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Time Traveller nods and James Filby slowly turns and, glancing back repeatedly, enters the Department Store.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm quite alright. JAMES FILBY  Then...goodbye, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the bitter taste of death for his old friend, David Filby, he slowly walks across the street and returns to the cottage.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Jaime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Time Traveller HEARS the SCREAMS of DIVING PLANES. He stops the Machine and looks up at:</context>
      <utterance>Suddenly, in nineteen forty I began to be buffeted from side to side. My first thought was that the Machine had a mechanical defect or a part had worn out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at:</context>
      <utterance>The last time I had stopped was in nineteen seventeen, twenty three years ago. And the war with Germany was still waging - now in the air with flying machines. It didn't seem possible they could go on fighting all these years and still have the means of fighting. Then I realized the truth of the matter. This was a new war. There must have been an interval of peace in between these wars. Yet they had learned nothing but to prepare even more effective means of destroying one another. I decided to push on into time and see the outcome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warden takes off his helmet. He is David Filby's son, James, whom we saw in 1917 as a young man. He is now in his mid-sixties.</context>
      <utterance>I can't understand you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Makes more noise than it does sense.</context>
      <utterance>Confounded radio in this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filby!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Mister Filby. - Didn't you hear the air raid siren?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean that horrible screeching?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't constructed for its aesthetic values, you know, but to warn silly young fools like yourself to get down into the shelter. Now go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm perfectly comfortable and I find your store magnificent. What splendid achievements, what gigantic strides mankind has taken, what...</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, young man. We'd better be going before the mushrooms start sprouting.  You do look familiar. Haven't we met somewhere before?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed we have. Right here. Many years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was sure of that, but the exact time escapes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was two wars ago, I believe. Nineteen seventeen. WARDEN  Why now I recall. The chap who inquired about my father -- and the house that used to be across the way.  But no...that's impossible. You haven't changed. You're not a day older. And your clothes...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's going to take me a little time to explain... You see... There is an insistent, EAR PIECING SIREN. It lasts for three seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the Time Traveller by the arm and drags him out.</context>
      <utterance>The last alert...hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Warden runs, looks back over shoulder, calling.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me! It's important. WARDEN  Look! An atomic satellite zeroing in! That's important!!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He descends into the air raid shelter.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry! Hide 'til the All Clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got to talk to you. The Time Traveller looks up as he hears the APPROACHING SIRENS OF AN AMBULANCE. Alarmed, he runs across the street directly in the path of the ambulance that threads its way between the cars left in disorder on the road. The driver spins the steering wheel and the ambulance tilts crazily in trying to avoid the Time Traveller. Suddenly there is a BLINDING FLASH. He stops and looks startled.</context>
      <utterance>All clear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ground shudders with an OMINOUS sound and sudden a great rent appears in the wide street ahead, as though the earth were being torn apart. It zig-zags down the street and from the widening fissure clouds of smoke and steam rise.</context>
      <utterance>The labor of centuries gone in an instant.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then Mother Earth, aroused by man's violence, responded with volcanic violence or her own!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I saw my own danger. I too was to be engulfed!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams the lever forward to its furthest position. The HUMMING SOARS TO A VERY HIGH PITCH.</context>
      <utterance>But to go back was unthinkable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I prayed...wondering how many centuries, how many eons must pass before the wind and rain could wear away the mountain that enclosed me. In the pitch darkness there are only the sounds of the HUMMING TIME MACHINE and the SLOW LABORED BREATHING of the Time Traveller. Then a match flickers. The CAMERA SCARES BACK. The Time Traveller holds up a burning matchstick, his face glistening with perspiration as he leans forward to look at the dials.</context>
      <utterance>The molten rock cooled.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darkness...darkness for centuries.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did I what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come after me. TIME TRAVELLER  I did it to save your life, young lady, which I'm afraid doesn't hold much meaning for you or anyone else. THE GIRL  It doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must have been fifty of your friends watching you drown. Not one of them so much as lifted a finger. -  A curious attitude - in a curious world.  Aren't you the least bit interested in what I am...where I come from? THE GIRL  Should I be? TIME TRAVELLER  Perhaps you'd better take me to someone a bit older I can talk to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Time Traveller is suddenly struck by the truth of her words. All of the little people seem to be of the Girl's age or younger.</context>
      <utterance>There is no one older.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girl makes no reply. Instead she gazes off at the sun which is low in the heavens. Shadows have already fallen over the distant hills.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't anyone age in this land of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weena.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you spell that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spell?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends over, picks up a stick and starts to draw on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Write! - Can't you write? Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are your people called? WEENA  Eloi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, perhaps curiosity has died. Perhaps even courtesy has died, but I have come a long way and there are things I would like to know. YOUNG MAN  Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I shall return to my time and they will ask questions such as what kind of government rules your world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have no government. TIME TRAVELLER  You must have a body of men who pass and enforce laws.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man in White looks at the Young Man beside him. They both shrug their shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>There are no laws. TIME TRAVELLER  How do you get your food and clothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't anyone work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. TIME TRAVELLER  Then where does this come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It grows. It always grows.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Am I right?</context>
      <utterance>But it must be planted, cultivated, nurtured...unless...  Unless you have an economy so well organized that you can devote all your time to study and experimentation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask many questions. TIME TRAVELLER  Yes! And I'm not ashamed of it. That is how man has learned and bettered himself. I must learn about you and your civilization. You have books, don't you? YOUNG MAN  Books. - Books! Yes, we have books. He rises and beckons. The Time Traveller's brow clears.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He too gets up and follows the Young Man.</context>
      <utterance>Books will tell me what I want to know. Books will tell me all about you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With sudden violence he slams his fist into a whole shelf of books. His hand plows through them and the dust swirls into the air. He turns back in anger.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...they do tell me all about you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one hand he grabs the Young Man and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done? Thousands of years of building and rebuilding creating and re-creating so that you can let it crumble to dust.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases him and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>A million yesterdays of sensitive men dying for their dreams. For what? So you can swim and dance and play.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you pounding...I came to tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you open that panel?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one opens it. Only the Morlocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of fear comes into her eyes. She drifts her gaze away from his, too frightened to answer. Gently he takes her by the shoulders and turns her to face him.</context>
      <utterance>Morlocks? - Who are the Morlocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Weena drops her eyes from him, but he cups his hand beneath her chin and tenderly turns her head back so that her eyes meet his.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you afraid of the Morlocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When they call, we must go below.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do the Morlocks live beneath the earth?  Why must you obey their command?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They give us the food we eat, the clothes we wear. We must do as they command.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weena looks up at him, her fears dwindling, find- ing comfort in this strange being whom she cannot understand. Then she glances high into the dark sky and the old fear returns.</context>
      <utterance>What happens to your people when they go below? WEENA  No one knows. No one has ever returned. TIME TRAVELLER  It won't happen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only children are frightened by the dark. - But then you are a child, aren't you?  I'll build a fire. WEENA  Let us go from here. TIME TRAVELLER  I can't, child.  My Machine is inside there, I intend to wait here 'til morning, then find some way of getting inside. WEENA  No, you must not. TIME TRAVELLER  Help me gather some wood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you from? TIME TRAVELLER  As a matter of fact, I'm from right here.  There's where my house stood many thousands of years ago. Here - to that monument, was my laboratory. About there was my library where I once sat talking with friends about my Time Machine. Meanwhile, Weena has seated herself near the bushes in the f.g.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hoped to learn a great deal. I hoped to take back the knowledge, the advancement, mankind made... instead what do I find? Vegetables! Meanwhile a pair of pale, hairy hands rise slowly from behind her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apparently no harm done, the Time Traveller releases her hand. He shakes his head in amazement and sits down beside her.</context>
      <utterance>I never saw it before.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know that the first thing which separated man from the rest of the mammals was his knowledge of fire?  No, I suppose you don't.  The next great stride came with the discovery of the wheel.  Do you know what that is?  I'm sorry I was angry with your people. I had no right to be. No more than if I had visited the Island of Bali in my own time. You were safe inside your great house, yet you came out into the night to warn me. The one characteristic which distinguished man from the animal kingdom was the spirit of self sacrifice. You have that quality, Girl. I'm sure all of your people have it. All it requires is someone to reawaken it. I shall try if you'll let me. Will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not understand you, but I believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good start. - Now try to tell me...who or what are the Morlocks?  Are they people or animals?  What do you know about yourself? The past? Don't your people ever speak of the past?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no past.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever wonder about the future?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no future.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen!  Do you hear? WEENA  Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Machines!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...Morlocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean those animals run machines?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are Morlocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but have you seen the machines?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA EASES BACK to include the Time Traveller as he reaches her.</context>
      <utterance>No, only heard of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The talking rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sort of rings?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rings that talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weena nods and starts off. He follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Can you show me these rings?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these the talking rings?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They speak?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things no one here understands.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weena takes the ring from the Time Traveller and lays it on a smooth topped porcelain block on its edge, like a coin, and spins it like a top.</context>
      <utterance>How do you get it to talk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weena shakes her head and, as though giving him a farewell gift, thrusts a large blossom into his pocket. The Time Traveller smiles as he dis- appears.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No bombs. No wars!</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, all clear? MAN IN WHITE  All clear! TIME TRAVELLER  Once....in the middle nineteen hundreds I heard a man...  The falling bombs!  That's over. Gone. Dead for hundreds of thousand of years. There are no more flying machines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the rings have told us that story.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you didn't listen. You didn't learn anything. All that is left is fear...a blind animal fear. Ages ago men were taught to hide in the ground when the sirens blew... taught to run from a raining death... but those men are dead! And so are the men who slaughtered them. Don't you understand?  You are slaves of a dead past... You don't even own your souls. You're led to slaughter like sheep! MAN IN WHITE  But there is nothing to fear now, it's all clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How are they to come back?</context>
      <utterance>What about those who went below?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unimpressed, the crowd begins to disperse, the Man in White following them.</context>
      <utterance>They never come back. Nobody can bring them back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs off.</context>
      <utterance>You can try. Won't any of you even try? He sees that the situation is hopeless. TIME TRAVELLER  Well, someone has to try!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>T.T.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she continues on with complete resignation to her fate. Unmindful of his own safety, he leaves his hid- ing place and grasps her by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Weena!</utterance>
   <speaker>T.T.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the T.T. pulls Weena toward the staircase, the Young Man follows.</context>
      <utterance>Girl!  Come to your senses! All of you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>[PAGE 90 MISSING FROM HARD COPY]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eloi below him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weena! Weena, get the torch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From now on they would have to work to survive. And looking at their faces, I somehow knew that they could start over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA MOVES CLOSE ON TIME TRAVELLER who looks up in concern.</context>
      <utterance>Another night was coming, but this night no Eloi needed to fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what of me? - I was imprisoned in a world in which I did not belong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sorry? He STOPS WHISTLING, but the MUSIC CONTINUES.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry? - Sorry for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you have to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. - I am sorry because I could tell so much to the people of my own time... I could tell them about the happiness and sorrow the future has in store for them. They could learn from it...or would they?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to stay, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't that, but I don't fit here anymore than you would in my time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like to see your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Girl, you wouldn't be very happy there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have someone like me - there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No one like you. But there are friends who will miss me. - As a matter of fact, I'm probably late already.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, men.  There is a woman too, of course!  She looks after my house for me. She is sixty-two years old. - Much older than you are. Weena, relieved, starts to comb her wet hair into a new arrangement.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do they wear their hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The women in your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up? - How?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Time Traveller puts the flower back into his pocket, gets up and walks over to Weena.</context>
      <utterance>Show me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gesture brings her eyes and lips close to his. He still holds her upswung hair and, as he gazes into her young eyes, he feels her warm breath on his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Would I be pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...you would be. More than pretty.  I wish we could go back together, Weena, back to my own time...or to times before that when the world was young. We could... EXCITED VOICES o.s. interrupt this interlude. They both look in the direction of the voices.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Filby is bent over his coffee playing absorbedly with the spoon which CLINKS loudly in the room's silence. Bridewell, of course, takes a big gulp from his brandy.</context>
      <utterance>It is ridiculous! Simply preposterous!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDEWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>hiccup quickly puts a period to that. Mrs. Watchett steps to the Time Traveller to pour him a bit of brandy.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's one thing I'll say for you, George. You always could tell a good story. Best adventure yarn I've heard for years.  You're a truly fine inventor, George! He alone starts to laugh at his 'joke', but a</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she exits Kemp looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I'll turn down your bed for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridewell examines the remaining brandy in his glass.</context>
      <utterance>Truthfully, where have you been for the past week?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDEWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, we shouldn't ask such questions, Walter. It's not hard for a man to lose a week now and then. TIME TRAVELLER  I understand your doubt. Take it as a lie if you wish. Now that I'm back I scarcely believe it myself.  Except that...  ...here are the flowers Weena gave me. He places the blossoms on the table before Filby. They are actually less than a day old and fairly fresh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DR. HILLYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rising hesitantly, Kemp turns to the Time Traveller.</context>
      <utterance>Are you coming, Kemp.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone gets up, Bridewell with difficulty, and starts to leave.</context>
      <utterance>It's getting late and you look exhausted. You had better get some rest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME TRAVELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With this he turns and goes into the house, closing the door slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, David, for being such a good friend - always.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KEMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Filby reaches a decision.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Filby? FILBY  One thing is certain. Those flowers couldn't have possibly bloomed in the winter-time. HILLYER  You don't really think that story was true?</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WHIP CRACKS.</context>
      <utterance>Look, you chaps go on. It's just a short walk home for me. HILLYER  Go on, driver!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it isn't like George. - To return empty handed. To try to rebuild a civilization without a plan.  He must have taken something with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around and discovers three empty spaces on the tightly packed book shelves. She walks to them.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing except three books.</utterance>
   <speaker>FILBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which three books?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WATCHETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, pondering the question as they leave the library.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. -- Is it important? FILBY  No, I suppose not. - Only...what three books would you have taken?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
