<movie id="98" title="Boondock Saints The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do believe the Monsignor finally got a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave.</context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy slaps Connor square in the face with the bloody slab. Connor's face is caked with blood as he stands stunned. He then leaps on Murphy, sending him into a pile of nearby hamburger. He grabs a large cow tongue from a nearby heap and begins slapping Murphy in the face with it as they both laugh and the workers cheer. Their boss, McGERKIN approaches with a very large woman. Her head is clean-shaven. The two are still laughing, out of breath, they turn.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCGERKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys this is Rose, Baum, Gurtle... Gurtle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rozengurtle Baumgartner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCGERKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be training her today, and do a good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a tattoo on her neck that reads untouched by man.</context>
      <utterance>Pleased ta meet ya Rozie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I prefer to be called Rozengurtle by men.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor exits with Roz.</context>
      <utterance>Okay then... let's get ya started.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, that's the largest woman I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCGERKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's self-imposed affirmative action. If we hire big, fat, angry lesbians, then the leftist groups representing big, fat angry lesbians, won't think we're violating their rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how politically correct you are. That's good stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCGERKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, those people can shut ya down. They'll sue you into the ground claiming they were put under mental duress, inner pain. and sufferin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy laughs as he jogs away.</context>
      <utterance>Well, as long as we're hirin' fat lesbians, give your ma a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCGERKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you Murphy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, just cut off as much fat as you can as it goes by and the rule of thumb here is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rule of thumb?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor holds up his thumb and stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where that term comes from? In the early 1900's it was legal for men to beat their wives as long as they used a stick no wider than their thumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns an icy stare. He hands her the knife. The co- workers all seem wary of Roz. Murphy stands on one side of Roz, Connor on the other, surrounded by a tight group of workers. Everyone is within ear shot of one another, cutting meat as it goes by. Knowing glances are shared by everyone. It is an uncomfortable mood.</context>
      <utterance>Can't do much damage with that. Perhaps, it shoulda been the rule of wrist. Ha!  Rule of wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Murphy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many feminists does it take to screw in a light bulb?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone burst out laughing. Rozengurtle jabs a knife in a piece of meat and turns to Connor. She pushes him and starts walking toward him. He starts backing up, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Two. One ta screw it in and one ta suck my cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you two pricks would give me problems. Give me shit cause I'm a woman. I'm not gonna take your male dominance bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on now Rozengurtle. I was just tryin' ta get a rise outta ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Just tryin' ta break the ice is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you...  ...and fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Employees gather around all the excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on its St. Patty's Day. It's all in good fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baumgartner sound Irish to you, fuck face?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches back and punches Connor full force in the face. He takes the hit very well. He stops backing up.</context>
      <utterance>Now look Rozengurtle, we're sorry. Just relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She suddenly drives her boot into his crotch, sending him to the floor reeling with pain. Two female co-workers leap to his aid.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you save all your aggression for protests and marches and what not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rozengurtle begins to turn, raising her fist to Murphy. Murphy winds up and punches her square in the face. She lands on her back. The on-lookers are stunned as he walks over and stands above her.</context>
      <utterance>You fuckin' slaves. Kowtowing to the needs of men! Get up! Get the fuck up! Leave him there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess you'll have ta change that tattoo now, won't ya Rozie!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Something is obviously wrong in her voice.</context>
      <utterance>Connor, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that worthless brother of your there? I want you both ta hear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy shuts off the water.</context>
      <utterance>Ma, what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fuckin' hot water man. That...</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy sees the concern in Connor's eyes and takes a step closer.</context>
      <utterance>Shut it. It's Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all your fault. Both you little bastards. I was a fool to believe you would bring me any peace. The day your Da left us when you were almost too young to remember, he said the two of you would do me right and make me proud, but he was wrong and I got nothin' ta live for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy is drawing closer with concern.</context>
      <utterance>Mother, what are you sayin'? You're talkin' crazy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with her?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doin' with Da's gun!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I got it ta my head now.</context>
      <utterance>I got it ta my head now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What are you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want ta tell ya one last thing before I pull the trigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull the trigger?! Have ya lost it woman?! Now just calm down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaaww, shit!... evil woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord have mercy. That was a good one ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Murphy holds the receiver in the air. Mom's still laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus! No ma! Christ ma! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, she's quite proud of herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both put an ear to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, seriously, both you listen ta me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom pauses and cackles endlessly once again.</context>
      <utterance>All right, we're both here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only 11:00 here boys so I got lot's more drinkin' ta do with your worthless relatives down at the Anvil.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just called ta torture us did ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Uncle Sibeal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know how it is with him. Always complainin' he's never turnin' a profit on St. Patty's. Whole damn family goes down there with no money, cause we know he can't bear ta charge us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's been havin' himself a nip or two as well... Been up the waitress' skirt all night, poor girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you tell him ta take it easy with that. He's gotta learn ta respect women the way Connor does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave him his first lesson in sensitivity toward the fairer sex just today.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even do it, ya bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got beat up by a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that was a girl I want ta see some papers. She had ta be just preoperative for Christ sakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord's name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother Mary, full of grace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do, Connor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we tried ta make friends and she gave me a shot ta the nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... the dirty bitch! I hope ya trounced her a good one!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I didn't but...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I respected the hell out of her for ya, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well listen, I know how my boys take ta scrappin' when they take ta drinkin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it now. I carried the two of you little bastards around in my belly at the same time you ungrateful pissants. Ya ruined my girlish figure in one fell swoop, and then ya sucked me dry.  My tits are saggin' down ta my ankles. I trip over em for Christ sakes, now ya listen ta me, NO FIGHTEN!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise me boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's my boys.  Shit. I gotta go. Looks like I caused a ruckus with that shot. Half the damn neighborhood is comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, love ya ma. Listen, before ya go just give us the goods, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's been twenty-seven years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still bickerin' over that, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, ma. Out with it. Who came out first?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys stand shoulder to shoulder, naked. They peer into the distance, ears to the phone, awaiting this most important information.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I suppose you have the right ta know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are ya ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slight pause as mom slams a shot of Hennessey.</context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he turns, he notices Murphy is fixated on his brothers crotch. A triumphant smile spreads across his face.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start. I've had ice on mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief is embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>...so these guys are just kickin' the shit out of each other. This guy  Picks up an old kitchen sink that some one threw out and crushes this guy  With it. All right, so it makes a big bang and alerts their friend, who's standin' look out around the corner. So he comes over and gets into it with this guy,  He's angry at him, right? They get into an altercation in which the look out guy crushes this guy by jumpin on him. And look at the damage here.  I mean this guy's fuckin' hamburger man. His spine is crushed. He's all twisted and shit. That guy had to be one big mother fucker. Huge, 3-400 pounds, fuckin huge. Smecker listens.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREELY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some detectives nod in agreement. Smecker chuckles as he shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Or, okay. Check this out. Say these two don't even know the huge guy. They're just staggerin' home from a bar this morning, still all fucked up from St. Patty's last night. So they figure they'll take a short cut down the alley and this big mother fucker, he's just waitin'. And what could be more perfect for strong arm robbery? Two drunk guys all bandaged up. They're already injured for Christ sakes. He takes a blunt object and whacks the guy with the bandage on his head, right? Cause he's smart. He knows the guy with the bandage on his ass, he ain't going nowhere. Matter of fact, this guy's probably helping his friend with the rectal problem along. They're limping around like a couple of decrepit old broads. So once this guy's out of the picture  this poor asshole, he tries to run. But look how far he gets fore the huge bastard catches up with him. Only a few yards. And what does he do? He gets creative. He picks up a sink and crushes the poor mother- fucker. Then, he ain't done yet. He comes over here, jumps on this guy's back and crushes him to death.  He steals their shit and beats it! Thanks for comin' out!  And look at this print... Greenly points out a large foot print on Vladdy's back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one big fuckin' shoe!... and think about it. Of all the ways to kill a guy, crushin' him to death. That's very particular. You don't get many of those. I dunno. I feel something big here. I wouldn't be surprised if we see more of these turning up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. So now we got a Huge guy theory and Serial crusher theory. Top fucking notch.  What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker saunters up to Greely and pulls his I.D. out of the breast pocket of his sport coat and lets it hang. The large, light blue letters, F.B.I. can be easily seen.</context>
      <utterance>Detective Greenly. Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the detectives seem disgruntled and look to the Chief for an explanation.</context>
      <utterance>That's who the fuck I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I gotta go by the numbers on this one. I.D. just came back on these guys. They've got connections to the Russian mob. That makes it a federal matter and Agent Smecker, here, is heading up the investigation with our full cooperation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you get me a cup of coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caf latte.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twist of lemon!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, what the fuck is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greenly looks helplessly to the Chief, who simply nods. He storms off the scene, upset. Smecker turns his back on everyone and puts earphones in. He reaches down and hits play. The choir song "Agnus dei" overtakes. He begins to investigate. He kneels at the bodies for a moment then stares at the opposite brick wall. He picks up a piece of porcelain and scrapes it with his thumb. He quickly cocks his head toward the sky and begins to chuckle as he says Jesus Christ, under his breath. He brushes some paraffin on each of the dead men's hands. Duffy and Dolly watch defiantly. They start to smile at one another as they collectively realize his homosexuality. He is slightly effeminate buy not overly fey.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet-n-low!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two uniformed officers approach.</context>
      <utterance>Mitchell, Langley!</utterance>
   <speaker>MITCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mitchell and Langley exit.</context>
      <utterance>Find the manager of this building. See if he has had any complaints of water coming down in any apartments, starting just this morning. If he's not there, knock on every door starting from the third floor up. Langley, you take this building, same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two more uniforms approach.</context>
      <utterance>Chaffey, Newman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look in the trash around their hands. See if you can find me two bullet casings. 45's, if my eye serves me right. Don't disturb them. Mark them as they lay. Newman, root through this shit.  If this was a sink find me some metal parts. Gimme a faucet or a drain cover or something. The two begin their tasks. Chaffey finds a casing near Checkov's hand, hidden under the edge of the pile.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The homicide detectives are surprised as Chaffey looks for the second shell. Smecker lights up a smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Got it. It's a 45.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a bullet hole in the opposing and tattered wall.</context>
      <utterance>Chief, could you get ballistics down here and tell them they have to dig a 45 slug out of a brick wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to another bullet hole at the dumpster's base.</context>
      <utterance>...and locate another that's been fired through a dumpster.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the best ballistics guy in the world. He's mobile. Got all his stuff right in the van. Can have him down here in 10 minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paraffin came up positive. And bullet holes are usually a big clue.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find the second one, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look under the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker turns to detectives with a smirk.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both nod.</context>
      <utterance>You guy's ready for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mitchell returns.</context>
      <utterance>This was no gangland assassination. Though creative, it was way too sloppy. Something went wrong here. This has personal written all over it. Now, these men were crushed and the first natural reaction the body has to such trauma is to tense up. So now the two shots fired here were reflex rounds. These guys weren't shooting at anything, but they were just about to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MITCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Smecker,  This is all illegal loft housing so there's no manager on the premises but I found a lady on the fourth floor said she's had water dripping down on her whole place. Started just this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourth floor huh? Then we're heading to the fifth. Let's go up and see just how right I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you thinkin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the detectives chant the affirmative. The doors close.</context>
      <utterance>Really want to know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker turns to Greenly in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>No way. You know how big a guy's gotta be to do that? Fuckin' huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The detectives exit the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't getting him no fuckin' bagel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll start the ass kissing with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MITCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Smecker. I know this neighborhood pretty good. There's a bar called McGinty's down the block. It's a good bet they were there last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Duffy. What the fuck happened here? You owe me. This is the one I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker is standing on the front steps in front of uniformed officers and homicide detectives.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go get a cup of coffee. You ain't gonna fuckin' believe this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want A.P.B.'s put out. I want more uniforms on the streets. One thing's for sure, wherever these guys are they're hurting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for comin', Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J-Jesus. What the fuck happened? Are ya b-boys all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands them a card with Smecker's name on it. They survey it with interest.</context>
      <utterance>An F.B.I. agent came by the bar. He left me his c-c, he left me his c-c, he left me this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in the E.R. looks at Doc in shock. Connor and Murphy don't even avert their eyes from the card.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!..........Ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to turn ourselves in. It was self defense.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>y-y-yeah that's what he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the fuck's he know that? We haven't spoken to anyone yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look puzzled. Murphy helps Connor down to his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know. He didn't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Doc, we need a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy hands Doc a partially filled garbage bag.</context>
      <utterance>A-anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold this shit for us, Doc. We'll be comin back for it when we get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc exits, say one more "Fuck,...Ass", on the way out.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker looks to Greenly. Dripping with sarcasm.</context>
      <utterance>First of all, I'd like to thank whichever one of you donut munching, barrel-assed dip-shits leaked this to the press. That's just what we need now, some sensational story in the papers making these guys out to be super heroes, triumphing over evil. And let me squash the rumors now. These two aren't heroes.  They are two ordinary men who were put in an extraordinary situation and they just happened to come out on top. Yes, nothing from our far reaching computer system has turned up jack shit on these two. All we know is what we found out from their neighbors. And the general consensus is that they're... angels.  But angels don't kill and we got two bodies in the morgue that look like they've been...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the cops and homicide detectives laugh and chide Greenly.</context>
      <utterance>...serial crushed by a huge fuckin' guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these me considered armed and dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not armed. If they had guns, they'd have used them. But dangerous? Oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MITCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think they're dangerous? They were just protecting each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, look! I'm not saying one way or the other. Just be careful and go by the protocol on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any tips on where these guys may be?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any word back from the E.R.s?</utterance>
   <speaker>MITCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No help at all. Swamped from St. Patty's. Packed with drunk, bloody Irish.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grunt police work is going to bring this one in.</context>
      <utterance>Just hit the bricks nice and hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is light chuckling from the police at this crack.</context>
      <utterance>But if you want to beat your head against a wall, then here's what you look for. These guys are scared like two little bunny rabbits. Anything in a uniform or flashing blue lights will spook them. So the only thing we can do is put a potato on a string and drag it through South Boston.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone turns and looks.</context>
      <utterance>You'd probably have better luck with a beer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all file out. Smecker and the boys look each other over.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is this!? This isn't a fuckin' tea party. Get out! Only thing I want in here is them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker reaches for the record button. Murphy puts out his hand to stop him.</context>
      <utterance>This conversation is going to be recorded. Just answer to the best of your knowledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy turns to his brother and speaks in Latin, in hushed tones. It is subtitled in English.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"What do we tell him about the guns and money?"</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We just got up and left. Bum musta rolled them before the police got there."</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker in intrigued with this tiny display. He hits the record button.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. We're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are not under oath, here. I am assuming you knew these two guys from before, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We... met them last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>They had some pretty interesting bandages. Know anything about that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would someone please come over here and...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>me up the...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone falls down laughing. Doc is angry and starts throwing ice at them. DAVID DELLA ROCCO makes his way through the crowd. Rocco is thirty-two years old. He has shoulder-length, dark hair and a full beard and mustache that wrap around his big smile. He charges up to the bar and yells to Doc.</context>
      <utterance>Ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This sends everyone even further into laughter. Doc throws two huge fists full of ice at him. He backs away laughing. The boys get up off the floor and have a huge group hug with Rocco as they all scream each others names. They all laugh and commence drinking.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Fuck! Ass! Get me a beer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor pauses then bursts out laughing. Doc calls everyone to gather round.</context>
      <utterance>...It's not that I'm homophobic. I'm just afraid of faggots.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause as everyone absorbs. They are upset.</context>
      <utterance>I got some bad news. Looks like I'm gonna have ta close d-down the bar. The Russians have been buying up buildings all over town, including this one... Fuck!... Ass! And they're not letting me renew my lease. I got 'til the end of the week to come up with 26,000 dollars, or they take the place. I left them a note telling them not to show their faces t- tonight. They been pressuring me ta close and take the last few days ta get all my shit outta here but it's my right to stay open ta the last.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is cut off by everyone who obviously opposes Mafia involvement.</context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to my boss, may I can...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone has quizzical looks on their faces.</context>
      <utterance>L-l-listen I don't want anyone ta know until the last possible moment. So you guys keep your traps shut. ya know what they say; People in glass houses sink ships.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know Doc, I gotta get you a, a, like a proverb book or something. This mix and match shit's gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A p-penny saved is worth two in the bush.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Ivan Checkov. You will be closing now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs. Ivan is angry.</context>
      <utterance>This is McCoy... we find Spock and we got enough for an away team.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, how extraordinary. A bunch of Irishmen... and they are being drunken idiots. You are killing the stereotype. I'm in no mood for discussion.  You! You stay. The rest of you go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The locals roll their eyes at Doc's blunder.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you make like a tree and get the fuck outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Murphy each grab a Guinness and a shot of Hennessey and they approach the Russians with the peace offering.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Doc. I'm sure they're reasonable fellows.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen fellas, Y'know he's got 'til this week's end. Ya don't have ta be hard asses, do ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's St. Patty's day. Everyone's Irish tonight. Now, why don't ya pull up a stool and have a drink with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Checkov slaps the beer to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You insult me. I would never drink that sewage. Especially with you people. You are fools.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look at each other, remembering what Mom said. They still hold the shots.</context>
      <utterance>This is no game! If you won't go, we will make you go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If ya want a fight, you can see you're outnumbered. We're trying ta be civil here, so I suggest you take our offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco pushes off the bar. He's had enough.</context>
      <utterance>I make the offers, ass-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Now, that wasn't too polite, was it?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Checkov is completely taken aback. All the Irish are fairly impressed as well.</context>
      <utterance>"I'm afraid we can't let that one go, Ivan."</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink the glasses together, throw back the Hennessey, ball up the thick glasses in their fists, drop to one knee and both deliver a devastating blow to each of Checkov's quads. Murphy on the left, Connor on the right. He's down for the count, writhing on the floor. The boy's each take a Russian guy and start fighting as the others start kicking and spitting on Checkov. This is a bar brawl, lots of punches don't connect. Connor dismantles his man quickly. Murphy is still fighting as all the Irish try to jump in and help Murphy but Connor goes into psycho mode, pushing them all back.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think Ma would mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all back off and start to cheer him on. Murphy and Vladdy are ripping each other apart. Vladdy backs him against a wall and pulls back, exhausted, for one good punch. Murphy reaches up behind his head with both hands and pulls two bottles of wine from a wall rack. He swings them toward each other with Vladdy's head as the mid-point. The bottles haphazardly connect, one on each side of his head. He crumples to the ground in an explosion of glass and wine. There is shock and silence.</context>
      <utterance>Let the boy go. He knows what the fuck he's doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicely done, boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they cheer, Connor lights up his smoke and tosses the match on Ivan's butt. The Hennessey is instantly ablaze and Checkov is screaming and wiggling in horror. Some just stand there stunned, but most of the remaining onlookers leap to Ivan's aid. They furiously pat him out and turn on Connor.</context>
      <utterance>Now, like my fine brother says, on St. Patty's everyone's Irish. And this piece of shit is about to be initiated.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEND #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are ya tryin' ta kill him, ya fuck?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHECKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Checkov walks towards the door and says "let's go" to Vladdy.</context>
      <utterance>I was going to kill you. But I'm not... I'm going to kill your brother. I'm going to take him down to the dumpster and I'm going to shoot him in the head. Then I'm going to throw his dead body in the garbage.  Trash guys are coming in 10 minutes, gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vladdy pulls him to his feet and leads him away following Checkov. Connor, blood running from his face, listens to absolute silence for just a moment. Suddenly his face reads the gravity of the situation. In a split second he turns into an animal. He's yelling, pulling, tugging and growling. His body is a whirlwind of motion. The skin on his wrists bleeds profusely.</context>
      <utterance>It was just a bar fight. You guys are fuckin' pussies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how is it that you guys are fluent in Russian?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We paid attention in school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know any other languages?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye. Our mother insisted on it. French. Murphy speaks flawless French with subtitles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you think he figured all this out without talking to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor speaks flawless Italian with subtitles.</context>
      <utterance>Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea. Maybe someone saw and talked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>German.  Not in our neighborhood, man. A hundred percent Irish. No one talks to cops. Period.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spanish.  Then I guess he's just real... real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers laugh. Chaffey enters.</context>
      <utterance>What are you guys doing working at a fucking meat packing plant?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Agent Smecker, we have a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The press is everywhere outside. They're going nuts for these guys. What do you want to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not being charged. It's up to you. Do you want to talk to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No pictures, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we could try the bag over the head thing. Walk you right out the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our mother can see through bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, she can.  Any way we can stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAFFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, we have an empty holding cell, They can... can they stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all chuckle. Chaffey is embarrassed. Smecker stands.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we'll have to check with your mother, but it's ok with me if your friends sleep over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Time to feed the dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy speaks with the characteristic gay man's lingering</context>
      <utterance>He's a nice guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destroy all that which is evil...</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so that which is good may flourish</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be right back...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duffy hands Murphy a jelly donut and a cup of coffee as Dolly spreads a copy of the Boston Globe in front of Murphy. The headlines read "The Saints of South Boston." All the detectives chuckle as Murphy is momentarily absorbed. He takes the paper.</context>
      <utterance>We would be honored, sir, if you would join us peasants, in a donut.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Saints?  I will not accept this pizzle until my feet have been properly anointed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>VINCENZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's the funny man. Give it here, package boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey Bevo said it was important. Said I had to give it to him myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Rocco. I'm the funny man. Heee Hee. I'm so fuckin' funny. Hee Hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you Vincenzo.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me a joke funny man. Hee Hee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincenzo's face drops he gets up and starts walking toward Rocco. Roc points at him from a seated position. He's scared.</context>
      <utterance>I caught your show down at the velvet room at the Holiday Inn, loved it when you busted into Viva Las Vegas.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Yakavetta jumps to a standing position. He yells.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the phone down. Rocco and Vincenzo are shocked but try to look composed.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! I could snap my fingers and have you dead in four hours, rotting in a truck off of Boyleston! You insignificant little fuck! I always get my fuckin' money!</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he speaks he unwraps the wax paper in the bag. Rocco looks over his shoulder. It's a sandwich. He's embarrassed. Vincenzo smirks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' 90's are killin' me. I shouldn't a done that. You're not supposed to tell a guy you're gonna kill him anymore. I gotta tip-toe through the tulips with these assholes. I prance. I'm a prancer. It's what I do... sucked all the fun right out of this job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poppa Joe, you want me to go now?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco starts for the door. Vincenzo begins whispering in Yakavetta's ear.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Thanks, Rocco. See ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rocco, wait. Come back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincenzo continues whispering for a few more seconds, long enough for Rocco to see. Vincenzo's lips are tight. His teeth grind.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always see you talking to the boys and making them laugh. They always come around telling me what a crack up you are. What is it they call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The... The funny man.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The funny man. Well, I got a new job for you, just for now. Roc, I'm having a real shitty day. I'm depressed. Tell me a funny story or a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Okay... um... you hear the one about the, no fuck that one... uh... oh! oh! Well... shit. Okay, there's a white guy. He's walkin' along the beach and he finds a, a pot, y'know and ah, he rubs it and this genie pops out. But this genie, he's a ni... he's a black guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a nigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And uh, he's pissed off. He says, "Why you crackers always gotta find my mother fuckin' pot? And he tells him he's gonna grant all his three wishes but he's gonna give all the black guys...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENZO AND YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Niggers!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yakavetta takes a long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry! Sorry! All the niggers on the planet get double what he wishes for. "I'll take a million dollars," he says. Genie give it to him and says every nigger on earth just got two million. "I don't care gimme a yacht." Poof there it is.  E-every bl... every nigger just got two yachts. Genie goes...  I'm sorry Poppa Joe. I can't. This joke sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue the joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco returns to terror. Yakavetta erupts again pointing at Rocco.</context>
      <utterance>Very good stuff, Rocco. Very good stuff. Tell me another one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what we need, man?... some rope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie Bronson's always got rope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, these guys always got a lot of rope strapped around em in the movies and they always end up using it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you've lost it, haven't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. That's stupid. Name one thing we're gonna need it for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know they just always need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor pulls a large hunting knife from Murphy's bag.</context>
      <utterance>What is all this "they" shit? This ain't a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right, Rambo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, get the stupid fuckin' rope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reuben throws an arm over Smecker's abdomen and places his head on Paul's bare chest as if to now force affection.</context>
      <utterance>Uh,huh.  Room number.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is visibly miffed with Reuben's sudden display. He tries to pull the arm away but Reuben holds tight.</context>
      <utterance>We got a time of death?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker is annoyed. He slaps Reuben semi-gently once on his exposed cheek. Reuben closes his eyes and holds even tighter.</context>
      <utterance>What's the body count?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bites his lower lip in anger and smack Reuben again on the same cheek, hard. Reuben jumps to a sitting position holding his cheek. He is shocked and hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. Immediately to Reuben, semi-angry.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be down there in a bit. Keep the press out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>REUBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just trying to cuddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuddle?...  What a fag!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's struck again, hasn't he, Greenly?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you always disrespect me like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Respect is earned, Greenly, never given. Guys like you should have to follow me around squabbling for the scraps from my table.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many bodies, Greenly?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker's eyes widen as he turns to Greenly.</context>
      <utterance>Eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker takes a beat. He addresses the detectives.</context>
      <utterance>No! Shit! I didn't see that one. Nine! Nine!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While Greenly's getting coffee, anybody else want anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker surveys the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Duffy, got any theories to go with that... tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These guys were pros. I think they were coming for one target, the fag man, he was the...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fat man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Freud was right. So you think they came for the fag man, huh? And what do you base this upon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the only one done right. Two in the back of the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the pennies?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New hitman wants to leave his mark</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a possibility. Y'know you Boston cops are perking up. That's two sound theories in one day, neither of which deal with abnormally sized men.  Another possibility is that they were placed there with religious intent.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Some cultures still put pennies in the eyes of the dead, or silver.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Greeks. The Italians.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Sicilians.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker tosses the Idiot glance to Dolly.</context>
      <utterance>What's the symbology there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker looks at his I.D.</context>
      <utterance>Symbology? Well, now that Duffy has relinquished his King Bone Head crown I see we have an heir to the throne. I'm sure the word you were looking for was symbolism. What's the symbolism there? Let me explain it to you. In Greek and Roman mythology when you died you would have to pay the toll to Charon, the boatman who ferried you across to the gates of judgment. This made sure the dead came to atone for what they did during their lives, Detective...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The detectives are impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Dollapoppaskalious.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>DOLLAPOPPASKALIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. You're the first one that's ever got that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The detectives chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... I'm an expert in name- ology.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up and gives a lesson to the now eager detectives. He points his two index fingers to the back of his own skull.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen burns like these before. They used silencers. Look at these entry and exit wounds. They're identical.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two bullets went in here, through the top of the skull, criss-crossed and exited through the eyeballs. This one clue tells us three distinct facts. Number one... Duffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They shot him at a downward angle.  They put him on his knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent! Number two. Greenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh.  Shit, I, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wide-eyed Duffy joins with Smecker, by nodding his head. Smecker is seducing all of them.</context>
      <utterance>It tells us that he was the last to die. All these men  Were carrying. They came in, dropped all in seconds and then took their time with fag man. Didn't they, Duffy?!  They sure as fuck did!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And number three, Dolly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... two shooters!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greenly and Duffy want to know how.</context>
      <utterance>Fan-fuckin-tastic!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now stay with me, boys. What did they do to make two such identical wounds? Did one guy put him on his knees, pop a cap in, sit him back up and shoot him again the same way? No. Two men of similar height dropped this guy down, each put some iron to his head and boom! That's all she fuckin' wrote!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about one guy with two guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possible, but unlikely. The angles are too extreme. A guy holding two guns to the back of your head is gonna shoot straight ahead. He wouldn't cock out his elbows, makes no sense. Besides, you telling me one guy came in here and killed eight men with eight extremely well aimed shots in just a few seconds? No way. Had to be at least two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker points toward the ceiling revealing a huge gaping hole in it just above the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Television,... television is the explanation for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The detectives nod in agreement. They are now completely taken in by Smecker's spell.</context>
      <utterance>You see this is bad television.  The little assault guys creeping in through the vents and coming in through the ceilings. That James Bond shit never happens in real life. Professionals don't do that. So we've got this up here, which has novice written all over it. And all this down here that's simply a perfect textbook assassination. So here's our two possibilities. We either have rank amateurs that got lucky or consummate professionals that fucked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go over and grab seats at the bar. Smecker mixes himself a gin and tonic on the other side. He is calming down now and going back into cool mode. He starts to tuck his clothes back in and fix his hair. He leans over the bar and sips his drink. The three detectives lean in.</context>
      <utterance>Join me in a drink, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All their faces read the gravity of the situation.</context>
      <utterance>With the exception of my coffee boy, you Boston detectives are starting to show signs of intelligence. So, I am going to make you privy to some information that you would not normally be. These men are all Russian mob. Not like those two peons in the alley the other day. These guys are all syndicate bosses and underbosses. I have a dossier on every man in this room. Since the Iron Curtain has gone down, the Russian syndicates have started to come here. And in the spirit of Glasnost the Soviets have opened their borders to the mafia. But the Italians, they're not convinced that the grounds in mother Russia are fertile enough for organized crime yet. So they ain't ready to commit. The Russians are coming here anyway. They are unwelcome. What we have here, gentlemen, is possibly the beginning of the first international mob war... unless I've totally missed something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, what is this going to look like to those who do not know what I just told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna look like the bad guys are killing each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And is there an American, shit is there a man seated among us that hasn't thought about it many times, let's just put them all on an island, give them guns and let them kill each other. This is our wet dream come true. You can expect federal and local law enforcement to go only deep enough to satisfy the law, then bury it from here on out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends. You either do your job or get ethical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator stops at the lobby level. Nine, well-dressed men enter. Their faces are not shown. The boys move to the back wall. One guy says something quickly to another in Russian. The other gives a one word Russian response. They boys look at each other. As the elevator climbs, their eyes focus. The door opens. As the men exit the elevator, each face is seen individually, all are victims from Smecker's crime scene. The elevator goes up half a floor. They hit the stop button and rummage in their bags. They suit up; black gloves and black masks. They strap on four 9mm. pistols with silencers, in shoulder holsters, one under each arm. Connor takes a large coil of black rope and drapes it around himself. He looks at Murphy and at the rope in his bag. Murphy is too excited to argue.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts it on. They drop to their knees, making the sign of the cross. Then, up through the ceiling they go.</context>
      <utterance>You and your fucking rope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See. I told you there'd be a shaft.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They jump into the air shaft.</context>
      <utterance>Just like on TV.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find it. Just calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy takes off the rope.</context>
      <utterance>No, fuck you. This rope is bullshit. I'm sweatin' my ass off draggin' this stupid thing around. Must weigh 30 pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're doing some serious shit here. Now, get a hold of yourself, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asshole!? I'm not the rope-totin' Charlie Bronson wanna-be that's getting' us lost!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor grabs Murphy's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Sh, sh! Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys get into a close quarters battle. An occasional insult is thrown as feet kick and fists fly. They begin to get tangled in their own rope. The seam of the duct breaks and a tangled mess of rope and MacManuses pour out.</context>
      <utterance>No, fuck you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the silenced pop from their guns we cut the sound and go to black and white. (Slo-mo) Choral music starts with Latin script being read in the background. They take their rosaries out. They slowly walk around, mumbling prayers as they care for the dead. They gently turn over the bodies that were on their stomachs. They brush the hair back from the victims faces. They place pennies in the eyes of al the corpses. When they finish their ritual, they pull off their masks and look at each other. They start to grin and look around. They work each other into a healthy chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>And shepherds we shall be. For thee, my Lord, for thee. Power hath descended forth from thy hand that our feet may swiftly carry out thy command. So we shall flow a river forth to thee and teeming with souls shall it ever be. E nomini patri, et Fili e spiritu sancti.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>That was some good fuckin' rope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was way easier than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On TV ya always get that asshole that jumps behind the couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and ya gotta shoot at him for ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we're good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are already striding for a suitcase full of money. Murphy picks up a wad of bills.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, there's a knock at the door. They snap into action. They stand at each side of the double doors, looking through the peepholes. They see Rocco on the other side dressed as a hotel employee. He wears a polyester shirt with gold trim and a name tag that reads Jaffar. He has a good cart in front of him. They look at each other and grin. Murphy nods. As they open the door, Murphy grabs the food cart and pulls it in. Connor seizes the mortified Rocco and pulls him in, slamming the door shut behind him. They run, dragging him and then throw him in the midst of the bodies. They put their guns right in his face.</context>
      <utterance>I love our new job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God! Don't kill me! We're on the same side! The boss musta sent you in as back up, huh? Oh, shit, please! I'm Rocco. I'm the funny man.  They call me the funny fuckin' man!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chest pocket.  Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a six-shooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine bodies.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're good. What were you gonna do? Laugh the last three to death, funny man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poppa Joe said there was only two. In and out.  Boy, you guys sure did a good job. You're good, huh? Cool masks. Where'd you get them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do him right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys put their faces close to his and demask. They start laughing but Rocco just lays there, wide-eyed, in shock. They boys saunter to the bar. Rocco takes a long beat.</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill me. Oh shit, please no. I'm Rocco. I'm the funny man!... the funny man... the funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?! Fuckin'... what the fuckin' fuck! Who the fuck, fucked this fuckin'? fuck. How did you two fuckin', fucks?......... FUCK!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly illustrates the diversity of the word.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing here? What, huh!? WHAT? WHAT? WHAT? ANSWERS!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco is silent and surprised. Murphy, also surprised, looks at Rocco. All is quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Get a hold of yourself, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy jokingly slaps Rocco a second time. Rocco instantly jumps on Murphy, cursing and punching. The brothers burst into laughter as they subdue Rocco. As he calms down, they release him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, get a hold of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy puts the two suitcases in his duffle bag and the two brush by Rocco who is still unsatisfied with his explanation.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, we gotta get outta here now. We'll take separate exits and meet at Rocco's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody you think is evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think that's a little psycho? A little weird?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird, huh?... Know what I think is weird? Decent men with loving families go home every day after work. They turn on the news and see rapists, murderers, and child molesters all getting out of prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mafiosos getting caught with 20 kilos and walkin' on bail the same day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little girls catchin' stray bullets in their heads, playin' hopscotch in their front yards. And everyone thinks the same thing... Someone should just go kill those motherfuckers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco ponders this as the boys continue to clean their weapons.</context>
      <utterance>Kill em all. Admit it, even you've thought about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys chuckle. Rocco steadily works himself into a humorous frenzy.</context>
      <utterance>You guys should be in every major city.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is some heavy shit. This is like Lone Ranger-heavy man. Fuck it! There's so much shit that pisses me off. You guys should recruit 'cause I am sick and fuckin' tired of walkin' down the street waitin' for one of these assholes to get me, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallelujah, Jaffar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look at each other and nod.</context>
      <utterance>So you're not just talkin' mob guys. You're talkin' anyone, right? Even like pimps and drug dealers and all that shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well fuck, you guys could do this every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're like 7-Eleven. We ain't always doing business, but we're always open.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicely put.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fuckin' guys. You ruined me. I'm fuckin' done. Permanent package boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says that? You could take credit on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, fuck it. If you think about it, it's all you can do really. You can't tell him it was us. Go in braggin' and shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Climb the corporate ladder, boy. Don Rocco.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys nod in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it! I'm doing it. I deserve it. I've been working for those fat bastards since I was in high school and look at this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco slams his fist down on the table next to Murphy's gun. The gun goes off with a bang! and blows the lounging cat right off the table. A softball-sized hole is blasted in the wall as a large splatter of blood sprays the area surrounding the hole. Everyone is in shock for a second.</context>
      <utterance>They're fuckin' me man! Hey, they can suck my pathetic little dick. And I'll dip my nuts in marinara just so the fat fucks can get a taste of home while they're at it. That's it, it's done, I'm doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't fuckin' believe that just happened!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna's gonna be angry about her cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. She's on every drug know to man. She'd have sold that thing for a dime bag. Screw her.  But I do kinda feel like an ass-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor lights up two smokes and hands one to Rocco.</context>
      <utterance>You sound real remorseful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't been around in weeks anyhow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. Something's been bothering me about last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... what if your boss knew how many guys were supposed to be there... in that room?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about it man. Nine men, six bullets.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they sold me out? No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He probably knew you'd end up nailing the fat guy, maybe one or two more, but he had to know you weren't walking out of there. Figure it out. Shooter's dead on the scene. No in-depth investigation. It'd slide right off his back. 'Cause as much as I love ya, you're not exactly Don Corleone. What would he be losing? A thirty- five year old delivery boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. That's just not the way things are done. Besides, how's he know I don't just get in there see there's too many and just serve em their fuckin' food and beat it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows you, man. He knows all you want is to move up. That's all. A smooth hitter woulda gone in there, seen it was a wash and slipped out. But a guy like you? Knowin' this is your only chance? Waitin' eighteen years?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No man. That's... that's... you don't know what you're talking about. That's bullshit. I know these guys. I mean, thanks for your concern, but that just ain't the thing of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor and roll it around for a bit on your way in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy stumbles enters scene with Rocco and Connor.</context>
      <utterance>No, look. No rolling. Nothing needs to be rolled.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you goin'?  Did you tell him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You don't know that shit for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. You're such a fuckin' retard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use your brain for once. Is it so unbelievable they don't care about you? You are fuckin' dead, you go in there today. Dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. You two fuckin' Micks know what's going on, huh?  Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A girl rides by on a bicycle, they pause as she rides between them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, this ain't a thing you should gamble on, Roc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck it! What kind of flowers ya want at your funeral? Ya dumb Wop. This is the last time I'll see you. Bye-bye ya stupid son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back at 9:00.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You get in there and start getting a bad vibe, get the fuck out quick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Murph.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roc. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Anybody call for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You sure you're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Rocco hangs up. Just then DONNA and her friend RAYVIE enter the apartment. They are consummate junky sluts who are very doped up and giddy.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fuckin' fine.  Catch you on the flip side.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here kitty, kitty...... kitty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was in here when it went down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can she I.D. them?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were wearing masks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course they were. How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker looks at Dolly surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only two did the shooting.  So what are you thinking, Russian retaliation?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker sits next to the girl. He has Compassion. She Cries.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, too quick half their infrastructure got taken out at the Copley plaza. Besides, if you're a hitter, you're either working for the Russians or the Italians. There's no riding the fence. Our little theory from last night just got blown to shit. Something... new is going on here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably shouldn't work another shift for awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck this job. I'm getting out of the porno business and I don't care who I gotta blow to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After talking to the dancer we know that their mark was the guy in the middle booth. After she watches them whack him, she passes out.  Why the two extra victims?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Witness?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker hits an orange button on the wall and a black steel door with a money slot comes slamming down in front of the first booth. He does the same thing to the last booth, leaving the middle one open. Both doors possess peep holes.</context>
      <utterance>No way they could have seen it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allow me to enlighten you gentlemen to the protocol of the porno industry, as I'm sure you've never been in one of these places before. A man goes into the booth, puts the money in the slot. The dancer gets it on the other side. She hits the button, door goes up, now there is only glass between you and it's  little fireman time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way they could have seen it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those doors were down... which means this. They looked down in through the peep hole, saw these guys and opened the doors from the inside. Pop, pop, pop, right through the glass. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe the three of them had something in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This guy is big time.  These two are street-walking scum.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got another thing to think about here. We got us a genuine Kennedy assassination style bullet theory. Two guns were used here, guns A and B. The guy in the middle was done with both. But this guy...  ...he was killed with bullets from gun A only. And this guy...  ...gun B only. But ballistics dug two slugs out of the wall from over here where the victim was done with</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's the same story over here. Why the crossover?  Theories.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just fucking weird. I have no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. I just can't think anymore. That scene over at the coffee shop today tapped me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy went nuts over off of Commonwealth today. Shot three guys to death in a coffee shop in broad daylight. Fled the scene. Don't have much on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why was I not informed of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They weren't related. The guy used a 38. No pennies. Totally amateur.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who were the victims?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple of peons for the mob and...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... it looks like we got us a cowboy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shooter knew these guys, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you figure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker flashes them a photo of a dead body. The victim is shot in the head and face down in his plate of food. His hands are on the table in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>Friends, Gentlemen. They were friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker looks over the bar.</context>
      <utterance>These guys were packing. Not one hand near a gun. It's simple human behavior. Someone you don't know approaches you, you put your hand on it. This guy's got his hands on the table. He's eating his food, for Christ sakes. They were friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These two fucking scenes are related. Too many coincidences. Same day? Five hours apart? Dead mobsters on both scenes. Now, why did he kill the bartender?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crime of passion. He just went nuts. He would have shot everyone in here. He just ran out of bullets.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duffy. This look like a fucking post office to you? This guy came in here with intent. Maybe he didn't know exactly what he was gonna do but he had a pretty good idea. The bartender wasn't a fucking accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we didn't get any help on that. A lot of people saw it. Nobody's talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms to the entry way.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking figures. Look, are you guys seeing the pattern here? We got big questions at both of these crime scenes, with no answers. WHY did they kill the guys in the other two booths? WHY did he do the bartender? It would seem unnecessary, even stupid.  God, I hate cold crime scenes! I'm fucking leaving now. And do me a favor, tell me when the next guy dies, cause these guys are not done yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Murph.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roc. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Anybody call for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You sure you're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes across the street and enters Salamone's.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fuckin' fine.  Catch you on the flip side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pack your shit! We gotta get outta here! We gotta get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed em! Oh, Jesus! I killed em all!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rocco?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey. Just calm down. Tell us what happened!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Fuck you! You start getting excited! We gotta fucking go!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rocco!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did you kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. Who? How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry the fuck up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is some crazy shit, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those cocksuckers sold me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I fuckin' tell ya, Rocco? They pull on you first?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I fuckin' do?... in the middle of the Lakeview.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lakeview the deli? Oh, shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! Ha! Roc, you got a jumbo set of coconut balls man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my cat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed your fuckin' cat, you druggie bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... oh god, why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt it would bring closure to our relationship!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, unsure of the cat's name.</context>
      <utterance>You killed my... my...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your what?! Your fuckin' what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My, my...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your what, bitch? I'll shoot myself in the head, you can tell me that cats name! Go ahead... Your what? Your precious little...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pee...Per...Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peeperman? WRONG? What color was it?!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was... It was...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Male or female, bitch?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYVIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you yell at her you fuckin' prick!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut your fat ass, Rayvie! I can't buy a pack of smokes without running into nine guys you fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco rummages through her purse and finds her car keys.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you yell at her!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit. Rayvie and Donna are hugging each other, crying.</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's get the fuck outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYVIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is my... I mean it's not really...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. It's not fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those rat fucks! All of them were all laughing at me man!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you killed them?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin-A-right I did. I had a goddam turkey shoot over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet it was a test. Vincenzo came in here shooting his mouth off. He was makin' sure we knew. But we did what we were supposed to, eh? We kept our mouths shut. You did your part. They know we're goodfellas now. We'll get taken care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco looks at Sal the bartender who reaches for the phone.</context>
      <utterance>What? Did everyone know? Next thing you'll tell me Sal was in on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all start laughing together.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck. Vincenzo told Sal first. That fat fuck knew before we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh as Rocco pulls his gun and shoots Oly in the head. He lands face down in his plate of food. He shoots Vinnie in the chest then turns on Sal. He yells "Funny, funny, funny" as he pumps the remaining rounds into him.</context>
      <utterance>At least we got our funny man back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody see ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck, man! I may as well have posted flyers. Right out in public, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liberating isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know it is, a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor pulls over directly in front of a pink neon sign that says The Sin Bin.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincenzo, that fat motherfucker, Yakavetta's right hand. He's the one who set me up. Then he went around shooting his mouth off, telling everyone I was as good as dead. He goes in there every Wednesday night around 10:00, he jerks off in the same booth to the same titty dancer. Never misses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So let's kill the motherfucker. I mean, what are you guys... like that's your new thing right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what the fuck? How do you guys decide who you're... I mean, who makes the cut? Is there a raffle or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, truth be known, those first ones just kinda fell into our laps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what'ya do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we really don't have a system of deciding who.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MEEE! ME! I'm the guy! I know everyone, their habits, where they hang out, who they talk to. I know where they fuckin' live. We could kill everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm strangely comfortable with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and is instantly taken with laughter at Rocco's appearance. Connor turns, and has the same reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Okay Roc, this is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are now pointing and laughing.</context>
      <utterance>What? You guys got masks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like Mush Mouth from Fat Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine! Fuck it! When we're done she can I.D. me. I don't care. Just tryin' to be professional, but no...</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begrudgingly puts it back on. They reassume their position.</context>
      <utterance>No. No. It looks good. C'mon, put it back on. It's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Roc. You sure you're O-B-kay-B?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to the middle door.</context>
      <utterance>Which one is he in?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his routine?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>H... h... he jerks off in there. Th... then he puts money through the slot and I raise the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to an orange button. Each door has a button to the left of it.</context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He watches me do my thing and f- finishes himself off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They back up and focus on the money slot. A hundred dollar bill comes through. Connor gives it to the dancer.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man. He is some sicko.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys begin to recite their prayer. Rocco is smiling and excited, he still hangs on to the now hyperventilating dancer. They press the button. The door goes straight up. Vincenzo has one moment of shock before the MacManuses decimate him through the glass with silenced bullets. The glass silently spiders and begins to fall in spots. His chest explodes, sputtering medallions and bits of gold chain inside the booth. The dancer faints and Rocco lays her down gently. The boys step down in the boot and begin their ritual. Rocco watches intently, intrigued. They finish and turn around to see Rocco is immersed in grabbing one of the unconscious dancer's breasts. They pull up their masks.</context>
      <utterance>You've earned this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I'll tip her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've teamed up with a sex offender.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, when are you getting a plastic fuck doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and starts tossing money on her as the boys giggle. Just then two more bills come through the slots of the other two doors, which have remained closed. Murphy looks through left peep hole, Connor the right. Smiles spread across their faces and they look at each other. They switch and each looks through the other guy's peep hole.</context>
      <utterance>All right. I'm sorry. I'm pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is like a scumbag yard sale.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco looks in one. He says "Oh, wow" as he crosses and checks out the other one.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta come down here once a week and clean house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look at each other affirmatively.</context>
      <utterance>You sure about this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man. You gotta let me do these guys. I'm such a moron. I gotta make up for the tit thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. I've been waitin' for this asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon. I gotta clear my family name here. I've brought shame to the house of Della Rocco.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give the guy a shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt-fuckin'-Earp, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys gotta teach me that prayer, man. That's some good shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. It's a family prayer. My father, his father before him that sort of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Augustus, I need your help, I got a serious problem here. I'm not screwing around.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus begins to remove items from his suitcase. First a plate. He sets it down next to the sink. Then assorted colognes, cigarettes and chewing gum. He begins arranging them in neat rows, always feeling with his guiding hands.</context>
      <utterance>I bounced you on my knee at family reunions, for Christ sakes. Your dad and me ran the whole east coast syndicate you snot-nosed little prick. And when you took the wheel, who was beside you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start with your shit. Don't you talk to me. Oh, hey Uncle Gussy, thanks for years of service. Here's a gold watch and a job sniffing other guys' shit eight hours a day. What am I, a retired bus driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need Il Duce.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Duke?  What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yakavetta puts an envelope of money in the plate.</context>
      <utterance>This kid, this package boy could bring down the whole east coast. If he decides to turn states he could dismantle us... totally. But it looks like for now, he's content with just killing us one by one. And even worse the kid is good at it. I mean I had a prodigy on my hands the whole time and didn't even know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen kid, I think you better understand who you're dealing with here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I was only twelve or thirteen when you guys used to talk about him, like he was a ghost or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your dad and I used him three times over twenty years, only when everything went totally fucked. Believe me kid, you don't want this guy unless you are 100% sure you need him. He is... a fuckin' monster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus hands him a piece of paper he scribbled on.</context>
      <utterance>I've had this guy in front of me, and I couldn't tell you what he looks like, sounds like. He is the Picasso of assassins, kid. He plants hair samples, blood. Puts skin under fingernails. He is a fucking genius. Only one problem. He's been rotting in prison for twenty-five or thirty years. Don't even know if he's still alive. Or if he's even up to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's ways around that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go find one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a poker game at the house every Saturday with a couple of guys you know. Why don't you come down? Wife makes a hell of a bar-g-que.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... yeah, I'd like that. Tell me something. What did they do?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worst day of my life, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sold.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Roc. We'll do this guy right and you'll feel a lot better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck was he, Rocco? I know you fuckin' know!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! I told you I never saw him before!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he sure as fuck knew you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene fades into total silence as they viciously argue. They then take turns hold each other down as they cauterize their wounds with the hot iron. Two guys will hold a third down and force a wadded up pillow case in his mouth, as they burn him</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you both! Ya ask me, he was aiming at you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy spies a young boy peddling his bike out of the driveway. He goes to the front of the van.</context>
      <utterance>They waited in a parked car down the street for the kid to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he goes.  Okay, gentlemen. Are we ready to bring this man into the light? Are we ready to truly do the work of the Lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A-fuckin'-men!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so fuckin' cool!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slowly punches in the numbers. Smecker is standing there smoking.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fuck with me lady. I'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco pulls a stun gun and zaps her with it. She goes down.</context>
      <utterance>The wife says she doesn't know what happened after she hit the code. She just remembers going down. But, judging by the burn mark on her back, I think what they did...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor reaches for the knob but Rocco stops him. They wait, guns drawn and focus on the door knob.</context>
      <utterance>...was use a stun gun on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knob turns and they kick it in.</context>
      <utterance>Now the guy knows a friend is coming to the game. And they know that this door can only be opened from the inside. So they wait... and when that door opens, man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin firing. Men are dying, their chests exploding. Smecker moves his hands like firing guns and yells over the noise.</context>
      <utterance>All of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker points to the pool table as the two players dive under it.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody was ready for it. Devastation, panic! This was like shooting fish in a fuckin' barrel!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker drops to his knees in perfect synchronicity with Rocco. They are side by side and leaning back. Rocco fires and the men under the table skip around as they are riddled with bullets. Smecker's mimicking hands follow him perfectly with each shot. The boys and Rocco demask. Rocco goes around to all the bodies and looks earnestly at each one, as Connor and Murphy pick up bullet casings.</context>
      <utterance>Now these guys dove under the table. The trajectory on the bullets show they came from straight across. So this means one of our shooters... dropped to his knees...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!... Shit! He ain't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean he ain't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look again for fuck sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what the fuck he looks like!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something went wrong. Right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is now being choked, as he glares at them in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Let the boy go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Roc!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Rocco is wrestling and punching on the floor. He looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Now, one of these guys is a real sicko. He knew this man. He wanted him to suffer, to feel every second of a painful death.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he fights harder)</context>
      <utterance>Help me you assholes!  He's gonna fuckin' kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy is one bad motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murphy is aching to help but Connor is more steady. A man who has been shot starts to regain consciousness. Connor turns his back to shoot him (slo-mo). Murphy sees his opportunity, pulls the cue ball from the table, and rolls it silently across the carpet toward Rocco. Connor fires with his left hand and as the casing ejects from the gun he catches it in mid air and makes the sign of the cross. Rocco is on his back, the man is straddling him. They both have each others throats and are trying to strangle one another. When the ball is within arms reach, Rocco slams his hand down on it and knocks his assailant in the skull. He straddles him and begins to mercilessly beat his face in with the cue ball, yelling "You sick fuck!" He finally stops, gets up, runs toward the boys, and throws an exhausted punch at Connor who just lays Roc down on the pool table and says, "Nicely done, boy". Murphy tends to Roc. Connor checks out the man and seems surprised. Murphy takes the bloody cue ball from Rocco's hand and polishes it off on his jacket, making sure Connor cannot see. He replaces it perfectly on the table. Smecker now stands in front of the table with the cue shining in the background.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna die!!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker exits to the left as Greenly enters from the right, following Smecker out. He walks by the table furiously scribbling in his notebook. Connor, Murphy and Rocco exit the room, pennies in the eyes of all the corpses in the background. Rocco holds two duffle bags full of poker money. Greenly stops, picks up the cue ball and looks at the dead man. He shakes his head and says, "Nah".</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen wounds like these before, but whatever he used on this guy, it was a blunt object and they took it with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our three heroes stand, their jaws dropping as their point of view reveals the Il Duce, standing alone, his hands folded in front of him. Suddenly, he throws open his trench coat to reveal a special leather vest beneath. Six guns, all different, are holstered on the front of it: three on each side extend from just below his collar bones to his abdomen. Connor and Murphy don't hesitate. They each draw one of their now unsilenced guns from their shoulder holsters and aim, one arm over each of Rocco's shoulders. The Duke draws his top two weapons and aims.</context>
      <utterance>Now they are staring at six guys with guns drawn. It was a fucking ambush.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all start shooting at once. The noise is deafening. The Taurus is being pierced and the front of the house is splintering as it is riddled with bullets. Smecker is still in the middle, hands raised to the heavens, turning circles. Rocco's pinky finger gets shot off, sending blood splattering against the house. He dives in the bushes reeling. He pulls a gun and starts firing. Murphy catches a bullet in the arm and dives for the bushes as well. Il Duce with lightening speed, drops the guns and pulls the next two down as he walks to his right about ten feet. He commences firing and the casings hit the sidewalk, all different calibers and sizes are dropping down the walk. It's him and Connor and nobody is backing down. They both grind their teeth as they fire rapidly at each other. At the same moment, The Duke gets hit in the arm and Connor takes a bullet in the leg. The firing ceases for a moment. Connor remains steady and Il Duce looks down at his arm and his own blood splattered on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>And this was a fucking bomb dropping in Beaver Cleaverville! For a few seconds this place was Armageddon! There was a fire fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>IL DUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the guns and pulls the last two as he moves to the right. He fires with wrath as he screams the word No over and over. Rocco and Murphy return fire from the bushes yelling and swearing, as Connor does the same from his position on the stoop. The Duke turns and runs, leaving a sea of casings, and guns that extend for 35 feet down the walk. There are also two blood stains. In a frenzy the boys and Rocco get up and withdraw some spray bottles from their bags. The begin spraying all their own blood stains on the stoop and the front of the white house. They then pick up their things and run off.</context>
      <utterance>No!... No! No!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GREENLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if it was just one guy with six guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the forensics guys at the front of the house and begins to walk over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you let me do the thinking, huh, genius?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is taking so long with those blood samples?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORENSICS WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker puts his finger through a big blood stain on the door and smells it.</context>
      <utterance>I can't get a good sample. There is variable here I'm not seeing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? That's it?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?  What, that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the guy that got us off the hook with the "Checkov" thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he is one smart man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy is very sharp. If he hasn't figured us out yet, he will.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet your ass he will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd say that makes him a lia- fuckin-bility.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He isn't to be touched.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... whatever.  My Mom's gonna kill me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boston Police Department.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reads a few names then hits David Della Rocco.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Maria, this is Smecker. Could you find me the visitor's list for the day the MacManus brothers were in and read me all the names?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs us, puts in a smoke, and knocks his head back in deep thought.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've had quite a bit, Paul. Are you sure you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He obeys. A good looking gay man comes up and whispers in Smecker's ear and points to the back room.</context>
      <utterance>Pour the drink, faggot-ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They proceed to the back. Smecker is stumbling.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... But I don't cuddle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! We gotta talk about this early morning church shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go now.  We're on the lamb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna do what I say, got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you're gonna hafta see this. Don't look at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I didn't see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Shut the fuck up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do this my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you no fear of God?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor gets the slider open. Rocco's long hair hangs just inches from Connor's face. Connor puts his thumb and forefinger through, desperately reaching for a lock of Rocco's hair. Rocco jostles the priest and puts the gun hard to his head.</context>
      <utterance>That's who I'm doing this for, now open the fuckin' thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, I'll do you right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You little fuck. Let him go. I'll drop you right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, just calm down. He could hurt us, brother. He could ruin the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pulls hammer back)</context>
      <utterance>Let him go or I will deliver you, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't do it Connor, you won't. You love me man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? You there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y-Yes my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do your thing Father. Don't fuck this up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just be natural, goddamit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long since your last confession, my son?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest can hear Connor and Rocco whisper, but Smecker cannot.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ, uh, I've never confessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor and Rocco stop and listen now.</context>
      <utterance>According to the dogma of the Catholic church, I should probably burst into flames right here in this booth. But I've come here for advice, not salvation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why have you come to a church for council if you're not religious?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why have I come to a church? I never have before. I guess I just... felt I should.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it my son?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's ethics. I put evil men behind bars, but the law has miles of red tape and loopholes for these... cocksuckers to slip through. I've found out there are these two young men who fix the situation with an iron fist. As if they have God's permission. But what they do is wrong and I should arrest them... technically.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco shakes the priest.</context>
      <utterance>God's permission? God doesn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But in this day and age I believe what they do is... necessary. I feel it is... correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco and Connor show their individual looks of surprise.</context>
      <utterance>You feel? A soul is what gives you feelings. Happiness, guilt, right or wrong. It is a conduit through which the Lord speaks to us. You felt that your answers would be here in the house of God today. You feel these men are necessary. The Lord has spoken to you twice this day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have entered the house of the Lord of your own free will speaking of beliefs and feelings. Is it so much to believe that God has brought you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look of surprise on Rocco and Connor's faces show that the priest is doing a hell of a job.</context>
      <utterance>It is easy to be sarcastic about religion. It is harder to take small hints from God, your feelings and listen to them... to take a stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those who do not act are in a constant state of ethical indecision.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to stand for what I believe in, father.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you must find out what your beliefs are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe these young men are right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know them personally?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think they would harm an innocent man, for any reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest starts to show signs of anger as he starts turning to Rocco.</context>
      <utterance>No. They would never do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fear returns to the priests face. Rocco presses the gun hard to the priests head and jostles him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the two Irish guys wouldn't. But the Italian guy, he might. He's kind of an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddam right, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rocco jostles the priest again.</context>
      <utterance>I'm beginning to see. I've been doing my job... well for fifteen years and it's just not enough. All the things I wish I could do, these guys are doing. Millions of dollars in tax payers' money wasted on shit like wire taps and surveillance. Theses boys go in and take care of it for the price of a bullet.  Ww-what do you think I should do? Because I'm a law man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The laws of God are higher than the laws of man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Yes! I was thinking that, too. No. I was feeling it. All I needed was to hear you say it! Amen! I'll help them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker exits and they all let go after a brief pause. Rocco turns and starts fixing up the priest's ruffled suit.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Father, thank you.  Whatever. Goodbye, amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have, uh, killed you, Father.  Dominus Ominus. Remember, you're bound. You can't talk about this... to anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the light caught the side of his face for a second. And it looked like he had a gray beard, maybe... late fifties, early sixties.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're telling me it was one guy with six guns? A-and he was a senior fucking citizen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's better if we find this man before he finds us again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see what I can do. How do I get in touch with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to hit Poppa Joe tonight, right in the comfort of his own home. Then we move on to New York. It's getting a bit hot for us here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(hangs up)</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you tonight, afterwards.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker tosses an envelope of cash in his plate, just as Yakavetta did.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know who he is. Nobody does.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he bring him in for?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needed an outsider. The package boy knows everyone. He'd spot our hitters a mile away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's the one shooting up all his guys, right? He's scared of the kid. Says he's real good, got every available gun in the city up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up where?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up his house. I don't know what's going on but I know it's gotta have something to do with this kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(runs out)</context>
      <utterance>Oh fuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you guys think?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're tough. No way they're gonna talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Rocco. He ain't smart enough for this shit. These other guys are the brains. He's just a player.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only one way to get them to talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta keep going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll keep going, Roc.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Rocco dies, they fall into prayer.</context>
      <utterance>You'll make it outta here. You can't ever stop, not ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHAPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yakavetta stops as if terrified with a thought.</context>
      <utterance>Once you set him in motion, you can't call him off. He thinks it's still on.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I...</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four guys are left alone. They all look far from confident except for Geno.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I don't have my name spray painted on the front of this house. There are no big pictures of me anywhere. If this guy thinks the job is still a go then I got green money says the mother fucker's out in the bushes already. I'm fucking gone! I'm leaving you guys to deal with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One fucking guy, so what.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take the front.  You guys cover those other exits and if you see him, don't flag him down, just kill the mother fucker. I'm going back down to work on these pricks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SMECKER AS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman speaks and it is apparent that this is actually Smecker in drag.</context>
      <utterance>Joey Bevo sent me over. As entertainment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen baby. Tonight ain't the night for this shit.  Bevo's so great. Always sending us hot girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smecker kisses him full on the lips and rubs up against him. Geno is convinced. He brings her inside.</context>
      <utterance>You look like you could use a quickie.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Chappy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't been laid in a week. Take five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I die cause you're getting a piece of ass, I'll come back and beat you to death with a big rubber dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far are we going with this, Da?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The questions is not, "how far?" The question is, "Do you possess the constitution, the depth of faith to go as far as is needed?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEDIA MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at his charisma. He's the next John Gotti.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll walk. Even with all this evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look.  All Yakavetta's people are on the right. All the families of the men he has killed are on the left. Everyone wants some justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him. He doesn't have a care in the world. He's gonna walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do these put a man down for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father zaps the incapacitated man a second time as he lay.</context>
      <utterance>Ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They suit up, Connor and Murphy in their usual masks and gloves, Dad is already in his usual dark hat and glasses. The boys start for the courtroom door but dad gently holds them back. He takes a moment, then slowly removes his hat and glasses. His sons look at one another and then remove their masks. The three look into each others eyes for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty is a bit better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three burst in, guns drawn, and are walking down the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>Due to the lack of hard evidence......</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terrified, they all obey. Connor and Murphy pull Yakavetta from the witness booth by his hair and place him on his knees just before the judge's bench. They face him toward the occupants of the courtroom. The father walks up and motions for the judge, who is now banging his gavel and shouting in protest, to come off the stand. As soon as he is within arms reach, dad takes him by the collar and drags him down the aisle all the way to where the media stands in horror. He turns and walks back down the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>All media to the back! Drop the cameras! Drop 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes to the front.</context>
      <utterance>You people have been chosen to reveal our existence to the world. You will witness what happens here today and you will tell of it afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAKAVETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father keeps them covered. He passes the front, he looks and sees a VIRGINAL-LOOKING WOMAN with her head down crying into her hands. She is on the left side. He gently tilts her chin forward, her eyes fixated on a faded blue butterfly on the back of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, you will receive us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do not ask for your poor or your hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do not want your tired and sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is your corrupt we claim.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is your evil, who will be sought by us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With every breath we shall hunt them down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each day we will spill their blood till it rains down from the skies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do not kill, do not rape, do not steal. These are principles which every man of every faith can embrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(points to Yakavetta)</context>
      <utterance>These are not polite suggestions. They are codes of behavior and those that ignore them will pay the dearest cost.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are varying degrees of evil. We urge you lesser forms of filth  Not to push the bounds and cross over into true corruption... into our domain.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For if you do, there will come the day when you look behind you and see we three. And on that day you will reap it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Connor and Murphy jump off the table. They approach Yakavetta and stand on either side of their father. All three men hold guns to his head and recite the prayer. As they speak, the right side of the courtroom screams in protest. The left watches in wide-eyed terror, although some men encourage them to do it. The MacManus' read the prayer. They do not falter as the flames rage behind them. Yakavetta, accepting his fate, closing his eyes. Peacefully, he does the sign of the cross. The all fire at once. The room explodes in confusion. The three exit the back.</context>
      <utterance>And we will send you to whatever God you wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER 2</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Were you in the courtroom miss? Did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>FRAIL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>(Slo-mo) She sees at the grande hall's end Smecker leading the three out, bags still over their heads. She sees Dad's butterfly tattoo. She knows.</context>
      <utterance>How do you feel about what they did?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The people who had been on Yakavetta's side of the courtroom threaten her and force their way through the crowd toward her, thus causing the two sides to fight. Everyone, even reporters are in it. The camera tilts up ending on the statue of the Blind Lady of Justice.</context>
      <utterance>I guess we all know what is right and wrong. We all know. Nobody needs to be convinced of what he was... I'm going home now to have my first real full night's sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
