<movie id="366" title="Majestic The The Bijou">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newsreel's just starting, folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me and my girlfriend. Her name is Sandra Sinclair, and this is her town, too -- she's from Cleveland. She came out here to be an actress, and that's just what she's doing. The first picture I ever wrote, a little potboiler called "Sand Pirates of the Sahara." Okay, it ain't "Citizen Kane," but you gotta start somewhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over a newsreel shot of a packed Congressional Committee Hearing Room, a title blares "HOLLYWOOD REDS GO TO JAIL!"</context>
      <utterance>Bringing the news of the world to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see several shots of WITNESSES engaged in heated verbal battles with congressmen, especially Committee Chairman T. JOHNSTON DOYLE and the Majority Counsel, ELVIN CLYDE.</context>
      <utterance>Four years ago, in one of filmland's darkest hours, ten men, the so-called "Hollywood Ten," were called to testify before the House Committee of Un-American Activities, investigating the proliferation of the dreaded Red Menace in Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over shots of several of the "Hollywood Ten" being led to jail in handcuffs, the newsreel narration continues.</context>
      <utterance>Refusing to answer the lawmaker's questions, cowering behind the Fifth Amendment's protection against self-incrimination, the ten motion picture writers dared Congress to come after them. Well, come after them they did! And after years of court wrangling, it's now time to pay the piper!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>newsreel moves on to a somewhat more innocuous subject, we</context>
      <utterance>And so, it's off to jail, the charge: Contempt of Congress! This should give you fellas something to write about now! A new round of investigations begins this fall, the mandate: Get the reds out of Hollywood! In the audience, one man YELLS "Lock up the commie bastards!," and a few others cheer and laugh. As the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete, there's time before the picture starts, you want to get some popcorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete kisses Sandra on the cheek, then stands and sprints up the aisle to the concession stand, a big unworried grin on his face.</context>
      <utterance>You bet, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were young, we were in love, and we were working in pictures. Life... was good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is nonplussed. Tips his hat. Regards Pete suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>Mornin', Ray. Whaddya know whaddya say? Me and Sandra caught "The African Queen" at the Chinese last night. Great picture, great picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with this "Mr. Appleton" crap? Your boss hiding in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're clear to go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray heads back to his kiosk, shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>What's that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete, covering his worry well, drives onto the lot.</context>
      <utterance>Have a pleasant day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up, startled.</context>
      <utterance>Louise... what gives?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Pete... they, uh, they gave everybody the day off... while they sort things out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort what out? Are my pages done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took 'em? Who took 'em? Louise, what's going on...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes past him. Pete doesn't quite know what to think.</context>
      <utterance>Pete, I'm not even supposed to be talking to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Pete turns. The voice belongs to Pete's agent, LEO KUBELSKY, a rotund man in his fifties. He wears a perfectly tailored silk suit.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo... what's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, their hands are tied. You see that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't believe this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying it's a mistake, that you didn't go to any meetings? They say you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell is this "they?"</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congress, the FBI, Red Channels, it don't matter who the hell "they" is. "They" know who "they" are, that's all that matters.  Now, did you go to any meetings?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Yeah... I... I don't know. Maybe I did. Leo, this was before Pearl Harbor. I was in college. It was a bunch of kids, and I was just one of 'em. I didn't believe in what they were saying. Hell, I didn't even know what they were saying!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're saying that it's true. You went to a meeting of a known communist organization.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo, I was trying to impress a skirt. You know me, I'm non- political. Republican, Democrat, Communist, there's not a dime's worth of difference between 'em anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should watch what you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who fingered me, but I'm not a communist!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, that cuts no ice with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? That I'm accused of being a communist when I don't happen to be one?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know you were at that meeting, Peter. They've been told, and they know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo, you're my agent. Tell "them" to take a flyin' piss. I didn't do anything wrong. I fought in the war, for crissakes!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fought? Come on, Pete, you ran the PX at Fort Dix.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was decorated.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. A Purple Heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke your arm. You were coming out of a bar. You were drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least I was on our side! Look, they want me to testify? I'll testify. I'll tell 'em anything they want to hear! Jesus, Leo, this is my career!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't testify.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo takes a gold cigarette care from his breast pocket, offers a cigarette to Pete and takes one for himself.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo lights Pete's cigarette and his own. Puts a fatherly hand on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take this personally, kid. If it were up to me, I'd have you testify wearing your uniform and your medal, wrapped in a flag with one hand on your heart and the other hand on a bible. What can I say? I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't want you to testify because you're not a big enough fish for them. They just don't want you writing pictures for now. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, that's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, I believe in you. More to the point, I read your new script... um...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Ashes To Ashes?"</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the one, "Ashes To Ashes." I think it's great. But it'll never get made with this communist business hanging over your head. You can't work until you're cleared -- and believe me, starting right now, I'm gonna do everything I can to make that happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, it is a blacklist.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that. There is no such thing as a blacklist.  Now, are you gonna play ball?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo blows out a thin stream of smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Leo, goddammit... this isn't fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, this is the United States Government we're talkin' about. Fair ain't the point.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>"SAND PIRATES OF THE SAHARA"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete shuffles the scripts and looks at the cover of the second one:</context>
      <utterance>By Peter Appleton A United Pictures Production February 19, 1951</utterance>
   <speaker>"ASHES TO ASHES"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams the scripts into one box and turns to the other box, which contains somewhat more personal items. A ragged gold pillow with tassels. Legal pads of notes. An old tin-toy fire truck, its bright red paint chipped and worn. He turns it around in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>By Peter Appleton</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Footsteps approach, and Pete swivels toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Huh. Red...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sandra appears in the doorway. She's in costume -- a Louis XIV courtier. She bustles past the Guard, rushes to Pete and embraces him.</context>
      <utterance>Pete? Pete...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss. The Guard watches their every move.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Pete...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly did you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you got let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't alone. Wasn't Frankie Ruskin directing the picture you're in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was, but he got sick. We got a new director today. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whatever Frankie's got, it's catching.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, he was... let go, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this last, Sandra has been ever-so-slightly pulling away from Pete.</context>
      <utterance>They're saying I'm a communist, Sandy. But I'm not, you know that. I'm gonna fight 'em, and I'm gonna win, but I'll need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra glances at the Guard, who is watching everything.</context>
      <utterance>A lot of good people are being accused of things they didn't do. Hell, even if I was a communist, this is America, goddammit, a person should be able to be whatever they want to be! Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete sees where this is going. She's edging toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, but I... I don't know how I... how much help I can be to you. This is the sort of thing... someone saying you're a communist... it can ruin your career.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you help me, Sandy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's out the door and gone in the blink of an eye. Pete looks at the Guard.</context>
      <utterance>I'll have to think about this. I have to get back... I should go...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard turns away. Pete moves back toward the boxes. Rummaging again, he comes up with a bottle of Jack Daniels with barely one swig left. He regards the bottle for a moment, looks to see if the Guard is watching (he isn't), pops the cork, puts it to his lips and drains it. He looks at it thoughtfully as we</context>
      <utterance>So nice to be a pariah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete. You think maybe you've had enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knocks it back and Jerry pours him another.</context>
      <utterance>Bought the bottle, didn't I?  To the United States of America. Long my she wave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Jerry. Tell me something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tight with J. Edgar Hoover?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The G-man?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zackly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete, if J. Edgar Hoover walked in here wearing a dress, I wouldn't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad. He says I'm a communist.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should watch what you say. You don't know who's listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I'm not a communist, don't you, Jer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I suppose. That why you're on a bender?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete drains his shotglass, puts it back on the bar. He watches Jerry, who is not about to refill it. Pete reaches for the bottle, but Jerry is faster.</context>
      <utterance>This is not a bender yet. This is the start of a bender. But I can see how you were confused, they look a lot alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete... go home. Come on, I'll call that girlfriend of yours, what's her name... Sandy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandra Sinclair.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimmee her number, I'll have her pick you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandra Sinclair. Wanna know her real name? Bella Iskowitz. No one's who they really are, Jer. Everyone's someone else. Even you. Even me. Especially me. I'm Peter Appleton, the communist who's not really a communist.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter stands, stubs out his smoke, drops a few crumpled bills on the bar and grabs his hat.</context>
      <utterance>I wanna close up soon. C'mon, let's call her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. Can't. We're through.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll call you a cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete's preoccupied with putting on his hat and getting his car keys out of his coat pocket, a daunting task in his condition.</context>
      <utterance>I'll save you the trouble.  I'm a cab. There. Did it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Sides, car's right outside. I'll be seein' ya, Jer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Pete...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Drive. Drive. Bad idea. Too drunk to drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the key and hits the starter. The engine hums to life. Pete sits up, opens his eyes wide, shakes off the haze and puts the car in gear. The Plymouth lurches forward a few yards, screeches to a halt and stalls.</context>
      <utterance>One-thirty. Huh! Early. Can't go home yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He re-starts the car, puts it in gear, and pulls away and down the deserted boulevard.</context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instantly, he grabs his head.</context>
      <utterance>Huh? Whatsa...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pete takes a deep breath... and starts coughing. He gets out his cigarettes and lights up. He takes a puff and glances at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>I had no idea how I got to Santa Monica, but it certainly was a good idea. I don't think I could've faced the headache I had alone in my apartment. At least I had the ocean air.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He starts the car and heads for the highway.</context>
      <utterance>Three forty-five. I had only been there for a couple of hours at most. Truth be told, I was still fairly drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd head north until the sun came up or I ran out of gas, whichever came first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INSERT - FUEL GAUGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pinning on "empty."</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He scans the road ahead -- nothing. Glances to his right.</context>
      <utterance>Guess which came first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pete looks ahead toward the town. Its few lights twinkle in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>I should've known better than to think that a service station in the sticks would be open at this hour, but it wasn't like I had a lot of choices.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pete pulls out onto the road.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell. At least there'd be a diner opening in a couple of hours. I'd get some pie and coffee, and then I could worry about the gas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete blinks up at the Old Man, his mouth gaping open.</context>
      <utterance>Mister, who are ya? my dog likes you, but that don't mean much, she likes skunks, too. Sweet n'stupid, that's why I keep her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister, you okay? You look wet. You in an accident or somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits up, and the Old Man gets a look at his head, which is caked with mud and blood on one side.</context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You best come with me. Can ya walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up shakily. The Old Man gives Pete a hand.</context>
      <utterance>I... yes, I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, we'll have the Doc look you over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My head hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they head toward the road to town. BOOMING UP, we SEE them pass a roadside sign:</context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't be surprises. You smell like that was quite a night before you had there.  Maggie! Let's go now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode>STANTON</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Stanton Lawson. My ancestors founded this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ancestors?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete takes the handkerchief and wipes the mud and some of the blood off his face.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, my grandpap. But "ancestors" sounds better, don't it?  Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete stops, thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>You look familiar, fella. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm... I... I honestly don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass the window of the drug store, COLE'S PHARMACY. Pete looks down and sees</context>
      <utterance>'Course they all know me. And I know all them. Town's got my name, don't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ernie Cole here just got himself elected mayor. Lost both his boys in the war. Kenny at Anzio and Willie at Normandy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mabel over there at the diner lost her husband Max. Okinawa, I believe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hungry, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Very.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete rummages in his pants pockets, and comes up with three quarters.</context>
      <utterance>Got any money?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they head across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Six bits. More'n enough to buy some breakfast. C'mon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pie's... good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you could tell.  Where'd you find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down by the wash.</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta put a rail on that thing before someone else gets killed.  Three people have died there, Mister. You're lucky to be alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mabel obliges. As she pours the coffee, she looks at Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. More coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you look familiar. You ever been in here before?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't remember who he is, Mabel. Gonna take him to the Doc, as soon as he gets in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete looks up at Mabel and smiles winningly.</context>
      <utterance>Doc should be in for his coffee and bear claw any minute...  You sure you never been in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mabel, thoroughly charmed, smiles back at Pete.</context>
      <utterance>I'd remember this pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just get you another piece.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Mornin' Harry. Fine day, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Doc. Yes, yes it looks just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plenty to do today?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're at the door of the diner. Doc opens it for Harry.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, plenty. Plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mornin' Mabel, Stan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner and Pete make eye contact, and the doctor notices the bump on his head.</context>
      <utterance>Mornin' Doc. Got some new business for you today.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, son. How'd that happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't know. And he don't know his name, neither. Found him down by the wash.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better come with me, son.  On my tab?</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner, Stanton and Pete rise and move to the door. Pete turns back, takes the three quarters out of his pocket, and puts them on the counter, smiling brightly at Mabel.</context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Great pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. Come again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was passed out cold. Maggie woke 'im.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete does. Lardner has a look as Stanton pulls out a pocket watch.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. He looks familiar.  Open your mouth. Say "ah."</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said as much myself, Doc. Can't place him, though. To look at him, you'd think the cheese slid off his cracker.  Well, morning's half-over. I'm off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mr. Lawson.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanton and Maggie exit. Lardner checks Pete's ears.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it. Whoever-you-are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any idea how you got here, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner sniffs him.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been drinkin' a bit, have we?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember. I guess so. Smells like it.  Tastes like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you've been wet to the skin. You must've fallen in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner takes a shirt off his counter and hands it to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky you got out, that water's got quite a pull, and it empties straight into the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, one of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete puts on the shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember if you were driving a car? Maybe you went over the bridge. No guard rail there, it's easy to do. It's happened before.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible. I just don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you don't know your name or who you are, that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... no, I... I just can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete stifles a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, son. We just need to call you something. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me... Ishmael?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least you remember "Moby Dick."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner hangs up and watches Pete looking at the pictures.</context>
      <utterance>Stanton found him by the wash. Not hurt too bad, but he took a nasty bump on the head and he can't remember who he is. We both think he looks familiar, but we can't place him. You bet. He'll be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me and my daughter Adele. My pride and joy. Charms the fish right out of the lake, she does.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's very pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner stares at him. Pete takes note, turns toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Well, Sheriff's on his way over, and maybe we can get to the bottom of who you are...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... sorry 'bout that, but you do look familiar to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish I could say the same thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecil! Cecil, there's a young man in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord love a duck, Harry, you wanna give me a heart attack right in front of the doctor's office?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eldridge keeps moving to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me! The young man in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stan Lawson found him unconscious by the wash this morning, and I'm here to investigate, and if we find anything interesting, it'll be in the paper, so why don't you just... Harry jumps in front of Eldridge and grabs him by the shoulders.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sheriff stops.</context>
      <utterance>Cecil, listen to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Luke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wallet, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No identification at all.  What're you thinkin', Cecil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm thinkin' is we got us one a'two things here. A mystery or a damn miracle. And by god I can't tell which.  Boy, you say you have no idea who you are? That right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever been in this town before, to your knowledge?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this place sorta reminds me of something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"It's a Wonderful Life."</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jimmy Stewart picture? I remember that one. Saw it over at the Bijou. So, you remember that, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"It's a Wonderful Life?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or the Bijou. Either one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff rises and crosses to the door.</context>
      <utterance>I remember the picture... but I don't remember where I saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc, with your permission, I want to bring someone in here. Maybe it'll jar this young man's memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eldridge opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>By all means.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry enters the office, doffs his hat, revealing a full head of snow-white hair. He nods to Eldridge and Lardner, and slowly turns to face Pete. He looks closer... and closer. Hesitantly, he takes a couple of steps towards Pete, who slowly rises out of his chair to meet the old man's gaze. Finally, they're standing practically toe-to-toe.</context>
      <utterance>Harry, why don't you come on in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying that he's...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry takes Pete in his arms and hugs him tightly, burying his face in Pete's shoulder and sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete doesn't quite know what to think. He clearly has no idea who this old man is.</context>
      <utterance>I knew all along. I knew you were alive! Oh, Luke...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother o'god...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give the man a hug, boy! That's your father! Pete looks at Harry. It's not so much that he remembers anything -- he's swept up in the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete wraps his arms around Harry and hugs him tightly, glancing over at</context>
      <utterance>My father...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, I'll give you two a lift back to the Bijou.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bijou?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where you live.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We live in a theater?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one in town.  Get in, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, when's Delly due back?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow afternoon...  ... oh my god...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to move away, then turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Get plenty of rest, Luke. You took a pretty big wallop there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eldridge starts the car and they drive away. (NOTE: Henceforth, "PETE" will be known as "LUKE." It'll be easier to keep track of things, since everyone's now calling him Luke, anyway. Trust me.)</context>
      <utterance>Good to have you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me... what's your, um, your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, son. Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And... what's my name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert Lucas Trumbo. But you've been "Luke" since you were a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks at the town as they drive down Commerce Street.</context>
      <utterance>Ah.  Luke. Luke. I like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eldridge looks at Harry, who stares ahead.</context>
      <utterance>How long have I been gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. The silence is too thick, and Harry has to answer. He turns around in his seat and faces Luke.</context>
      <utterance>How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never came back from the war. We were told you were missing and presumed dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did I leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke sits back against the back seat and lets this sink in.</context>
      <utterance>You joined up one month to the day after Pearl Harbor. January seventh... nineteen forty-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine and-a-half years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine and-a-half years...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comin' up on the Bijou, gents.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke peers across the street... his mouth gapes open...</context>
      <utterance>Well, son, you're home!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the lift, Cecil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it. Welcome home, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke opens the back door and slowly steps out. Harry grabs his arm and pulls a ring of keys from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait'll you see the inside!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been closed for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke walks toward the auditorium doors and slowly, cracks one open.</context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly how long has the Bijou been closed?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmmm... after you left, it was difficult, and then Lily -- that's your mother -- she took ill and died... we haven't shown a picture since forty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, after the war, with so many of the town's boys killed, people around here didn't much feel like going to the movies, I guess. Some of 'em moved away -- Los Angeles, Sacramento, San Francisco. Wasn't much to keep 'em here, I expect. And now with this "television" thing -- people just aren't going out as much as they used to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you have any help?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I had Irene and Old Tim but they really couldn't help much. Broke their hearts when we closed up. Broke mine, too.  But now that you're back, well, things will be different around here, that's for sure.  C'mon, I'll show you where we live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>The day you shipped out. That was a proud day for your mother and me. Last time you saw her. Last time I saw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke sets it down and picks up another photo, that of a fine looking woman. It's a formal portrait, dating perhaps from the 30's.</context>
      <utterance>Till today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Lily. Your mother, rest her soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother.  She's beautiful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Morning, Son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is speechless. It he dreaming this?</context>
      <utterance>Sleep well?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They couldn't wait to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who... are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the staff of the Bijou.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. What... what time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke sits up on the sofa and tries to get a little more awake. He rubs the side of his head that is still bandaged. The elderly woman nudges Harry gently.</context>
      <utterance>Six-thirty. I thought we'd get an early start.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke stands and shakes MRS. TERWILLIGER'S hand. She's tiny, seventy if she's a day. She smiles and curtsies slightly. Her eyes sparkle brightly, her manner almost coquettish.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry, they know you, but you don't... you need to be re- introduced. Luke, this is Mrs. Irene Terwilliger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head cashier and refreshments clerk. So glad to have you back, my boy!  Much more handsome than I remember him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLT TIM is -- well, old. His clothes are a tad shabby, but well maintained, though they hang loosely on his gangly frame. He wears an old blue knit cap, which he quickly removes as he shakes Luke's hand. He's a man of few words, his manner is painfully shy -- and he never smiles.</context>
      <utterance>And this fine fellow is our head usher, resident fix-it man and custodian. Luke, meet Old Tim.  You remember Luke, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a young Tim?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, why do they call you "Old Tim?" Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry steps forward, takes Luke's arm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm old.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, lots to do, so we'd better get a move on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fraid this has seen better days. Well, I was meaning to get a new screen, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks at Old Tim, then at Harry.</context>
      <utterance>I n-need me a new uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promised him a new uniform when we re-opened.  And you'll get one, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence from the group.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I hate to bring this up, but screens and uniforms and paint and repairs are going to take money, which I'm willing to bet none of us has.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Harry brightens, clambers down the steps and races up the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>I thought so.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone want to see the projector?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The carbons sputter and die. The light flickers out. Harry is crestfallen, turns off the motor.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful. Bright and even from edge to edge. See for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's always been a bit tricky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both stop their work and glance warily at the door marked "OFFICE."</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Timothy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you suppose they're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunno. Boy's smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he seems to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad for us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... Harry? Did I ever keep the books here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, your mother did, then I did after she passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scans down a page.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm the first one to admit that I don't know anything about bookkeeping, but there are some very interesting things in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"February 10, 1942. Picture 'Ball of Fire.'"</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gary Cooper. And Barbara Stanwyck. Yowsa.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Eight p.m. showtime, ninety-six admissions, receipts including concessions, $84.75... plus one fryer and two-dozen eggs." He closes the book and looks expectantly at Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"one fryer and two-dozen eggs?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-two was a lean year around here. The war had just started... you were gone less than a month... and we were coming off a bit of a drought as I recall. Not everyone could ante up the price of a ticket, and a chicken's as good as money if you ask me. At that time, it meant a lot to the folks around here to be able to come to the pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know, but poultry...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry puts his hand on his chest and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I know it's hard to believe, son, but this place, this little place this wasn't a theater then, this was a palace! Any man, woman, child, you, me, it didn't matter, you bought your ticket and you walked in and you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inspired, Harry stands, takes Luke by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>... you were in a palace. It was like a dream. It was like heaven, like you died and went to a palace in heaven, that's what it was like. And spotless, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drags him out of the office and into the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie Chaplin. Keaton and Lloyd. Swanson. And later on, Clark Gable and Claudette Colbert and Jimmy Stewart and James Cagney and Bogart and Becall and Judy and Mickey... and Fred and Ginger.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the screen.</context>
      <utterance>They... were... like... gods!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry comes over to Luke.</context>
      <utterance>And that... was the altar. Would you remember if I told you, we felt lucky to be here, to have the privilege of watching them?  This television thing. Why would you want to sit at home and watch a little box with a little screen? Because it's convenient? Because you don't have to get dressed and put on a coat and a tie and a hat? Because you can just... sit there? How can you call that "entertainment," all alone in your living room? Where are the other people? Where's the audience?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands behind Luke and whispers in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the magic?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns Luke around and looks him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you. In a place like this, the magic is all around you. All the time. Everywhere. In every thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>The trick... is to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still looking at Luke, Harry takes a step back, then slowly walks up the aisle, disappearing into the lobby. Luke walks down the aisle. At the edge of the orchestra pit, he stands looking up at the screen. The orange tabby cat MEOWS, and Luke glances toward it, standing onstage by the edge of the screen. They exchange looks as we</context>
      <utterance>Son, I think you loved the Bijou even more than I did. You've got to remember that. You've got to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner rises as Adele comes into the living room. They embrace warmly.</context>
      <utterance>Delly? In here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not as bad as I thought it would. I think I passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my girl!  Did you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No hiccups, which was good. Who wants an attorney who gets the hiccups when she gets nervous?  "Your  honor, I  object!" They laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner gives her an extra squeeze, continues to hold onto her just a bit too long. Adele detects something amiss.</context>
      <utterance>I always told you, baby...  ... it's all up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Dad? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele breaks away from him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god... who died?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises the glass to her lips.</context>
      <utterance>Drink slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a particularly gymnastic way in which to drink water, but Adele accomplishes it with aplomb. She waits for a moment -- then hiccups again.</context>
      <utterance>From the other side of the glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think  it's worse  now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That always used to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well it's not everyday you get  news like this. You're sure he's  okay? Other than the  bump on the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner sits at the table and takes Adele's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't remember anything, Delly. Doesn't know how he got here, doesn't remember his father, the town, the Bijou, anyone...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... including me. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not. He looked right at your picture without batting an eye. But it's probably temporary. He got all the way to Lawson, so he clearly knew who he was and what he was doing until he hit his head. I'm sure it'll all come back to him. It just takes a catalyst.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean,  me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Adele's thoughtful hiccuping, we</context>
      <utterance>It's possible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ERNIE COLE, a slight, balding man in his 50s, is locking the door of his pharmacy across the street, when he spots Harry and Luke.</context>
      <utterance>I take breakfast and supper at Mabel's every day except Sunday. Have for years, since Lily died. If it weren't for Mabel, I'd probably starve to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie runs across the street and, slightly winded, stands before Luke, staring. Luke shoots a glance at Harry, who taps Ernie on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Harry! Hold on a second!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really him, Ernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sticks his hand out and Luke takes it. Ernie pumps it enthusiastically.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By god, Luke, if it isn't good to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, thanks. Good to see you again, too, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Ernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just gonna get some supper. Would you like to join us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three walk toward the diner, but before they get two steps, they hear:</context>
      <utterance>Would I ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to see a stout woman, KATIE RUTHERFORD, 40s, rushing toward them. She rushes right into a very surprised Luke's arms and hugs him tightly.</context>
      <utterance>Is that Luke Trumbo?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Luke, it's so good to have you back!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Katie, would you like to join us for dinner? The more, the merrier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few people shake their heads, smile and laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Luke, remember the time you and me, we was playing with firecrackers and the one you was lighting blew up too soon and singed all the hair offa my head?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of TITTERS are heard.</context>
      <utterance>Well... um, all the hair got singed offa my head. It was pretty funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke leans toward Harry, who never looks up from his chicken.</context>
      <utterance>Even my eyebrows. But they grew back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl. Friend of yours from high school. Everybody calls him "Cueball."</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hi Cue... Carl. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke smiles and nods at the young man sitting next to Carl.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, heck, that's all right. It's just good to have you back. Isn't that right, Bob? Hey, Luke, you remember my brother Bob? You two joined up the same day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, I know there's a question that's on everybody's mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes on Luke. He freezes, having just taken a forkful of food in his mouth. Harry jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>Well, now that you're back, what're your plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MURMUR goes through the crowd. Stanton Lawson, standing behind Luke, taps him on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna re-open the Bijou, that's what.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That true?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... we're gonna try.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot of work, son. Place's been closed, what, three, four years now. Gonna be tough.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone shouts "That's the spirit!," another shouts "Hear, hear!," and a chorus of VOICES join in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>If it's tough, that means it's worth doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, where's Spencer Wyatt?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, back here, Mr. Mayor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPENCER WYATT steps around from the back of the crowd near the door. He's a tall, dark-haired, gangly, bespectacled kid, no more than 19 or 20. Painfully shy, he clutches a clarinet case to his chest. He timidly smiles and waves at Luke, who smiles and nods back.</context>
      <utterance>Well, come on out here so's we can see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Spencer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spence, that band of yours -- you think they're ready to play?  Spencer and his pals went ahead and got together a good ol' big band.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been practicing... uh, sure, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vociferous general AGREEMENT from the crowd -- which is quickly quieted by a MURMUR, which starts at the front door. The crowd parts and grow silent, revealing a woman standing in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how about tomorrow night, eight p.m., in city hall square? What I'm proposin' is a "Welcome Home Luke" celebration.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you... remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mabel, clutching a napkin, leans over to Katie.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen you before. Your picture...</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele leans up and kisses him softly. He looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>... but I don't think I remember you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mabel and Katie dab at their eyes, we</context>
      <utterance>But I'll sure try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I... I just wondering where you've been all this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look... different.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a little. I think you grew an inch or so. And you've lost weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tentatively, she takes his hand and holds it. From behind them, we HEAR A SHUFFLING SOUND. Adele turns...</context>
      <utterance>I did? Huh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can all go home, now. He's not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Go on home, folks. And thanks for the welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be home in a little while, Harry. Don't wait up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two have a lot of catching up to do, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the rest of the crowd disperses, variously wishing the pair goodnight. Luke and Adele watch them disperse.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, son.  'Night, Delly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn and start walking.</context>
      <utterance>There. We're alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why do I feel like we're still being shadowed?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele brightens.</context>
      <utterance>Well... where can we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs his hand and they run toward the town square.</context>
      <utterance>I know a place. Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>City hall?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs his hand and they run to the side of the building.</context>
      <utterance>You must not remember anything. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be a gentleman. You have to help me down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, there was a lot more room before they stuck the memorial down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd they get it inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to the memorial. Squinting, she examines its base.</context>
      <utterance>Through the door. It comes apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Your name's on here. See?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here. "Albert Lucas Trumbo." And all the others. I knew them all. So did you. We went to school with most of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't seem right, this being down here. It ought to be where people can see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her for a long moment. There's an electricity between them, and they both feel it.</context>
      <utterance>After they commissioned it, no one could ever agree on where to put it. The Methodists wanted it in front of the Methodist Church, the Presbyterians wanted it in front of the Presbyterian Church, the city council wanted it in the lobby of City Hall. Everyone finally got tired of the fighting. So they stuck it down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're really gonna be a lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. You don't know how many times I've heard that. "A lady lawyer? Are you crazy?" Like a woman couldn't be as good a lawyer as a man. Or better, in fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you always wanted to be a lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... don't remember, but yes, ever since I was a little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did... what did I want to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away, rubs his head.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well... I guess you... in high school, you were a pretty good first baseman. And we were on the debate team together. But... I think you were gonna run the Bijou. You were brought up there, and you loved it so much. And I think you knew how much the town needed a place like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to her.</context>
      <utterance>I just wish I could remember some of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have a boyfriend or anyone... you know... like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I was married. For four years. But... well, we didn't fit together. I'm divorced now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay. See, when two people belong together, the other person should be the... the key that unlocks the rest of you... I'm not making sense, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you are. I know exactly what you mean. It's not that you're missing something. It's that the other person gives something to you... that you had all the time. You just didn't see it until they came along.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were in love... weren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She instantly covers her mouth, but it's no good. She has the hiccups again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Hic!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have the...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke smiles and watches Adele as she makes the decision to not struggle against the hiccups. She has them, and that's just the way it is.</context>
      <utterance>I'm  fine. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were we going to get married?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. She's strikingly beautiful at this particular moment and in this particular light -- hiccups and all. He moves closer to her. She moves closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>Eventually. We were going to be  engaged... when you came back from  overseas...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as she smiles and kisses him again we</context>
      <utterance>Hey... it worked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The humming stops, and after a moment, the door swings open, revealing Old Tim, a pipe in his mouth, holding the cat, stroking its fur.</context>
      <utterance>Um, Old Tim? Sorry, it's late. It's Luke. Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Found me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Tim moves into the room and gestures for Luke to follow him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I hope you don't mind. I didn't know anyone lived here... well, besides Harry. And me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I guess this fellow belongs to you. What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cat. That's simple. I like it.  Hi, Cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We thought you was dead, you know.  It's okay that I live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause, then suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks up at the old man, who stammers when he speaks more than a couple of words.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I'll get me a new u-u uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Tim puffs on his pipe, strangely detached.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do everything I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T-t-thank you. Thank you. I... I always... I always wanted to wear my uniform from the Great War, but your daddy, he always said no, that's not an usher's u-u-uniform, that's an army uniform and the Bijou, she's not the army. They give me a medal, but I lost it in the h-h-hospital. I forget things sometimes. Since the w-w-war.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We HEAR the key in the lock and the door swings open, revealing the building SUPER, 50s. Behind him is Leo Kubelsky. They enter the room, and the Super sniffs the air.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton? Mr. Appleton? You in there? This is the Super, I have the master key and I'm coming in!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell gas?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't smell nothin'. He must not be dead in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo moves to the boxes and rummages through them. He picks up the empty bottle, examines it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's the best way to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he's drunk somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't blame him if he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, his rent's past due and he said to call you in case of an emergency. He lose his job or somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his rent?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo peels off a hundred-dollar bill.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's three months rent, and a ten spot for no more questions and to keep an eye on his place. Now, I need a moment alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a hike. Am-scray.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Super exits and Leo crosses to the phone and dials "O."</context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh, sure. Just pull the door shut when you leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police department. I want to report a missing person.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clyde's SECRETARY knocks on the door, sticks her head in.</context>
      <utterance>You say you know nothing about it. You say this, yet you offer no proof. How am I supposed to believe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Clyde? Agents Saunders and Brett need to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do see that I'm busy, do you not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clyde's eyes brighten.</context>
      <utterance>It's about Appleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Saunders and Brett stride into the office.</context>
      <utterance>Tell them to come in.  I'll have to call you back. I love you too, Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a situation developing...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop, shuck off their hats. Saunders starts over again.</context>
      <utterance>Will you take those goddamn hats off?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clyde grins darkly.</context>
      <utterance>We've got a situation developing out on the coast. Appleton's just been reported missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is good. This is very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clyde considers this for a beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Los Angeles Police Department investigated. His car's missing. No signs of forced entry or struggle at his apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two are on this as of now. Tell the LAPD their investigation has been federalized on my order. You find me this Appleton.  I want to see what this one has to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The object of my affection, Can change my complexion, From white to rosy red..." Luke takes a breath:</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Between a new screen, paint, plumbing for the concession stand, and about a hundred other repairs around the theater... it's going to cost at least nine hundred dollars to get the Bijou into shape to open up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine hundred...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you have sixty-eight dollars and thirty-seven cents in the bank. Your only source of income are my veteran's death benefit of forty dollars a month, to which you're no longer entitled since I'm alive, and these ten dollar a month cash deposits you make. What are those?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my r-r-rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all my fault. I was neglectful and this is the price of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off everyone's worried looks, we</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's true. Wanting to open this place back up. It's folly, Irene, pure and simple. Might as well just call it what it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, that's Luke, can you let him in? I'll be right down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, I... I can't... it's the...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves from his spot. The reception goes bad, and he marches to the door. He opens it, and Luke is standing there, wearing a slightly out-of-date coat and tie.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lardner freezes, staring at Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Evening, Doctor Lardner.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no... just seeing you standing there, it reminded me... there's a word for it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele comes down the stairs. Halfway down, she stops suddenly and stares at Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean the suit. Harry kept all my old clothes. Fits okay, but it's a little big.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward pause. Adele's staring at Luke, Lardner's staring at Luke, and Luke's getting nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele comes down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't have worn the suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... you were wearing that suit the last time we went out before...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and It's just... well, deja vu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another awkward pause as Adele and Luke stare at each other. Lardner breaks it.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Deja vu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kids off to the dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not much of a dancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, Daddy's still trying to figure out how to get his new television set working.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the TV set. The picture is suddenly crystal clear.</context>
      <utterance>I had it, a minute ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele takes Luke's arm and they exit, exchanging goodnights with Lardner, who closes the door and turns toward the living room. S-l-o-w-l-y, he sneaks into the room, watching the TV carefully all the while. The reception is staying perfect. Caesar and Coca are involved in an intricate bit of business, and Lardner wants to laugh, but he's afraid to. He stifles his urge, and heads for his chair. Gingerly, he sits. Still perfect. Satisfied, he finally LAUGHS out loud and puts his feet up. The picture goes completely haywire again.</context>
      <utterance>... ooooh, It's back.  Well, you kids have fun now...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is strange. Do you feel it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've done this before, so many times. The last time was so long ago, but it feels like yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, everyone's so excited about the Bijou re-opening...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna cost over nine hundred dollars to open the place, Delly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine hundred...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and needless to say, none of us has that kind of money lying around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a loan? You could go to the bank...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A loan to a man who ran his business into the ground and his son who can't account for the last nine-and-a-half years of his life? Not likely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's got to be a way...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele stops.</context>
      <utterance>Have you got a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you start smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tried to once. It was pretty pitiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele glances curiously at Luke as we</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they're not. I'd say your investment was paying dividends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back in '37, you heard Benny Goodman play for the first time, so you went out and got a used clarinet. You wanted nothing more than to be able to play like him. You tried hard, but it wasn't long before it was clear that Benny Goodman would never be looking over his shoulder. So you gave the clarinet to Spencer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh. That was nice of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had a hidden agenda, though. See, when he was five or six, little Spence used to follow you around like a puppy. Bothered the hell out of you. But as soon as you gave him the clarinet...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... he started practicing, and he left me alone from then on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. And he got good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance a bit.</context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, did you remember that, or...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. Just filling in the blanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as they dance away, we</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the luckiest guy in town, Luke. Delly's 'bout the prettiest thing ever come outta Lawson.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Alex. He's Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir, 'bout the prettiest thing we ever seen, ain't that right, Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers laugh goofily.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks boys, ya flatter me no end.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, she's doin' that movie star, what's her name...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Delly, what was that test you was outta town takin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called the State Bar Exam.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine that, Charlie! A lady bartender!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you tell those two apart, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex and Charlie? Simple. Alex is the smarter one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh and dance a bit more.</context>
      <utterance>That's... pretty frightening.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your dancing's very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It never used to be. You were two left feet on the dance floor. Like pulling teeth to get you to do a little box step.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke dances Adele away, a slightly nonplussed expression on her face. The band finishes the song, and everyone enthusiastically APPLAUDS. Spencer bows shyly, blushing slightly. He nods to the band, and they bow before he motions for the crowd's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Guess I must've learned.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd yells "No!," "You guys sound great!," etc.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, folks. Gee, can you tell we never played in front of people before?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the clarinet and scans the crowd until he sees Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this is our first time, and it's really all because of Luke. I mean, it's because of Luke coming back that we're here tonight -- but I'm talking about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd APPLAUDS warmly.</context>
      <utterance>When you didn't come back, I learned how to play this so I could remember you. And now that you're back, well, I'll never forget you.  Luke gave me this clarinet, but he gave this night to all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd APPLAUDS as Ernie Cole mounts the band riser. He turns and addresses Avery Wyatt, on drums.</context>
      <utterance>Okay folks, here's Mayor Cole!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avery smiles broadly and beats the KICK DRUM five or six times to register his reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty proud of your boy, Avery?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>APPLAUSE again, and Ernie waits for it to settle. As soon as he starts speaking, the crowd becomes totally silent.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you might have to find someone else to mix paint at the store, 'cause I think Spencer's got a big career ahead of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie's voice cracks slightly with emotion. He clears his throat and continues.</context>
      <utterance>You know folks, here in Lawson, we gave a lot for our country. A lot. And we never complained and we never faltered. And we never forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd APPLAUDS. Adele takes Luke's hand and smiles. Ernie wipes his eyes and changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>We never forgot. And so when one of our own came back to us, I gotta tell you folks, it was like a miracle. Luke, seein' you walking down the street, it was... well, it was kinda like seein' one of my boys alive again. I think I speak for everyone here when I say that not a day goes by when we don't keep our boys' memories alive. But Luke, having you back among us... well, it helps us keep their spirits alive, too. God bless you, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Spencer kicks the band into the next tune as we</context>
      <utterance>All right, enough a'that. This is a celebration, so let's have us a good time -- but not too good a time, 'cause I see just about every member of the city council here tonight, and we have an eight a.m. council meeting tomorrow morning, and I expect y'all to be there! All right, take it away, Spencer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you two get out there and dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Terwilliger blushes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't danced with another man since Mr. Terwilliger passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry touches Luke's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Nineteen-oh-nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goodnights are exchanged, and the trio leaves. Alex McKenna comes up to Adele and taps her on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Son, we're gonna go. You two kids have a lovely time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delly, can I have a dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex leads her to the dance floor as Adele shoots Luke a little "help me!" look. Luke smiles back and watches the dancing crowd. After a moment, a man in a white suit and bow tie, ROSCOE FITTS, 40s, comes over to Luke and extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, you probably don't remember me, Roscoe Fitts, I'm the grocer here in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to meet you. Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Ernie said, we're all glad to have you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I hear you and Harry are planning on re-opening the Bijou.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna try. Place needs a lot of work.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can only imagine. You know, I spoke with your Dad last year about maybe taking the Bijou off his hands. I don't think he gave it very much thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he loves the place. It's his home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, I'm hopping you can help him see the reality of the situation. I'll come to the point. I want to buy the property, and I'm prepared to offer six-thousand dollars for it. And that's just for the property, mind you. If you want, I'll leave it to you and your father to dismantle and liquidate the building for whatever salvage value it has, and you keep those proceeds. I just want the land.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's... well, that's very generous, but if you've already got a store...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The days of the storefront grocery are numbered. I plan on putting up a free-standing supermarket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A super market. Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fitts takes Luke's hand and shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>You think it over. No reason to risk financial ruin for the sake of a crumbling old building.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Luke watches Fitts walk off, we</context>
      <utterance>Good to have you back, Luke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, son, I wish I could've shown you more, but this is all that's left. Just this one reel that never got sent back from a picture we showed here a long time ago. Nineteen twenty-five, to be exact...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father and son look at each other for a long moment -- searching each other's eyes. Harry smiles a sort-of half- smile at Luke, and, still clutching the reel, crosses to the rewind bench. Methodically, he mounts it and threads the end of the film onto an empty reel. Slowly, he begins to turn the crank, rewinding the film. He stops and looks to where Luke was standing... but he's not there.</context>
      <utterance>You know, since you've been back, that's the first time you've called me "Dad."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke... what time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six-thirty.  I thought we'd get an early start.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>VERA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Vera speaks, the meeting room door opens and Luke, Harry, Old Time and Mrs. Terwilliger slip inside and take seats on the unoccupied benches.</context>
      <utterance>Finally, Roscoe Fitts moved, and Red Curtis seconded, that the council form a committee to investigate the adoption of a new property taxation structure. Motion carried, nine to two, one abstention.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie notices Luke and the trio.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Vera.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the chair notes the presence this morning of Luke and Harry Trumbo and the rest of the Bijou staff. Frankly, the chair notes the presence of just about anyone who ever finds their way into one of these meetings. G'moring, folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE &amp; THE TRIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke stands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just guessing, but I bet it's not a sudden interest in Lawson politics that brings you all here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DALEY THORNHILL, 30s, the council parliamentarian, pipes up. He's waving a copy of "Roberts Rules of Order."</context>
      <utterance>Well, no...  I wanted to thank you all for giving me such a nice welcome, and making me feel at home. But I... we're... actually here on business of a sort...</utterance>
   <speaker>DALEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Point of order, Mr. Mayor, this comes under the heading "New Business," and this is not the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we can make an exception here, Daley.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie rolls his eyes, then quickly and mechanically, without inflection:</context>
      <utterance>It'll need to be moved and seconded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, motion to hear the speaker out of order.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seconded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Motion on the floor, discussion open, discussion closed, all those in favor signify by saying "aye."</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Ernie turns to Luke and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Opposed? Hearing no opposition, the motion is carried.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Well, I'll make this short and sweet. The Bijou needs a lot of repairs, and the truth of the matter is, Harry, um, that is, Dad and me, Mrs. Terwilliger and Old Tim, we can't possible afford them all. So, I'd like to ask your help to... well, to scrounge around a bit, and see if you have anything that might help us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinds of things are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fitts leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, paint, brushes, plaster, light bulbs, yardage, and if you can't come up with any of that, we can use some old-fashioned elbow grease.</utterance>
   <speaker>FITTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... you do intend to fix the place up after all?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Harry and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Fitts, with all due respect, I think Lawson needs the Bijou a bit more than it needs a super market. And I think Lawson deserves the Bijou. There's not a lot that can be done to help us get past the pain we've all felt...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The council members MURMUR amongst themselves, then:</context>
      <utterance>... but I think a good dose of magic is as good a place as any to start.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Motion to encourage the citizenry of Lawson to help out the Bijou in any way they can...</utterance>
   <speaker>DALEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... short of the allocation of city funds...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... short of allocation of city funds.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seconded!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Motion on the floor, discussion open, discussion closed, all those in favor signify by saying "aye."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I taught you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can play the piano?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits at the piano.</context>
      <utterance>Oh dear, yes. You were an excellent student, before all that clarinet nonsense. You loved Chopin. You used to call it "heaven music." "Teach me some heaven music," you used to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit. Play with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Luke sits down to her left. As she begins to play a Chopin waltz, she encourages him to keep the 3/4 time.</context>
      <utterance>Some of it might come back to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's clear Luke has no idea what he's doing. He's just plunking bass notes. But after a moment, the bass figures he's improvising start to change -- and before long, it's transformed into the eight-to-the-bar figure of a boogie woogie beat. Mrs. Terwilliger stops playing, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>That's good... that's good...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and moves away. Luke keeps playing, grinning madly -- he's loving it! After a moment, Spencer Wyatt runs over and takes Mrs. Terwilliger's place, improvising the top half to Luke's bass line.</context>
      <utterance>Really, Luke! That's no way to treat Mr. Chopin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GREGORY</speaker>
      <mode>ONSCREEN</mode>
      <context>Khalid lunges and draws Gregory's blood.</context>
      <utterance>You don't think you can win this, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Ha! I'd say I was winning!"</utterance>
   <speaker>KHALID</speaker>
      <mode>ONSCREEN</mode>
      <context>Luke's look is "How did I know he was gonna say that?" Onscreen, an EVIL HENCHMAN is sneaking up behind Gregory.</context>
      <utterance>Ha! I'd say I was winning!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Gregory! Look out!"</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>ONSCREEN</mode>
      <context>Onscreen, Gregory turns and kills the Henchman, then quickly dispatches Khalid. He stands over the body, catches his breath and says:</context>
      <utterance>Gregory! Look out! Pete did it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGORY</speaker>
      <mode>ONSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Rebecca.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>ONSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGORY</speaker>
      <mode>ONSCREEN</mode>
      <context>REBECCA, a beautiful American woman, comes into view and takes our attention because she's being played by Sandra Sinclair, Pete Appleton's ex-girlfriend...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Rebecca. He's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns away, he feels a sudden, sharp pain in his left arm. Wincing, he grabs his arm, staggers back towards a chair, and sits heavily. He tries to clear his throat, but it dissolves into a hacking, choking COUGH. He tries to stand, but drops to his knees, clutching his left arm harder than before.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good girl. No matter what I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry falls to the floor, and as he does</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke stares wide-eyed at the old man.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Luke!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke! Luke, something's wrong! The film broke, and I can't raise Harry on the house phone!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, Luke pulls himself together, hears the audience noise, and moves toward the auditorium doors.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to talk to them before they tear the theater apart!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd quiets down a bit. Luke shields his eyes from the light and calls up to the projection booth.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, folks, this happens every once in a while, just settle down...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reaction. Just the flickering beam of light.</context>
      <utterance>Harry! Harry, why don't you cut the projector and bring up the house lights?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke, gripped by a sudden fear, rushes up the aisle and into the lobby. The crowd goes silent...</context>
      <utterance>Harry? Harry...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The film broke...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN pops his head into the projection booth door.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know... keep still.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get Doc Lardner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pretty massive heart attack. His lungs have filled with fluid, and, well... it seems as though his body is just... shutting down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we get him to the hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry's eyelids flutter.</context>
      <utterance>Even if we could, and the move didn't kill him, there'd be very little we could do there that we can't do here.  I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke rushes to Harry's side and takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Did you... did you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you... did you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you fix the damn film? It broke in the last reel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Everyone went home. We offered them refunds.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Vultures...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not happy about this, mind you, but if I have to go, at least I'm going in my own bed, the same bed my Lily died in, and... knowing that my son is alive. That's not too shabby, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going anywhere, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry smiles. Luke kisses his hand and leans up, whispering in Harry's ear:</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me, I know about these things. I've seen it before. It's all right. It's... all right. You're here. Oh, God, I love you, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry smiles faintly, looks at Luke. He nods, then closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>And I love you... Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone bows their heads.</context>
      <utterance>We commit to the earth the mortal remains of Harry Bernard Trumbo, safe in the knowledge that his immortal soul is at peace and at last reunited with his beloved Lillian in the bosom of the Lord. Let us pray.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks up at the sky, then steps forward and lays a single rose on Harry's casket. Then, as everyone surreptitiously watches, he turns and walks away from the gravesite, toward the cemetery entrance. Adele watches Luke depart...</context>
      <utterance>"The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want, he maketh me to lie down in green pastures..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ADELE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Luke looks up, squinting. Adele stands above him, backlit by the golden light of the sundown.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits next to him. Tentatively, she touches his shoulder. He leans into her, and she enfolds her arm in his. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Adele feels as though she's walking on eggshells.</context>
      <utterance>Your father said... that I would start to remember things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... do you remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... everything. It started coming back a couple of days ago. I remember everything now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes. All her suspicions are suddenly confirmed.</context>
      <utterance>Delly. I'm... I'm not... Harry wasn't my father. And I'm not... I'm not Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her tears start, and she moves to hug Luke -- but instead, she starts hitting him, flailing, beating on his chest. He hugs her tightly, and she completely lets go.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, god, I knew! I knew! I knew from the start! I wanted you to be Luke! I wanted you to be alive! You're so much like him, you have no idea. No wonder everyone else accepted you! You don't know what you -- what Luke meant to this town, suddenly being alive! You don't know what this town lost! You just don't know... She pulls away, stands, and looks him in the eye. Luke rises.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke moves toward her. She backs away.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you weren't Luke! And I tried not to fall in love with you! And... I don't even know your name! Oh, god...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's still sobbing. He moves to her, takes her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I fell in love with you, too, Delly. Only now I don't know how I feel, about you or about anything. I only think I know how Luke would feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delly, shhhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs off, crying...</context>
      <utterance>No... I can't... I have to... I can't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the sheriff?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I got the uniform to prove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They flash identification, which Eldridge notes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Special Agent Walter Saunders, this is Special Agent Steven Brett, FBI. May we have a word with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit across from Eldridge. As Saunders speaks, Agent Brett pulls a photo from his coat pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Please, sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple of days ago, a county flood control maintenance crew pulled a car out of the Lawson Wash ocean outlet. They checked its registration, and when the owner was identified, they notified us. Agent Brett slides the photo toward Eldridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that'd be Luke Trumbo. Looks like you boys've solved a little mystery we've had going on for a few months.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, that's a photo of man named Peter Appleton. He's been missing from Los Angeles for close to three months now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No, there's got to be a...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff -- this man is a suspected communist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eldridge glances at Agent Saunders, who stares at Pete impassively.</context>
      <utterance>Am I under arrest?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no, but these gentlemen would like to get some answers...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what else to tell you. I wasn't hiding out. I hit my head and I didn't remember anything until a few days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that you remember who you are, were you planning on telling anyone your true identity?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My girlfriend. If she still is...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would that be Miss Sinclair?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Saunders glances at Eldridge.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, not Miss Sinclair. I'm talking about Adele Lardner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>The doctor's daughter. She was Luke Trumbo's sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, I have reason to believe you're holding something back, and that just rubs me the wrong way.  Sir, are you a communist?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. All right. We'll see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE AUDITORIUM.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at his watch, then turns to Old Tim and Mrs. Terwilliger:</context>
      <utterance>Every seat is empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mrs. Terwilliger and Old Tim silently shamble off, Pete goes over and flips OFF several light switches. Most of the theater goes dark.</context>
      <utterance>Let's close up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele climbs onto the roof, comes over and sits down next to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure a lot of people down in L.A. are worried sick about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I'm sure a lot more people down in L.A. want a piece of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Luke was a pretty good guy, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Yes, he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... let me tell you, I'm not Luke. I know who I am now, and you don't. And... I don't like me very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's going to take me a while to get used to calling you Pete.  Pete. Pete. It's a nice name.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, I like it. I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete can't believe he just said that -- but he did.</context>
      <utterance>Delly, I want to do the right thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth is, I'm a lot of things, but communist isn't one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you only went to one meeting, why does anyone care? Besides, why should it even matter if you were a communist?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Delly, look at the country today. We're fighting communists in Korea, we're paranoid about the Russians, we've got this thing with the Rosenbergs and the atomic bomb...  You think they want "suspected communists" entertaining the American public with party propaganda like, gosh I don't know, "Sand Pirates of the Sahara?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Forget about all that. You want to do the right thing? Then defend your name. If someone says something about you that's untrue, you have to stand up and say so. I know the law, and the law's on your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you, Delly?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete smiles and puts his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>I am, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll stand by me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss, and we</context>
      <utterance>Whatever happens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here with Mabel Lanier, the owner of the diner here on Commerce Street where Appleton often took meals. Mrs. Lanier, tell me, what are your thoughts about having such a celebrated suspected communist in your midst all this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, its kinds hard to believe, 'cause Luke -- I mean Peter -- is such a... I mean, since he's been back, I've never seen the town so happy and all. It's like he gave us some... I don't know... some hope, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What she's referring to folks, is yet another bizarre twist in this story. Not only is Appleton alive, but he's been suffering from amnesia and living here in Lawson, where, due to a startling resemblance, everyone in town for the last three months has taken him for one of Lawson's dead war heroes, Albert Trumbo...</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mabel glances at Bob, who lowers his head.</context>
      <utterance>Luke. We always called him Luke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The FBI can't arrest you, because you haven't done anything wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a relief. I understand they usually don't let that stop them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However... you're gonna be subpoenaed to testify before the Un-American Activities Committee when they open hearings in Los Angeles. Now, if you play ball and tell them what they want to hear, they'll clear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I won't be a communist anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo stands and walks to the window.</context>
      <utterance>So it doesn't make any difference that I'm not one now, and have never been one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, don't get philosophical with me. This is a game, but it's not your game. You play by their rules, or they'll ruin you. And they have the power to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo turns to her and smiles. His tone is charmingly matter- of-factly, not condescending in the least.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't it bother anyone that this is a perversion of democracy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo takes out a cigarette, lights it.</context>
      <utterance>Darling, don't kid yourself. We don't have a "democracy" in this country. The Declaration of Independence? The Constitution? These are pieces of paper with signatures on 'em. And you know what a piece of paper with a signature is? It's a contract. And you know what a contract is? Something that can be re-negotiated at any time. It just so happens that the House Un-American Activities Committee is re- negotiating the contract this time around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time, it might be the FBI. The time after that, it might be the President. But it'll always be someone. Count on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the country Luke fought for.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lest we forget, Peter, your own military career was somewhat less illustrious than Luke's.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's wrong, Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo pulls a folded paper from his coat pocket and hands it to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Peter, don't let that stop you all of a sudden.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a knock at the door. Leo opens it. Standing there is a small MAN wearing a serious suit and an even more serious fedora.</context>
      <utterance>Here. When you're called, read this to them. Just tell the bastards what they want to hear, and we can all get on with our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter Appleton?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man reaches into his breast pocket and withdraws a blue backed folded document, which he hands to Pete. As he does, a FLASH lights the room. At the door, a pair of PHOTOGRAPHERS and a NEWSREEL CAMERAMAN are jockeying for position. Pete rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You found him.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete takes the subpoena. There's an awkward moment, as the newsreel camera is still rolling. Pete cradles the subpoena like an Oscar statuette and smiles into the lens.</context>
      <utterance>Peter Appleton, you are hereby subpoenaed to appear as a witness before a special session of the House Committee on Un-American Activities. You are to appear in Los Angeles, California, at the Biltmore Hotel, at the date and time specified herein.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a great honor. I'll treasure this always. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I, Peter Appleton, do hereby renounce my membership in the American Communist Party, and by way of purging myself of my indiscretion, wish to provide the following names of fellow members to this committee, so that those persons may have the opportunity to do as I have done..." He scans down the page. It's a long list.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He HEARS a "meow!" And turns to look.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, Old Tim appears in the doorway, wringing his knit cap in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Old Tim?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I... Can I t-t-talk to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete stands, gestures Old Tim to the chair, as he sits on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Come on in. I was just packing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll come back, you know. They'll all c-c-come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The customers? I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete turns to Old Tim, fixes him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>They will. They w-w-will.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tim, I have to tell you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause, as Pete gathers courage and tries to find the words.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm... I'm not Luke. Luke is dead. He died in the war. He's not coming back, and I'm not him. I don't even belong here. This whole thing started out as an accident, and that's all it is. An accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>My name isn't Luke. It's Peter. Peter Appleton. Old Tim stands and looks askance at Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you think I didn't kn-kn-know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans down to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>I know more than you give me c-c- credit, that's for sure. Don't you see, it don't m-m-matter who you are? All that matters is what you g-g-gave us. And you can't take that away now. You're wrong, Peter Appleton. You do belong here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Tim straightens up, nods at Pete. Then, silently, he picks up Cat and exits.</context>
      <utterance>You hafta give us back the B-B- Bijou.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Except a chance in hell of coming out of this intact.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be fine. No matter what Leo Kubelsky says, you've got a hundred and seventy-five years of American law on your side. Don't forget that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you were coming with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terwilliger?</context>
      <utterance>And who's gonna run the projector until you get back? Mrs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile as the train's HORN blows.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we could train Cat to run the projector. You know, a system of scratching posts, and gears, and levers...</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete picks up his suitcase and they walk toward the passenger compartment.</context>
      <utterance>Board!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring along something to read?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele pulls a pocket-sized leather-bound book out of her purse and hands it to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Damn...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think so. Here. This is mine, you can borrow it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNOTATED EDITION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete looks at the book, then at Adele.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly light reading, I know. Believe it or not, I've read this since high school, and it got me all the way through law school. Besides, there's something in there that'll help you. You won't have to get very far, it's near the beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delly... thanks, thank you. I'll take good care of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just remember two things. First, the law is a living thing. It made us free and it keeps us free. Sometimes it gets twisted around by people for their own purposes. Sometimes it makes mistakes, sometimes big mistakes. But in the end, the law prevails for the just. Sometimes, it takes a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks for a moment. She needs the right words.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. What's the second thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The train pulls out. Adele and Pete exchange waves as we</context>
      <utterance>I'll be here... if you come back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's perfect, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Lardner forces a smile at Mrs. Terwilliger and Old Tim.</context>
      <utterance>The committee and the chamber will come to order.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This television's a grand little invention, isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Doyle scans the room. He clearly means business.</context>
      <utterance>The agenda for this morning's special session of the House Committee on Un-American Activities shows a number of witnesses, and I'd like to admonish those that are here to view the testimony of our first witness to keep order at all times, or this chamber will be closed. I'm referring especially to the ladies and gentlemen of the press. I hope that's clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes and cameras swing toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Call Peter Appleton.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete does as instructed.</context>
      <utterance>The witness will please stand and raise his right hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you swear that the testimony you are about to give before this committee of the United States House of Representatives will be the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth, so help you god?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be seated and state your full name and place of residence for the record.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter Kenneth Appleton. Hollywood, California.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chair notes that you are appearing without the benefit of counsel today, Mr. Appleton. We certainly hope this means that you intend to be fully forthcoming with this committee?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do my best, Mr. Chairman.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, we're informed that you have a statement you'd like to read, is that correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle and Clyde exchange glances.</context>
      <utterance>A statement?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. A prepared statement.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete turns in his chair and winks at Leo. Leo rolls his eyes and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Um... no. I don't have a statement at this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TERWILLIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's doing very well, so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They haven't called out the dogs yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>The TV shot swings to see Elvin Clyde. He puts on his glasses and fixes Pete with an oily grin.</context>
      <utterance>Very well then, the questions will be asked by the Majority Counsel, Mr. Clyde.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I spoke too soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Mr. Chairman, and thank you Mr. Appleton, for appearing today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, you mention that your home is Hollywood, California. But isn't it true that for the last several months, you've made your home in a town called Lawson, California?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, that is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, do you know an "Albert Lucas Trumbo?"</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke Trumbo? We never met. But I'd like to think I know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that because you were masquerading as Luke Trumbo while you were in Lawson?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Clyde you're twisting things around. I wasn't masquerading. Luke Trumbo... Luke was a good man who gave his life for his country. I just... happen to look a little bit like him. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I see that Private Trumbo was reported missing in action and is presumed dead. I also see that you were posted stateside during the war. Fort Dix?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few spectators titter.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure we're all glad to see you came through it all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, I see that you've been running a movie theater in Lawson called "The Bijou," is that also true?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. But I didn't go to Lawson to run The Bijou, that was... that was something that just happened. You see, I was involved in an accident in Lawson, and I spent some time recovering there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone who reads the newspaper is quite familiar with your... "accident," Mr. Appleton. An accident which, conveniently, came hard upon your dismissal from United Pictures. Tell us, this "accident" of yours, are we given to understand that it affected your memory?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Pete smiles.</context>
      <utterance>And what is the state of your memory now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience LAUGHS. Clyde nods at Pete, forces a tight smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, what was the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Appleton?</context>
      <utterance>We... appreciate... your little note of levity, Mr. Appleton, but this is a very serious matter, and it merits your fullest attention.  That state of your memory now, Mr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm interested in knowing if you remember things you did in your past, or if they've been conveniently "blotted out" as a result of your "accident."</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Clyde, I remember everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete looks on the table and finds the roster. He's surprised to see it.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Good.  Now, I hold in my hand a photostatic copy of the attendance roster for the "Bread Instead of Bullets Club" of the University of California, Los Angeles, dated October 11, 1935. A copy of this paper is before you, Mr. Appleton. Do you recognize it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Referring to line thirty-seven of the document, does your printed name and signature appear there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, please tell this committee what was the nature and purpose of the "Bread Instead of Bullets Club?"</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Clyde, do you want to know what I knew then, or do you want to know what I know now? They're two different things?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start with what you knew then.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd direct the attention of counsel and committee to line thirty-six of the document, and the name printed and signed there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see it. For the record, it reads "Lucille Angstrom." What's the point of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's what I knew then. Or who I knew, I should say. You see, I was trying to court Miss Angstrom. I went to the meeting to impress her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you asking this committee to believe that you attended a meeting of a communist party front organization in order to impress a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience LAUGHS. Doyle BANGS his gavel.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if you'd seen Miss Angstrom...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience LAUGHS. Clyde shoots a look at Doyle, who BANGS his gavel.</context>
      <utterance>You asked for the truth. That's the truth. I had no idea what the meeting was about. I just sat through it so I could be near her. I'm sure even a Majority Counsel like yourself is familiar with the concept of impressing a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clyde shuffles some papers and looks back at Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Chamber will come to order.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Mr. Appleton. That was what you knew then. What do you know now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I know that I lost my job because of one meeting I went to when I was a kid in college. I know that I've been branded a communist, which I'm not, but even if I was, it shouldn't matter, or what do we have a Bill Of Rights for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few members of the audience APPLAUD. As Pete speaks, their numbers grow.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Chairman, the witness is being non-responsive...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle BANGS his gavel several times. Pete stops and the room falls quiet.</context>
      <utterance>I know that a lot of good, honest, decent people, people that I consider my true friends, feel betrayed by me, not because of who and what I am, but because of what you say I am! I know that I...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, you will respond to the questions of this committee without elaboration or speechmaking, or the chair will find you in Contempt Of Congress. You will not be warned again, is that clear?  Continue, Mr. Clyde.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clyde takes a long pause for effect, then looks up at Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you now, or have you ever been, a member of the communist party?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you refuting this evidence and your previous testimony?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not refuting anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet you're contradicting yourself. You earlier testified that you attended a meeting of a communist party-run organization, yet you just said, under oath, that you were not now -- nor ever -- a member of the communist party.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not a contradiction at all, sir. I went to the meeting, but I didn't go as a member.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Pete smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, as what did you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little hesitant to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete shifts in his chair, then leans into the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>The witness need not be hesitant to say anything before this committee, as long as it's the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chamber erupts in LAUGHTER. Even the other COMMITTEE MEMBERS are laughing, except Clyde and Doyle, who BANGS his gavel vigorously.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I went as... a horny young man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, you are making light of a legally constituted committee of the United States Congress. Believe you me, you do not want to incur our wrath.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, I have no intention of making light of this committee. And I have no intention of incurring your wrath, Mr. Chairman. I have a few friends who have already incurred your wrath. They've sent me letters from jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Chairman! Mr. Chairman, the witness is making another speech. I would ask that Mr. Appleton be admonished...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, there is no question before you at this time, but I'm sure Mr. Clyde has plenty more prepared, and if you'd like to either answer them or plead the Fifth Amendment, we can at least get on with the business of this committee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them Pete. Tell them...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Clyde working for you.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Chairman, as I understand it, the Fifth Amendment pertains to self-incrimination, and I can't incriminate myself because I've done nothing wrong. Besides, incrimination is why you have Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Chairman...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete's sweating under the lights. He's bluffed his last bluff, and he's on the ropes. He reaches into his pocket... and takes out the prepared statement.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, Mr. Appleton, just what is your intention?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her hand goes to her mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Pete. No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, Mr. Appleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I, Peter Appleton, do hereby..." He stops suddenly. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton? Mr. Appleton?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I need a drink of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete fills a glass from the pitcher. Nervously, he spills a bit, and is splashes onto his coat. As some of the spectators chuckle, Pete brushes the water off. He reaches into his pocket, and pulls out Adele's copy of the constitution. The cover is wet. He wipes it off and sets it down on the table. He takes a sip of water. Looks at the book. Picks it up. Pete's terrified, but in control. He speaks slowly -- he's making this up and thinking it out as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Chairman... there's... another Amendment... that I'd like to invoke at this time, but it's not the Fifth Amendment. I wonder if you're familiar with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the book and reads, tentatively at first.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Appleton, you will...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances." Pause. Silence in the room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pin-drop silence in the room. Pete scans the faces of the panel. All betray anger.</context>
      <utterance>That's the First Amendment, Mr. Chairman. It's the backbone of this nation. It's everything that gives us the potential to be right and good and just -- if only we'd live up to that potential. It's what gives me the right to sit in this chair and say my piece before this committee without fear. It's the most important part of the contract that every citizen has with this country. And even though this contract...  ... the Constitution and the Bill of Rights -- even though they're just pieces of paper with signatures on them -- they're the only contracts we have that are most definitely not subject to renegotiation. Not by you, Mr. Chairman, not by you, Mr. Clyde, not by any member of this committee -- or anyone else -- ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Pete closes the book, picks up the prepared statement, rips it up, pushes back his chair, stands and walks toward the door. The cameras swing with him, and FLASHBULBS fire like machine guns. Doyle BANGS his gavel insistently.</context>
      <utterance>And when you get right down to it, that's really all I have to say to this committee. Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then, slowly, APPLAUSE builds in the chamber, reaching a crescendo as Pete reaches the door and exits.</context>
      <utterance>The witness will resume his seat! Did you hear me?! You are not excused, Mr. Appleton!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Chairman! Mr. Chairman...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FIRST REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete! Are you going back to writing pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a commie, Pete?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, of course not...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the girl, Pete? You gonna marry her? Is she coming to Hollywood, or are you...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete is trapped in the crowd, when he feels a hand on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Look, fellas, I don't have anything to say...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was quite a show you gave them today. We shoulda sold tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sorry for what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit in silence again for a moment until Leo reaches into his pocket and withdraws a gold cigarette case, which he opens and offers to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>No, of course not, why should you be sorry? You're the new Peter Appleton. You exercised your rights as a solid citizen, first amendment, freedom of speech, all that. Very noble.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo takes one for himself and lights up. Pete takes off his hat and nervously scratches his head.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd you quit smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke didn't smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see. But you're not Luke. You're Peter Appleton, the picture writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo, you were in there, you saw what I did. You think they're gonna let me write pictures? Hell, they're probably gonna throw my ass in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, I don't even know if I want to write anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before Pete can answer...</context>
      <utterance>What, you're going to go back to that hick town and run the projector and marry the doctor's daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, I'm an agent. I buy lunches and get deals made for guys like you. That's what I do. You're a writer. You write pictures. That's what you do. And trust me, you'll be back doing it again tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, you gave them what they wanted. This committee, it feeds on names. The more names, the better. But for some high-profile witnesses, like yourself, any name will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo, I didn't give them the names. I wouldn't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete freezes. He slowly turns to Leo.</context>
      <utterance>What, all of a sudden, "Lucille Angstrom" isn't a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name was right there in front of them. They gave it to me, I didn't give it to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's not what they think.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo, she was... she was a girl I knew in college...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should keep track of your old school chums. Turns out she eventually joined the communist party.  On top of which, she's Lucy Angstrom Hirschfeld now, and she happens to be a writer for "Studio One" on CBS.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, oh, god, no, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, our lawyers had a talk with the Committee's lawyers. That Elvin Clyde fella won't be too happy about it, but we cut a deal. They cleared you -- and they're gonna thank you publicly for your testimony purging yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank me publicly? For what? For ruining this woman's life?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete is dumbstruck. He slumps in his seat, ashen.</context>
      <utterance>Climb down off your cross. They already knew about her.  She was subpoenaed six months ago! Who the hell do you think named you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete's breathing shallowly, on the verge of tears or screaming -- or both.</context>
      <utterance>All of which means... "Ashes To Ashes" is gonna be made, and you've got your job back.  Congratulations, kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete comes back and takes his hat. Leo grabs his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Peter! Your hat!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the limo pulls away, we</context>
      <utterance>I was lookin' out for you all the time, kid. You did good. I'm real proud of you.  Okay, let's go.  Get some rest, kid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Super moves to the door and turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a new key for ya. That Mr. Kubelsky, he's got you paid up through this month. You got one swell friend there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits as Pete reaches into one of the boxes and pulls out the tin-toy fire truck. Distractedly, Pete puts the toy back in the box and replies too late:</context>
      <utterance>Good to have you back, Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets his suitcase down and takes off his coat. As he does, Adele's copy of the Constitution slips out of his coat pocket and falls open to the floor. Pete picks it up and absently turns it over -- and the inscription inside the front cover catches his eye:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mabel's mouth drops open.</context>
      <utterance>Luke... um, I mean, Pete, if it weren't for you, I wouldn't have had the nerve to ask this fine woman to marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob, congratulations! When'd you ask her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mabel kisses Bob for all she's worth, Pete continues into the crowd, where he's kissed, embraced, patted on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Holy moley! Just now!  Yes, Bob! Yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you got the telegram.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete, I'm so sorry about what they did to you. I didn't think you'd come back, I thought you'd want to write again...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dell, I can't write unless I'm happy, and I can't be happy unless I'm here -- and with you.  This is me, Delly. Pete Appleton. And I love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss again. Pete pulls away and looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>And  I love you, Pete!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Dell, we gotta go. Showtime in fifteen minutes. The train whistle BLOWS as it slowly pulls out of the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE'S NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We BOOM UP to see Pete and Adele moving into and being enveloped by the crowd. Spencer Wyatt's band is assembled in front of the depot office, and they kick into some up-tempo boogie-woogie as we move up and away -- still in the same shot -- moving over the town, settling down again to grab a shot of the Bijou's marquee. The neon chaser lights POP ON, illuminating the sign, which reads:</context>
      <utterance>"Happily ever after" is a relative term, folks. My world is much smaller now, and my dreams are very different than they were. But I have something now that I never had before: I have the magic. And it's for sale at the Bijou, every day of the year. All you need is the price of a ticket.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
