<movie id="139" title="Cooler The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FIGURE/BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DORIS THE BARTENDER wanders over with a small container. She starts to pour... Empty. We quickly STEADICAM AROUND to reveal BERNIE LOOTZ's features for the first time. His sad sack eyes register scant surprise at the empty cream container.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Doris, you got any cream?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's just about to leave, when an attractive COCKTAIL WAITRESS cruises up. NATALIE BELISARIO -- late 20's-mid-30's. Everything about her sparkles, except her eyes. They're post-mortem. She appears frazzled. Sifts through some coin tips.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sheepish look comes over Bernie. He tries to catch her eye. She doesn't even glance at him.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.  Dewars and a Diet Coke. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. Only the faintest hint of recognition.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Bernie.  Hey, you seen Shelly around? He promised to position me at the tables tonight. I've been on skid row all week.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't settle me from last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doris mutters something under her breath -- heard that one before -- and dumps Natalie's drinks on her tray.</context>
      <utterance>No? You sure? Fuck... And I was way under. It's been, like, an A.A. convention the whole week. I'll make up for it tonight. Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie grabs up her tray. Doesn't even look at Bernie.</context>
      <utterance>If I see Shelly, I'll let him know. That you're looking for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch. That's the third time this month...  Let me get you that cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises the empty cream container for effect, turns it over. A few drops dribble out.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get sweet on that, Bernie. Not unless you're looking to get short- changed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FLOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bernie, Shelly needs you on eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie just smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Joe said I should stick around. You say something to Shelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She offers up a smile. It jump-starts those dormant eyes. Her whole face comes alive. Notches her up from an eight to a ten. Bernie immediately glances away. He's afraid what she might read in his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. That was fast. Hey, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie gestures her over to table eleven. Immediately makes the HIGH ROLLER in question. A good old boy named BULLDOG. He's the one boasting loudly as he shakes the dice with one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULLDOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie grabs the drink from Natalie's tray, intentionally bumps Bulldog...</context>
      <utterance>I'll make you a fortune on five and nine. C'mon forty-five-sixty-three fifty-four!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, buddy, is this your drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULLDOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another man gladly accepts the drink. Meanwhile, Bulldog sends the dice high up into the air. They drop perfectly on the table. The stickman calls it.</context>
      <utterance>Back off, pal. I'm on a roll here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BULLDOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother-fucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The croupiers hungrily devour the chips from the table. Bernie moves on quietly before anyone notices. But he's been noticed all right. By Natalie. Not quite sure what she's just witnessed. Who is this guy? We hear a VOICE over the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for those bets, folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bernie reacts immediately to the code words over the speaker.</context>
      <utterance>Conway, party of twelve, please check your reservation at the Paradise Lounge.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, I'm comin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky reaches out to shake Shelly's hand. Gets nothing back, then remembers.</context>
      <utterance>Nicky, how the hell are you? I didn't know you were coming in...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky grabs Shelly, embraces him.</context>
      <utterance>Whassimater? You think I don't wash up after goin' to the John? Forget about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shoulda called ahead. I woulda sent a car...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ehh. We thought we'd surprise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly sizes up the corporate types.</context>
      <utterance>Well, anytime, Nicky. Anytime.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly sees where this is going. Larry extends his hand...</context>
      <utterance>Shelly, I want you to meet one of our smartest VPs, Larry Sokolov. And his numbers guy, Marty Goldfarb.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...then catches himself. Quickly pulls it back. Shelly stares him down for a tense beat.</context>
      <utterance>How do you do, Shelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off their uncomfortable expressions...</context>
      <utterance>What can I get you boys to drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks cautiously across the table.</context>
      <utterance>So... what brings you to town, Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Shelly, this is your joint, you run it the way you see fit. But we got a smart kid here and he's got some good ideas on how to revitalize the Shangri-la.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky shoots a look over at Larry and Marty. Larry takes this as his cue.</context>
      <utterance>Revitalize? What are you talking about? We did thirty-five million last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First off, Shelly, I want you to know, I have nothing but respect for you. You've done a fantastic job with the Shangri-la for the last sixteen years. No one would dispute that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly nods carefully. But...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no one doubts that, Shelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, the business has changed out here. You just have to take a look at the Strip to see what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky and Larry exchange looks. Marty drops his gaze into his lap.</context>
      <utterance>You mean, that amusement park mook fest out there? You know what that is? That's a fucking violation of something that used to be beautiful. That used to have class. Like a gorgeous high priced hooker with an exclusive clientele. And then that Steve Wynn cocksucker knocks her up and puts her in a family way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now she's nothing but a cheap, fat whore hiding behind too much makeup. I look at her and see all those ugly stretch marks and I want to cry. 'Cause I remember her as she was.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well... there's no denying the bottom line. Those eyesores are raking it in. And we can't compete against that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You think I'm trying to compete with that? You think this joint's about bringing in the stroller crowd? Fresh off some fucking E-ticket ride, looking to break the house on red and black. Fremont's never been about that bullshit. This is where old time and real money comes to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly is close to losing it. He catches himself, takes a breath.</context>
      <utterance>The numbers, they don't back you up, Shelly. Nostalgia's grand. We all love nostalgia -- but it belongs in a museum. I think it's time to decide whether you're running a museum or a casino.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, forget about it. We'll talk later. Over dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry shoots him a disapproving look. Off Shelly's disturbed expression. He's already calculating serious damage control.</context>
      <utterance>So, how's the action?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie. Mr. Cool. Got a moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just heading over to --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly escorts Bernie over to a nearby bar area. The BARTENDER zips over with some drinks.</context>
      <utterance>It can wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shrugs. Natalie steps up to the bar a few feet away. Puts in a drink order. She catches Bernie's eye. Nods. Bernie smiles.</context>
      <utterance>How's the knee?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was speaking to this orthopedic surgeon over at Vegas Memorial. He tells me they can replace a man's entire kneecap with titanium. It's the kinda thing that costs a shitload, but since the man's into us for five hundred large, I'm sure we could --</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm not gonna be around after Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you gonna go, Bernie? Where the fuck are you gonna go that's better'n here? I got you covered in this town. People, they know you work for me, that's currency in your pocket. That's fuckin' respect when you walk the floor. Where you gonna get that anyplace else?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hooker just nods.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. I like to know who's shopping it in my neighborhood. You wanna keep working the Shangri-la, you come see me tomorrow morning in my office. We'll go over the rules together. And before you come, you bring me a clean bill of health. OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off. At the same time Natalie leaves with her drink order. They walk in the same direction. Shelly mistakes Bernie's wandering look for interest in the hooker.</context>
      <utterance>All right, get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie just stares after Natalie, Shelly finally picking up on it.</context>
      <utterance>You want that, Bernie? She's yours. Anytime. I'll keep a tab running for you.  What's a matter? Not your type?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He limps off. Shelly stares after him. A predator seizing up his prey. Calculating.</context>
      <utterance>Things are getting hot on fourteen. I gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinkerton reaches for the drink without taking his eyes off the table. He throws a hard six. The crowd cheers again. He turns around, stuffs a hundred dollar chip down her shirt and slyly cops a feel.</context>
      <utterance>Seven and Seven?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie shudders in disgust. She spins around to leave... runs smack into Bernie, spilling her tray of drinks on him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, dollface.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie wipes himself off, helps her pick up the pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit... Sorry... I'm such a klutz.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie tries to wipe him down a bit more.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. Happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, this guy... fuckin' hands, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie wiggles his way next to Pinkerton. He gives the stickman a certain look.</context>
      <utterance>S'okay. You might want to stick around.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Pinkerton. You have no hard eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie just watches as Pinkerton throws the dice.</context>
      <utterance>Gimmie a hundred dollar hard eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players go nuts. The stickman taps the felt in front of the shooter.</context>
      <utterance>Eight the hard way!</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine hundred dollars to Mr. Pinkerton.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boxman seated at the center looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Parlay! Parlay!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boxman feigns concern, then nods in approval.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. You can take that action.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as the stickman feeds Pinkerton the dice, Bernie flips a dollar chip over toward the center of the table. Natalie peers between them to catch a glimpse.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm talking about. None of this low limit bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chip lands on Pinkerton's parlayed bet. He releases the dice from his stubby little fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Dollar hard eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players cry out in defeat. Pinkerton grumbles to himself. He fingers his rail of chips.</context>
      <utterance>Eight easy! Easy eight! Hard eight comes down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws in the chips. The croupier places his bets. The dice are fed back to him. He throws.</context>
      <utterance>Five hundred dollar hard eight. And press my nine up two units.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinkerton is fit to be tied. After a passing moment of clarity he empties his entire rail.</context>
      <utterance>Easy way eight! Eight easy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire table stops down for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Hard eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Pinkerton sets his dice carefully and lets them fly.</context>
      <utterance>Way to go, Pinkie! Bet the farm.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinkerton slams his fist down on the table. He turns to leave the table to find Natalie smiling at him.</context>
      <utterance>Seven out!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKERTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinkerton starts to lose it. Security moves in, right on time. Natalie shoots Bernie a satisfied look. He averts his eyes shyly and limps away. She stares after him for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck you smiling at, bitch?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly. I was a goddamn embarrassment tonight. I shouldn'a let you talk me into going on.  It's definitely strep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly throws a pair of red silk panties to Buddy. We see a room number scribbled on the crotch area.</context>
      <utterance>You were velvet out there, pops. Silk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were hanging on the door outside. Forget your tonsils. When the muff confetti stops coming, that's when you got yourself a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get a receipt?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charmayne's in the lobby. They got these on sale in the window. Victoria Secret's Valentine's Collection. And the broad waiting in the room, what she set you back? Always Grade-A for Ol' Buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly feigns as if he's leaving.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding me? Gimme that.  You don't fucking deserve this. All those ladies going home with a sweet breeze between their legs because you still do it for them and you're fingering me for some kinda Buddy Stafford ego pimp. Hey, fuck you, old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Whassimatter, kid? You got that Nostradamus look.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever watch those nature shows on</utterance>
   <speaker>TV?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen this one a dozen times. It's about lions. Cycle of life thing. The leader of the pack...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pride. It's called a pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, pride. The leader of the pride... when he gets on in years. It's just a matter of time before some young male arrives on the scene to challenge him. They go at it and the old cat gets the crap beaten outta him. It's humiliating. In front of all the females, this goes down. And after he's defeated, he's cast out of the pride, to scavenge and die alone in the bush.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, nature's got a real sick sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit. It's fucking tragic because the old lion can't figure it out on his own. That he's past it. It'd be so much easier for him to just walk away and save himself all that pain and humiliation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's like admitting to yourself that you're already dead. I prefer nature's way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly holds Buddy's gaze in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Me, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly's expression: no. But he heads over anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Shelly, got a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, this is Johnny Capella.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny extends his hand. Shelly ignores the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Shelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you from somewhere, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny's been opening for Danny Ganz at the Mirage. Sony's talking about signing him to a three album deal. They're positioning him as the new Ricki Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I should be interested in this, why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny's looking to headline. I told him we might be interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, if this is a bad time...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if I were interested, Buddy's got ink with us through 2003. I just renegotiated his contract last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny nods at Shelly, takes off. Shelly and Larry eyeball each other for a long, cold beat. Shelly's about to say something, when Nicky and Marty approach. Larry shrugs, flashes a chilling smile.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like the two of you need to get on the same page.  If I don't hear from you by Thursday, I'm taking the Stardust's offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Buddy? I wanna buy the old fart a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddy asked me to send you his regards, Nicky. He's not feeling so great. I think he's got that stomach flu that's going around.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? That's too bad.  Well, another time then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly eyeballs Marty for a tense, extended beat. What do I look like, some fuckin' pimp, college boy? Just as Marty's starting to get real uncomfortable, Shelly cracks a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Shelly, Nicky says you might be able to hook us up with some showgirls. Something with class.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, no problem. You got any preferences?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Something with big headlights, nice rims and low mileage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly looks to Larry.</context>
      <utterance>You got any Asian babes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We linger on Shelly's unsettled look. This guy is bad news.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'll just stick with the tables.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I just know what the outcome's going to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The outcome? There's not, like, one particular outcome. A lot of things enter into it. The planets, moon phases...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The outcome won't change with me. It'll be all bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I have never met anyone who was so down on themselves. I used to be down on myself, OK? I don't go there anymore. I've got just three more correspondence classes with this stuff, then I'll have my certificate and everything. And you know how I got OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had your chart done.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, as a matter of fact that is perfectly correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what I do at the Shangri- la?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked around. You're a "cooler." You turn winners into losers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do you know how I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know there's stuff that goes on in casinos all the time --</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do it by being myself. People get next to me and their luck turns. It's always been that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie maintains eye contact with Natalie for an extended beat. Then drops his head, gazes at his glass.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds to me like a self fulfilling prophecy. There's a whole chapter on that in my course. Anyways, I can see a big factor in your life is that you're lacking companionship. There's nobody to deflect off. If you've got, as you put it, bad karma, then you need someone with good karma to neutralize it. Well, that's my take on it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie nods. Bernie motions to stand. Natalie just remains seated. Keeps talking.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about you, but I'm real tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have this recurring dream where I'm on some beautiful island in the Bahamas. I'm sitting on the beach, taking in this amazing sunset with one of these in my hand  ...and then it starts to rain. And I wake up and it's my roof leaking on me. Yeah, I'm also real tired, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only got six more days. Well, almost five really. Then I'll be leaving town.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie covers Bernie's hand with hers.</context>
      <utterance>Only five more days?  Then we shouldn't waste any more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go back to your place?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie flinches slightly. Then swiftly regains her composure. It's Vegas. An honest mistake.</context>
      <utterance>I, uh... If this is... I don't know... I don't know if I can afford...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god... I'm so sorry... I didn't mean... You see -- that's exactly what I'm talking about. I've gone and "cooled" the damn table.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, just shut up, Bernie. You haven't gone and cooled anything. Not by a long shot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should complain about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here that much. Drink? Sorry, all I got's gin.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie walks over to the dresser, pours himself a shot. Natalie glances around. She notices Bernie's dead plants...</context>
      <utterance>Nah. I've had my fill. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes land on the empty cat bowl. She's about to say something, when she picks up on Bernie's expression. Let's not even go there. She gestures to an old record player in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>You know, once they're dead, they don't really grow back. In case, that's what you're waiting for.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie opens one of the kitchenette cupboards. Bare shelves... except for a lone RECORD up on top. He brings it down. It's a Sinatra album. Never been opened. Natalie looks on as Bernie meticulously removes the record from its sleeve. He blows a few particles of dust from its surface. Then delicately lays it on the turntable. The way he goes about this is incredibly ceremonious. With as much care as given to disarming a nuclear weapon. Natalie can't help but smile. Bernie lowers the needle to the first cut of the record. Everything seems to be going so well, until... SKREEEEEE! The needle skids across the surface of the record with a sound worse than chalk on a blackboard. Bernie opens his mouth in a silent grimace... and a delicious laugh comes out. It's Natalie's laugh. Talk about a tension breaker. Bernie turns to her, shrugs. He tries again. This time the needle catches... and Sinatra takes command of the room. He's singing "This Town," a finger snapping upbeat Valentine to Vegas. Marred only by a slight clicking caused by the scratch. Natalie summons Bernie over with her wagging forefinger. He picks up his glass, shuffles over.</context>
      <utterance>So... got any music?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit. Relax. I promise you, at least one of us has done this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not my first --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts massaging his shoulders, eliciting involuntary moans from him. Bernie is almost in tears. Nobody's touched him like this in years. And it shows. Natalie takes Bernie's glass, gulps down the remains herself, then sets it on the floor. She drops down next to Bernie. Starts kissing him. Takes it slow.</context>
      <utterance>Sssh. Surprise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fall back onto the mattress. Natalie taking the reigns, maneuvering her hips, kicking off her panties... Bernie gets an eyeful of a tattoo on her butt. A pair of dice. Both twos. In seconds, Natalie has separated Bernie from his pants and underwear, taking him inside of her, Ol' Blue Eyes keeping the rhythm... Natalie moans uninhibitedly. Surprise: she's a real screamer. Moments later, we hear banging from the hooker's side of the wall. Some John telling them to keep it down. Bernie, with tears of elation in his eyes, thrusts away at Natalie... for all of thirty seconds, before he explodes, convulsing in her arms with a stifled gasp. Frank winds down "This Town" a few seconds later. Poor Bernie, he didn't even make it through the song.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie wraps her arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie rests his head on her breasts. Closes his eyes. We hold on him. A few seconds pass... and he breaks into a smile. Fade to black.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Bernie. I've had worse. We'll try again later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie just looks up at her; replay on the goofy smile. Heaven.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, so, you wanna get some breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I did six months at Rikers for running numbers. It was Shelly's thing, but I took the rap for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Bernie talks, Natalie spies a very PREGNANT GIRL (20's) coming out of the restroom. Her eyes follow the girl back to a table where a YOUNG MAN (20's) waits on her.</context>
      <utterance>After I get out, I call up Shelly and he tells me to come out here. I figure he's going to set me up good at the Shangri-la. But he tells me they got all these rules about casinos employing felons. So he gets me this gig doing telemarketing for one of their fronts -- trying to scam pensioners out of their retirement money. I lasted two weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(taps his knee)</context>
      <utterance>Already, I was getting in deep. Finally it got so bad, I had to beg Shelly to take on my markers around town. That just bought me more time to keep losing. I put Shelly in an awkward position. I understand why he did what he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did that to you? What, he shot you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baseball bat.  I got off easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's getting off easy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was out of control.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he maimed you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you something. I'm grateful for what he did.  No kidding. Every time I get an urge to play off the clock -- to so much as drop a quarter in a slot -- I reach down and squeeze what's left of my cartilage. It's one helluva reminder.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie holds her gaze her for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus... I thought stuff like that didn't happen no more. Like that was just in the movies or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Natalie can respond, we hear the pregnant girl start to moan out loud. The waitress rushes over.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, Shelly and I worked out a payment plan. Two years off the books at the Shangri-la, cooling tables. Five more days and I walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a quick moment of confusion. Bernie feels a bit thrown by it all.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PREGNANT GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie pulls Mikey aside.</context>
      <utterance>I'm OK now. False alarm. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey? Is that...? You're not the...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what the fuck, it runs. Anyways, we gotta be somewhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your mom doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna pretend like you give a shit and tell you, she's getting by. As long as she's wasted. Bernie nods. He gazes past Mikey to the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Charlene, in case you were wondering. Looks like she's carrying a whole litter in there, don't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlene sidles up alongside Mikey.</context>
      <utterance>When was the last time you saw a doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This clinic in Jersey. Maybe six months ago. I wasn't about to go back after they treated me like cattle. Just because I didn't have no insurance. And those places, they're crawling with T.B. from all 'em spies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're in town...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe a week or so. Got some business to take care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want, stop by the Lucky Star Motel. Give us a chance to catch up. I'm on three to eleven shift at the Shangri-la. I work the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit. Well, how 'bout that? Yeah, maybe I'll do that. We can play catch up. For the kid's sake. Gotta split.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey helps Charlene into the front passenger seat. They drive off. Natalie looks to Bernie. She's curious, but doesn't ask. He appears thankful for that.</context>
      <utterance>Take care.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie sits at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie peels off a hundred from his billfold. Lays it on the felt.</context>
      <utterance>Hundred dollar minimum here, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money plays one hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, pal, but there's twenty other tables. What do you wanna come sit on my head for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanna play one hand. Feeling lucky tonight. I got this voice in my head, says this is the table...</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this is the table. I'm already doing good here. It's my fucking table --</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, heard the one about the fella walks into a bar and says, "Hey, who owns that big great dane outside?" A man at the end of the bar raises his hand. "I do." The fella says, "Yeah? Well, my dog just killed it." The dealer finishes shuffling, begins to deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie starts laughing. The player is less than tickled. Just then the dealer interrupts them.</context>
      <utterance>"Whaddya mean your dog just killed my great dane? What kinda dog you have?" The fella just shrugs and says, "A chihuahua." "You tellin' me your chihuahua just killed my great dane? How?"  "I dunno," the fella says, "I think he got stuck in his throat."</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the dealer's got an ace showing.</context>
      <utterance>Insurance?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The player waves off the insurance, as does Bernie. The dealer checks. Nothing. As the hand plays through the dealer busts out. Bernie glances over at the dealer. What the hell? Bernie places his chips again.</context>
      <utterance>God damnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said, one hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dealer plays. Bernie and the high roller win again. Bernie glances around him uncomfortably. We see Shelly approaching. Shelly just has a nose for when things aren't running smoothly. Larry is lurking behind him. The dealer turns up some cards. And again, Bernie and the high roller win. Bernie looks absolutely perturbed. Shelly gestures something with his head. Bernie cashes out.</context>
      <utterance>Keep going.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie strolls over to Shelly. Shelly guides him away from the table under Larry's watchful eye.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, stick around, pal. You and me, we make a great team.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shrugs, still confused.</context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shakes his head. Larry sidles over.</context>
      <utterance>Well, what fucking gives? Is it McGann? He's been with us twelve years. The man's as standup as my dick.  Maybe he's got money problems. I'm gonna pull him. He wasn't counting 'em, was he? The mook with the streak?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, there's no problem. Fella's on a streak, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me guess? This is one of your "coolers?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you announce it to the whole fucking joint?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, they told me you were a stickler for the old ways. But coolers? What is this guy, some kind of degenerate gambler? Reformed card shark? He doesn't look too effective to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the best. Take it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Whatever. But there ways -- subtle ways -- to keep things in our favor. I'm talking more forward thinking methods.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That right? I suppose you got a whole fucking prospectus on the subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact I do. Like, right off the bat, I can tell you this wallpaper isn't going to cut it. It's too uplifting. I would go with more muted tones.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Wallpaper?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly looks to Bernie. You believe this mook? Larry extracts a CD from his jacket...</context>
      <utterance>And personally, I think the waitresses can all pop another button or two. Myself, I wouldn't hire anything less than a C cup.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly is close to losing it. When MORRIE, the manager of the Paradise, comes running up...</context>
      <utterance>Know what this is? Music to be sure. Pleasant, non-intrusive. But blended in at a subsonic level is a mantra. "Lose... lose... lose." And that's just skimming the surface. We really need to talk, Shelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, you better come quick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a hold of his daughter. Assist her with the arrangements. The Shangri- la will take care of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the Paradise?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She goes dark tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly and Larry exchange looks again. Bernie picks up on it. The tension in the room threatens nuclear fission. A loud ANIMAL ROAR reverberates on the soundtrack... accompanied by jungle-like percussion... as we CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>That won't be necessary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RING TOSS WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie drags Bernie over. She pays her money and the worker hands her the rings. Natalie throws, and misses all eight. The man pats her on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Over here, young lady! C'mon, give it a try. Eight for a dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>RING TOSS WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie is about to take him up on it, when she catches Bernie's eye. His look suggests she's being played for a sucker. She decides against it. They walk off down the midway. Bernie chuckles to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry there, sweetheart. Better luck next time. Wanna try again?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. You're just an easy mark, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An easy mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Easy mark. You never heard that term?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie looks down at her shoulder where the man patted her. She brushes it for effect. Bernie smiles. They take a seat at the end of the midway. Natalie locks onto a little toe-headed BOY being dragged around by his OLDER BROTHER and the brother's FRIEND. The kid has a glazed look in his eyes. Natalie fixates on the boy with a haunted expression. Bernie picks up on it.</context>
      <utterance>When we were kids, Shelly and me, we used to work Coney Island during the summer. When a guy would walk up and seemed eager to open his wallet, we would always mark him with chalk. We'd pat him on the back or arm with the chalk. Like, 'Hey buddy, good job!'  Meanwhile, he had no clue the other guys saw him coming a mile away. Easy mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You notice last night, that tattoo on my butt?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie hides her face behind her soda cup. Looks off in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, two twos. Little Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a son. His name was Joe. I was his mother for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you don't have to tell me this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tears her eyes away from Bernie. Bernie can't believe what he's hearing. That she wants to be invested in him. What could be so bad?</context>
      <utterance>I want to, Bernie. Better you know the worst of me up front. Later, when I'm already invested in you, it'll be too hard to come clean. After I tell you this, you'll probably... I mean, I'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lowers her soda. Turns to Bernie. He studies her for a lengthy beat, stoic features. She wipes away her tears. Oh well, that's that. Bernie stands up. Looks around... focuses on the arcade clock. It reads 1:40 a.m. He turns to her...</context>
      <utterance>I gave my son up for adoption. I just wanted my life back. I was seventeen going on eighteen and I was selfish. My family, they didn't want to have nothing to do with me after that. So I hitched a ride out here. Figured I could make it as a showgirl. Ten years later...  I like to think that if it happened when I was older -- with some guy I cared about -- maybe things would have been different. I think about my Little Joe. And, I do know he's better off. I'm convinced of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Natalie's tear-filled features. She breaks into a laugh- cry...</context>
      <utterance>So, you wanna go try your hand at the dime pitch? It's early still.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the door after her.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go pee. I'm always peeing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told the desk clerk Bernie was my old man. He let us wait inside. That a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie's looking for a parking space.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Natalie? Is he paying you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie doesn't dignify Mikey with an answer. She stares him down unflinchingly. Mikey reaches out to Natalie's ear, "pulls" out a $20 dollar chip.</context>
      <utterance>My old man, is he renting your ass? 'Cause otherwise I just don't get it. A loser like my pops in the company of some primo T &amp; A. It don't compute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the chip down Natalie's cleavage. Natalie still doesn't react. Mikey reaches up, starts caressing her face. She flinches. Right then, the door swings open. Bernie enters. Mikey snaps his fingers and a rose appears in his hand. He extends it to Natalie. She ignores the gesture, steps aside.</context>
      <utterance>This enough to get me a taste? Family discount?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bernie. I told you I was gonna stop by.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlene emerges from the bathroom. Natalie heads over. She doesn't want to be around Mikey. She stops in front of Charlene, points to a sprinkling of white powder on the side of her nose.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I figured you'd call ahead. We were out at breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlene immediately swats the coke off. Natalie enters the bathroom. Closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>You missed some.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie scratches his head, thinks on it for a moment or two. Then heads over to the kitchenette cupboard. Pulls down a coffee can. Extracts a thick wad of bills. Hands them over to Mikey.</context>
      <utterance>You see, the thing is, Bernie, we're kinda strapped. I mean, Charly here's expecting like yesterday, and we don't have the dough to make with the right nutrition for her an' all. So, I was wondering if you would care to invest a little in your grandchild's future... his well being.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's about three grand there. That's all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you, Bernie.  You know, Michael, I -- think we should name her Bernadette. After your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie seems quite moved by it all.</context>
      <utterance>You mean, Bernie. Trust me, it's a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna feel her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think... I don't want anything to hap...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She places Bernie's hand over her stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, I just felt her kick. C'mon, Bernie, gimme your hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey takes Charlene by the arm...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I think so...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlene kisses Bernie on the cheek. He blushes.</context>
      <utterance>We'll catch you later, Bernie. I think I'm gonna take Charly over to the hospital right now. Get her checked up real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care, Pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey turns in the doorway, eyebrows raised. Yeah?</context>
      <utterance>Mikey...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey plays it dumb. Huh?</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to try anything stupid while you're in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey nods, backs out of the room. Charlene giggles. They disappear into the parking lot. Natalie emerges from the bathroom. She lights up a cigarette, just stares at him as if to say: sucker. Bernie shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>You mess up and they'll cut you no slack. That's all I'm saying. You got a kid to think about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, I hope you don't mind...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry we didn't say nothing about this earlier... but the deal wasn't closed yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky gestures to Larry. Larry whisks the plastic sheet off the table... ...to reveal an impressive SCALE MODEL of a redesigned SHANGRI-</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Shelly, you're gonna love it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Shelly's startled expression --</context>
      <utterance>The new Shangri-la Hotel and Casino. We break ground on her in six months.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're thinking? Where's she gonna go? You need space to expand, right? Well, that's been taken care of. We're now the proud owners of The Golden Frontier next door.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's perfect. Three floors of gaming, IMAX theater, entertainment center, boutiques, restaurants, rollercoaster, you name it. She'll pay for herself in three years, and then it's easy money.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly slowly approaches the model like a condemned prisoner mounting the scaffolding. We see his stoic features reflected in her sparkling swimming pool.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't she great, Shell?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In "Lost Horizon," these people, their plane crashes in the Himalayas -- and they get rescued and taken to this Utopia in the mountains. Shangri- la. It's beautiful. The place is completely isolated. Untouched by the outside world. There's no war, no greed, no bullshit... Time is slowed down. People, they don't age. It's... paradise. That's what Shangri- la is. Paradise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly whirls around, yells:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we've all seen the movie. And your point is?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't fuck with paradise! All'a ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jesus, c'mon, Shelly. We're not trying to fuck with it. We're trying to make it better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How... how, Nicky, could it be any better? Right now it's perfect. It's the last of its kind. It's pure... and this.  ...this is just... it's a mockery. An insult. Trying to make something of it that it isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? It's right outta the movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense silence ensues. Nicky, Larry and Marty exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Whose talking about a fuckin' movie? This ain't a fuckin' movie. This is my life. This is my house of worship. You people are shittin' on all that's sacred to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got just one question? Where you gonna be when they decide to change it back? When the people, they come looking for the real Vegas, from before all this Epcott Center bullshit. Who's gonna it give it to them? You guys? I don't think so. You know who? The same fucks who started this shit in the first place. It's all gonna come full circle and bite you in the ass. Mark my words. Shelly falls silent. Massages his forehead. Shit, that wasn't the way to handle it. Nicky gets up from the sofa, walks over to Shelly, places a hand on his shoulder. Shelly flinches, but doesn't pull away.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make some good points, Shelly. Maybe it'll swing back the other way, who knows? But the smart money suggests we roll the dice. I'm not gonna bullshit you; naturally there's gonna be a lot of restructuring in the months to come, but I want you to know, you'll always have a place with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's that? Behind the bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind the bar, that's a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you should take some time and think things through. All this, it's a lot to digest, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly stares right through Marty. Choke and die on it, motherfucker.</context>
      <utterance>Speaking of things to digest, I'm starving. How's that buffet they got in the Valley of the Blue Moon? You recommend their prime rib, Shell?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's food.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly nods at Nicky, then shifts his gaze to Larry. Larry's all smiles. He steps forward to join them, his hand dropping down and caressing the surface of Shelly's desk behind him. A subtle gesture not lost on Shelly. Shelly mentally unloads a full chamber into Larry's chest. Returns the smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, my arteries can use a workout. Lead us to the trough, Shell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait up a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only now do we see Bernie has arrived to cool the table of its hot shooter -- A LOUD, pudgy, overdressed SUBURBANITE. Shelly eyes Bernie.</context>
      <utterance>I thought we were gonna eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we wanna play over there. Less crowded.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly signals Bernie to back off. Bernie steps back. Shelly, Larry and Marty head for the restaurant. Nicky quickly slaps down some green. The stickman slides the dice over to the suburbanite who is shooting. He scuttles the dice. They bounce up over the rail and spike Nicky on the forehead before dropping back on the felt. The players chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, let's play here. This is my lucky table. I always play here.  Go on ahead. I know where to find you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky rubs his forehead, glares at the suburbanite. He fires back.</context>
      <utterance>Out! Seven, line away seven...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky says nothing. The table is quickly cleared by the dealers. The stickman skips the next shooter and feeds the dice to Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>C"mon, pops! What the hell? I coulda paid my mortgage with the money I just lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey? I'm supposed to be next...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suburbanite is still fuming over his loss. Nicky places a couple hundred on the passline.</context>
      <utterance>File a grievance, shithead.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky throws in some chips to the center.</context>
      <utterance>We're coming out. Crap Eleven, any seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suburbanite watches as Nicky runs through a lengthy pre-shot routine. Lots of hand jive and cuff shooting.</context>
      <utterance>Hundred dollar big red.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky throws.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry it up, gramps. Your soup's getting cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The croupiers takes down the pass line.</context>
      <utterance>Crap, Ace Deuce. Line down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky is fed the dice again. Same routine. Nicky just fires an incendiary look back at the suburbanite.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Busketti, maybe you should try shuffleboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky throws.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Palsy? Shake'em this direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players make their bets.</context>
      <utterance>Four, hard four. The point is four.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky slowly starts his routine defiantly.</context>
      <utterance>Good now throw it before you fucking keel over and die, old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky throws.</context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday to me. Happy Birthday to me... Jesus, fuck, I'm another year older already.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky claps his hands dealer style -- for effect -- and with a gentlemanly smile steps back from the table. Nicky's chips are quickly swept up by the croupier.</context>
      <utterance>OUT! Seven! Line away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky locks eyes with the suburbanite. Then flashes a smile that suggests he's going to brush it off. He turns away from the table...</context>
      <utterance>Don't take it so hard, pops. Everybody craps out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBURBANITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky makes like it's all in good jest. Yeah, that's real cute. He heads around the table to the suburbanite, holds out his hand as if to say: Hey, no hard feelings. The suburbanite shrugs. What the fuck? I was just playing with you, pops. He reaches for Nicky's hand... when Nicky suddenly headbutts him. Before anyone can react, Nicky starts laying into the suburbanite. The man goes down and. Nicky continues pummeling him...</context>
      <utterance>Now go change your fucking Depends.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly alerted to the fracas, rushes back to the table. He takes immediate control of the situation. Snaps his fingers at security. The suburbanite is whisked away with a pocketful of comps and a bruised ego. Shelly takes Nicky aside, attempts to calm him. Nicky keeps railing at Shelly:</context>
      <utterance>Who's laughing now, huh? ya fuckin! prick! C'mon, crack wise again... Ya fuckin' smooth as a Ken doll, no- dick, suburbanite scum. How's that for a game?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't right, Shelly! Guy fucks up my game like that. Who the fuck does he think he is?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. He's just a piece of shit. Forget about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky catches himself. He looks at Shelly for a beat. There's an unspoken understanding between them. "The good old days." We see Bernie in the b.g., looking more than a bit shocked.</context>
      <utterance>I thought this joint had more class. Used to be, we wouldn't even let bums like that in...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This town... You know, Natalie, all I want to do is go some place where I can tell day from night. Where they got clocks on the wall. I can't breathe around here no more. Four days and I'm gone. I'm not even sure I can hold out that long.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where does that leave us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A week ago, I didn't remember what it was like to have a woman's hands on me. I'm still pinching myself, expecting to wake-up from...  Come with me, Natalie. I want you to come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, Bernie, that's...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to spring that on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie's look: Why?</context>
      <utterance>Bernie... I want to be with you. I do. But I don't know if I can leave with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was working on a compatibility chart for the two of us. And it looks good, really, it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie's expression: Oh.</context>
      <utterance>That's with us here. In Vegas.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I was being presumptuous, 'cause I knew you were leaving... and I tried working it in different ways... It wasn't good, Bernie. I got scared. But that's just for now, for the immediate future. Once the planets realign, maybe a year from now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A somber mood falls on the table. Bernie reaches for Natalie's hand. Instead, he knocks the salt over. It spills out in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie... I can't... Not another year. Not another week.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think... we probably shouldn't see each other anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Bernie? We only got a couple days left together. Why not make the most of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if I spend one more night in your arms, I'm not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie just stares at her, shrouded in sadness. Natalie stubs out her cigarette, rises.</context>
      <utterance>And that's so bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie casts his eyes to the mound of spilled salt in front of him. Nods. A few beats later he raises his head...</context>
      <utterance>Take care, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gone. A WAITRESS appears.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie, don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get you another?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you better bring me the bottle. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey throws down a bet for the dealer.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mikey. This is our future. Don't blow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stickman thanks him as they place the bet. Mikey throws down more money. We can see Mikey has bets all over the table.</context>
      <utterance>Put this on the line for the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With shoes!</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dealer's got shoes. Hands high, the dice are out! The point is nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As everyone dotes over Charlene, Mikey quickly swaps the dice before anyone can see. He throws.</context>
      <utterance>Come on all you's. Put a good thought in for our baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey is paid nine thousand by the croupier, as is Charlene. Bernie stands frozen. He doesn't bother trying to get any closer to the table. He knows it'll do no good.</context>
      <utterance>Six the hard way!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie looks over at Charlene. Their eyes meet for a second. It's as though Natalie knows it's a scam and Charlene's acknowledging it. Mikey throws again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my god, I just felt him kick! He knows. He knows you're all pulling for him. God bless you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another nine grand. Mikey's rail is nearly full. Charlene hops around awkwardly causing more distraction. Bernie is really sweating it out now. Then Shelly arrives. Larry is hot on his tail.</context>
      <utterance>Six the hard way! Look out, we got a shooter!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly's expression tells us he isn't so sure. Something definitely isn't kosher. As Charlene chatters on, Mikey switches the dice back. Shelly makes him.</context>
      <utterance>Eighteen thousand since I stepped up. I'm sorry, Shelly, I guess I've been hit and miss lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey throws...</context>
      <utterance>Fucking amateurs...</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players and crowd, though disappointed, applaud Mikey's achievement.</context>
      <utterance>Seven out! Line away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey moves his rail of chips to the felt.</context>
      <utterance>I thank you. My wife thanks you. My unborn child thanks you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry notices Shelly slipping on a pair of leather gloves.</context>
      <utterance>Color me up will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've gotta be kidding me.  That's not how I propose we handle it. We'll turn the matter over to the authorities. They'll be blacklisted, their credit ruined...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly walks over to Mikey and Charlene, Larry lingering behind him.</context>
      <utterance>And then we'll give 'em both a lollipop for the ride home. Come watch and learn, Harvard. A little lesson on how to protect your investment -- the old school way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that was some run you had back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey steals a tense glance at Charlene. She starts to fidget nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, thanks. Just lucky I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Security (Tony and Lou) corrals the couple. Leads them away. Bernie watches as they pass by. Mikey looks into Bernie's eyes. They both know he's been made. Natalie doesn't say anything, just looks at Bernie.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go do this in my office? I don't like to hand out all this amount of cash on the floor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie rushes over to Shelly...</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... I can feel the contractions coming on...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, stop them! Don't do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost, Bernie, this got nothing to do with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone stops dead. Freeze frame. Shelly gets a weird look in his eye. A fuse has just been lit...</context>
      <utterance>It's got everything to do with me. He's my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, he's my --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly smashes Mikey across the shoulder with the bat. AARRRGGGGHHH!!! Shelly raises the bat to cream Mikey again... Bernie grabs Shelly's arm. Shelly shoves him back. Raises the bat again...</context>
      <utterance>Who? This little prick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pop, help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly freezes. He lowers the bat, throws it aside. Grabs Bernie by his collar...</context>
      <utterance>Shelly, don't you fucking do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you in on this? Jesus, you better come clean with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly releases Bernie. There's a strange look in Shelly's eye. We see the wheels turning...</context>
      <utterance>NO! God, no! I didn't know nothing about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie sees where Shelly's going with this. We can almost hear the cell door slamming in his head.</context>
      <utterance>How much you think their lives are worth, Bernie? Myself, I don't think they're worth piss. But, hey, it ain't my kid...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie glances over at Natalie. She has tears in her eyes. He looks to Shelly pleadingly. Please don't do this...</context>
      <utterance>Let me see: they were up almost a hundred and fifty grand. That's 150 G's someone's gonna have to account for. What do you say, Bernie, seventy- five grand a piece?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I know you don't have that kind of cash. But, since you're a friend of the house, I'm willing to front you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly glances over at Lou, nods. Lou kicks Mikey in the face. His nose snaps like a twig.</context>
      <utterance>Shelly, they didn't get away with the money... You didn't lose anything...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlene clutches her belly, moans...</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus... Yes! All right. It's on me. 150 G's.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, oh god... you gotta get me to the hospital... contractions...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, please help her. That's my grandson...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, why don't we all break out the champagne? Lootz is about to become a granddaddy.  How you doin' there, sweetheart? Must hurt like crap, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurts so bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Shelly kicks Charlene in the belly! WHAM! She screeches out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even Shelly's goons can't believe what they've just witnessed. Larry is aghast. Bernie rushes Shelly, starts raining blows on him. Shelly swats him off. He drops down next to the squirming girl, rips her sweater and blouse up over her stomach... ...to reveal a mound of fake padding. He tears the padding away from her, throws it at Bernie.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus NOOOOO!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The muscle start laughing it up. Relief. Larry emits a nervous giggle. Natalie's jaw hits the floor. Bernie takes a step back. He's about to go into serious shock. Charlene curls over, sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Here! It's a fuckin' boy. Anyone got a cigar?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie holds his son's gaze for a beat. He's almost tempted to... He just shrugs and nods at Shelly.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make it up to you, Pop, I swear...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?! I thought we had --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie turns her head. She's about to throw up. Larry watches, unflinchingly. Charlene is making with some serious pleading now.</context>
      <utterance>150 G's buys their lives. This is just a little slap on the wrist to remember me by.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly steps up to Charlene, tapping the base of the bat in the palm of his hand. He smiles reassuringly at her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh god... it wasn't my idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, motherhood is a beautiful thing. This... you made a mockery out of it. Maybe you'll get to experience it for real one day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want... to be a mother... please don't hurt me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly turns his back on her. Charlene starts sobbing relief. They're not going to hurt her. It's going to be all right. Wrong. Shelly throws the bat to Lou. The heavy steps up to the plate (as we RACK FOCUS to Shelly walking away) -- CRUNCH!!! followed by the girl's SHRIEKS. Natalie buries her head in Bernie's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get 'em outta here. You ever see them in this joint again, kill 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly catches Larry's eye: I hope you were taking notes.</context>
      <utterance>You two, you're still on shift.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie's hand lowers the needle onto the Sinatra record. "Nice 'n' Easy" starts up. She walks over to Bernie, takes the bottle away. Helps him to his feet. He gives himself over to her reassuring embrace. Natalie raises Bernie's face to her's.</context>
      <utterance>I did this to myself. I planted the seed. When Angela took off with Mikey, I didn't... I never made an effort to get back in his life. I figured, the kid don't need a loser for a father. Now it's all come full circle. I give him the money, I open the door to all this... I musta had it coming. Payback.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shakes his head. It's too late for that now.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie, it's a big world out there. If you just took off -- if we took off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grunts something inaudible.</context>
      <utterance>You awake, Bernie?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie tenses up. Huh?</context>
      <utterance>I -- think I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie raises his head, not quite sure he heard her right. Natalie sits up, hugs her knees. Bernie finds himself staring at her back.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think. I'm pretty certain of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie reaches out, caresses her back. She emits a shiver...</context>
      <utterance>You blind-sided me, Bernie Lootz. I never saw this coming. You shouldn't do that to a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie pulls Natalie back toward him.</context>
      <utterance>There's still things you don't know... should know... I don't want to ruin it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't make any difference, Natalie. Whatever you come clean about, I'm not gonna feel any different about you. I'd say the words, but with my luck...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say 'em anyway. To hell with rotten luck. That's overs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie smothers her lips against Bernie's. He enshrouds her in his arms. Fade out...</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Natalie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cat jumps off his chest and slinks over to her empty food bowl. Meows again. Bernie breaks into a wide smile.</context>
      <utterance>Trixie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shields his eyes from the bright sunlight streaming in through the blinds. Huh? This is a first for him. He's never gotten direct sunlight in his room before. What's the deal? Did the world just turn on its axis? He glances over his shoulder... No Natalie. Just her impression in the sheets. And a note on her pillow. For a moment his heart stops. He conjures up the worst. Grabs up the note, unfolds it. We see a lipstick kiss and the words: HAVE A SPECTACULAR</context>
      <utterance>Trix. You came back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can answer, Doris hands him a container of cream. A full container. Taken aback, he starts pouring it into his cup, when he hears a VOICE over the intercom:</context>
      <utterance>Got any cre --</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bernie looks to Doris.</context>
      <utterance>Lovett, party of six, your table is ready, Lovett, party of six.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duty calls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FLOOR MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Shelly a cup of quarters, takes off. Shelly looks to Bernie. He's trying to keep a lid on his anger.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Shelly, check it out. The new Mega-Million. I call her Marnie, 'cause she's one frigid broad. Sure, once in a while she'll flash you a bit of tit, but your chances of hitting a home run -- one in twenty million. Here, give her a shot...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna tell me what's going on out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly pulls the lever.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean... Marnie immediately spits out a small jackpot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, you don't know? We're down almost a mil out there. Doesn't seem strange to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I'm having an off day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly starts feeding Marnie again.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have off days, Lootz. You're shitty luck incarnate. What's wrong? You coming down with something? You've got this look about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's wrong. Fact is, I've never felt better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the mention of Natalie's name, we hear a shrieking SIREN, followed by a deafening toll of slot bells. Shelly's just landed the million dollar jackpot. Shelly stares at the slot in surprise -- then looks over at Bernie. Realization hits hard. Fuck! The floor manager staggers over. His expression is priceless.</context>
      <utterance>She loves me, Shelly. She told me last night. Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SEVERAL CASINO WORKERS have gathered to witness the deflowering of Marnie. They gaze reverently upon her, as if witnessing the "Close Encounters" mothership for the first time. Shelly drags Bernie out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus... you popped her cherries.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie nods, a huge grin wrenching his cheeks apart. He's about to go helium on us.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie? She told you, she loves you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie, startled, drops her cigarettes. She kneels to gather them up.</context>
      <utterance>Put that fucking thing out!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should be. You've gone and fucked it up big time. I paid you to be his cooze companion, not his fucking true love. But, no, you had to go and get all profound on the poor schmuck.  "I love you, Bernie." You know what you've gone and done, sweetheart? Those four little words of endearment have already cost this casino a million and counting today.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly walks around his desk to Natalie.</context>
      <utterance>Lady luck. You never heard'a lady luck?! That's what's goin' on out there. Lootz is Kryptonite on a stick. He should have 'em throwing ice cubes out there, but instead I got a fuckin' meltdown on my hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, here's what's gonna happen. You're outta his life by the time he gets home. Don't even tell him to his face, just leave a note. I'll make some calls, situate you at another joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't an act. I meant it. I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's there to fuckin' love? He's a loser. Always has been, always will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were his friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie rushes from the office in tears. Shelly closes his eyes for a moment -- gotta keep it together.</context>
      <utterance>And I thought you were a smart cookie when I picked you out. You do not want to fuck me over, darlin'. I'll see to it that your next John's a rattlesnake out in the desert. Now get the fuck outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Any of you seen Natalie around? I'm supposed to give her a ride home.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCKTAIL WAITRESS #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Bernie's expression: Oh...</context>
      <utterance>I think she left already. She wasn't feelin' too good. We been covering for her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. He heads over. Finds it empty. Concern spreads across his features. He glances around the room. Notices the closet wide open. Natalie's clothes missing.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie? You in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's when he catches sight of the note taped to the dresser mirror. He rushes over, rips it off.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to tell me the truth, Shelly. Did you say something to Natalie? Did you muscle her --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie shrugs an apology, shifts his gaze to Johnny Cappella.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Bernie, is that what you think of me? That I would fuck with your happiness? That hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's all flash. No soul. I miss Buddy. Place isn't the same without him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddy was tired. I gave him an easy out. It coulda been a lot worse...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He woulda never taken the buy-out offer. Buddy woulda stuck to his guns, no matter what. And they woulda ended up hurting him. I couldn't let that happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... you... How can you sit here and justify it? Like you were Dr. Kevorkian or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Bernie's shocked expression --</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, you dumb fuck -- I loved that sonofabitch. But his time was up. What I was supposed to do, leave him to those corporate wolves? What I did, it was the humanitarian thing. That I have no doubt about. Afterwards, I held him in my arms and I cried like a fucking baby. What? You got this look -- what's this fucking look?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie? You awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie looks over at her.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just take off.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it. Let's just pack up and go. Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that. I've got an obligation to Shelly. There's no --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie cuts her off.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck Shelly. He doesn't give a shit about you. Let's just climb into your car and get the hell out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie finishes her cigarette. Well, she's made her bed. Bernie starts nuzzling her. She turns away.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do that, Natalie. They'd come after me. And because you were with me... I wouldn't want that on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hold me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got no fucking right...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I tell you?! What did I fuckin' tell you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried... I couldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly heads over to the closet, rips it open, pulls out a suitcase. He starts throwing Natalie's clothes into the case.</context>
      <utterance>I don't give a fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gone, sweetheart. History. Kiss paradise goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck do you think you are? You ain't nobody! I could make you disappear like this...  And nobody would ever notice you were gone. Nobody!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slashes Shelly across the arm. Ouch, fuck! Before Tony and Lou can make a move, Shelly ensnares her wrist -- snaps it backwards -- AARRRRGGHHH!!! Shelly snatches up the shard, shoves her back on the bed. We see her terror reflected in the jagged glass against her cheek...</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony and Lou look on with mutual expressions: Shelly's getting a little carried away here. Shelly staggers to his feet...</context>
      <utterance>You fuckin' cunt... He slices her cheek open.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly reaches into his jacket, pulls out a wad of bills. Throws them at Natalie.</context>
      <utterance>You think that's bad? That's just a taste, bitch. You're still here when Bernie gets home and I'll finish the job. I'll cut you into so many fuckin' pieces, the vultures'll be trading on you for a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly gestures to Tony and Lou. They exit the room, leaving Natalie sobbing into one of Bernie's pillows.</context>
      <utterance>Here... go get yourself some cosmetic surgery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie fumbles for the light switch...</context>
      <utterance>Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't. I've got a headache.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you take something? I got some aspirin in the --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's just enough moonlight in the room for Bernie to make out Natalie curled over on the bed. As he approaches, he trips over Natalie's suitcase on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I already took something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts himself on a splinter of shattered glass as he staggers to his feet. Which draws his attention to the mirror. Moonlight glows off the edges. That's all there is -- edges. On the dresser: his bottle of Ten High. Empty. Confused, Bernie fumbles his way over to Natalie on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out to touch her face... instead his hand makes contact with a lump.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie, what happened? The mirror...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jerks back, flips on the nightstand lamp.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie chokes at the sight of her. She clutches a bloody rag to her cheek. Blood on the pillow... blood on the sheets... And tears.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie, no! Shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus... Natalie, who did this to you? We need to call the police...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Bernie. I just want you to know that. I fell in love with you. That wasn't part of the plan. I thought... easy money...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly. He paid me to get next to you. To keep you around. Whatever it took...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie slumps down on the edge of the bed. Sucker-punched. Trying to make sense of it.</context>
      <utterance>You got it right the first night. I was for sale. Bought and paid for. You were the easy mark, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At first you were just another John. But then I started to take a closer look. For the first time, here was someone who wasn't trying to hustle me. Wasn't pretending to be somebody he wasn't. Just a decent guy trying to get back on track. And it didn't hurt any that you put me up on a pedestal. It sure puts the gutter into perspective...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie stands shakily.</context>
      <utterance>Shelly wants me gone. He says I bring you luck. Lady luck. I stayed... to tell you to your face... and then you wouldn't want me no more... and I could just go...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta get you to the hospital. We'll talk about this later.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie doesn't answer her.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell me one thing, Bernie. Tell me there's gonna be a later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me again, Bernie. Tell me it's all gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie leans over and kisses him. As she does so, she catches sight of her face in the mirror. Starts to tear up.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's gonna be fine. This is our time. This is you and me and we're going for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks into Bernie's eyes. Sees the most beautiful girl in the world. Tears roll down her cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>You look in the mirror, you don't like what you see, don't believe it. You look in my eyes. That's the only mirror you gonna need. Look in my eyes, Natalie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Natalie's startled reaction...</context>
      <utterance>I love you. Marry me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I do. I have to tell him right to his face. I will not look over my shoulder for the rest of my life -- our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie, your chart... that first night. I wasn't being straight with you. It's the worst chart I've ever seen. There's nothing in the cards for you. I'm scared...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Natalie shakily opens her purse, pulls out a handful of hundreds. Pushes the money at Bernie...</context>
      <utterance>Don't you see, that was before you opened your heart to me. Everything's different now. I got lady luck on my side. Ain't nothing gonna happen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's three thousand dollars. Take it. Maybe Shelly'll accept it as a down payment. We can send him the rest in installments... after we get settled.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie stuffs the cash in his jacket. Climbs out.</context>
      <utterance>Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever happens, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns away. Stares out the window, tears streaming down her cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>I know, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie throws something in Shelly's face. It's that bloody rag Natalie was holding to her cheek. It lands on the table in front of everyone. Shelly swats it away with disgust. Jumps to his feet. WHAM! Bernie slugs him one. As Shelly doubles over, Bernie gets in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie, what's the matter? You look a little fucking spooked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly's goons quickly move in, grab Bernie. Drag him away. Shelly composes himself, turns to his guests.</context>
      <utterance>You lay another finger on her, I swear to God I'll kill you. You hear me? I'll fuckin' kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes off. Nicky shoots Larry a resigned look.</context>
      <utterance>Will you excuse me for a moment?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Why, Shelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you never give up a good thing, Bernie. You are a good thing. The best fuckin' cooler there ever was. And I need him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't never comin' back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a dead man talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm through with this joint, Shelly. Natalie and me, we just got married. We're outta here. I'll get a job out there in the world. Send you half my paycheck every month. Make good on my obligations.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try to walk on me, Bernie, and I'll fuckin' bury you. The both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly's expression: Oh yeah?</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You whack me, then Bernie Lootz ain't the world's biggest loser no more. That honor's gonna fall upon you, Shelly. And maybe you had it all along.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck? Me? I'm the loser?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you got? What do you got in your life besides this joint?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck more do I need?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly looks to Tony and Lou:</context>
      <utterance>You got nothin', Shelly. This place -- your legacy -- it's a mirage. You turn your back and it don't even exist. There's no day, there's no night, it's all just one big fuckin' blur and it don't count for nothin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie gets eye-to-eye with Shelly. A first.</context>
      <utterance>You believe this fuckin' guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie turns his back on Shelly, strides over to the door.</context>
      <utterance>I feel real sorry for you. Yeah, you got this fear of germs thing. But it goes deeper than that. You can't get close to no one. On an emotional level. You're the worst kind of gambler there ever was: too scared to put his chips on the table. Too scared to open his heart... to extend any real kinda friendship. Always afraid it's gonna end out in the desert. Well, sweet fuckin' dreams, pal, 'cause I'm out and if that's where it ends, that's where it ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie turns, looks at Shelly. Shelly's dead serious. They hard stare each other for a beat. Bernie doesn't say anything. At least, not out loud. His eyes do all the talking: "I guess you leave me no choice either." HOLD on Bernie's steely resolve.</context>
      <utterance>That's a real heartfelt speech, Lootz. All that Jimmy Stewart in ya face intensity. You almost sold me.  Man, I've got a fucking lump in my throat.  But it still don't change things. You bail on me without making good on my 150 G's and I'm gonna be forced to close the books on you. You and the broad. You leave me no choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CREW working the table stop down as they realize who it is. The table is dead. Bernie couldn't be needed. The croupier slowly gathers up the green, hands it to the boxman.</context>
      <utterance>Change only...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROUPIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boxman counts the cash.</context>
      <utterance>Check change three thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOXMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This a pleasure cruise, Bernie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOXMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it'll be a short one. Table's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROUPIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others chuckle. The boxman counts out the chips; they're given to Bernie. He places them all on the passline. The stickman pushes over the dice. Bernie picks a couple. He throws....</context>
      <utterance>It is now, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie picks up his three thousand dollars in winnings. He lets it ride. The table quickly fills up with hungry players. Bernie throws the dice again...</context>
      <utterance>Yo Eleven! Pay the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie is now paid six thousand dollars on his pass line bet. The other players also collect their winnings. They can feel something in the air. Bernie, forehead beaded with sweat, rubs the felt a little before he picks up the dice. He throws...</context>
      <utterance>Winner seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie takes double odds on his bet. The boxman isn't sure what to do. Does he stop him? Does he dare? In the b.g., people gather to watch the action. Whatever it is, it's catching. The table next to them bursts into applause.</context>
      <utterance>Six easy. Easy way six!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie takes a thousand dollars in chips, tosses it gently to the croupier.</context>
      <utterance>Natalie... this is you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire crew stop for a moment out of respect. Bernie notices. They all nod as the boxman locks up the tip money.</context>
      <utterance>For the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, we're coming out. Get your YO bets, C&amp;E, any seven...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boxman looks up nervously.</context>
      <utterance>How much is he up?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOXMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly mouths the words under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Around three hundred thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't one of you fucking geniuses call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOXMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The game resumes.</context>
      <utterance>We tried. You weren't picking up. Besides, it was Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie stops.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. We're coming out folks, hands high...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody quiets down to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie points to Shelly standing in the pit. The crowd watches the drama play out.</context>
      <utterance>Color me up a hundred fifty thousand.  And give it to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boxman colors up a hundred fifty thousand in chips, lays them out on the table. He counts it and claps his hands together for the cameras.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I owe you, Shelly. There it is. We're square.  Let it be known, Bernie Lootz lives up to his obligations.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOXMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly stands motionless. Staring into Bernie's eyes. The whole crowd watches. After what seems like an eternity, Shelly nods. Then the Boxman feeds the chips in with the others. A moment later, we can nary tell they were ever gone. Larry appears next to Shelly. Nicky and Marty watching from the sidelines -- dour expressions.</context>
      <utterance>One hundred fifty thousand, coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you? He's one of ours and he's taking us to the fucking cleaners.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lootz's off the clock. As long as he's off the clock, he's free to play. Just like every other schmuck in this joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly suddenly jabs Larry in the throat with the tips of his fingers. Larry gasps, starts to cave. Shelly keeps him upright, escorts him to a nearby men's room. Nicky and Marty looking on in amazement.</context>
      <utterance>It smells wrong. I'm shutting him down. He's not leaving here with a dime --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd gasps in horror as Bernie's twenty five grand is quickly raked in. He replaces it with another stack of chips. The dice are pushed over to him. He rubs the felt real gently before throwing. Then lets loose the dice. All eyes follow the dice. They hit the felt and bounce around behind a stack of chips. The stickman can't spot them.</context>
      <utterance>Crap ace deuce! Line down!</utterance>
   <speaker>STICKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A croupier makes the call as anxious players rubberneck to get a look.</context>
      <utterance>Call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROUPIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd groans again. It appears the streak is over. Bernie looks out over the felt. This is his moment of truth. He unloads his entire rail and puts it on the field. He yells out.</context>
      <utterance>Twelve crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd chimes in with every opinion under the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty thousand dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the field? What're you fucking nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The dice are slowly pushed over to Bernie. The crowd is feeling it. The entire casino is feeling it. Bernie lets out a long soulful sigh. His whole life depends on the next throw and everyone knows it. Bernie rubs the felt as usual and lines up the dice to show a six and a six. He picks them up.</context>
      <utterance>Shake it, don't break it, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Locks eyes with Shelly -- then lets loose. The dice fly from his hand. Slowly, ever so slowly we watch them sail across the table. The entire table holds their breath in anticipation...</context>
      <utterance>Come on sixty-six!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie just looks at her. Pale, mournful features.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God... I thought for sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer. Just starts up the car...</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, right? You guys worked it out. He took the three grand? Tell me it's okay, Bernie?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie throws open his door...</context>
      <utterance>What are you stopping for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throw up. And he does. It's as if he's choking up the entire city. Everything that's bad about it. Finally, he pulls himself back into the car. Slams the door. Natalie touches his cheek, a reassuring look in her eyes. Suddenly, he's smiling. He opens his coat and a huge wad of cash tumbles out. He throws it up into the air. Natalie almost chokes with surprise.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly an EXPLOSION OF LIGHT! A flashlight. In the hand of a MOTORCYCLE COP. He raps on the window...</context>
      <utterance>Bahamas, here we come, baby. She throws her arms around him...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step out of the car please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop runs the flashlight over the bundles of cash littering the car interior.</context>
      <utterance>What's the problem, officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie and Natalie exchange unsettled looks. The cop lowers his hand to his gun. Bernie nods at Natalie. They climb out. He directs them off to the side. Shines his light in their faces.</context>
      <utterance>Just step out of the car, please. Both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If my driving... if I was going a little fast -- I was just over excited, officer. See, we just had a big win at the Shangri-la --</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop pulls out his revolver, trains it on them.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't win nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, Bernie, I knew it. It was too good to be true. Who were we kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him in shock. He gestures them to the ground behind Bernie's car. We CUT TO a shot from the highway: just the cop standing at the tail-end of Bernie's car, Natalie and Bernie hidden from view.</context>
      <utterance>Get down on your knees. Both of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(catches himself...)</context>
      <utterance>He was drunk. It was just freak luck...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATALIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give it a name, Bernie. It scares me. All I know is, you're still running hot and that's a good thing. But we're only winners if we keep going. No looking back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her furiously. Then drags her over to his car. They climb in. Drive off.</context>
      <utterance>Lady luck, Natalie. I'm calling it. Lady luck. And we got it as long as we're together. They can't touch us now.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
