<movie id="287" title="Hudsucker Proxy The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We are TRACKING HIGH THROUGH the night sky. From the streets far below we hear the sounds of TRAFFIC muffled by the falling snow, and the DISTANT sound of many VOICES SINGING. We are DRIFTING AMONG the buildings; the tops of skyscrapers slip by left and right.</context>
      <utterance>The's right... New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The SINGING, a little MORE AUDIBLE, but still not close, is "Auld Lang Syne."</context>
      <utterance>It's 1958 -- anyway, for a few mo' minutes it is. Come midnight it's gonna be 1959. A whole 'nother feelin'. The New Year. The future...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We are MOVING IN TOWARDS a particular skyscraper. At its top is a large illuminated clock.</context>
      <utterance>...Yeah ole daddy Earth fixin' to start one mo' trip 'round the sun, an' evvybody hopin' this ride 'round be a little mo' giddy, a little mo' gay...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We hear a SERIES OF POPPING sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Yep...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A big band WALTZ MIXES UP on the track.</context>
      <utterance>...All over town champagne corks is a-poppin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The LOMBARDO MUSIC gives way to the CHANTING of a distant CROWD: "Sixty! Fifty-nine! Fifty-eight!"</context>
      <utterance>...Over in the Waldorf the big shots is dancin' to the strains of Guy Lombardo... Down in Times Square the little folks is a-watchin' and a- waitin' fo' that big ball to drop...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The CHANTING has MIXED back DOWN AGAIN TO leave only the WIND. Still TRACKING IN TOWARD the top of the skyscraper, we begin to hear the TICK of its enormous CLOCK. The clock reads a minute to twelve. Above it, in neon, a company's name: "HUDSUCKER INDUSTRIES." Below it, in neon, the company's motto: "THE FUTURE IS NOW."</context>
      <utterance>...They all tryin' to catch holt a one moment of time...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We are MOVING IN ON a darkened penthouse window next to the clock. The window starts to open.</context>
      <utterance>...to be able to say -- 'Right now! This is it! I got it!' 'Course by then it'll be past.  But they all happy, evvybody havin' a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A young man is crawling out of the window onto the ledge. With the opening of the window, "AULD LANG SYNE" filters out with greater volume.</context>
      <utterance>...Well, almost evvybody. They's a few lost souls floatin' 'round out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The man gingerly straightens up on the ledge. He is perhaps in his late twenties. He wears a leather apron. Printed on the apron: "HUDSUCKER MAIL ROOM/The Future is Now." He looks with nervous determination into the void.</context>
      <utterance>...This one's Norville Barnes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The CAMERA obliges. We TRACK IN SLOWLY, ENDING VERY CLOSE.</context>
      <utterance>...Let's move in for a closer look.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Norville sways in anguish as the TICKING of the CLOCK grows louder and the WIND blows in his face.</context>
      <utterance>...That office he jes stepped out of is the office of the president of Hudsucker Industries. It's his office...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Norville is tensing his body, peering out over the ledge, preparing to make a swan dive into oblivion -- but the CAMERA'S continued MOVEMENT is LOSING him FROM FRAME. We are MOVING IN ON the enormous CLOCK, whose MECHANICAL THRUM becomes very loud indeed.</context>
      <utterance>...How'd he get so high? An' why is he feelin' so low? Is he really gonna do it -- is Norville really gonna jelly up the sidewalk?</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The second hand of the clock is nearing the twelve -- bare seconds to midnight. Distant CHANTING from Times Square MIXES UP: "Nine! Eight! Seven!"</context>
      <utterance>...Well the future, that's something you can't never tell about...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...But the past... That's another story...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TRACK has ENDED IN a CLOSEUP of the man at the end of the table, who still smiles benignantly at the droning Executive. The smile is serene, almost otherwordly. This is WARING HUDSUCKER.</context>
      <utterance>...The competition continues to flag and we continue to take up the slack. Market share in most divisions is increasing and we've opened seven new regional offices...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTING EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He drones on.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Our international division has also shown vigorous upward movement in the past six months and we're looking at some exciting things in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hudsucker looks up from his watch, smiles, runs his palms back over his fringe of hair.</context>
      <utterance>...Our nominees and assigns continue to multiply and expand extending our influence regionally, nationally and globally. So, third quarter and year- to-date, we've set a new record for sales...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hudsucker pulls his sleeve cuffs to expose just the right amount under the suit.</context>
      <utterance>...new record in gross...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hudsucker takes one puff from his cigar and carefully sets it in his ashtray.</context>
      <utterance>...new record in pre-tax earnings...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He deliberately unstraps his wristwatch and looks at its face. The sweep second hand is starting the last revolution that will end at precisely noon.</context>
      <utterance>...new record in after-tax profit...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hudsucker lays the watch carefully on the table.</context>
      <utterance>...and our stock has split twice this year...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Savoring a pause, the Executive looks around the board table.</context>
      <utterance>...In short...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This draws an appreciative chuckle from the board. It is cut off by:</context>
      <utterance>...we're loaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The board turns expectantly to Hudsucker, who sits in the f.g. Beyond him is the length of the board table and the large picture window. He rises to his feet, slowly and deliberately, and rubs his palms together. He swings his chair out. He steps up onto the chair. The board stares. He steps up from the chair onto the board table. The heads of the board members swing up in unison. Hudsucker is FRAMED FROM MID-TORSO DOWN. He shakes the tension loose from each leg, then waggles both arms dangling at his sides, like an athlete preparing for a sprint.</context>
      <utterance>Ahem...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Mr. Hudsucker?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other board members unfreeze, their worst fears confirmed.</context>
      <utterance>Pity to waste a whole Monte Cristo.</utterance>
   <speaker>AN EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could've opened the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waring Hudsucker never did anything the easy way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Things were going so well!</context>
      <utterance>My God, why?! Why did he do it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I a headshrinker? Maybe the man was unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't look unhappy!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, he didn't look rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waring Hudsucker was never an easy man to figure out.  He built this company with his bare hands. Every step he took was a step up. Except of course this last one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, he was a swell guy, but when the president, chairman of the board and holder of eighty-seven percent of the company's stock drops forty-four floors --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRECISE EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-five --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counting the mezzanine --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Then the company has a problem. Stillson, what exactly is the disposition of Waring's stock?</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, as you know, Hud left no will and had no family. The company bylaws are quite clear in that event. His entire portfolio will be converted to common stock and will be sold over the counter as of the first of the fiscal year following his demise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning simply that Waring's stock, and control of the company, will be available to the public on January first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stillson shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>You mean to tell me that any slob in a smelly T-shirt will be able to buy Hudsucker stock?</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The company bylaws are quite clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God! You're animals! How can you discuss his stock when the man has just leapt forty-five floors --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRECISE EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-four --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Not counting the mezzanine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit showboating, Addison, the man is gone. The question now is whether we're going to let John Q. Public waltz in and buy 87 percent of our company.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIPE-SMOKING EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you suggesting, Sidney? Certainly we can't afford to buy a controlling interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not while the stock is this strong. How long before Hud's paper hits the market?</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>January first.</utterance>
   <speaker>AN EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A month at the most.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One month to make the blue-chip investment of the century look like a round-trip ticket on the Titanic.</utterance>
   <speaker>AN EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We play up the fact that Hud is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long live the Hud!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We depress the stock --</utterance>
   <speaker>YET ANOTHER EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- to the point where we can buy fifty-percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRECISE EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty-one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not counting the mezzanine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAUTIOUS EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could work.</utterance>
   <speaker>OPTIMISTIC EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It should work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRACTICAL EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's working already. Waring Hudsucker is abstract art on Madison Avenue. All we need now is a new president who will inspire real panic in our stockholders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENTHUSIASTIC EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a puppet!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A proxy!</utterance>
   <speaker>YET ANOTHER EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger strides across the room from the still CHATTERING TICKER TAPE MACHINE and lowers himself into Waring Hudsucker's chair. He takes a last puff from his cigar and slowly exhales a cloud of smoke.</context>
      <utterance>A pawn!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. Some jerk we can really push around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You punch in at 8:30 every morning except you punch in at 7:30 following a business holiday unless it's a Monday and then you punch in at eight o'clock! You punch in at 7:45 whenever we work extended day and you punch out at the regular time unless you've worked through lunch!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's exte --</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People on either side bellow at Norville and stuff envelopes and packages under his elbows, into his pockets, under his chin, between his clenched teeth, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Punch in late and they dock ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST SCREAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Urgent!</context>
      <utterance>This goes to seven! Mr. Mutuszak!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Incoming articles, get a voucher! Outgoing articles, provide a voucher! Move any article without a voucher and they dock ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND SCREAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this up to the secretarial pool on three! Right away! Don't break it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Letter size a green voucher! Folder size a yellow voucher! Parcel size a maroon voucher!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD SCREAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one's for Morgatross! Chop chop!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong color voucher and they dock ya! Six-seven-eight-seven-zero-four- niner-alpha-slash-six! That is your employee number! It will not be repeated! Without your employee number you cannot cash your paycheck!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOURTH SCREAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This goes up to twenty-seven! If there's no one there bring it down to eighteen! Have 'em sign the waiver!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inter-office mail is code 37! INTRA- office mail is 37-dash-3! Outside mail is 3-dash 37! Code it wrong and they dock ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIFTH SCREAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was supposed to have this on twenty- eight ten minutes ago! Cover for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has been your orientation! Is there anything you do not understand? Is there anything you understand only partially? If you have not been fully oriented -- if there is something you do not understand in all of its particulars you must file a complaint with personnel! File a faulty complaint... and they dock ya!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He raises his voice over the mailroom din:</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ANCIENT SORTER considers this as he continues whisking his mail.</context>
      <utterance>Say, what do you do when the envelope is too big for the slot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whisk. Whisk. Whisk.</context>
      <utterance>Well... if ya fold 'em, they fire ya...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville takes out a pencil and writes on the face of the envelope:</context>
      <utterance>...I usually throw 'em out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got hired today!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, entry level!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got big ideas, though!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is taking an envelope from his pocket and handing it to the Ancient Sorter.</context>
      <utterance>For instance, take a look at this sweet baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ancient Sorter is pulling a ragged piece of paper from the envelope. On the paper is a crudely-drawn circle.</context>
      <utterance>...you look like you can keep a secret...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ancient Sorter looks questioningly from the circle to Norville.</context>
      <utterance>...Something I developed myself. Yessir, this is my ticket upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ancient Sorter nods with feigned understanding as Norville takes the paper back.</context>
      <utterance>...You know, for kids!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So ya see, I won't be in the mailroom long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He resumes his sorting.</context>
      <utterance>Nooo, I don't guess you will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long've you been down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whisk. Whisk.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-eight years...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whisk. Whisk. Whisk.</context>
      <utterance>...Next year they move me up to parcels...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...If I'm lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>A BELL CLANGS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM SPUTTERS to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>All HUBBUB ABRUPTLY STOPS and the sounds of HEAVY MACHINERY, HISSING STEAM PIPES, and GENERATORS WIND DOWN TO leave total SILENCE. After a moment:</context>
      <utterance>Attention Hudsucker employees. We regretfully announce that at 12:01 this afternoon, Hudsucker time, Waring Hudsucker, Founder, President, and Chairman of the Board of Hudsucker Industries, merged with the infinite. To mark this occasion of corporate loss, we ask that all employees observe a moment of silent contemplation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The MACHINERY GROANS back INTO ACTION and the people return to their jobs just as:</context>
      <utterance>...Thank you for your kind attention. This moment has been duly-noted on your time cards and will be deducted from your pay. That is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>A STEAM WHISTLE SCREECHES.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM:</context>
      <utterance>ALARM BELLS go OFF.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Blue letter! Blue letter!' The mail room is thrown into pandemonium.</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One MAN spins to face the CAMERA, his hands pressed over his ears. STEAM JETS and HISSES behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Blue letter...! It's a blue letter...! They're bringing down a blue letter!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Animated for the first time:</context>
      <utterance>Blue letter!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mail carts and other paraphernalia are abruptly swept out of the crowded aisle to form a clear path running down to an elevator in the b.g. With a SIREN SOUND, a light above the elevator goes on. The elevator door sweeps open. It reveals a wall into which a four-foot high hinged door is set. This door swings open and an old dwarf emerges: Old man HUTCHINSON, the boss of the mailroom. He emerges from the blinding light of the interior of the elevator. He is holding aloft a letter. He takes loping drawf strides down the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>Jumpin' Jehosephat, a blue letter!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANCIENT SORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville gulps.</context>
      <utterance>It's a blue letter... top, top level... confidential communication between the brass... usually bad news... they hate blue letters upstairs... Hate 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCHINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville looks over his shoulder, but the Ancient Sorter has disappeared.</context>
      <utterance>You!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCHINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he points, the people around Norville shrink away.</context>
      <utterance>...Yeah, you! Barnes!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCHINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRAMATIC TRACK IN ON Norville. As Hutchinson talks, he thrusts the blue letter into Norville's face. Norville looks at it with terrific apprehension. As Hutchinson's speech ends, we are TIGHT ON Norville's sweating face.</context>
      <utterance>...You don't look busy! Think you can handle a blue letter?  ...This letter was sent down this morning by the big guy himself! 'At's right, Waring Hudsucker! It's addressed to Sid Mussburger! Hudsucker's right-hand man! It's a blue letter! That means you put it right in Mussburger's hand. No secretaries! No receptionists! No colleagues! No excuses!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts his pillbox hat to reveal a white crewcut, then lets the elastic chin strap snap the cap back down onto his head.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, buddy! The name is Buzz, I got the fuzz...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand but as Norville reaches to shake it he snaps it away and pats down his crewcut:</context>
      <utterance>...I make the elevator do what she duzz!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cackles and powers the ELEVATOR into GEAR. Norville's knees buckle under a huge upward surge; Buzz is accustomed to it.</context>
      <utterance>...Hang it up to dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What's your pleasure, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-fourth floor, and it's very --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-four, the top brass floor say, buddy! What takes fifty years to get up to the top floor and thirty seconds to get down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a powerful DOWN-SHIFTING SOUND, Buzz brakes the elevator to a sharp halt. Norville continues upward with the inertia, painfully smacking his head against a corner of the elevator. Buzz opens the door and a couple of people enter.</context>
      <utterance>Waring Hudsucker! Na-ha-ha-ha-ha! Say, buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kline, up to nine. Mrs. Dell, personnel. Mr. Levin, thirty-seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LEVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An obese MAN enters, smoking a cigar:</context>
      <utterance>Walk down. Ladies and gentlemen, step to the rear; here comes gargantuan Mr. Grier.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz has already thrown the doors shut and sent the elevator into its power-rise. Norville, bracing himself now, sinks only a little under the G-force.</context>
      <utterance>Buzz.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, buddy! Who's the most liquid businessman on the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to look at Norville.</context>
      <utterance>Waring Hudsucker! Na-ha-ha-ha-ha! Say, buddy! When is the sidewalk fully dressed? When it's 'wearing' Hudsucker! Na-ha-ha-ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All heads in the elevator turn, aghast, to look, and those near Norville shrink away.</context>
      <utterance>...Ya get it, buddy, it's a pun, it's a knee-slapper, it's a play on Jesus, Joseph and Mary, is that a blue letter?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELEVATOR SCREAMS into overdrive and we:</context>
      <utterance>...Cripes a'mighty, whyn't ya tell a guy?! Hold on, folks, we're express to the top floor!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELEVATOR DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweeping open. Norville staggers out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door sweeps shut. Norville looks nervously around. Behind him the elevator doors suddenly open again.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator doors slam shut and we hear its ENGINES SCREAM as it power-dives away. Norville turns toward the executive offices. Plush, thick-carpeted silence. Norville starts walking. A SCRAPING SOUND stands out in the high-powered executive quiet. Norville looks to one side. A workman in painter's overalls squats in front of a pair of heavy oak doors. With a razor blade he is scraping off the name "WARING HUDSUCKER."</context>
      <utterance>-- You'll need it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scraper looks sullenly over his shoulder at Norville. With a jerk of his thumb he indicates the direction. Norville enters the adjacent office.</context>
      <utterance>...Mr. Mussburger's office?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have an appointment?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhh, no, I -- The filing secretary sneers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens an enormous leather-bound book with yellowed crinkly pages.</context>
      <utterance>Shall we look in the book, hmmmmmmmmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am, ya see, I wouldn't be in the --</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is groping in his apron pocket.</context>
      <utterance>We don't seem to be in the boooook.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am, ya see I don't have an --</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we had an appointment we'd be in the booook.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A low, unearthly WAIL fills the room, the sound of a million souls moaning in purgatory. The Receptionist looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I know but ya see I have this -- here it is, this letter --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swivels around to face Norville, who stands deferentially at the door. Still listening at the phone, Mussburger waves Norville forward.</context>
      <utterance>-- Sure sure, Parkinson's stupid but he's ambitious, too hard to control...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He covers the mouth piece.</context>
      <utterance>...No! Not McClanahan; sure he bungled the Teleyard merger, but that means he's got something to prove...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Who let you in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atwater? Tremendous. Except I fired him last week -- The INTERCOM BUZZES fiercely.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mussburger hits the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bumstead is waiting downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him I'll be right there...  Well, what is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="50">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, maybe you're the company's biggest moron. We can't use Morris, he's been with us too long, he's a nice guy, too many friends. Matter of fact, why don't you fire him. No -- scratch that; I'll fire him.  ...Make it fast, make it fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- The INTERCOM SQUAWKS.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bumstead is getting very --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second PHONE on Mussburger's desk RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right there. Give him a magazine.  ...What're you, a mute?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>...Yeah, how's the stock doing? ...Bad, huh? Well it's not bad enough.  ...Look, chump, either you find me a grade A ding-dong or you can tender your key to the executive washroom.  And that goes double for you.  Ear-clay?  Ood-gay!  This better be good. I'm in a bad mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his mailroom apron and hands a scrap of paper across the desk to Mussburger, who stares, frozen, at Norville, making no move to take the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sir. I've got something for you from the mailroom, but first if I could just take a minute or so from your very busy time...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville, undaunted, holds up the paper since Mussburger will not take it. Mussburger doesn't even look at it; his eyes are locked on Norville's. Mussburger smolders.</context>
      <utterance>...to show you a, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger's burning eyes finally shift momentarily to look at the crudely drawn circle; he looks back incredulously at Norville.</context>
      <utterance>...a little something I've been working on for the last two or three years...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You know, for kids! Which is perfect for Hudsucker -- not that I claim to be any great genius; like they say, inspiration is 99 percent perspiration, and in my case I'd say it's at least twice that, but I gotta tell ya, Mr. Mussburger, sir, this sweet baby --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one last click the perpetual motion ball bearings abruptly stop. As Mussburger's eyes burn in on him, Norville stands mute and paralyzed. His eyes locked on Norville's, Mussburger circles the desk. He stands toe-to-toe with Norville. He thrusts his face into Norville's, whose head moves reflexively back. Mussburger's nose is almost touching Norville's, his eyes are burning, searching, studying, evaluating. Finally he draws his head back.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! Sudden quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one hand he thrusts his cigar into Norville's gaping mouth. With his other hand he raises Norville's chin so that his teeth clench it.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back, eyes still on Norville. He jerks his thumb over his shoulder, indicating his chair behind the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Umm-hmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville, his lips puckered around the unaccustomed ciger, looks bemusedly from the chair to Mussburger.</context>
      <utterance>Siddown.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville obeys, reluctantly, stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>...Go ahead. Try it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is again reluctant.</context>
      <utterance>...Put your feet up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville obeys. Mussburger studies.</context>
      <utterance>...Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville's eyes squint against the cigar smoke wreathing from between his teeth. Mussburger seems to relax.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmmm... Let's get to know one another, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville beams.</context>
      <utterance>...Let's chat!  ...Man to man!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves vaguely towards his head and searches for a euphemism.</context>
      <utterance>...You weren't blessed with much...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...education, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm a college graduate --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, but you didn't excel in your studies...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I made the dean's list.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville sputters out some more cigar smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the Muncie College of Business Administration.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. And did your classmates there call you 'jerk' or...  ...'schmoe'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...'Shnook'? 'Dope'? 'Dipstick'? 'Lamebrain'?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even behind your back?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir! They voted me most likely to succeed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, sir! --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he struggles to comply:</context>
      <utterance>Get your feet off that desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville, squinting against the cigar smoke, pulls the cigar out of his mouth as he doubles forward, feet still up, groping for a place to set down the cigar. He sets it blindly on a loose stack of papers.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of my sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God! The Bumstead contracts!!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The top page radiates a circle of incipient flame from the cigar's live end.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You nitwit! I worked for three years on this deal!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville runs across the office to a large water cooler.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger plucks the cigar off the contract and tosses it into a wastebasket. He pats the fingertips of one hand against his tongue and then efficiently pats out the crinkling orange circle on the top sheet of the contract. At the other end of the office, Norville is wrapping his arms around the glass water tank, which he pulls off its base. He runs back across the vast expanse of office toward the desk, hugging the water tank whose WATER GLOOB-GLOOBS out its open bottom and splashes down onto his pumping knees. As he reaches the desk, the near-empty tank is now light enough for him to hoist with one arm, which he does, and cups his other hand under it to catch its last glub of water. He tosses the TANK to the floor where -- CRASH -- it SHATTERS, and stands looking about for a place to dump his handful of water.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it. Just get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you nitwit. You almost destroyed the most sensitive deal of my career!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is reacting to the wastebasket on his side of the desk, which Mussburger cannot see. It is sprouting flame, at which Norville ineffectually flecks his remaining drops of water.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is already running to the window, which he runs both palms over, desperately seeking a way to open it.</context>
      <utterance>Now out of here! Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that way! Through the door!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The windows do not open. Norville furiously stomps on the flames in the wastebasket and -- his foot sticks. Further stomping only makes the flaming wastebasket roar up and down with his foot.</context>
      <utterance>But, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville has dropped to the floor, trying to wrench the flaming wastebasket off his leg.</context>
      <utterance>Right away, buster! Out of my office!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up on your feet! We don't crawl at Hudsucker Industries!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville finally succeeds in getting the flaming wastebasket off his foot. Now the problem is what to do with it.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, my leg is on fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville picks up the flaming trash receptacle.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of this office, you dithering nincompoop!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winds up and throws it through the closed window. The GLASS SHATTERS and the flaming basket plummets to oblivion. With the picture window broken a FEROCIOUS DRAFT ROARS through the penthouse office.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God! The Bumstead contracts!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger lunges for the contracts as they are sucked out the window. He runs, jumps onto the sill, grabs -- his fist clenches around one wafting page -- he is about to fall --</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eeeeeeaaaahhhhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Desperately hanging onto Mussburger by his legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger's screaming abruptly stops.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Mr. Mussburger! I gotcha. I gotcha by your pants!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUIGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meester Moosaburger, I give-a you pants a nice-a dooble stitch. Make 'em strong, and they look-a real sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Single stitch is fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUIGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But please-a, Meester Moosaburger, the dooble stitch she last-a forever --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why on earth would I need a double stitch? To pad your bill? Single stitch is fine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking. Thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Struggling to hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm. Contemplating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He absently removes a cigar from his breast pocket and sticks it in his mouth. He holds his lighter under the cigar, not noticing that the flame is pointing the wrong way. He looks at Norville.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Facts, figures, charts! They never sold a newspaper! I read this morning's edition of the Argus and let me tell you something: I'd wrap a fish in it! I'd use it as kindling! Hell, I'd even train my poodle with it if he wasn't a French poodle and more partial to the pages of Paree Soir! But I sure wouldn't shell out a hard-earned nickel to read the dadblamed thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, chief, give us a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suuuure, Tibbs, take a break! Go to Florida! Lie in the sun! Wait for a coconut to drop, file a story on it -- it'll be more of a grabber than your piece on the commie grain surplus! The human angle! That's what sells papers! We need a front page with heart and the whole idea of the 'Idea Man' idea can put it there!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, if we had more access --</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without even looking in its direction, the Editor has slammed down the lid of the cigar box on his desk, towards which one Reporter's hand had been idly reaching. The Reporter jerks his fingers away as the Editor spares the briefest moment to glare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and if a frog had wings he wouldn't bump his ass a-hoppin'! I don't want excuses, I want results! Whack! --</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna know what makes the Idea Man tick! Where is he from? Where is he going? I wanna know everything about this guy! Has he got a girl? Has he got parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody has parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, how many? How 'bout it, Parkinson, you've been awful quiet over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER NEXT TO HIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still waters run deep, chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing that runs deep with Parkinson is the holes in his ears. Yes, the Idea Man! What're his hopes and dreams, his desires and aspirations? Does he think all the time or does he set aside a certain portion of the day? How tall is he and what's his shoe size? Where does he sleep and what does he eat for breakfast? Does he put jam on his toast or doesn't he put jam on his toast, and if not why not and since when? He thrust his face into that of the Reporter.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>...Well?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ahh, you're useless. Yes, Idea Man! Creator! Innovator! Cerebrator! Tycoon!--</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fake.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huhh!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell ya the guy's a phony.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phony, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a three-dollar bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sez who?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Reporter is leaning into another to keep his voice low:</context>
      <utterance>Sez me! Amy Archer. Why is he an Idea Man -- because Hudsucker says he is? What're his ideas? Why won't they let anyone interview him?...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five bucks says she mentions her Pulitzer.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again? You're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...On payday! The only story here is how this guy made a monkey out of you, Al.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, monkey or not I'm still editor of this rag. Amy, I thought you were doing that piece on the F.B.I. -- J. Edgar Hoover: When Will He Marry?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I filed it yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, do a follow-up: Hoover: Hero or Mama's Boy? The rest of you bums get up off your brains and get me that Idea Man story!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, chief... We'll do our best, chief... I'll give it a shot, chief...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the wagering Reporters grins at the other, who is taking out a five dollar bill. The door bursts open and Amy sticks her head in.</context>
      <utterance>Al, he's the bunk. Slam!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll stake my Pulitzer on it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is entering the elevator in his new executive outfit.</context>
      <utterance>Say, buddy! Where'd ya get the new duds?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz is instant decorum as Mussburger enters the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>...and say, buddy! How'd old bucketbutt like his blue letter? Na-ha-ha-ha-ha! Did he bust a gut? Did he die? Did he -- Well, hello, Mr. Mussburger, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville has been worriedly patting at his pockets since the mention of the blue letter.</context>
      <utterance>...How're you this fine morning, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That reminds me, Mr. Mu... uh, Sid. I never did give you that--</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lobby. We haven't got all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he talks, Mussburger pats at his suit pocket, takes out a cigar, inspects it.</context>
      <utterance>Right away, Mr. Mussburger sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the cigar in his mouth and Buzz's hand is right there with a lighter.</context>
      <utterance>Well I'm starved. I understand it'll be quite an affair this afternoon, and the executive roast tom turkey at the Bohemian Grove redefines the word superb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pleasure, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roast tom turkey. Gee, I'm hungry too --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator doors open.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz turns to Norville. He is puzzled but trying to hide it:</context>
      <utterance>It's been a pleasure serving you, Mr. Mussburger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and it's been a pleasure serving you too, uh... buddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger gives an artificially hearty laugh and claps Norville on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Say, Mr. Muss -- uh, Sid! Shouldn't we be a little bit concerned with the downward spiral of our stock these last few days? I mean, you're the expert, but at the Muncie College of Business Administration they told us --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, Norville. It's only natural in a period of transition for the more nervous element to run for cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Sid. Like I said, you're the expert, but --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You don't happen to remember the plan I outlined to you the day I set fire to your off -- uh, the day I was promoted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do remember and I was impressed. Anyway, that's all forgotten now. Driver!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Sid, but the reason I mention it is, it would require such a small capital investment -- again, you're the expert here --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damnit, where's my car!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- But there's such an enormous potential profit-wise given the demographics -- baby boom -- discretionary income in the burgeoning middle class -- A black limousine pulls up to the curb.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- So if you think it's appropriate, I'd like to bounce the idea off a few people at lunch -- Mussburger is getting into the back seat --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And, to Norville's surprise, slamming the door shut behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, tell whoever you want...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCREEEECH -- the CAR pulls away. Norville is left talking to himself on the empty sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>...And I'd like to hear more about it at some point, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Sid, I thought you and I were...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, bud, could you keep the sidewalk clear here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm the president of this -- aww, forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got gas, Bennie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kiddin', Bennie. I got gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya get the special?</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He gives a low whistle under his breath as a woman enters from the street and hesitates by the door, looking around. Still attractive but looking somewhat down-at-the-heels, it is Amy Archer.</context>
      <utterance>Fah from it...</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Enter the dame.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one in every story.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten bucks says she's looking for a handout.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty bucks says not here she don't find one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The woman's eyes settle on Norville, and she heads for the empty stool next to his.</context>
      <utterance>She's looking for her mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She finds him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The woman says something to the counter waitress, who exits.</context>
      <utterance>She sits down.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and awduhs a light lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She is holding her wallet upside down.</context>
      <utterance>She looks in her purse...</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...No money.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Beat. Norville, however, is not noticing: He is staring intently at his coffee spoon, his hat pushed back on his head, his other hand propping up a cheekbone; the woman's presence does not seem to have registered yet.</context>
      <utterance>The mark notices.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He's not noticing, Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't look wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The woman starts crying.</context>
      <utterance>Plan two: Here come the waterworks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yellowstone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old Faithful.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Niagara.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As the woman cries, she accidentally-on-purpose jostles Norville and he finally does indeed notice.</context>
      <utterance>He notices.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The woman mouths words at Norville who reacts sympathetically and waves his hands at the waitress.</context>
      <utterance>He's concerned.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She explains her perdicament, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1 &amp; #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The waitress is entering to set a plate in front of the woman. The woman continues to talk to Norville, smiling wanly at him.</context>
      <utterance>...entuh the light lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got other problems, of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Her mother needs an operation...</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...adenoids.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Veteran 1's enunciation of "lumbago" falls into perfect sync with the woman's moving lips. Norville is listening sympathetically, but he suddenly notices his watch.</context>
      <utterance>No, Bennie: Lumbago.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Norville is rising to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>She's losing him, Bennie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As Norville turns to leave:</context>
      <utterance>He don't look wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She puts the back of her hand dramatically to her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>How does she pull this out?</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She isn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And indeed she does: Faint dead away, falling backwards on the stool, so that Norville has no choice but to catch her. Norville holds her awkwardly, looking around for help.</context>
      <utterance>She is!</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's good, Bennie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A WAITRESS enters extreme f.g. to BLOCK OUR VIEW of the swooned woman and the embarrassed Norville. The Waitress is FACING the CAMERA and the two O.S. Veterans; the CROPPING gives us only her torso and the steaming pot of coffee she holds.</context>
      <utterance>She's damn good, Lou.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get you boys anything else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VETERAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Bromo.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Bromo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry we had to take the stairs. It was just that horrible little elevator boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. You're light as a feather.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still wheezing horribly, Norville staggers over to the couch and deposits her gently on it. He straightens up and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>The couch, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He perches drunkenly on the edge of the couch and puts his head between his knees, still fighting for breath.</context>
      <utterance>Just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Speaking into his knees as he wheezes:</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what came over me. I suppose it was the shock of eating after so long without; the enzymes kicking in after so long, or whatever. But then you couldn't possibly know what it is to be tired and hungry...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hungry, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville rises and starts putting throw pillows behind her head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to bore you with all the sordid details of my life; it's not a happy story...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville jumps, startled, then looks where she is looking. On the white sofa cushion where he had been sitting is printed, in wet ink, right side around: NORVILLE BARNES, President.</context>
      <utterance>...Suffice it to say that I'm jobless -- though not for want of trying, that I'm friendless, with no one to -- thank you -- take care of me; and that had you not come along at just exactly the moment that you did -- She screams, staring down at the couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville stares dumbfounded at the sofa cushion. When the nickel finally drops, he spins around to try to look at the seat of his pants. Distracted but still modest:</context>
      <utterance>Norville, I didn't know you were president here!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unbuckles his trousers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's nothing really. Just determination and hard work...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Of course, when I started in the mailroom last Tuesday I thought it might take more time -- Buzz enters holding a brown paper bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He freezes, taking in the scene: Amy reclining on the couch; Norville standing in front of her with his pants around his ankles, still breathing heavily; the bottle of whiskey in his own hand.</context>
      <utterance>Say, buddy, here's the whiskey you asked f --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leering:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Buzz, just leave it on the desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns to leave:</context>
      <utterance>Happy days, buddy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After the doors shut behind Buzz:</context>
      <utterance>...and I'll tell your secretary you're not to be disturbed. Yowzuh!! He snaps the elastic strap under his chin.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a horrible little person.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Buzz is pretty harmless, really --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville pours a glass of whiskey and brings it over to her.</context>
      <utterance>At any rate I arrived in town not ten days ago, full of dreams and aspirations, anxious to make my way in the world --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little naive perhaps but -- thank you -- armed with determination, a solid work ethic, and an indomitable belief in the future --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I myself -- He crosses back to the desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville takes a cigarette from a large wood cigarette box on the desk and sticks it in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Only to have that belief, that unsullied optimism, dashed against the marble and mortar of the modern work place --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you. Seek and ye shall find, work and ye shall prosper -- these were the watch words of my education, the ethics of my tender years --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- these were the values that were instilled in me while I was growing up in a little town you've probably never heard of --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is pouring himself a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses back his drink, gags, looks at Amy with his eyes bulging.</context>
      <utterance>Be my guest. A little town you've probably --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He waves his arms and talks with a thick rasp as he staggers to his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his exit Amy leaps to her feet and scurries over to his desk. At the top of her voice:</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- I -- executive washroom... He staggers out a side door.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws open the top desk drawer. Inside two lonely lead pencils roll through the otherwise empty drawer. Amy expertly flips a cigarette into her mouth and strikes a match off the desktop.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the washroom:</context>
      <utterance>...Is it your lunch? The chicken a la king?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Amy throws open another drawer, empty except for an appointment book. As she hurriedly flips through page after blank page an arctic WIND WHISTLES emptiness. One page only has a notation: 11:45. Address Wilkie Grammar School Junior Achievers Club.</context>
      <utterance>No, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy shoves the appointment book back into the drawer.</context>
      <utterance>Is the a la king repeating on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She mutters:</context>
      <utterance>...I'm fine, I... You were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hastily stubs out her cigarette and waves her hand to disperse the smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Values... watchwords... uh, tender years...  -- A little town you've probably never heard of...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scurries back across the room as we hear the FAUCET BEING TURNED OFF: she re-strikes her languid pose on the couch just as the washroom door opens. Norville gapes, one hand pressing a dripping rag to his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>...Muncie, Indiana.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're from Muncie?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville starts making pumping motions with his fists and loud syncopated grunting noises. Amy gapes at him. He starts singing, off-key:</context>
      <utterance>Why yes, do you know it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy lamely fakes singing along, coming in louder on the last, obvious rhyme. Norville jumps an octave on it; she quickly follows sit, also pumping her fists. As Norville crosses his hands and locks thumbs in front of his nose to make bird wings of his extended fingers:</context>
      <utterance>'Fight on fight on dear old Muncie Fight on -- Hoist the gold and blue You'll be tattered, torn and hurtin' Once 'The Munce' is done with you!'</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville excitedly sits behind his desk.</context>
      <utterance>...Goooooooo Eagles! Amy awkwardly imitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...A Muncie girl! Talk about the cat's pyjamas! Tell you what, Amy. I'm gonna cancel the rest of my appointments this afternoon and get you a job here at the Hud.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, really, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother to thank me, it's the easiest thing in the world. Matter of fact, I know where a vacancy just came up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Amy:</context>
      <utterance>...Mail room.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...This'll only take a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon to ya, this is Norville Barnes --</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Norville thumps at his pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Barnes! Where the hell have you been! And where's my voucher?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Well, I'm not sure where I --</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need that voucher! I told you a week ago it was important!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look, I'm president of the company now and I --</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLICK. The intercom goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care if you're president of the company! I need that voucher! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, of all the foolish... Listen, do you take shorthand? Are you familiar with the mimeograph machine?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course -- I went to the Muncie, uh, Secretarial Polytechnic! Norville excitedly smacks a fist into a palm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- A Muncie girl! Can you beat that!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I just don't know how to thank you, Mr. Barnes --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he reaches to shake:</context>
      <utterance>Please! Norville!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches for his hand but Norville snatches it away and, winking at her, hooks thumbs in front of his nose and makes wings of his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>...It's my pleasure!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Gooooooo Eagles!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But we PULL BACK to reveal that the girl is now in a newspaper office, demonstrating the fight sign to SMITTY, a reporter wearing a fedora with a bent-back brim. Smitty howls with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Gooooooooo Eagles!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I pulled the old mother routine --</context>
      <utterance>And is this guy from chumpsville?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adenoids?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind her an ancient man wearing an inksman's visor and sleeve garters toils over a large checkerboarded surface over which he shuffles letter blocks and black spaces. Smitty gives a low whistle.</context>
      <utterance>Lumbago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS and Smitty reaches for it.</context>
      <utterance>That gag's got whiskers on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, Smitty, the board of Hudsucker is up to something --</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT PUZZLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without a break in her typing:</context>
      <utterance>Say, Amy, what's a six-letter word for an affliction of the hypothalmus?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smitty holds the phone away from his ear.</context>
      <utterance>-- And it's a cinch -- Goiter -- it's a cinch this guy isn't in on it. How much time to make the Late Final?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still typing, Amy whistles and nods to her shoulder. Smitty tucks the phone into it as she continues typing.</context>
      <utterance>Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smitty is looking at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Chief, just the person I wanted to apologize to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About seven minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I was all wet about your idea man... Well, thanks for being so generous... It is human, and you are divine... No, he's no faker. He's the 100% real McCoy beware-of- imitations genuine article: the guy is a real moron -- To the Ancient Puzzler:</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- as in a five-letter word for imbecile -- Back into phone:</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>-- as pure a specimen as I've ever run across... Am I sure he's a nitwit? Heck, if working at the Argus doesn't make me an expert then my name isn't Amy Archer and I've never won the Pulitzer Prize...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...In 1957... My series on the reunited triplets -- come on down here, hammerhead, and I'll show it to ya...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCIENT PUZZLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy, what's a three-letter word for a flightless bird?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, Morris, I'm busy -- That's right, I said hammerhead, as in a ten-letter word for a smug bullying self-important newspaperman -- To Morris:</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Gnu -- Into phone:</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- who couldn't find -- To Morris:</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- That's G-N-U -- Into phone:</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Morris:</context>
      <utterance>-- couldn't find the Empire State Building with a compass, a road map and a native guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams down the phone. To Smitty:</context>
      <utterance>-- or emu.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smitty bursts out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>...And that's just the potatoes, Smitty, here comes the gravy: The chump really likes me. A Muncie girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she continues to type:</context>
      <utterance>Better off falling for a rattlesnake.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tellin' ya, this guy's just the patsy and I'm gonna find out what for. There's a real story, Smitty, some kind of plot, a setup, a cabal, a -- oh, and say, did I tell ya?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't offer you money.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sawbuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten dollars? Let's grab a highball!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rips the page out of the typewriter, swivels in her chair to FACE CAMERA as we TRACK IN CLOSE and she hollers:</context>
      <utterance>On Norville Barnes!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Copy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Muttering to himself:</context>
      <utterance>Miss Smith, can you come in please to take a letter...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy is bustling in holding a steno pad and a pencil. As she seats herself in front of his desk, he rises to pace behind it.</context>
      <utterance>...of all the cockamamie...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Did you happen to see the front page of today's Manhattan Argus?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I... didn't bother to read the article. I didn't think the picture did you justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The picture was fine! It's what that knuckle-headed dame wrote underneath! Of all the irresponsible... Amy, take this down: Dear Miss Archer. I call you 'Miss' because you seem to have 'missed' the boat completely on this one! How on earth would you know whether I'm an imbecile when you don't even have the guts to come in here and interview me man to man! No, change 'guts' to 'courage.' No, make it 'common decency.' These wild speculations about my intelligence --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- or lack thereof?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drifts into thought.</context>
      <utterance>-- these preposterous inventions, would be better suited to the pages of Amazing Tales Magazine. If the editors of the Manhattan Argus see fit to publish the rantings of a disordered mind, perhaps they will see fit to publish this letter! But I doubt it. I most seriously doubt it. As I doubt also that you could find a home at Amazing Tales, a periodical which I have enjoyed for many years. Yours sincerely, et cetera.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all, Mr. Barnes?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Well, you know me, Amy, at least better than that that dame does. Do you think I'm an imbecile?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure I --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, tell the truth; I trust you and I put a lot of stock in your opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips the cover sheet off a display pad resting on an easel to reveal a large piece of graph paper with a circle rendered onto it. Amy looks, puzzled, from the circle to Norville's proudly beaming face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, you're biased -- you're a fellow Muncian. But would an imbecile come up with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy is bewildered. Norville explains:</context>
      <utterance>...I designed it myself and this is just the sweet baby that can put Hudsucker right back on top.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You know! For kids!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Why don't I just type this up...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aww, naw, Amy, that won't be necessary. I shouldn't send it; she's just doing her job, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know; maybe she does deserve it. Maybe she should've come in to face you man to man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she probably had a deadline...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, but -- she could still have gotten your side for the record!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up to leave, and is heading for the door when Norville adds:</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's done now -- what's the use of grousing about it. Forget the letter, Amy, I just had to blow off some steam...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy turns at the door.</context>
      <utterance>...She's probably just a little confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confused?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know, probably one of these fast-talking career gals, thinks she's one of the boys. Probably is one of the boys, if you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm quite sure I don't know what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know. Suffers from one of these complexes they have nowadays. Seems pretty obvious, doesn't it? She's probably very unattractive and bitter about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is that it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know. Probably dresses in men's clothing, swaps drinks with the guys at the local watering hole, and hobnobs with some smooth talking heel in the newsroom named Biff or Smoocher or...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. And I bet she's ugly. Real ugly. Otherwise, why wouldn't they print her picture next to her byline?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she puts her work ahead of her personal appearance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares.</context>
      <utterance>I bet that's exactly what she tells herself! But you and I both know she's just a dried-up bitter old maid. Say, how about you and I grab a little dinner and a show after work? I was thinking maybe The King and I -- Whap! Amy slaps him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she stalks out of the office:</context>
      <utterance>...How about Oklahoma?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares, rubbing his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Norville Barnes, you don't know a thing about that woman! You don't know who she really is! And only a numbskull thinks he knows things about things he knows nothing about!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, what gives?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Memo. From the desk of Sidney J. Mussburger. Executive order number 530 slash A49. To: Director of the Jacksonville Facility. Copies to: Legal Affairs, Business Affairs, Central Files. Re: Movement of Raw Materials from the Huron Facility. Due to unfavorable news in the slag markets, Jacksonville inventory must be reduced by 15 percent with overflow diverted to the Waukegan Stamping Facility. Memo. From the desk of Sidney J. Mussburger. Executive order number 530 slash A50. To: Director of --</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watchoo doin' down they, Miss Archuh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She straightens and turns. Facing her is a very old BLACK MAN in a janitor's jumpsuit with HUDSUCKER INDUSTRIES/The Future Is Now emblazoned across it. We might recognize his voice as that of the narrator who opened the movie.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? How did you know who I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>BLACK MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah guess ole Moses knows jes about ever'thing, leastways if it concerns Hudsuckuh.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- who are you -- what d'you do here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah keeps the ol' circle turning -- this ol' clock needs plenty o' care. Time is money, Miss Archuh, and money -- it drives that ol' global economy and keeps big Daddy Earth a-spinnin' on 'roun'. Ya see, without that capital fo'mation --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah. Say, you won't tell anyone about me, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't tell no one nothin' lessen they ask. Thatches ain't ole Moses' way.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you know everything about Hudsucker, tell me why the Board decided to make Norville Barnes president.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that even surprised ole Moses at fust. I didn't think the Board was that smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That smart?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then I figured it out: they did it 'cause they figured young Norville for an imbecile. Like some othuh people ah know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why on earth would they want a nitwit to be president?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws a circle with his finger in the air.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause they's little pigglies! They's tryin' to inspire panic, make that stock git cheap so's they can snitch it all up fo' themselves! But Norville, he's got some tricks up his sleeve, he does...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To punctuate, he gives a little jerk of his hips.</context>
      <utterance>...you know, fo' kids? Yeah, he's a smart one, that Norville, heh-heh, he's a caution. Wal, some folks is square, an' some is hip --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...But I guess you don't really know him any better than that board does, do ya, Miss Archuh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe I --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' only some kind a knucklehead thinks she knows things 'bout things she, uh -- when she don't, uh -- How'd that go?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hardly the same --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you don't even know y'own self -- you ain't exactly the genuine article are you, Miss Archuh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, in connection with my job, sometimes I have to go undercover as it were --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean that! Why you pretendin' to be such a hard ol' sourpuss! Ain't never gonna make you happy! Never made Warin' happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Miss Archuh.  ...I got gears to see to.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is answered only by WHIRRING MACHINERY.</context>
      <utterance>I'm plenty happy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As OMINOUS MUSIC SWELLS, we --</context>
      <utterance>Them po' young folks. Looks like Norville's in fo' the same kind o' heartache ol' Warin' had. But then, she never axed me 'bout dat...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't print this!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not, it's all true! The board is using this poor guy! They're depressing the stock so they can buy it cheap!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pure speculation! Why, they'd have my butt in a satchel!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ol' satchel-butt...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know they're gonna buy that stock --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know anything! Fact is they haven't bought it! The stock is cheap, Archer! What're they waiting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy's hunches are usually pretty good, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't accuse someone of stock manipulation on a hunch, Ignatz! The readers of the Manhattan Argus aren't interested in sensationalism, gossip and unsupported speculation. Facts, figures -- those are the tools of the newspaper trade! Why it's almost as if you're trying to take the heat off this Barnes numbskull -- like you've gone all soft on him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Chief, that's a low blow. Archer's not gonna go goey for a corn-fed idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I was out of line. But you're out of line with this stock swindle story. Gimme some more of that Moron-from-Sheboygan stuff --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muncie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. That's what sells newspapers.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got an even hotter story -- The Sap from the City Desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch it, Archer --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about a dimwitted editor who --</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a companionable goose.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, Amy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whirls and slaps him.</context>
      <utterance>...Let's grab a highball and calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smitty rubs his cheek, staring as she storms off.</context>
      <utterance>Back off -- smoocher!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, what gives?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- So we'd gone out to the Hamptons and the garden was in positive ruins!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That must have been quite a disappointment, Mrs. Mussburger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws her head back and roars with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Disappointment? J'etais destroyee! I was in bed for a week! Positively sick with fury! I called in the gardener and said, 'Monsieur Gonzalez, either those azaleas come up next spring or you are terminee!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm brushing up on my French with the most charming man, Pierre of Fifth Avenue. Do you know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't had --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger has ENTERED FRAME.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney and I are planning a trip to Paris and points continental -- Aren't we, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIXING DOWN as they leave her:</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. I'm going to borrow Norville for a while, if you don't mind, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, frankly, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Muss -- uh, Sid.</context>
      <utterance>You have a charming wife, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they tell me. Norville, let me shepherd you through some of the introductions here. Try not to talk too much; some of our biggest stockholders are, uh -- scratch that: Say whatever you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring Norville's proffered hand:</context>
      <utterance>Norville Barnes, allow me to introduce Mr. Zebulon Cardozo, one of Hudsucker Industries largest and most loyal stockholders.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDOZO</speaker>
      <mode>BUSINESSMAN</mode>
      <context>Norville gives him a forced but hearty laugh of reassurance.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit boy, what's this I hear about you bein' an embecile? What the hell is ailin' ya?! A week ago my stock was worth twice what it is now! I'm considering dumping the whole shootin' match, unless I see some vast improvement! Dammit, boy, It's a range war! Either you pull our wagons into a circle or I'm pullin' out of the wagon train!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need for concern, sir; it's only natural in a period of transition for the more timid element to run for cover --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDOZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts peeling off his tuxedo jacket:</context>
      <utterance>So I'm yella, am I?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDOZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His WIFE, a small wiry woman, steps in as Mussburger starts dragging Norville away.</context>
      <utterance>...We'll see who's yella!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CARDOZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he reluctantly starts shrugging back into the jacket:</context>
      <utterance>Zebulon, you mind now and quit bein' sech an ole grizzly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDOZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aww, I wasn't gonna hurt the boy, Lorelei...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thump! Dabbing at his brow, Norville has walked square into the back of a debonaire man holding a martini. The drink sloshes and the man turns testily to face him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Sid, I thought maybe if I showed him the long view we might --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville nervously pumps Findlandsen's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Norville, this is Thorstensen Finlandsen, who heads a radical splinter group of disgruntled investors.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Findlandsen raises his hand to look quizzically at Norville's handkerchief which he now holds himself, apparently having been given it during the handshake. He hands it back to Norville.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Finlandsen, so sorry to meet you -- uh, happy to walk into y -- uh, pleased to make your --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stuffs it nervously into his outside breast pocket as Findlandsen stares at him. Mussburger stands watching in the executive at-ease, hands dug into his pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Norville's hand drops from his breast pocket the handkerchief, perhaps caught on his sleeve, whips out of the pocket and follows his hand down. Findlandsen looks down and Norville follows his look, and stoops BELOW FRAME to retrieve the hanky. Findlandsen leans quizzically forward and peers down at Norville, who continues, O.S.</context>
      <utterance>...I understand your concern about the down-ward, you know, but I think you'll find under our strong new leadership...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>In rapid fire, Norville straightens up into -- crunch -- Findlandsen, whose head snaps back, eyes rolling, a hand pressed to his nose, drink sloshing; Norville, one hand pressed to the back of his own head and the other wildly waving his hanky for balance, takes a staggering step forward onto the toe of an elegantly-gowned MRS. FINDLANDSEN.</context>
      <utterance>We anticipate, in short order, an upward...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FINDLANDSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a drum roll and, as the lights dim:</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going, Mr. Mussburger?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not bad enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be better, it could be worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THREE EXECUTIVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stock's got to drop another five points if we expect to get controlling interest. Norville tells me he's got some hot idea. Can't be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it can't be bad!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't be better if it couldn't be worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and we see that it is indeed Norville, holding a dripping icepack against one eye.</context>
      <utterance>...Norville?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Nothing, really, just... the more timid investors are no longer running for cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does.</context>
      <utterance>Let me look.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid found me the icepack.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me hold it, or you'll have a real shiner.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. People seem to be pretty hot over this imbecile story.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she rolls the pack gently across his eye:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it isn't your fault, Amy. You're the one person who's been standing by me through all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville... there's something I have to tell you. You see, I'm not really a secretary.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that, Amy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that you're not very skilled yet in the secretarial arts. I'm not that skilled as president. Oh sure, I put up a big front --  -- not that everyone's buying it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe in you, Norville -- At least I believe in your... intentions --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't blame them, really. I guess I have sort of made a mess of things. These folks have to protect their investment. Most of them are very nice people --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They gaze out at the city.</context>
      <utterance>Norville, you can't trust people here like you did in Muncie...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Certain people are --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didja ever go to the top of old man Larson's feed tower and look out over the town?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, on farm route 17.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes! In Muncie!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! In Vidalia! Farm Route 17!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh -- Yes. Seventeen. Yes, I -- well no, I -- I never really... There's a place I go now, the cutest little place near my apartment in Greenwich Village. It's called Ann's 440. It's a beatnik bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you can get carrot juice or Italian coffee, and the people there -- well, none of them quite fit in. You'd love it -- why don't you come there with me -- they're having a marathon poetry reading on New Year's Eve. I go every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every year?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods out at the city to avoid Norville's quizzical look.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- this year -- if it's good I plan to make it a tradition. Uh, my it certainly is beautiful --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...The people look like ants.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the Hindus say -- and the beatniks also -- that in the next life some of us will come back as ants. Some will be butterflies. Others will be elephants or creatures of the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a beautiful thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you were in your previous life, Amy?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. Maybe I was just a fast-talking career gal who thought she was one of the boys --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, Amy, pardon me for saying so but I find that very farfetched.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville, there really is something I have to tell you --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That kind of person would come back as a wildebeest, or a warthog. No, I think it more likely that you were a gazelle, with long, graceful legs, gamboling through the underbrush. Perhaps we met once, a chance encounter in a forest glade. I must have been an antelope or an ibex. What times we must have had -- foraging together for sustenance, picking the grubs and burrs from one another's coats. Or perhaps we simply touched our horns briefly and went our separate ways...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish it were that simple, Norville. I wish I was still a gazelle, and you were an antelope or an ibex.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morosely:</context>
      <utterance>Well, can I at least call you deer? Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! Seriously, Amy, the whole thing is what your beatnik friends call 'karma' -- the great circle of life, death and rebirth.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What goes around comes around.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think I've heard of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps his fist into his palm.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. A great wheel that gives us each what we deserve...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sadly:</context>
      <utterance>...Tomorrow's my big presentation to the board. I've gotta show Sidney and the guys that I deserve all their confidence!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Norville --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiss me once, Amy! Kiss me once for luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a peck. They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Norville, sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>...Oh, Norville! She embraces him. They kiss again.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIC TENETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crooning the end of his song.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANCING COUPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn to the bandstand and applaud.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE AND AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the midst of a passionate kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mussburger's forgotten match has burned down to his fingertips. With a wince, he shakes it out. The Board is staring.</context>
      <utterance>...It's fun, it's healthy, it's good exercise; kids'll just love it, and we put a little sand inside to make the whole experience more pleasant. And the great part is we won't have to charge an arm and a leg!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but... What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it have rules?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can more than one play?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think it's a game?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a game?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it break?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #6</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It better break eventually!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there an object?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you supposed to make it fly off?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it come with batteries?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could we charge extra for them?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it safe for toddlers?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you tell when you're done?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you make it stop?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a girl's model or a boy's?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can a parent assemble it??</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you get tired before it's done?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #6</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a larger model for the obese?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you do it around your neck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And finally... what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, for kids! It's... it's ... well, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Board looks at Mussburger.</context>
      <utterance>It's brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles weakly at Norville.</context>
      <utterance>...It's genius. It's just exactly what Hudsucker needs at this juncture. Sure, sure, a blind man could tell you that there's an enormous demand for this, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Congratulations, kid, you've really outdone yourself. Reinvented the wheel. I'm going to recommend to the Board that we proceed immediately with this, uh... with the, uh... that the dingus be mass-produced with all deliberate speed. Of course, as president of the company the ultimate decision is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As furiously BUSY MUSIC STARTS:</context>
      <utterance>Well... I'm for it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll call it the Flying Donut!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Dancing Dingus!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jerky Circle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something short.</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a little jazz.</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Shazzammeter!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Drawing a circle in the air:</context>
      <utterance>The Hipster!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Daddy-Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Circle-o'-Gaiety!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hoopsucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hudswinger!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hoop-dee-doo!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The third ad man, slouched motionless at the typewriter up until now, finally raises his head.</context>
      <utterance>The Hudsucker Hoop!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #3</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fellas. Fellas!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya got somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya got somethin'?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AD MAN #3</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fellas! I got somethin'!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Swish over to Norville, agog, who picks up his phone and, voice breaking:</context>
      <utterance>He's on! He's on the line!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRACKLING VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A half-wipe leaves a split screen with half of the screen remaining Norville, the other half becoming a still of Ike standing in a tank turret, pointing commandingly. Under the photo: VOICE OF GENERAL DWIGHT D. EISENHOWER.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Norville. This is the President...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I just wanted to congratulate you. I'm very proud of you, Norville...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Flash bulb explosion effects a...</context>
      <utterance>...Mrs. Eisenhower is very proud of you. The American people are very proud of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is holding one hand up to shield his eyes from the unaccustomed light. Amy stands next to him, beaming.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, how'd ya come up with the idea for the hula hoop?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was no great idea, really. A thing like this, it takes a whole company to put it together, and I'm just grateful for the opportunity --</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, did you have any idea there'd be such a huge response?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, frankly, I don't think anybody expected this much hoopla -- He is surprised by a burst of laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Hoopla on the hula hoop' -- can we quote you on that, Mr. Barnes?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well sure, I guess --</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, are you thinking of giving yourself a nice fat raise?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash bulb explosion effects a...</context>
      <utterance>Ha-ha-ha-ha. Come on, guys...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A title supered over the Scientist's chest identifies him as Professor Erwin Schweide.</context>
      <utterance>What scientific principle explains the mind-bending motion of this whipping wheel of wonder?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ze dinkus is kvite zimple, really. It operates on ze same principle zat keeps ze earth spinning 'round ze sun, and zat keeps you from flying off ze earth into ze coldest reaches of outer space vere you vood die like a miserable shvine! Yes, ze principle is ze same, except for ze piece of grrrit zey put in to make ze whole experience more pleasant --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, did the board consider you an 'idea man' when they promoted you from the mail room?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess so -- I don't think they promoted me because they thought I was a jerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, what's the next big idea for you and Hudsucker Industries?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, I don't know. An idea like this sweet baby doesn't just come overnight...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, are you --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is smiling as he enters the elevator. As its doors start to close, leaving Amy behind:</context>
      <utterance>-- Although I'll tell you one thing: I certainly didn't expect all this 'hoopla'! This TIRED old joke brings some polite laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash bulb explosion effects a...</context>
      <utterance>...And you can quote me on that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A burning cigar emerges from the lather around Norville's face. It waggles as he talks.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, Mr. Barnes, Rumpus magazine has called you the most eligible bachelor of the year, and the society pages have been linking you with high-fashion model Za-Za. Would you care to comment?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to one side.</context>
      <utterance>There's no truth to the rumors; we're just dear friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Isn't that right, Za-Za?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZA-ZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The newsmen react.</context>
      <utterance>Gr-r-r-r-r-r-r-oww!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ho-leeee!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whither Norville Barnes?</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barnes, whither Hudsucker?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barber is periodically pinching Norville's nose to shave under it; as he alternately pinches and releases, Norville's voice breaks from nasal to normal and back.</context>
      <utterance>How do you respond to the charges that you're out of ideas? Has Norville Barnes run dry?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. Why, just this week I came up with several new sweet ideas. A larger model hula hoop for the portly. A battery option for the lazy and handicapped. A model with more sand for hard-of-hearing. I'm earning my keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of that, Mr. Barnes, do you expect to get a raise?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, by anyone's account I've saved Hudsucker Industries; our stock is worth more than it's ever been. So, yes, I expect to be compensated for that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Addison snuffles.</context>
      <utterance>Pull yourself together, Addison.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You sold all of our stock?</context>
      <utterance>Nobody told me! Nobody told me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We dumped the whole load. Now quit showboating, Addison --</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had twenty thousand shares! I'd be a millionaire now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, we'd all be millionaires. There's no point in looking back. At the time, Stilson thought dumping our position would panic the market, further depress the stock -- then we'd buy it all back, and more of course, once it got cheap --</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs up onto the board table.</context>
      <utterance>Cheap! Cheap! It's never been more valuable! And I'm ruined! Ruined!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting off this merry-go-round!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Addison!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myron!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs down the length of the table and hurls himself toward the window and: Thwok!</context>
      <utterance>Aaaaahhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plexiglas. Had it installed last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Myron?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure, sure, the wheel turns, the music plays, and our spin ain't over yet.</context>
      <utterance>All right, so the kid caught a wave. So right now he and his dingus are on top. Well, this too shall pass. Myrtle J. Mussburger didn't raise her boy to go knockkneed at the first sign of adversity. I say, we made this kid and we can break him. I say, the higher he climbs, the harder he drops. I say, yes, the kid has a future, and in it I see shame, dishonor, ignominy and disgrace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The musicians' playing dribbles away to silence.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it!...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All sit frozen. You could hear a pin drop.</context>
      <utterance>...Nobody move, nobody breathe...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes narrowed, he gazes off into space, squinting for his idea.</context>
      <utterance>...An idea... is coming...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>EXTREME CLOSE ON FLOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the PIN -- PING! -- hits.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deflates. He glares at the tailor.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The musicians resume playing. Everyone else resumes work. The INTERCOM BUZZES and a female voice announces:</context>
      <utterance>It's gone now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Norville leans forward to hit his intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Amy here to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she in the book? -- The door bursts open and Amy storms in.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Pete's sake, Norville!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Hello, Amy -- was it -- I thought she said, Mamie --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes a piece of paper at Norville.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind about that...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You know what those nincompoops in the boardroom are doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wouldn't call them nincom --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to discharge eight percent of the work force here at Hudsucker. Why, in New York alone that means eighteen hundred people out of work, people with wives and children and families --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well yes, we're pruning away some of the dead wood, but if --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you know about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know about it? You think the Board would do anything like this without my authorization? No, this was my idea from the start.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your i --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to be realistic, Amy. You know things have slowed down a little here at Hudsucker --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This was addressed to the chamber orchestra, whose playing dribbles off. They look inquisitively at Norville, then rise to pack up their instruments and sheepishly leave the office.</context>
      <utterance>You're awful kind to yourself, Norville Barnes -- the fact is you've slowed down, sitting up here like a sultan, not doing a lick of work! Why you know it's ideas that are the lifeblood of industry and you haven't come up with one since the hoop and the reason's plain to see! You've forgotten what made your ideas exciting for you in the first place -- it wasn't for the fame and the wealth and the mindless adulation of -- would you get out of here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I've been watching you, Norville Barnes, even though you've been trying to avoid me --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Aim --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shutup! -- and don't think I haven't noticed how you've changed. I used to think you were a swell guy -- well, to be honest I thought you were an imbecile --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Aim --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shutup! -- but then I figured out you were a swell guy, a little slow maybe, but a swell guy! Well, maybe you're not so slow, but you're not so swell either and it looks like you're an imbecile after --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Aim --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shutup! -- after all! You haven't talked to me for a week and now I'm going to say my piece. I've got a prediction for you, Norville Barnes: I predict that since you've decided to dedicate yourself to greed and sloth and everything bad, you're going to lose all the good things that your good ideas brought you. You're going to throw them all away chasing after money and ease and the respect of a Board that wouldn't give you the time of day if you... if you...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Goon looks up from his funnies.</context>
      <utterance>Worked in a watch factory?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh-huh-huh!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shutup!  Exactly! Don't you remember how you used to feel about the hoop? You told me you were gonna bring a smile to the hips of everyone in America, regardless of race, creed or color. Finally there'd be a thingamajig that would bring everyone together -- even if it kept 'em apart, spacially -- you know, for kids? Your words, Norville, not mine. I used to love Norville Barnes -- yes, love him! -- when he was just a swell kid with hot ideas who was in over his head, but now your head is too big to be in over!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Amy --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bodyguard is on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Consider this my resignation -- Thwock -- She slaps him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crack -- Amy kicks him hard in the shin.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Awooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She strides to the door, leaving Norville rubbing his cheek and the Goon hopping around on one leg.</context>
      <utterance>-- Effective immediately!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddy... Ya busy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his eyes and looks stuporously about. Buzz is grinning down at him in his little pillbox elevator cap.</context>
      <utterance>Huh-whuh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like ya nodded off there, buddy! Say, ya got a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh... Buzz... Is it important?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns an easel to face the desk.</context>
      <utterance>I like to think so! It's this little idea I been working on!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The easel displays an oversized sheet of graph paper. Onto it has been rendered a top view, which is a perfect circle, and a side view, which is a vertical line. Norville gazes stupidly at the circle.</context>
      <utterance>...Ya see, I don't intend to be an elevator boy forever! Take a look at this sweet baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces a tall glass of lemonade with a straw sitting in it.</context>
      <utterance>...Ya get it, buddy? Incredibly convenient, isn't it? Ya see --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds his head over the glass to drink from the vertical straw.</context>
      <utterance>-- this is how it works, it's these little ridges on the side that give it its whammy! See, ya don't have to drink like this anymore --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends the straw to drink from it at the horizontal.</context>
      <utterance>-- Now you can drink like this --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville, who has been stewing, finally barks:</context>
      <utterance>...I call it the Buzz-Sucker, get it, buddy? -- After me! Buzz! Why, people are just dyin' for a product like this, and the great thing is we won't have to charge an arm and a --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the lemonade glass, looks at it, sneering.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Why, this is worthless.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville yanks the straw out and crumples it up.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?! But, buddy --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the most idiotic thing I've ever seen in my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but, buddy --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses to belch.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody wants a hare-brained product like this! Ya see, Buzz, it lacks the creative spark, the unalloyed genius that made, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...say, the hula hoop such a success.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, buddy --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you mean barging in here and taking up my valuable time! I've got a company to run here --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, buddy, you were --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I can't have every deadbeat on the Hudsucker payroll pestering me with their idiotic brainwaves!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, I'm sorry, buddy --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz looks over his shoulder, turns back to Norville.</context>
      <utterance>An example must be made!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wuddya mean, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz's jaw drops. His elastic chin strap snaps under the pressure.</context>
      <utterance>Fired! You're fired! Is that plain enough for you, buster!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwww, buddy --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz sinks to his knees, weeping. He clutches pathetically at Norville's pants legs.</context>
      <utterance>And don't call me buddy! Out of here! Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, please, sir -- this job, it's all I got!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand if ya don't like the Buzz-Sucker! Just lemme keep my job, I'm prayin' to ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz stumbles away, still weeping.</context>
      <utterance>We don't crawl at Hudsucker Industries! Get out of my office! Leave your uniform in the locker room!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, buddy... I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As we TRACK IN ON Norville, laughing, there is a low, unearthly RUMBLE, and his face seems to DISSOLVE INTO:</context>
      <utterance>Buzz... off! Ha-ha-ha-ha!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late, Sid. That back nine at Riverdale is really murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, it's a tough course. Well thanks for coming, kid. I thought the board room would be a swell place to chat undisturbed -- it seems we're having some security problems here at the Hud.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya don't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm. Ordinarily I wouldn't bother you with it, but -- this is embarrassing, kid -- it seems to concern you directly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that, Sid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not important in itself -- some elevator boy you fired came to me claiming you'd stolen the idea for the, uh, the hoop dingus from him --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?! He -- no, I -- he's just -- maybe I was a little rough on the boy, ya see I --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is shoving a file towards Norville, who opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Ah forget it, kid, ya don't have to explain to me. He's a little person. He's nothing. Like I say, ordinarily it would just be a nuisance. But it seems -- well, there was a spy in the company...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We TRACK DOWN the length of the board room table TOWARD Norville, who stares horrified at the file.</context>
      <utterance>...Sure, sure, we tried to kill the story. But her newspaper won't play ball... Looks like her story's coming out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We LOSE Mussburger FROM FRAME as we TIGHTEN FURTHER ON Norville, Mussburger continuing off:</context>
      <utterance>...See, kid, the problem the Board'll have... you hired this woman. Kept her on, while she made a chump out of you. Serious error of judgment... I mean, business is war, kid -- ya take no prisoners, ya get no second chances. And a boner like this... I'm afraid when the Board meets, after New Year's, your position... well, it looks like you're finished... stick a fork in ya, you're done... washed up...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Norville is slowly dragging the golf cap off his head.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm sorry, kid. I understand this dolly who betrayed you, she used to be a friend of yours...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Norville stares, perfectly still.</context>
      <utterance>...And this elevator dope used to be a friend, too...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Norville's IMAGE TURNS TO:</context>
      <utterance>...Well, they've got your throat pretty well slit. And when you're dead, ya stay dead. Ya don't believe me, ask Waring Hudsucker... Yeah, looks like curtains. Well, condolences, kid...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't print that!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grins wolfishly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are printing it! She's hittin' the streets this evening --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and she's dynamite!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Al, it's the bunk! Norville showed me his design for the whatsit the day I met him! Why Buzz couldn't have invented it -- look at the man -- he's an imbecile!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Archer, you're a broken record. Fact is Gunderson did design it -- apparently he's some kind of prodigy --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says who?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not the only one with sources, Amy --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith has a source on the Hud board -- very senior, very hushhush --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and I'll bet his initials are Sidney J. Mussburger!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've lost it, Aim. You've gone soft by the looks of it -- soft on the dummy from Dubuque --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muncie!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever! It's no dig on you, Archer, but this story is hot and you're no longer on top of it. Why, it's the scoop of the century -- the other papers won't have the Gunderson dope 'til tomorrow -- The Allemeinischer Zeitung, Le Figaro, they'll be choking on our dust come mornin' --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fools, both of you! It's obvious they're out to crucify Norville! They're trying to destroy him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is near tears.</context>
      <utterance>Amy -- take a break. You've worked hard on this story -- heck, you broke it for us! But it's passed you by and Smith here has taken up the slack.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want slack, I'll give you slack. You're not putting me out to pasture, Al, I quit! Consider this my resignation -- She turns to Smitty --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and swings -- but he catches her before contact, holds her by the wrist, and sneers:</context>
      <utterance>-- effective immediately!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy swings her free arm to -- thwack -- blindside his other cheek.</context>
      <utterance>...Soft.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GERMAN VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dell me vat is first zing droppensie head ven I menzhon ze vord... Zex?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aww, what's the difference.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GERMAN VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Und ven I zpeak of authority?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awww, I dunno.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GERMAN VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eggzplain please ze zignifikanz of ze straw.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuthin', really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANALYST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image on screen cuts to four inkblots. The Analyst sweeps in a pointer and thwoks each image as he comments on it.</context>
      <utterance>Patient dizplayed liztlessness, apathy, gloomy indifference und vas blue und mopey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANALYST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ven asked vut four Rhorschach stains reprezented, patient replied, 'Nussink much,' 'I don't know,' 'Chust a blotch,' und 'Sure beats me.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANALYST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Image cuts to a sine wave on a graph, the top of which is labeled "Euphoria," the bottom of which is labeled "Despair," and a reference line through the middle labeled "Normal." There is an X on the declining side of the wave, near but not yet at the bottom, which is labeled "Patient."</context>
      <utterance>...Patient shows no ambition, no get- up-und-go, no vim. He is riding ze grand loopen-ze-loop --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANALYST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- zat goes from ze peak of delusional gaiety to ze trrrroff of dezbair. Patient is now near -- but not yet at! -- ze lowest point; ven he reachensies bottom he may errrrrupt und pose danger to himself und uzzers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casually puffing on a cigar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diagnosis, Dr. Bromfenbrenner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROMFENBRENNER</speaker>
      <mode>ANALYST</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patient is eine manic-depressive paranoid type B, mit acute schizoid tendencies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He interrogatively twirls a finger 'round his temple.</context>
      <utterance>So patient is...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROMFENBRENNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The board murmurs.</context>
      <utterance>Prezizely. Knots.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prescription?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROMFENBRENNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Electroconfulsif therapy. Maintenance in eine zecure wazility. As he scores each point it is illustrated on the screen behind him: A patient is forced into a straitjacket by two brawny, unshaven attendants; electricity arcs between two leads on a wire cap being wielded by a technician; and lastly, a steel- barred door is slammed shut behind a stooped and broken patient who is led, shuffling, away. Here the FILM runs out, CHATTERING, and the screen goes white. The projector is shut off and the lights go on. The board politely applauds.</context>
      <utterance>Sree sinks! Kommitment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up and we HINGE WITH him to bring the length of the bar into view. Norville dishevelled, is on the other side bellowing.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just get down here -- he says he's a friend of yours... He won't say, but man, is he from squaresville.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a martini! It's New Year's Eve and I want a Martini!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, it's like I been tellin' ya --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barman is taking rolled-up blow-beepers out of the cardboard box and loading them into tumblers to set along the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you served misfits here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, daddy, that's a roger, but we don't sell alcohol.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of bar is it if ya can't get a martini?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a juice and coffee bar, man, like I been tellin' ya --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a martini! On this bar, right now! I've had a martini in every bar on the way down here, and I'm not about to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly enraged:</context>
      <utterance>Martinis are for squares, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts awkwardly peeling off his suit coat.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you call me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You son of a --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks stupidly about, the shoulders of his coat down around his elbows. He sees Amy rushing up.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Oh, it's you! Lookin' for a nitwit to buy your lunch?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville's attention has already left her. He looks for the missing bartender.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Norville, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barman! Set'm up, fella!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville, I'm sorry, I... I tried to tell you... so many times... It's hard to admit when you've been wrong. If you could just... find it in your heart to -- to give me another chance --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Where's that martini?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just give me another chance, Norville -- I can help you fight this thing. I know this last story was a lie! We can prove it! We can --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aww, what's the difference. I'm all washed up... When you're dead, ya stay dead... Hey, fella!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that just about does it! I've seen Norville Barnes, the young man in a big hurry, and I've seen Norville Barnes the self-important heel, but I've never seen Norville Barnes the quitter, and I don't like it! She starts pumping her arms, slowly chanting.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps back off the stool. Norville watches her dully, his head swaying.</context>
      <utterance>...Fight on, fight on, dear old Muncie.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks hopefully for some effect, but after staring at her for a slack-jawed beat Norville can only bring out:</context>
      <utterance>...Fight on, hoist the gold and blue; You'll be tattered, torn and hurtin' Once 'The Munce' is done with you! Goooooo Eagles!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lurches off his stool toward the door. Watching him, despair fights with confusion on Amy's face.</context>
      <utterance>You lied to me! I can't believe you lied to me! a Muncie girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She realizes that, though shattered, he is still the simple innocent she loved --</context>
      <utterance>But Norville... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two loud REVELERS reel INTO FRAME, one of them uncurling a blow-beeper at the weeping Amy.</context>
      <utterance>... Oh, Norville! -- and bursts into tears.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVELER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Newby-Newby-New!</utterance>
   <speaker>REVELER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1959 we dig you the most!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWSIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Norville's hand ENTERS FRAME to push the newspaper away and leave us looking up the empty street. Norville's back ENTERS as he stumbles off alone up the street, pulling up his coat collar as he recedes, the NEWSIE's VOICE continuing:</context>
      <utterance>Extra! Extra! New Year's Eve Edition!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ring out the old! Ring in the new!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The board murmurs appreciatively.</context>
      <utterance>...The barred-window boys are out looking for him now, and we'll see how Wall Street likes the news that the President of Hudsucker Industries is headed for the booby-hatch. Why, when the doc gets through with him he'll need diapers and a dribble cup...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louder murmuring. One board member leers, a trace of spittle at the corner of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>...Let me remind you that our secret post-New Year's party will be held in the office of the President shortly after midnight tonight. Remember, it's strictly stag, so leave the wives at home; we'll be showing some films and, yes, gentlemen, there will be exotic dancers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With an unnatural rumble he straightens his papers and we...</context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's all...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>HIGH NIGHTMARISH DUTCH ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>of the assembled around the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long live the Hud!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville trudges on, faster, sweatier.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>People come and go, laughing, talking, blowing noisemakers, making merry.</context>
      <utterance>Ring out the old! Ring in the new...!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Thoomp!! Norville has run into someone. He looks up, dazed.</context>
      <utterance>...Ring out the old! Ring in the new! Ring out the --</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>It is Buzz, the elevator boy, dressed in an ill-fitting tuxedo and a conical party hat. Za-Za is on his arm, towering over him, leering at Norville.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, watch where you're -- Say, buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Uh... Buzz, I'm sorry, I -- Buzz, you gotta forgive me! I shouldn't a fired you, I didn't know what I was doing! I was a little funny in the head, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, buddy, I don't care about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, that's all forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Mr. Muss -- uh, Sid said I could have the job back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely, Buzz, I'm glad he --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he told me you stole that swell hoop idea from me. What gives!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Buzz --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, that was a swell idea!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Buzz, you know I never --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Sid says you stole it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Buzz --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZA-ZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz swings and Norville hits the snow hard.</context>
      <utterance>Well wuddya waiting for, Clarence -- ? Pop him one! Boffo!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville groggily raises his head.</context>
      <utterance>Think about that, idea man!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSERBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville looks dopily up at the people in furs and party hats starting to gather.</context>
      <utterance>Say, isn't he that lunatic?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville staggers to his feet. The crowd cringes.</context>
      <utterance>...that big-shot faker... the Wall Street fraud guy... nuttier than a fruitcake... they say he's a menace... wuddya waitin' for, call a cop!... We hear SIRENS.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz starts giving chase, followed by the braver souls, followed by the entire mob.</context>
      <utterance>...He's on his feet... We can take him! Norville bursts through the crowd, running.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>runs, gasping, turning a corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Norville, the crowd rounds the corner, led by Buzz. A VAN is SCREECHING to a halt and out jump two burly unshaven men in white, one of them holding open a straitjacket, the other carrying a large butterfly net. They join in the chase. Norville turns down an alley. A DRUNK drooping off a lamppost gaily waves a bottle at him.</context>
      <utterance>...Down here! He went down here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd is running past the mouth of the alley, missing the turn-off.</context>
      <utterance>Ring out the old! Ring in the new!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STATUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mutely -- mockingly -- dignified.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He staggers off to the elevators.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We have COME IN CLOSE ON Norville. A lone tear runs down his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Three... two...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BONG! The toll is right at Norville's ear. Startled, he reaches up to press hands against his ears. Distantly:</context>
      <utterance>...One...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville waves.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is hanging onto the icy ledge by his fingertips. His feet dangle away. Snow falls.</context>
      <utterance>-- No, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking STEEPLY UP.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its second hand is making its descent.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Falling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSSBURGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Descending.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be comin' around the mountain when she comes, She'll be comin' around the mountain when she comes...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gapes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love that tune. How ya doin', kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr... Mr. Hudsucker?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode>ANGEL</mode>
      <context>Presenting himself, he spreads his arms and stamps his forward foot, forgetting that there is nothing beneath his foot to stamp. He lurches forward, momentarily losing his balance.</context>
      <utterance>Ta-daaaa!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rights himself. The halo spinning lazily over his head has been jarred askew. With a flick of his forefinger he rights it.</context>
      <utterance>...Wooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blows a dismissive raspberry.</context>
      <utterance>...How d'ya like this thing? They're all wearin' em upstairs now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats at his robe, produces a white cigar.</context>
      <utterance>...It's a fad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He casually flicks his thumb out of his fist, lighting it. He lights the cigar off his thumb, takes a puff.</context>
      <utterance>...Anyway. I hear you've been having, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pain reminds him that he has forgotten to extinguish his flaming thumb, which he now waves frantically about.</context>
      <utterance>...Been having some problems with the board. The more things change, know what Iyayayeeeeee...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Jesus Christopher -- That smarts... Where was I? Oh yeah, the board. I guess Sidney's been puttin' the screws to ya, huh, Norman?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norville.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm. Well, say what you like about the man's ethics, he's a balls-to- the-wall businessman. Beat ya any way he can. Straight for the jugular. Very effective.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway. Any particular reason you didn't give him my Blue Letter? I mean, Jesus, Norman, just a dying man's last words and wishes, no big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh, geez, Mr. Hudsucker, I apologize, there was an awful lot of excitement and I guess I must've mislaid --</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville reaches in and -- pulls out the wrinkled Blue Letter.</context>
      <utterance>It's sittin' in your apron pocket, right where you left it. Imbecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, geez.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Failure to deliver a Blue Letter is grounds for dismissal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, it's New Year's, I'm not gonna add to your woes. I'm just saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why don't ya read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, go ahead. Might learn somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears open the envelope, reads:</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'From the desk of Waring Hudsucker. To. Sidney J. Mussburger. Regarding. My demise. Dear Sid. By the time you read this, I will have joined the organization upstairs -- an exciting new beginning. I will retain fond memories of the many years you and I --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, it's the standard resignation boilerplate -- go down to the second paragraph.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Norville reads Hudsucker casually examines his fingernails, then pats down a yawn.</context>
      <utterance>'Many years, uh... I know that you will be wondering why I have decided to move on, ending my tenure at Hudsucker, and here on Earth. You will be thinking, Why now, when things are going so well? Granted, from the standpoint of our balance sheet and financials, sure, sure, we're doing fine. However, Sid. These things have long since ceased to give me pleasure. I look at myself now and no longer see the idealistic young man who started this company. Now I see only an empty shell whom others call a 'success.' How has this come to pass? When and why did I trade all of my hopes, dreams and aspirations, for the emptiness of power and wealth? What the heck have I done?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville is interrupted by loud blubbering. He looks up. Hudsucker is weeping loudly into a white handkerchief. He saws at his nose, gives it a loud honk, and urgently quavers in a voice strangled with emotion:</context>
      <utterance>'...Looking back now, Sid, I see that I allowed time and age to corrupt my dreams. Instead of fiercely guarding what was timeless inside of myself, I let the hubbub of earthly commerce erode my character, and dissolve my better self. How is it that some manage to preserve themselves where I have failed? Sidney, I do not know. Perhaps if others love you, you may more securely love yourself -- but I am alone. I loved a woman once, Sid, as you well know -- a beautiful, vibrant lady, an angel who in her wisdom saw fit to choose you instead of I...'</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves his hankie in get-on-with-it circles.</context>
      <utterance>Skip this part...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norville looks down the page.</context>
      <utterance>...Last paragraph, last paragraph.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'...And so, Sid, the future does not belong to such as I -- nor even you. We have made our compromises with time. The future belongs to the young, who may more energetically wage the battle against corruption. Accordingly, in the spirit of hope, and the ringing in of the new, I hereby bequeath my entire interest in the company, and my seat on the board, to whomever is Hudsucker's most recent employee at the time of my demise. I know this will disappoint you -- you, Sid, who have served so diligently and for so long. But --'</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He roars with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>-- tough titty toenails!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He merrily wipes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...That'll show the bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yeah, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'...But Sid, let me urge you to work closely with the new president, and to keep giving Hudsucker Industries all your energies -- but not your soul. For while we must strive for success, we must not worship it. Long live the Hud. Waring Hudsucker...' Norville gives a musingly appreciative nod.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pleased with himself:</context>
      <utterance>...Geez.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hudsucker picks up his lyre and heads back up toward the stars.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. It's all there. Well, see that it gets delivered in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUDSUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeel beeee...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SWEEP SECOND HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lurching forward --</utterance>
   <speaker>PERPETUAL MOTION BALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swinging down --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Amy looks at Norville, startled. After a moment she reciprocates the sign.</context>
      <utterance>What the heck's he doin', Benny?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the heck's she doin', Lou?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Norville and Amy embrace.</context>
      <utterance>What the heck they doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what they're doin' now, Lou.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This I know, Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Our PULL BACK ENDS LOOKING ACROSS an elbow of the bar, TOWARDS Norville and Amy, now in WIDE SHOT. Resting on the bar in the extreme f.g. are two champagne glasses, half-full of fizzing champagne. Norville and Amy kiss.</context>
      <utterance>This you're familia' with.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Geez.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear LABORED, RASPY BREATHING.</context>
      <utterance>...Geez.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>In a quavering voice:</context>
      <utterance>...Y'all right, Benny?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lou also is beginning to sound choked up:</context>
      <utterance>...Yeah, I'm... It's just... It's beautiful, Lou!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Almost weeping as Norville and Amy continue their embrace:</context>
      <utterance>It is beautiful, Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It's the most beautiful t'ing I ever saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A BARTENDER ENTERS to BLOCK our VIEW of Norville and Amy. He is youngish, with a beat goatee, wearing dungarees and a sweatshirt with cut-off sleeves. He looks to either side at Benny and Lou.</context>
      <utterance>It's the most beautiful t'ing I ever saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cats comin' from a party?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cabbies' affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hacks' New Year's gala.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy. Get you anything else? Sangria? Carrot juice? Herbal tea?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny is wearing nothing but an oversized diaper, a baby bonnett and a sash across his hairy chest and thick belly that says "1959." He chucks himself in the heart, cocks his head and sucks in air, then blows it back out.</context>
      <utterance>Bromo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Bromo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The hand reenters to lay down a wallet, and then to deposit a burning cigar in an ashtray.</context>
      <utterance>And so began 1959. The new year...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We TILT UP to show that Mussburger is walking toward the boardroom window. Board members silently remonstrate with him as he tries to wrench it open.</context>
      <utterance>...And the start of a new business cycle. When he learned that Norville owned the comp'ny, ol' Sidney was upset at first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Doctor Bromfenbrenner stands to one side watching, brow furrowed, a pencil pressed to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>...It's a good thing Doc Bromfenbrenner was there...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We...</context>
      <utterance>...'cause he was able to keep Sidney from harmin' his ol' self.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Norville takes a drop cloth off of a piece of plastic on a pedestal. He has the board's complete attention.</context>
      <utterance>...and started dreamin' up them excitin' new ideas again. You know, for kids! The board members look at the design, puzzled.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He picks up the plastic disc and as he sails it we...</context>
      <utterance>...An' that's the story of how Norville Barnes climbed away up to the forty-fourth floor of the Hudsucker Buildin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OUTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As it floats out the boardroom window.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We BOOM UP, AWAY FROM the boardroom, to the great Hudsucker Clock.</context>
      <utterance>...an' then fell all the way down, but didn't quite squish hisself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We FADE OUT on the clock as Moses' LAUGHTER grows distant and END MUSIC SWELLS.</context>
      <utterance>...Ya know, they say there was a man who jumped from the fortyfifth floor... but that's another story. Heh-heh-heh! Ya-heh-heh-heh!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
