<movie id="442" title="Power of One The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The dust the Boy has been watching reverses itself. An unseen vehicle comes up the road.</context>
      <utterance>My father died before I was born, and even though I was raised by my Zulu nanny, with my mother, depending on her health, in nominal attendance, it was decided, with her departure, that I, too, would depart...  ... for boarding school.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Out of the dust a large black Buick ROADMASTER ROARS up the road and into the yard, scattering chickens and geese, stopping in front of the wide-eyed six-year-old and his tremulous nanny. A huge Zulu jumps out of the front passenger seat and opens the rear door. A moment passes, and then two splayed, cracked feet descend from the car and settle into the dust. INKOSI INKOSIKAZI, 100 years old, small, black, wizened, hair and beard whiter than cotton, a leopard skin draped over his shoulders, a beaded fly switch in one hand, a trussed chicken in the other, exits the car.</context>
      <utterance>But before I could be sent out into the world one very serious matter had to be dealt with.  I was a chronic bedwetter. Since my nanny was the one responsible for my well-being, she did what any responsible Zulu mother would do. She called on the greatest medicine man of her tribe -- Inkosi Inkosikazi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Boy jumps, cascading down the falls and into the pond below. He clambers up the first rock. It is slippery. He falls off and climbs back on, buffeted by the spraying water. He makes his way stone by stone toward the other side.</context>
      <utterance>The medicine man instructed me to jump off the falls and climb along the ten stepping stones, counting as I went until I reached dry land.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The progress from one step to the next gets progressively harder as the Boy keeps slipping into the swirling water, coughing and sputtering.</context>
      <utterance>Even though it was only a dream, I felt as if my struggle to reach dry land was terrifyingly real. The water was like ice, bone- chilling, cold, and as I made my way from one stone to the next I could feel my strength desert me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was three rocks in when I ran out of gas. I couldn't pull myself any further. No matter how hard I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A mob of boys, led by a big bully, JAAPIE BOTHA, runs the six-year-old through the bathroom and into the showers, fully clothed. He tries to run out. Jaapie Botha grabs him and throws him back in, holding him with one ham-fisted hand under the shower head and turning the shower on with the other. The six-year-old stands miserable as the stinging water pelts him.</context>
      <utterance>I spoke only English. The hated tongue. The language of the enemy who had usurped power and stolen the country through political chicanery and military brutality.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During the Boer War of 1896, 26,000 Boer women and children were herded into detainment camps by the British, where they died like flies from dysentery,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>7.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The six-year-old in his first soccer game receives the ball. He tries to move upfield, but he is kicked and pushed, the ball taken from him. He gets up gamely to follow the chase, only to be flattened, blindsided by Jaapie Botha.</context>
      <utterance>malaria and black water fever. And it seemed I was destined to shoulder the responsibility for each and every one of those deaths.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no one made this more evident to me than Jaapie Botha, a wheat farmer's son from the Transvaal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other boys chorus in.</context>
      <utterance>God has sent Hitler to deliver us from the English bastards who stole our country and killed our people. Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will swear a blood oath. When Hitler comes we'll rise up and kill the Verdomde Rooineks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jaapie bends down and grabs the six-year-old by the shirt front, yanking him up.</context>
      <utterance>A blood oath! A blood oath!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jaapie slaps the Boy across the mouth three times. Blood flows from his mouth and nose. Jaapie dips his finger in the blood and smears it across his new tattoo. He holds up his bloodied fingers.</context>
      <utterance>With your blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We swear allegiance to Adolf Hitler. Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We swear allegiance to Adolf Hitler. Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chorus repeats.</context>
      <utterance>Death to all Englishmen in South Africa. Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voices come back to him stronger.</context>
      <utterance>God bless the fatherland. Heil Hitler!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jaapie grabs the six-year-old again.</context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives a command. The boys at the far end of the room part. The six-year-old's eyes open in terror.</context>
      <utterance>See what we have in store for you when Hitler comes, Rooinek. Hoy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before he gets two steps towards the chicken he is gang-tackled and held. Jaapie picks up a sling and a rock.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For crimes committed against the whole Boer people. I, Jaapie Botha, the judge and Uberfuhrer, sentence you and your Rooinek kaffir chicken to death. Heil Hiter.!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jaapie starts to swing the sling around and around. The six-year-old struggles to get free.</context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SLING WHISTLES through the air, faster and faster.</context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jaapie releases the stone. It flies true, catching the SQUAWKING, struggling CHICKEN flush in the chest. The flapping stops as blood soaks through feathers.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>11.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jaapie flings his hand forward, victorious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy takes the opportunity to break loose. He rushes Jaapie, whose arm is outstretched, putting him off balance. The Boy catches him low, driving his head into Jaapie's exposed stomach. Jaapie falls back and gets the knife used for his tattooing right in his ass. Jaapie Botha bellows like an enraged bull as he grabs futiley for the embedded blade. His cohorts laugh, thinking it tremendously funny, until Jaapie removes the knife and turns with it, dripping his own blood, his eyes murderous. The laughter dies. Jaapie's breath comes hard.</context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few boys protest.</context>
      <utterance>Hang him up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Botha is murderous, intent on revenge.</context>
      <utterance>Jaapie! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves the bloody knife in the air. Three boys grab the six-year-old and drag him to where the chicken is hanging. Two more boys throw a rope over the same rafter. Others bind the struggling boy, trussing his hands to his sides.</context>
      <utterance>Hang him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys who tied the rope now yank it over the rafter. The six-year-old is hoisted up until he is eye-level with the chicken.</context>
      <utterance>You will pay for the deaths of our grandfathers and grandmothers, our aunts and uncles. All Rooineks will pay and you will be first. Pull!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAAPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the name of Adolf Hitler and the fatherland, I sentence you to die, Verdomde Rooinek.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came to after being unconscious for two days, the rock missing my eye by half an inch. After a week in hospital it was decided I'd be sent to my grandfather's house in the English town of Barberton, at least until passions at school cooled. Jaapie Botha was expelled; sent home to his family's farm in disgrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so the first recorded South African casualty of Hitler's insanity was not a Boer, nor a Rooinek, but a tatter-feathered, half-bald kaffir chicken. PK finishes. The end of class BELL RINGS. Offstage, other classrooms are exiting into the common hall, but no one in St. John's study moves. St. John takes his</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John rises, lecturing.</context>
      <utterance>Very evocative, yes. Particularly the image of the chicken. Good choice there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes roam from face to face, fixing his point.</context>
      <utterance>Any ideology that needs to attack the thing that least threatens it is an ideology that will not outlive its own generation. Inclusion, gentlemen, not exclusion, is the key to survival.  Something our new government should take heed of, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MORRIE, a bright-eyed kinetic, speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Next week we have Mr. Levy who will enlighten us on...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sport and wager in Imperial Rome, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys bolt for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Very apt, Mr. Levy. We look forward to the experience.  All right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>P.K.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PK approaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well-written.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've received notice from the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>14.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oxford selection committee. You are to appear before them in three weeks. I assume you'll be reading a piece of your fiction as your presentational.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A word of caution. Contemporary to most of these fellows means the seventeenth century. Try and keep your theme, um, classical, if you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. I will.  Will the scholarship be decided at the same time, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Different committee.</context>
      <utterance>Money's a different matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John picks up a book and opens the pages. He begins to read. PK takes it as a cue for his dismissal. He goes to exit.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK turns at the door.</context>
      <utterance>And P.K...</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John returns to his book. PK exits.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie consults the book.</context>
      <utterance>How we doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You win and your dream comes true. You lose, we're back to bread and butter sandwiches till term's end. What'd he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My appointement before the Oxford committee came through.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A snap.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a brain like you, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you'll read one of your pieces, they'll be begging you to attend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But will they pay for the privilege?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well let's bloody hope so. It'll be a lonely time without you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrie Levy. Is that the voice of sentimentality I hear coming from you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sentimentality my ass. Practicality. Where am I going to find a sure thing like you to make book on at bloody Oxford?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves Morrie playfully out the door and follows.</context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear Sutcliffe screwed Bartlett's sister when he stayed with them over holidays?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard it from Bartlett's own lips. He's selling reservations for next holiday. A pound for one night; three pounds for four.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You register?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHEERING crowd grows LOUDER the closer they get to the double doors.</context>
      <utterance>For both of us. Took the whole holiday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the double doors. Still in CLOSEUP, Morrie turns to face PK for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Christ! I'm about to have a calf. This bloody Boer gets lucky, we're in the poorhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK is so focused his eyes seem to bore through the doors. He does not move his head a hair.</context>
      <utterance>Now remember. We're not here to exhibit our wares. We go in, we do the job, we get out. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stands explode with cheers.</context>
      <utterance>And at the end of six matches in all weight divisions, the score is Prince of Wales three victories, Helpmakeer three victories.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge cheer goes up for JANNIE, muscular, bare-chested, as he dances and shadowboxes for the crowd. PK enters the ring. He stands, robe on, eyes intent on Jannie. When the noise subsides the Announcer continues.</context>
      <utterance>And now for the final bout to determine which school will win the Johannesburg 1950 public school boxing team championship. In this corner, weighing 140 pounds, standing 5'8", from the Helpmakeer School with a record of 13-0 on the year, Jannie Geildenhaus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the English schoolboys cheer for their man, but PK does not respond. He barely moves. He raises an arm in bare acknowledgment. His attention stays focused across the ring on his shadowboxing opponent. PK watches Jannie dance closely when a low CHANTING begins from outside the stadium -- African, tribal, mystical harmonies of black voices building until the white voices inside the stadium are stunned to silence. The song carries beautifully in the night. For the first time PK's focus is broken, but not like the others in the audience, who haven't a clue as to what's happening. He has heard this before. This is familiar.</context>
      <utterance>And in this corner, representing the Prince of Wales School, the current Johannesburg Public School welterweight champion, also with a record of 13-0 on the year, also 140 pounds, Kid P.K.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK, focused again, meets Jannie at the REFEREE.</context>
      <utterance>We thank the native population for their spirited display of enthusiasm. But now, on to the main event. Fighters to center ring, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fighters slap leather. PK turns back to his corner when his focus is broken dramatically by a face in the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>You both know the rules. No butts, no elbows, no low blows. First man to score three knock downs wins. Let's have a good clean fight. Good luck to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie looks down at Maria.</context>
      <utterance>First row, third from the left. Find out who she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in a bloody war here, in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>19.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams the mouthpiece into PK's mouth as the BELL RINGS. PK turns to an onslaught by Jannie, a real brawler. Jannie's big, overhand rights almost nail PK until he finds his footing and dances away. Jannie comes after him hard, his schoolmates bellowing encouragement. But PK's far superior boxing skills put Jannie at an immed- iate disadvantage. It is a classic battle of a boxer versus a fighter. PK's jabs keep Jannie at an arm's length, until he closes with a combination. Jannie, willing to take three punches to land one, absorbs PK's point scoring combinations and tries to land knockout punches. When he has had enough punishment he lunges into a clinch.</context>
      <utterance>case you forgot. Let's keep our mind on that, hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK pushes off as Jannie hammers at his kidneys. Backing up, PK repays the compliment with two quick jabs to the face. PK works Jannie, turning him left then right, working the angles, keeping him off balance while he racks up the points. Jannie goes left. As PK chases him that way his eyes fix on something out of the ring.</context>
      <utterance>Blery Rooinek. I'll kill you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But PK is seeing double. He shakes his head, trying to clear it.</context>
      <utterance>Get up! Get up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up! Up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>20.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>him, counting.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jannie comes rushing in, banging PK with a series of hard rights, but dropping his left each time he throws one. PK absorbs the punishment as best he can, backing up, dancing away. Jannie is all over him just as the BELL RINGS. Jannie goes back to his corner, triumphant. PK goes back to his and sits down with a blank ex- pression. Morrie goes to work on a small cut over his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK turns and looks at the two Africans at the rear door. Morrie's eyes follow him, tensing as he sees the two men.</context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to do, bankrupt us? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! If they get caught in here they're dead.  What the hell's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, worry about it later. In case you haven't noticed, this Boer bastard is trying to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see the way he drops his left when he throws the right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL RINGS. PK and Morrie trade a look. Jannie comes rushing over and throws a big right. PK steps to his own right side and pops Jannie right over his dropped left hand. He looks at Morrie again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands PK the money.</context>
      <utterance>Here you go, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the treasurer of this company. You hold it. Did you find out what I asked for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>22.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, listen, P.K. You know in this world there is no greater proponent of sins of the flesh than Morrie Levy. But do yourself a favor on this one. Take my advice. Pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the advice. The information please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Professor Daniel Marais.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know who her father is?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? He's the Nationalist Party's resident intellectual. The man is one of the architects of this damned system of -- what are they calling it? -- apartheid? He has about as much use for a Rooinek Englishman rutting after his daughter as the Queen does for balls, pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie sighs.</context>
      <utterance>What's her name and where do I find her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK slips his school blazer on.</context>
      <utterance>Maria Elizabete Marais, Seniors Cottage, Room 22, Devilliers School. They don't call it 'Fortress Virgin' for nothing. You'll never get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to take book on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Already have. Three-to-one says you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took a big position you do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria, frozen with surprise, steps back. PK enters, gently closing the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>May I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to scare you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She speaks in Afrikaan-accented English.</context>
      <utterance>You can't be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know how else to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could be expelled.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>25.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls don't usually come to boxing matches.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK ignores her anxiety.</context>
      <utterance>We went on a dare. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was...  ... exciting. You were very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm glad I impressed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak the Taal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll speak Zulu if it'll help me see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need my father's permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it hard to get?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Impossible for an English one.</context>
      <utterance>Hard for an Afrikaaner boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of a sudden there is a KNOCK on the door. Maria starts. PK moves quickly behind the door as it opens to</context>
      <utterance>How about your permission? Do I have that? Maria blushes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Want to come?</context>
      <utterance>We're having coffee upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to finish this paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They close the door. Maria reinforces it with her body.</context>
      <utterance>Come when you're finished. We'll be up late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't answer my question.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What makes me so important?</context>
      <utterance>There are plenty of English girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is so direct she can only blush deeper. Her response is indirect but affirmative.</context>
      <utterance>The way I felt when I saw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father will insist on meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.S., the outside door to the dorm opens. A matron's voice calls out.</context>
      <utterance>I can't wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATRON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lights out, ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK opens her window and starts to climb out.</context>
      <utterance>Now please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Maria Marais.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, PK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>27.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PK pauses.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember telling you my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't remember telling you mine. PK smiles back at her. He drops to the ground. Maria closes the window and watches him scoot across the campus until he is swallowed by the night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jan Piet Marais. My uncle. At 22 he led a kommando for three years before your people caught him and hung him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My people?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The English.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I consider myself an African, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As do I. As do the Zulu, the Xhosa, the Pongo, the Ndebele. We're all Africans. But all from separate tribes, ay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's the whole tribal idea that creates our problems here in South Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The problems of South Africa, my boy, do not come from tribalism. They come from counter-tribalism. From people insisting that natural laws which have been in place and operating since God's creation, should be tampered with. Does the gazelle sleep with the lion? Does the rhino graze with the mouse? The separation of things is not coincidental. Do you think a Zulu wants to see his culture, his sense of identity, replaced by someone else's anymore than I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. But I don't think he wants being a Zulu to mean he is denied the same rights as everyone else has.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why civilization is defined by the ability to live under the rule of law. Laws define rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But do they define justice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. Justice. The banner behind which the English marched as they gobbled up a quarter of the world? Justice, my boy, is only relative to who's in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how long they stay in charge is only relative to how well they dispense that justice...  ... with all due respect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa, would you like coffee in the library or the parlor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria smiles at PK and exits. He leads PK towards the library.</context>
      <utterance>The library, mein leib.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't figure out if you're brave or foolish.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is that, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come here to ask for permission to see my daughter. Correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And knowing who I am, what I stand for, do you think this sort of discussion is going to put that request in a favorable light?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought a man of your intellectual reputation wouldn't want his daughter seeing someone who didn't think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me give you some advice then. You're right. I admire a keen mind. But intellectual reputation or not, I am first a Marais, a member of the Volk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you're trying to impress a member of the Volk with your intellect, don't do it espousing liberal ideas picked up in an English private school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marais opens the library door.</context>
      <utterance>These ideas I picked up somewhere else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt from an expert on race relations.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, sir, from an expert on cactus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>FIGURE</mode>
      <context>DOC, speaking in German-accented English, moves off from the sun's glare down to PK's level. On his back is a knapsack with a cactus sticking out of it.</context>
      <utterance>Ja. Perfect. You will excuse me, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc clicks his heels together and bows his head slightly.</context>
      <utterance>This I do not normally without permission do, ja? But to catch the expression. After all, it is the expression that is important. Ja? Without the expression the human being is just a lump of meat. You have some problems, I think. I am Professor Karl von Vollensteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand. Doc takes it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm P.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a young person with such an</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>31.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eighteen-year-old PK narrates.</context>
      <utterance>old expression. I think we can be friends. Ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Doc and PK walk the veldt across craggy mountain trails, down dry river beds, through the jungle, always collecting cacti and aloe samples, Doc always talking, always explaining.</context>
      <utterance>That was how I met Doc, as he insisted I call him. A chance meeting between a directionless seven-year-old boy and an old German professor out collecting cacti on the African bush veldt.  So began my education.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc believed the brain had two functions and that the South African public school system unfortunately dealt with only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc and PK sit high up. PK watches the endless animal migration below while Doc points things out across the landscape.</context>
      <utterance>The brain, P.K., has two functions. It is the best reference library ever, which is a good thing to have. Ja? But also from it comes original thought. In school you will get all filled up with the facts. Here your brain will learn where to look, how to look, how to think. And then you will have for yourself all the brains that have ever been.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc knew everything. He had a love of learning. But his real passion was centered around two things -- music and cacti.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>32.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>packs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until he was fifty, Doc had a successful career as a concert pianist all over Europe. On his fiftieth birthday he gave it all up and moved to South Africa. From that point on it was all cactus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc touches a cactus needle.</context>
      <utterance>If God would choose a plant to represent Him, I think He would choose of all plants the cactus. This one plant has all the blessings He tried but failed to give man. It is true. Look. The cactus is humble but not submissive. It grows where no other plant will grow. The sun bakes its back, the wind rips it from cliffs, or drowns it in the dry desert sand. Not a complaint. In good times or bad it will still flower. It protects itself from danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it harms no other plant. It</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>33.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>has patience and solitude and modesty. In Mexico there is a cactus that blooms once in a hundred years and then only at night. That is saintliness of the highest order I think. Ja? From cactus comes medicine to heal the wounds of men and little buttons if you eat one you can touch the face of God or stare into the mouth of hell. It is the plant of patience, solitude, love, and madness. Modesty, beauty. Toughness and gentleness. Of all the plants I think it is closest to God. Ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc was a hard man to disagree with. So when he decided I must spend as much time with him to remedy the flaw in my educational environment I didn't argue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc shows PK a small tree with an even smaller vine attached to it.</context>
      <utterance>Everything fits, P.K. Nothing is unexplained. Nature is one big chain reaction. Everything depends on everything else. From the smallest to the biggest. Always in life an idea starts small like a tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc rips the vine away from the tree.</context>
      <utterance>This tree can grow so high it can touch the face of the sky. But this little vine can choke it and keep it small. Most people are like these vines. Afraid of new ideas. Afraid to let things grow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always listen to yourself. Follow your own idea. If you are wrong, so what? You learn something. And with learning you grow stronger. And if you are right at the beginning? An even bigger bonus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only Afrikaaners to live in Barberton were sent there to work at the government prison, just outside town. Germany had covertly supported the Boers in their two unsuccessful wars against British rule, supplying food and medical supplies as well as ample stocks of ammunition.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Germany was an old friend, a trusted friend. And in a country where a handshake is a friendship and a friendship a bond for life, as the war in Europe grew fiercer tensions in Barberton heated up. Suspicion was afoot. Spies were everywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at PK.</context>
      <utterance>Grammar: satisfactory. Science: satisfactory. Mathetmatics: satisfactory.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>P.K., if there is one thing I know you to be that is a lot more than just satisfactory. Ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't want to be known as a brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think gets beaten up on all the time in school?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands PK the report card, his displeasure obvious. As they crest the hill the cottage comes INTO VIEW along with a parked Army car and two armed soldiers leaning against it. Seeing Doc and PK, the soldiers smarten up, raising their rifles and advancing. Doc's face grows pale, his lips tight. PK pulls close to him for support.</context>
      <utterance>My boy, to be smart is not a sin. But to be smart and not use it, that is sin number one. And as for getting beat up on, use your brain to figure out how not to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc puts na arm around PK's shoulder, drawing him close, comforting him. One of the soldiers pulls a pair of handcuffs out of his pocket as he advances.</context>
      <utterance>Again it begins. The stupidity. Do not be frightened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, even if the scholarship doesn't come through, my old man said he'd lend you the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. All right. We'll call it the 'Levy Carpet Emporium Scholarship for Poor but Proud Christian Gentlemen.' How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your father I appreciate the offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I hate people who can't be bought.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK nods in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Personality disorder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys come to their destination marked by a rickety, faded sign: "GOLDMAN'S GYM." Excitement shines in PK's eyes. He bounds up the narrow flight of stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Undoubtedly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But PK has his mind on other things. His eyes fix on an OLD MAN across the room standing by ringside.</context>
      <utterance>How do they get away with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, he's old.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK leads Morrie across the gym. PK passes an African fighter. He stops training when he sees PK. He turns to another African fighter, glancing at PK. One by one the blacks in the gym stop training to look at PK. PK and Morrie approach the rheumy Old Man yelling at the two fighters in the ring above him in a thick Polish- Jewish accent.</context>
      <utterance>And he's the best. C'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>OLD MAN</mode>
      <context>He moves his creaky body back and forth to demonstrate.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. God gave you two hands so you can knock a man out from either side. Left-right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly turns to the boys. A look of bemusement comes over his face when he sees their blazers.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Goldman?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You boys lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the one who called you yesterday. From the Prince of Wales School?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right?</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, yeah. The champeen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly rolls his eyes to heaven.</context>
      <utterance>The champeen's manager.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know you train here it's not like those nice school fights you're used to. Three knockdowns you win. Just then, as if to underscore his point, one of the fighters in the ring gets caught witha solid shot to the jaw. He hits the canvas inches from where they are standing. Solly, PK and Morrie all look at him, and then at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Oy gevalt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it cost for you to train him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie pulls out a wad of money and proffers it to Solly.</context>
      <utterance>For my personal attentinons, Mr. Manager? Fifty pounds a month. For one of them...  ... less.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly pushes the money back.</context>
      <utterance>Here's for six months in advance. Three hundred pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six months? I don't know your boy'll last six minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly notices that every black fighter in the gym has stopped working and is staring at PK.</context>
      <utterance>I'll last.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>41.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blacks go back to work.</context>
      <utterance>What are you staring? Punch, don't stare. C'mon. Work or you're out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your gear?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go change in the back. We'll see if you couldn't find a better use for all that money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK heads towards the rear. Solly turns to Morrie.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's he want to do this, a nice- looking schoolboy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly breaks up laughing.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to be welterweight champ of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, sure. And I'd like to be twenty-five again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like to make book on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You giving odds?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly gives him a long look.</context>
      <utterance>You name them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly walks away.</context>
      <utterance>You both meshugah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits the bell. The fighters circle. PK's opponent starts punching, jabbing, probing. After two feints he comes after PK in earnest. PK steps left and peppers him with three quick blows to the face. Solly's interest is suddenly piqued. Again the fighters circle. Again the opponent sets up with jabs and again he attacks. This time PK dodges, hits him hard and spins him around, hitting him twice more. A smile appears on Solly's face. The opponent, angered now, gets more aggressive. PK keeps bobbing and weaving, sticking and slipping punches. The opponent unloads, banging away at PK with everything he has. PK backs up two steps, then shifts positions. The opponent's momentum carries him into the ropes. As he comes off the ropes PK throws him an eight-punch combination, demolishing his opponent. PK steps back. The opponent sags. Solly hits the bell, clearly excited.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just start out nice and easy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where did you learn such a thing?</context>
      <utterance>Never I seen someone so young throw an eight-punch combination.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In prison, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly and Morrie head off toward Solly's office. PK watches them go, a small victorious smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>You trying to be a comedian and a boxer? Mr. Manager, come to my office. We'll talk terms. You, get showered, and see me after. We'll talk training.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode>KOMMANDANT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you are PK.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He alludes to the bucket.</context>
      <utterance>I am Kommandant Von Zyl. The professor has requested you to be his visitor so you can continue your studies on piano and he can continue with his studies on cactus. This is the first specimen?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the bucket up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Kalanchoe Thrysiflora.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>44.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hands PK a pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This pass is good for any time, any day. Would you like to see him now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Von Zyl rises and opens the door for PK. They exit.</context>
      <utterance>Come. I will take you myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have cleared a little plot behind the cellblock for the cactus. And tomorrow we have the professor's piano moved here. There is not another instrument like it in the territory. Maybe one day the two of you can give a concert for us, hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then the sound of GRUNTING and THWACKING fills the air. PK passes a room set up as a boxing gym. Through a crack in the door he sees a dozen boys being coached by some guards. Some guards are also being coached by a second man. A third man, LIEUTENANT SMIT, oversees the whole training session. PK watches, mesmerized.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like to box?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Are the boys prisoners?</context>
      <utterance>I would like to learn, meneer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(points to a</context>
      <utterance>No, no. The sons of the guards. See that one there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smit looks down at PK.</context>
      <utterance>We have room for one more on the squad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a little small, Kommandant.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll build him up then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. But I really don't have anyone to spare to teach him right now. You know, with the tournament coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smit looks around the hall.</context>
      <utterance>There must be someone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GEEL PIET comes shuffling over, properly submissive.</context>
      <utterance>Piet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode>BLACK MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You teach this boy basics, and you teach him good or I knock your black head flat, you hear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I teach him best I know, baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We train every day. First thing in the morning. Miss two trainings, you're gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, meneer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come tomorrow. See this old kaffir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, meneer. Thank you, meneer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men step off to the side.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, a word?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, little baas. Little can beat big any day. First with the head, then with the heart. Little defeat big when little is smart. You can remember that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'Specially in front of the guards.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. Don't never call me sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piet. Geel Piet.</utterance>
   <speaker>COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet assumes his submissive posture again.</context>
      <utterance>Kaffir. Towels.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at PK and shuffles off. A BELL SOUNDS.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, baas. Coming, baas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took a big chance talking to my father the way you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. Going in I was behind on points with him. I'm English. I attend a politically suspect school. I'm a boxer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He likes boxers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get on line for the Ferris wheel.</context>
      <utterance>All men like boxers. But not for their daughters. So I had to find some way to make an impression.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have picked a more agreeable topic.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And made much less of an impression. Talk to someone about their passion. Even if they disagree they'll remember you. It was really the most logical strategy if you think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you spend hours thinking about how to deal with me, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>Know what I think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>48.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their turn comes to mount the Ferris wheel. They get into the seat and strap in.</context>
      <utterance>You're dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ferris wheel starts to go up.</context>
      <utterance>When I was little we would go to my grandfather's farm in the high veldt for holiday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father would take me to the top of the highest hill and we'd play this game, 'What Do You See' until we ran out of things to see. Do you ever play that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to try?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ferris wheel stops to let more people on. Johannesburg glitters beyond.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wheel begins to move a little higher and then stops.</context>
      <utterance>I see a forest. It goes on forever. There are giant trees which keep getting bigger and bigger over thousands of years. Now you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see little trees growing on the forest floor, learning to grow with the little bit of light the big trees let in. Now you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wheel stops again at its highest point.</context>
      <utterance>I see the big trees getting bigger, their leaves and branches making one great green umbrella over all of Africa.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>49.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see the sun growing weaker, giving off less light. I see the big trees dying because they cannot live without a lot of light. I see the little trees take over the forest because they learn to adapt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes sparkle, making her irresistible. PK leans forward. Maria turns her face towards him. Her lips part slightly. They kiss tenderly. The CAMERA RISES FROM them TO the star-littered sky twinkling above. The sky goes from black to grey as the CAMERA PANS DOWN.</context>
      <utterance>You tell a very good story.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>That's it. Good. Good.</context>
      <utterance>Can't hit you, can't hurt you. Can't hit you, can't hurt you. Can't hit you, can't hurt you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wear out this old man. See? See how it can work? How little beat big?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. But when do I get to punch?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He demonstrates.</context>
      <utterance>You not going to just punch, man. You going to combination.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One-two. One-two. C'mon. Now you. One-two. One-two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>50.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PK does his best to mimic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc appears in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh do we have a boxer here. Yes sir. We build you to eight-punch combination. The Geel Piet eight. Then you catch afire. One-two. One-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is the next Joe Louis this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Try and hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc takes a half-hearted swing. PK bobs expertly.</context>
      <utterance>No. C'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc sets up and swings left, then right. PK avoids both swings.</context>
      <utterance>No. Try hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm going to learn the Geel Piet eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK points to a nearby bucket.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, yes. But right now you have to come learn the Beethoven Fifth for one hour so we can get to the cactus before it's too hot to plant. Did you bring her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parchypodium Namquanium.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent. Excellent. We make from you a champion and a brain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, big baas. But can I talk to the small baas?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet looks hesitantly from the man to the boy and then begins.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day I see you bring the bucket and in the bottom is some tobacco leaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It keeps the roots wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens to the leaf after?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little I use in some water to make a bug spray for the plants.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet fidgets. He drops his head, speaking low.</context>
      <utterance>And the rest we throw away.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you leave the pail when you go plant is a problem, small baas?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are the forgotten in here.</context>
      <utterance>Is like this. You see how hard the life is for the people here in prison. Only little pleasure they take from this hard life maybe sometimes when no one watching late at night -- a little smoke. Now with the big war in Europe tobacco is plenty hard to get outside. Inside it is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have bunches of leaves at home. I'll bring a whole bucketful tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Mustn't do that, little baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Geel Piet means is it can be dangerous. Something the guards might not want the people to have.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with tobacco? Why wouldn't they want them to have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong is people whose job it is to punish. After a little while it is all they know how to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of a TRUNCHEON on METAL turns them to the door where SERGEANT BORMANN, a side of beef with a sadist's eyes, stands, truncheon in hand. He enters the room and circles the trio.</context>
      <utterance>This is for you to answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pokes Geel Piet with his truncheon.</context>
      <utterance>I smell something not right here, ay, kaffir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, meneer sergeant. Everything okay here. Bormann swings his truncheon into the back of Geel Piet's knees, buckling the little man to the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glares at Doc and PK.</context>
      <utterance>I don't fuckin' believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're up to something I'll find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schweinhund.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet goes hobbling off, picking up towels. Doc and PK go to exit. At the door PK turns.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. This old kaffir's okay. Sorry to make any trouble, little baas. We just stick to the boxing now on. Sorry, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet turns.</context>
      <utterance>Geel Piet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet breaks out a smile he usually keeps to himself and exits. PK looks up at Doc who tossles his hair approvingly.</context>
      <utterance>I leave my bucket on the side by Doc's toilet when I practice piano.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK and Doc exit.</context>
      <utterance>PK, to me you are the champion of the world already. Come. Let us go box now with Mr. Beethoven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK pours it on, laying in the Geel Piet eight. Solly is silently counting.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. That's it. Move him around. Jab jab. Slip slip. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK fires the last three punches like lightning and backs up.</context>
      <utterance>And... one-two... one-two-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The opponent becomes aggressive. PK starts dancing, slipping punches.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. That's it. Now work around the defense. Jab jab.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you get away with this, Mr. G? Why don't they close you down? I mean, there are laws about blacks and white boxing each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WHISTLE from across the gym draws Solly's attention. He and Morrie turn to his office where his assistant stands with the tall black man from the Schoolboy Championships. Solly's face takes on a serious ex- pression. He rings the bell. He turns to Morrie.</context>
      <utterance>In a public match. Not in a gym. Not yet anyway. The Boer is a funny people. Outside the ring the black is not equal. Inside he is. But only in private, not in public. So I keep my mouth shut, the police go a little blind, and that's that. It's a crazy world, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly heads for his office.</context>
      <utterance>Work him on the heavy bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK stops, relaxing. Morrie throws a towel over his shoulders. One of Solly's ASSISTANTS comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Six, seven, eight, nine, ten. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK and Morrie look at each other and head for Solly's office.</context>
      <utterance>Solly wants to see you two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to see us, Mr. G.?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wants to put you in a match.</context>
      <utterance>Close the door.  Someone I got a lot of respect for asked me to make a request.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gideon Mandoma.</context>
      <utterance>A young guy just turned pro.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A black fighter! They want him to fight a black fighter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a black township. Sofiatown.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the question. Not even up for discussion. C'mon, P.K.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>56.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrie goes to exit. PK doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who asked you to ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man who promotes all the fights in Sofiatown -- Elias Nguni.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you trust him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In thirty years I know him, number one on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're both out of your minds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he tell you why he wants the match?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you what he told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just talking boxing -- how do I match up with Mandoma?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty even.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean besides getting thrown out of school and into jail, do you know what else happens you do this? He's a pro. The minute you fight him you're a pro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no purse being offered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good career move. Risk everything to gain nothing. Very sound business sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK exits with Morrie steaming behind. They head for the locker room, PK clearly perturbed.</context>
      <utterance>Tell Mr. Nguni I'll think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well why don't you tell me what you do know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an African myth about an outsider who comes one day and unites all the tribes into one against their oppressors. They call it the myth of Onoshobishobi Ingelosi -- the tadpole angel. That chanting at the school championships?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK begins to disrobe.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't heard it in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how did this honor fall on your broad back?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you about bringing tobacco to the prisoners at Barberton? Well after that was going for a while I learned that even though they could send and receive letters, they never did. They couldn't read or write.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you did it for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And after that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One thing sort of led to another.</context>
      <utterance>A clothing program for their families and a food program.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see where 'angel' would be an appropriate title.  But it was, uh, this Geel Piet who was really behind all of it, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was very good at pointing things out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man like that should be running a country, not rotting in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK steps into the shower pulling the curtain closed.</context>
      <utterance>He's not in prison anymore.  He's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd surprise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you succeeded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Goldman was explaining the theory behind the left hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You may have heard about me?</context>
      <utterance>Beats talking about the weather.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>59.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Morrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly's Assistant whistles for him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. How d'you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, nice meeting you, Maria.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice meeting you, Mr. Goldman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly moves off.</context>
      <utterance>We never had a girl come to the gym.  It's not such a bad thing, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria lifts her jumper a bit, displaying the results of treeclimbing on her knees.</context>
      <utterance>You got a pass to come out on a weeknight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK moves Maria and Morrie off down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Your tree pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you box too, Morrie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I look that daft?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrie's the brains of the operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit the staircase.</context>
      <utterance>He means the bank. Your boyfriend has a great head for literature but none for finance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you, Nguni.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They talk across the narrow street.</context>
      <utterance>I see you, P.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have heard my request?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Why do you make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A woman has thrown the sacred ox bones. She has made a fire and read the smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she read?</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That the Onoshobishobi Ingelosi who is a chief must fight the one who one day will be a chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's not true that I'm a chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows what is true and what is not. The legend of Onoshobishobi Ingelosi is very powerful among the people. They see you box the Boer and always you win. They have heard the stories from Barberton. The people live with little hope. They must see if the spirit of the boy still lives in the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I lose? If the spirit of the Onoshobishobi Ingelosi does not exist in me anymore, then what will they live with?</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Less hope. But still they must</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>61.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment a spotlight blinds them. A police car comes up the alley, stopping in front of them. The POLICE exit, threatening.</context>
      <utterance>see. It is our way.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria is gripped by fear. Morrie is cautious, unmoving.</context>
      <utterance>What's this here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An old family servant, Officer. From home. We just ran into each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nguni reaches into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Papers, man. Come on, be quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you coming from?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gym, sir. I train there.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Police look at each other and share a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I'm his manager.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're the sparring partner, hey? The Police laugh. Police 2, satisfied Nguni's papers are in order, hands them back.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have an hour to curfew and a long way to go, kaffir. Be off.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nguni moves off, no semblance of the proud man in his gait.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, baas. Going right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>62.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nguni turns.</context>
      <utterance>Nguni.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nguni smiles and disappears into the night. PK watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared for you, PK.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Solly's a great teacher. He wouldn't put me in a fight I couldn't handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean about how involved you are with the black people. That scares me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you don't understand them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you did you wouldn't be so scared. You ever have a conversation with a black person?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria's silence is her answer.</context>
      <utterance>Besides a servant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate it when you tease me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her again. This time she responds, kissing him back. The kisses become more passionate, touching, feel- ing. The heat in both of them begins to rise when a car passes, its headlights arcing across the tree, startling them out of their passion. They cling to the shadows until the car turns the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss once, lightly. PK boosts her over the wall and waits until she is safely on the other side before run- ning off into the night.</context>
      <utterance>I better go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lewis reads the last sentence with a tinge of amusement in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>According to your submission you have ambitions to be a writer and the welterweight boxing champion of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you find seeking a career as a pugilist and reading for a degree at Oxford a bit, how shall we put it, intellectually</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>64.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>incompatible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the other Examiners coughs theatrically to hide his smile. Lewis looks down the table at the man.</context>
      <utterance>Lord Byron was a boxer, sir. And I've never heard anyone question his intellectual integrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not recall Lord Byron actually engaging in matches for money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, sir, there are several recorded instances of Lord Byron engaging in matches for quite large sums of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXAMINER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lewis has heard enough.</context>
      <utterance>Quite right. Yes. In a letter to his wife Shelley makes mention of just such a thing. For hundreds of pounds, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's move along, shall we? As your presentational you've requested to read from a work of your own fiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His sarcasm is not lost on PK. PK ignores it, opens his folder, and begins to read.</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, let us hope we'll be treated to the stirrings of another Byron.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Concerto for the Southland and the Death of Geel Piet.  His name was Geel Piet -- yellow Peter. He was a mix of half the blood in Africa -- Dutch, Portuguese, Zulu, Sotha, and who knew what else. His father</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know every time they do that I want to jump up and say I'm just a twelve-year-old. I'm not anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To them you are. You are the one who brings the smoke, the one who writes the letters, the one who puts clothes on their children when they are cold. You are Onoshobishobi Ingelosi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you know that's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc comes running up, excited, waving a newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>Who is to say what is true and what is not true, kleine baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Allied armies have crossed the Rhine into Germany. It is almost over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Geel Piet.</context>
      <utterance>That's great, isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>67.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, kleine baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a good faker, Geel Piet. but you don't think it's great at all. It means you lose your star letter writer and tobacco importer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter that, Professor. We always manage here. What pains me most is I lose my boxer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, kleine baas. You leave this damn place you don't come back never.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geel Piet, when a painter finishes a work of art he doesn't lose it. He sends it out in the world so everyone can see the genius of his creation. This is what you are going to do. And to celebrate the launch of such a work of art as you have made our boxer here, I have composed an entire concerto -- 'The Concerto for the Southland' -- which it is my intention to play in concert for the prisoners before I leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not possible. The kommandant never allow the people to have such a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll think it's a concert for him and the brass. But we'll know, ay? And the people will know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll never let black be with white here, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the black is part of the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>68.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>orchestra, like the piano, he will.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the people have no instruments in this place, big baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have their voices. Each tribe a different voice, a different language -- all singing together. It is brilliant, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except the tribes don't trust each other. They don't even talk to each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. This is correct. This stupid hatred.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEL PIET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will do it for you, kleine baas. You are Onoshobishobi Ingelosi. You bring the tobacco. You write the letters. You put clothes on their children's bodies and food in their bellies. All you do is ask and they all sing for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet smiles as he lifts the watering pot to exit. A truncheon stops him. All turn to Sergeant Bormann.</context>
      <utterance>He's right. Wunderbar. You are the smartest of us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kaffir smarter than all of us? You are a strange German, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That little maniac with the moustache in Berlin you admire. He is the strange German. And soon kaput, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's true you'll not be long for this place, eh, Professor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sergeant. God willing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Geel Piet's hand.</context>
      <utterance>And you, too, little Rooinek. But you, kaffir, Hitler comes or goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He forces Geel Piet's hand closer and closer to a cactus with long thorns.</context>
      <utterance>You are going to stay with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Geel Piet's hands onto the cactus needle. Geel Piet does not cry out.</context>
      <utterance>And I will find out all your secrets once your friends are gone. One slip...</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets go of Geel Piet's hand. Geel Piet removes it from the cactus, bloodied.</context>
      <utterance>I have you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geel Piet takes his watering can and goes.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc and PK glare at Bormann. He smirks and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>You see, Professor, they are not like us. A white man would scream bloody murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PK and Geel Piet appear before various tribal leaders, talking, agreeing, shaking hands.</context>
      <utterance>As the weeks went by and the date for the concert grew closer, my life was a whirlwind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having obtained the cooperation of all the tribal groups, we set about instructing them. Four men from each tribe were taught the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>70.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK and Doc instruct. Doc plays the piano. PK leads the singers. Geel Piet turns the pages for Doc.</context>
      <utterance>intricacies of their group's parts. They were the choral leaders responsible for teaching the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At night the prison hummed with the men in their cells practicing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally the night of the concert arrived. The prison atmosphere, normally tense, was keening. Each prisoner entering the yard is searched. It was prison policy to keep tribal rivalries boiling. Divide and conquer. The policy of control.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>All the prisoners are seated on the ground behind Doc, who is raised with the piano on a small stage. Guards surround the prisoners -- a solid, edgy border encasing a black center. The front of the yard is filled with seats on which sit the Kommandant, his wife, assorted prison brass, politicians, and a smattering of the local Afrikaan Hierarchy. PK is overseeing the seating of the prisoners when Doc comes up to him.</context>
      <utterance>This was to be the first time in the history of the South African prison system that the tribes were allowed to mingle. And if trouble came, it would be the last.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen my page turner?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He asks a prisoner in Zulu.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man shakes his head. PK looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen Geel Piet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kommandant, all medals and polished leather, mounts the stage, signaling a beginning to the festivities.</context>
      <utterance>He will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Bormann? I need Bormann to translate to the prisoners.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Kommandant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem here, Kommandant?</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to address these filthy kaffirs but I don't have a translator.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll translate.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can speak Zulu, PK?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He addresses the prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Listen up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them this concert is the gift to them from the professor who, even though he is in prison, is not a dirty criminal like them but a man of culture and learning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Kommandant welcomes you and looks forward to the great singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For such a man I am happy to do this. But one hair of trouble and it's finish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hopes each tribe will sing its best and bring honor to its people.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One wrong move and you get marched back to your cells and don't come out for a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says tonight let us be one people under the African sky. The prisoners break into spontaneous applause. Von Zyl looks at PK, unsuspecting, pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did a good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the stage over to the professor and takes his seat. The professor sits at his stool, poised. PK, in front of the singers, watches him for a cue. Doc drops his head. PK points to a group of singers. MUSIC and VOICE blend spontaneously. "The Concerto for the Great Southland" begins. Doc plays magnificently with great style. PK focuses on leading the singers. Each section, each tribe singing its own songs with its own distinct cultural imprints on rhythm, pace and tone.</context>
      <utterance>Professor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, Bormann jumps out of the ring and runs off. PK scrambles into the ring and cradles the lifeless, blood- ied head in his lap, and begins to sob. PAN DOWN along Geel Piet's arm to his bloodied hand, holding the snapshot of him and PK. The Concerto grows LOUDER around PK until it enfolds him in its melodies. The voices of Africa, the music of Europe, reaching for a musical and spiritual crescendo.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geel Piet died of massive internal hemorrhage, the result of Bormann's ramming a truncheon up into the little man's body until his entrails spilled out. When I reached him he was already dead. I sat there crying, stroking his head and crying with African</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK rises and goes to exit.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much. You will be notified as to the University's decision by mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK turns.</context>
      <utterance>Point of curiousity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your headmaster told me your work is somewhat autobiographical.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Bormann, he was real?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was justice ever served?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK turns and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Sergeant Bormann died of cancer...  of the rectum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to make a stop first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The night won't last forever, boychick.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly puts the car in gear and drives off.</context>
      <utterance>It'll only take a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The night I escaped from the Tsar's Army it was just like this. Six of us -- four Jews, two Ukranians. Dark as anything. No streets. In the day we hid in bushes. At night we went.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You deserted?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nguni steps out right into the path of the headlights. Solly hits the brake hard, throwing everyone forward.</context>
      <utterance>Whey they come take you at thirteen years old and tell you it's twenty-five years in the Army, it's your duty to desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said the end of the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens Solly's door with some urgency. Nguni sees Maria.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes. Sorry. I drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, miss, welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nguni turns into the township and is swallowed by the dark.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Onoshobishobi Ingelosi.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria takes PK's hand, a little nervous. PK smiles at her confidently.</context>
      <utterance>The people have come from everywhere to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the men?</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The muffled sounds of VOICES SINGING reaches them, grow- ing louder as they approach. Maria is tense. Nguni senses this. He turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>They are to be witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops the car at a door in a high wooden wall guarded by two big men.</context>
      <utterance>No worry, miss. It is the sound of happiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone gets out of the car and passes through the door which shuts behind them.</context>
      <utterance>We are here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see why we have to weigh in. They're going to fight anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to an arch which leads into a big empty room. In the center of the room stands a scale and a dozen Africans, all dressed in worn but neatly pressed suits. Mandoma, the other man who attended PK's fight at school, clad only in boxing gear, waits on PK.</context>
      <utterance>It is very important the people see everything is correct.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you, Gideon Mandoma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you, PK.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want you to know you fight a man. Onoshobishobi Ingelosi is just a name I was given at Barberton Prison. It means nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An old man, one of the dignitaries says something to Nguni.</context>
      <utterance>It is not for you or me to say what it means.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions for PK to step on the scale. PK does. The weight is duly noted. Mandoma then does the same. The twelve men are satisfied. They head for the exit.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NGUNI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions for the others to follow. PK goes to walk with Maria. Nguni pairs him with Mandoma. They exit the room.</context>
      <utterance>It is time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK looks back at Maria who is a bit unnerved, as are Morrie and Solly. He looks across at Mandoma whose face is a mask looking straight ahead, betraying nothing. The two men climb into the ring and stand in their corners. The Old Woman shuffles over and peers into PK's face. She mutters something inaudible, then turns to the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Onoshobishopi Ingelosi. Shobi shobi Ingelosi.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd picks up the chant. She waves and the crowd goes silent. Somewhere in the darkness a single voice begins to sing "Nkosi Sikelel I Afrika" -- the African national anthem. The crowd picks it up. PK looks down to the front row where Nguni sits courteously attending to Maria in a seat of honor among the twelve men in suits. The African national anthem finishes. The BELL RINGS three times. The Old Woman is led from the ring. An Indian Referee in all white enters the ring and waves the two fighters forward.</context>
      <utterance>Onoshobishobi Ingelosi.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK and Mandoma touch gloves and go to their respective corners.</context>
      <utterance>You are listening to me please. When I am shouting break, you must break at once. When a knockdown is coming, it is for an eight count. No heads, no elbows. You fight clean or by golly I am giving you penalty points. Good luck, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly watches Mandoma dancing across the ring.</context>
      <utterance>What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>A very tough fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma comes charging across the ring and begins to fire everything in his arsenal at PK, overwhelming him. PK cannot get away from him and takes a series of devastat- ing combinations which end in a left hook to PK's jaw. PK drops like lead. The Referee starts counting. PK shakes his head clear and rises at eight. The Referee checks his gloves. There is a cut under his right eye.</context>
      <utterance>Watch the left hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, Mandoma comes charging hard. PK defends himself as best he can, trying to counter. But Mandoma's offense won't allow it. He beats on PK until the round ends. PK sits down in his corner. Morrie works on his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, he hits like a truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going for the quick knockout. He can't keep it up. Soon the truck runs out of gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL SOUNDS. PK is hardly off his stool when Mandoma is on him, pummeling him. PK backpedals, bobs and weaves. Mandoma's punches come fast and furious, each one looking to end the fight. Mandoma gets PK against the ropes and bangs away. PK covers up. Mandoma punishes his arms and kidneys. PK swings back and es- capes. Mandoma pursues him. He catches PK with a body chop and then a chopping left. PK goes down again. The Referee starts to count. The crowd is completely silent. The BELL RINGS. PK returns to his corner, shaking his head, trying to clear it. He flops onto his stool.</context>
      <utterance>If he catches me again like that I'll run out of gas -- permanently.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's had it. He's got no strength in his punch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could've fooled me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>82.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- he's taking water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pokes PK's belly.</context>
      <utterance>See. Where that water goes -- you go. Right to here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL RINGS. Mandoma comes charging out. PK goes on defense. He hits Mandoma hard to the head. Mandoma whips around and hits him hard. PK spins and hits the canvas. His vision blurs, doubles. The SOUND of a WATERFALL fills his head.</context>
      <utterance>You put your punches there, you win. You don't, you lose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK rises. The crowd goes wild. The Referee holds up six fingers.</context>
      <utterance>... seven... eight... nine...</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many fingers?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a fight behind on points.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma rushes in for the kill. PK feints and comes up under one of Mandoma's punches, burying a body shot into his gut. Mandoma grunts and backs up. PK pursues him. Mandoma tries to recover. He throws another big punch. PK ducks under it and puts two more hooks into Mandoma's stomach. Mandoma starts to back up for the first time in the fight. PK boxes, jabbing, feinting, pushing Man- doma around the ring, taking control. Mandoma, heading for exhaustion, throws another big punch in desperation. PK hits him with three punches in return. Mandoma swings again with a last desperate effort, and PK buries the Solly Goldman thirteen into every part of his body. PK steps back and with his last punch, puts Mandoma down. The crowd goes silent. The Referee counts Mandoma out. He raises PK's hand. Still, the crowd is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Solly look around at the somber black faces flick- ering in the shadows of the ring light. PK looks down at Mandoma in silence. Mandoma rises unsteadily. He stands in front of PK, staring into his eyes, and then he raises PK's arm above his head.</context>
      <utterance>We're in the shit now. Nice knowing you, Solly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd goes wild, chanting, singing over and over as PK and Mandoma stand in center ring, arms raised.</context>
      <utterance>Onoshobishobi Ingelosi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Seniors Dance is two Saturdays from now. I would like it if you could escort me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maria Marais with a rooinek at the Senior Dance? What will people think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll think what they think and I'll think what I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria touches his face. Her eyes soften.</context>
      <utterance>And what is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK swallows hard. They kiss and embrace. PK caresses her face.</context>
      <utterance>I think I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria beams.</context>
      <utterance>I would be honored to be your escort.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK kisses Maria once more.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't doubt it for a minute. Solly HONKS the HORN.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK stirrups his hands. Maria boosts up to the first branch of the tree. She crests the wall.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a boost.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and drops down behind the wall. PK runs back</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for tonight. You were great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you and your manager first came to me with that meshuganah idea to be welterweight champion of the world you did not have a big believer here. But I gotta tell you. Now you do. In London lives Benny Rosen, the greatest trainer in the world today. When you go to your Oxford I give you a letter to Rosen. Whatever I can't do for you, he can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly pokes Morrie awake.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Mr. G.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK and Morrie exit the car and run back to the school.</context>
      <utterance>And I give the address of a very good bookmaker. Teach you also a thing or two. Now, go on back to being fancy-schmancy English gentlemen. I'm proud of both of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>86.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>for his daily constitutional.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're up early, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best time for walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best time for running too, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John eyes the bruise on PK's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Have to put in the roadwork, sir. You know, keep those legs strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Quite a fresh bruise there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tripped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at their shoes. Both boys are wearing pro- per shoes; not at all what would be worn for roadwork.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should change your footwear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Busted, the boys squirm uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>To something a little more appropriate for...  roadwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John fixes them with a look, and then walks off. The boys bolt into the dorm.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK is surprised. Mandoma nods.</context>
      <utterance>You speak English?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a great fighter, Gideon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second greatest in this room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma shakes his head. He waits for a moment, then begins.</context>
      <utterance>But you didn't come to talk about fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you say to me, Onoshobishobi Ingelosi means nothing, you are right. And you are wrong. The legend gives the people hope for a good tomorrow. But hope alone will not make a good tomorrow for the people. You cannot write our letters, get us clothes, food, work. These things we must do ourselves, so we can be part of this country's good tomorrow. If we are not, the hope will disappear. The people will grow tired. The tired will grow angry and there will be no good tomorrow for anybody -- black or white.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you asking from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be part of something you must know what everyone else knows. We have our own knowledge. We need yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get our knowledge in schools, Gideon. We're not born with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it must be the same with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have schools.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And teachers who cannot do more than their own ABC's. We have a system made not to teach us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am only seventeen years old, Gideon. I cannot teach five million people how to speak English and do sums.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma rises.</context>
      <utterance>You taught the singing to thousands at Barberton Prison. You were only twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a great fighter, PK.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma exits through the window.</context>
      <utterance>Second greatest in this room, Gideon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are asking me for a lot, young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only asking you to put what you've taught us into practice, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are asking me to put the reputation of this school in jeopardy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reputation of this school, sir, is based on its integrity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm aware of that. I'm also aware of what will happen if this ever gets out. We live in a country where the rules are being rewritten.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John regards PK.</context>
      <utterance>Then we'd better be careful to keep a firm hand on our pens...  ... sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. I will allow it on a trial basis. Here are my conditions: you tell no one; you operate at night on Saturdays when the student body is gone; you involve no one besides yourself and Mr. Levy. If you can comply, you can have your school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both take off. Maria runs as hard as she can. PK catches up to her. She strains with the effort. PK crosses the finish line first. Maria trips and falls, rolling in the sand. PK comes back to her. He kneels down.</context>
      <utterance>Ready. Set. Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to let me win.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you'd say I was being condescending.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were guilty of that when you gave me a head start.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK grows uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Get your formal yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dance is only a week away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maria...  I can't come to the dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an obligation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you change it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria cannot believe what she is hearing.</context>
      <utterance>It's a permanent obligation. Every Saturday night...  It starts tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're breaking up with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what could be so important that it takes all your Saturday nights?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria starts to cry. She throws her arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>I really can't say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>91.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>P.K., I love you. Please don't go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you are. I can feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria pulls back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not. I'm just tutoring.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria's sadness turns to anger.</context>
      <utterance>I started a school...  ... for Gideon Mandoma and some others in the seniors library.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm losing you to a bunch of kaffirs?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not losing anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Are you escorting me to the dance? Are you going to see me on the only free night they give us?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maria, this is important to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs off in tears. A pained PK doesn't attempt to go after her.</context>
      <utterance>And my life's important to me. Damn you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>92.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the cliff in full bloom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ach. You see how beautiful?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever hear of glycerine, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Going-To-Oxford-Smarty-Pants. Of course I know about glycerine. Triglycerine. Biglycerine. Monoglycerine. What do you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you don't use it. It's only a little pill under the tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tongues were not made to put little pills under. When I have to start with that, I become something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLAP of THUNDER cuts into their conversation. Thick roiling rain clouds appear suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Well, until you become something else, the little pills would make this easier on your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lightning splits the sky. Rain begins to fall, pelting the escarpment.</context>
      <utterance>Little pills or no little pills -- we don't find cover, we both turn into something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK starts to move horizontally across the cliff face like a spider on a wall. Doc follows. The rain becomes torrential. PK turns to look back at Doc.</context>
      <utterance>Look for a cave. Always in this kind of rock there is caves. Quick! Quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me. Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breathing too hard to reply, Doc shakes his head in the affirmative. PK looks out at the rain forming a sheer wall of water outside. He turns to Doc, who is getting up, flashlight in hand.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exploring.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just rest?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strikes a match. A wind from inside the cave blows it side to side.</context>
      <utterance>Plenty time for resting when I am something else. Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When does a cave have wind? This</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>94.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc crouches down and follows the beam of his flashlight to the rear of the cave where there is a small opening. He shines the light into it.</context>
      <utterance>is more than some little cave, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before PK can say anything else, Doc has wriggled through the small opening. PK, a bit peeved, takes his own flashlight and follows.</context>
      <utterance>Here. See? There is a passage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc stops crawling. So does PK. A DRIPPING can be heard.</context>
      <utterance>You know the pyramids are nothing more than man's attempt to recreate the first safe home our species had -- the cave. It is the ultimate safe resting place. The first place man could lay down and have a good night's sleep without worrying about waking up as something's supper.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc starts moving quicker.</context>
      <utterance>You hear that? There is something waiting for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc squeezes out of the small space. PK joins him in a slightly larger tunnel, the same size as the first one -- stoop height.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope it's not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better, ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that smell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>95.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of a sudden there is a RUSTLING noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc recognizes the sound. He pounces on PK, knocking him to the floor and covering him with his body. Not a moment too soon. For a thousand bats fill the tunnel flying through.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's stopped raining.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who can think about rain when you are on the edge of the great unknown cave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc heads off.</context>
      <utterance>The bats didn't come from a shoebox, Mr. Know-It-All.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I think maybe sending you off to that fancy-shmancy school was not such a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was your idea. Your'e the one who pushed for me to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ja. But who knew they do such a good job of boxing up part of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>96.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>your brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which part is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ahead in the tunnel is a luminous glow, filling an entrance.</context>
      <utterance>The one where is all the questions. The curiosity center. Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc and PK hurry on.</context>
      <utterance>Did I tell you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc, in his own world of wonderment, wanders down into the cave among the stalactites. PK follows, soon losing sight of Doc behind the large crystal columns.</context>
      <utterance>How many hundreds of thousands of years to make this masterpiece? Everything outside can change, P.K. This remains the same. We are in the heart of Africa, P.K. The heart of Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if a person stayed here for 100,000 years what would be</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>97.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>left? Crystal. Like a crystal mummy. Incredible, ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc's preoccupation with death irks him. He studies a piece of crystal.</context>
      <utterance>Incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc does not answer.</context>
      <utterance>I wish we had brought the camera. Think there's enough light to shoot?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His concern rises. He moves through the maze of crystal, his pace quickening.</context>
      <utterance>Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His vision obscured, PK reaches the elevated slab. He clambers up the buttress for a better view. When he reaches the top he stops cold.</context>
      <utterance>Doc? Still no answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc opens his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>This is not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc rises.</context>
      <utterance>This is incredible! The crystal. You can feel the life go right through you. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come try it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's all right. Can we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's the matter, P.K.?</context>
      <utterance>We have only just gotten here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All day long you've been talking about becoming something else, about dying. You never talked about dying before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm 87 next month. It's natural.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc realizes what PK is saying.</context>
      <utterance>Not to a sixteen-year-old it's not. It's painful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc starts to whistle "The Marriage of Figaro" by Mozart. The RESONANCE of the WHISTLING off the crystal sounds beautiful, exotic. Doc beckons PK to join in with him. PK does so, hesitantly. Then pleased with the sound and the feeling, more fully. Doc and PK exit through the stalactites, whistling.</context>
      <utterance>You are right. I am sorry. Sixteen-year-old ears should only hear life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to prepare the coffee.</context>
      <utterance>I'll just set you up with some coffee here, so in the morning you won't have to bother making it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to tell you what</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>99.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>you can and can't talk about back in the cave today. I guess I just don't like to think of you being...</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>There is no reply.</context>
      <utterance>... becoming...  ... something else. I know it's natural law and it's the way it is with everybody...  I just wish it weren't with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK turns to Doc, dead asleep, still sitting up. PK goes over and gently lays the old man down. He removes his boots and throws a blanket over him. PK blows out the kerosene lamp and goes to exit. He is about to hang their two rucksacks on two hooks by the door when Doc's voice turns him.</context>
      <utterance>Doc?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The crystal cave will be our secret, ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc lays down.</context>
      <utterance>Ja. Good. I rest a little.  The heart of Africa, P.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! If someone would have told me this is where I'd be on a Saturday night, last term of my senior year, I'd call them batty.  You know, you're going to owe me for the rest of your life on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That all? I figured you'd hold me to it longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get the insider friend's rate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A black groundskeeper comes walking along, seemingly on his duties. PK pokes Morrie.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, mate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you, P.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you, Gideon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get inside before the whole bloody world sees us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clasps Morrie's hand, first in a traditional hand- shake, then in an African handshake. Mandoma smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Morrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie is taken by his sincerity.</context>
      <utterance>You some great friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group moves out.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go. Stay to the fence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps his chest.</context>
      <utterance>All right, class. I know you don't understand a word I'm saying, but part of learning a language is hearing it spoken. So -- I am P.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the chalkboard.</context>
      <utterance>P.K. This...  ... is Morrie. Now you all have a chalkboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chalk and an eraser. I will say</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>102.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You will write the letter.</context>
      <utterance>the letter. You will say the letter. I will write the letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrie will check the letter. All right? Here we go. 'A'...  ... say it. 'A.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK hurries over to Maria. Not a word needs to be spoken. Her presence says everything.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK hands her the chalk.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you might need some help. Or I can just sit and watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK takes up his position with Morrie, ready to check the chalkboards. Maria takes the front of the class.</context>
      <utterance>Class. This is Maria. She is now the teacher.  We're doing alphabet, from the letter 'A.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are one brave Boer, Miss Maria.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kids PK. PK blushes.</context>
      <utterance>And you are one lucky English.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He playfully pushes Gideon out the gate and closes it. He turns to Maria and Morrie.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Gideon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nice to see you, Maria.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I think I'll go... um... lay on my back and count the cracks in the ceiling. 'Night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK takes Maria around.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Morrie. Morrie runs off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace and kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I am one lucky English.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>P.K. Can I ask you a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have to go in or anything. You can hear the music from outside. I'd love to have one dance with you before I graduate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel so good. Race you to the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a headstart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off. PK follows.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thrusts one of the letters at PK.</context>
      <utterance>We made it! We made it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK looks at his letter.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I couldn't bear the suspense after I read mine. I had to open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three months and we're out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches PK's letter.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dear sir. It is our pleasure to inform you that you have been accepted to matriculate at Trinity College, Oxford,' etc., etc., etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says nothing about the scholarship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another BOY comes over.</context>
      <utterance>A technicality.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St. John wants to see you two in his study.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good news travels fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get showered and changed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanted to see us, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the door closes, BRIGADIER JOHANNES BRETYN, a quiet but formidable man, comes into their line of vision. Trouble is in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Come in. Close the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bretyn just nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>This is Brigadier Bretyn from the police department.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has come to deliver, in person, an order to close the Saturday school.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it is illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're only teaching them how to read and do sums.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have certification to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prince of Wales is a certified school.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But not certified for that</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>107.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sort of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can he do this, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John meets Bretyn's steely eyes. He cannot hold the man's gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I can do it. Would I be here if I couldn't? Come now meneer headmaster. Let's end this now. I have a full day ahead of me still.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Saturday school is to be disbanded until further notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bretyn goes to exit.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, meneer headmaster. Your cooperation in this matter is very appreciated. Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John tenses.</context>
      <utterance>You know it can't go on like this forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can't?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bretyn exits.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just doing my job. And if you'll take some advice, you should just do yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that really the end of it, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the moment I'm afraid it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we let them get away with it on our own grounds, it will never</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>108.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>change. It'll just get worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>History disputes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>History takes too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it does. But it is never kind to those who try to hurry it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel we should resist, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do I, P.K. But this is not a subtle government. They mean to have their way and damn the consequences. And I cannot jeopardize this school, no matter how I personally feel. I'm sorry.  I heard you were accepted at Oxford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Received notification today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St. John looks at PK who remains silent.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uncomfortable silence lingers.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll talk before you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Will that be all?</utterance>
   <speaker>ST. JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll be all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard checks his list.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see Maria Marais please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. She's not allowed visitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if I could just talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK backs away and moves off down the street. He turns the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrie. Morrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at his watch and turns over.</context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see it later?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Morrie out of bed. Morrie groggily starts pulling his clothes on.</context>
      <utterance>No. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, when we get to Oxford -- separate rooms.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there some girl out there waiting for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Stunning. Breasts like casabas. Just waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK throws a jersey into his chest and pulls him out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're fooling yourself into thinking the bastards won't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a church. Didn't you ever hear of the Christian concept of sanctuary?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But I'm not the one who has to respect it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even the Boer has limits, Morrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure he does, but I'd still like to see a big bolt on the inside door.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Caretaker pulls a large deadbolt out of his pocket, with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Levy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK and Mandoma circle. Mandoma throws a jab.</context>
      <utterance>Now move it nice and easy, the both of you. Time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK counters.</context>
      <utterance>They want us to close the school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma lays in a combination.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK throws a combination.</context>
      <utterance>We are still game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are we.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mandoma and PK start boxing in earnest, both smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Would you two find some other time to chat. This is a boxing ring, not a social club.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want to make love to you, P.K. PK's eyes fill with her words. She releases him. They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK leans forward and kisses her, awkward, as if for the first time. As their lips part, their breath shortens. Maria moves forward slowly, lifting PK's hand to her breast. He touches it. The heat builds. Passion overwhelms them. They begin to make love.</context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Africans head toward their desks. PK turns to Morrie.</context>
      <utterance>If you'll all be seated we can begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie's response is to throw the new deadbolt into its slot with a skeptical eye. PK takes his place at the head of the class.</context>
      <utterance>So far so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you all for having the courage to come tonight.  Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A woman whispers something to Mandoma. Mandoma raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I will be teaching the first part of class tonight and Mr. Levy will teach the second.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gideon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDOMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Marais. Will she not be coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>115.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK writes on the blackboard the word "see."</context>
      <utterance>This causes a flurry among the women.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says the word in Zulu.</context>
      <utterance>See.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves his hands, eliciting response.</context>
      <utterance>I see. You see. We see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK holds up a book with a picture of a boy.</context>
      <utterance>I see. You see. We see.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see the boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK holds up another picture.</context>
      <utterance>I see the boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girl. I see the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a KNOCK on the door. Everyone freezes.</context>
      <utterance>I see the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie pulls the bolt, opening and shutting the door quickly. PK and Maria look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>P.K., it's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to say goodbye to my students...  ... and to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>116.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The four women in the class speak in unison.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria smiles, surprised. The moment is shortlived as a SOUND from behind the pews in the rear of the room turns everyone. In the shadows, risen from behind the piles of furniture against the two opposite walls, stand 20 policemen with long menacing riot sticks. Bretyn steps into the light. Mandoma gives a command and the Africans form a phalanx around the women.</context>
      <utterance>We see the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once warned. Twice punished.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're violating the sanctity of the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You are with your damned race mixing ideas, rooinek.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least let the women go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Morrie throws the bolt.</context>
      <utterance>You want everything to be equal, little Boetie. Why not men and women too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to charge out the door, but to his chagrin the door does not open, locked from the outside.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>117.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bretyn smiles cruelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has walked right up to Morrie, not taking his eyes off Morrie's for a moment. Morrie meets his gaze evenly. The moment is broken as Bretyn's baton slams into Morrie's stomach, dropping him to this knees.</context>
      <utterance>Locks keep people out but they also keep them in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs Morrie hard in the jaw, knocking him out cold.</context>
      <utterance>Get up, you bloody commie Jew!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two police lines start to move towards each other, sandwiching the Africans, PK and Maria. Mandoma gives an order. The blacks pick up anything they can to face the inevitable--stools, chairs, a flagpole.</context>
      <utterance>Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Wait. We'll leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too late. You never should have come. At the ready. The two police lines tense to charge forward. The blacks brace to defend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police charge from both ends of the room, yelling, clubs held high. The Africans respond with their own war cry and engage the club-swinging police. A policeman swings at PK who ducks and buries a hook into the man's ribs followed by another to his jaw. The man goes down.</context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>119.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniel Marais steps forward and shovels the first dirt down after it. As Marais looks up he sees PK standing behind the mourners, 20 yards off. His anger replaces grief. Marais advances towards PK, clutching the shovel as a weapon. Several MEN restrain him.</context>
      <utterance>The coffin is lowered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of a sudden a thousand African voices cut through the air, SINGING songs of mourning.</context>
      <utterance>Daniel. No. Marais glares at PK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>120.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're applying to South African universities?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case the scholarship doesn't come through.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK takes the applications back just as a TELEGRAPH DELIVERY BOY comes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you so bloody stubborn? You don't belong in a South African university any more than I belong in the priesthood. Will you take my father's loan?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There a Mr. P.K. here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie grabs the telegram.</context>
      <utterance>It's your scholarship.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sign here. Odd name -- P.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waldo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie scribbles his signature and proceeds to open the telegram. PK snatches it away from him. He pulls the telegram out. His face falls to worry.</context>
      <utterance>You're not one to talk about names.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc's missing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK looks out at the cactus garden, watered now by drip irrigation.</context>
      <utterance>Since his pneumonia last year I've had one of the men drop by once a week to see if he needed anything. Of course you know the professor. He never did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON ZYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK looks at the pegs where the rucksacks hang. There is only one hanging.</context>
      <utterance>At the beginning of the week he wasn't home so I decided to drop by myself. Waited a whole day here. When he didn't come back I sent search parties. After three days I sent the telegram. Seven days is a long time for him to be gone. Do you have any ideas where he went?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>PK turns the sheet to page two which is a whole side of music.</context>
      <utterance>That I love you with all my heart? That you have given me more in our ten years of friendship than three lifetimes could fill? That the last thoughts I have before becoming something else will be of music, cactus, and you? You know all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PK looks down at Doc as a PIANO CONCERTO, beautiful, haunting, BEGINS TO PLAY.</context>
      <utterance>Last night this music came into my head. It is my music for Africa. My music for you. So go. Be welterweight champion of the world. Be a writer. A great writer. Remember -- the only thing between a dream and a reality is you. Until we meet again, your friend, Doc.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Mr. G? Anyone here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PK heads for the office. He finds Solly packing up his mementos from the cluttered office.</context>
      <utterance>In here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Goldman, why isn't anybody</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>124.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>training? What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A repeat performance of history, my boy. Solly Goldman's being deported. Of course last time I didn't have the luxury of being able to pack.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their reason is that I'm here illegal. I didn't enter the country with a passport. Like the Czar was issuing passports to Russian Jews in 1910.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is because of me, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Want a glass tea?</context>
      <utterance>No, boychick. This is because of them. They are the problem, not you. Don't ever think different. You look tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly opens his arms. PK hugs him.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. I have to get back to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your head screwed on right. Don't let these meshuganahs screw it on wrong. Now go on. You want to find me, look at Benny Rosen's gym in East End, London.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Solly waits for a moment, then goes back to packing.</context>
      <utterance>We're not finished yet. PK smiles and exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a very good writer. The subject matter is a little inflammatory but the style is interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands PK the applications as he rises.</context>
      <utterance>I came to inform you that you will not be receiving aid from the National Scholarship Fund. Neither will you be admitted to any of the South African universities. Here are your applications back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARAIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and PK glare at each other, implacable enemies. Marais exits. PK looks out his window, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>I told you when you came to my house. I am first a member of my tribe and I will defend it any way I know how.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't want you here any more than they want me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the hint. Screw the scholarship. Come on. Let's leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a small handbag, throws a few books into it and Doc's picture. He picks up his notebook and packs that too. He goes to exit.</context>
      <utterance>If I leave or if I stay in South Africa it's because I choose to, not because they choose for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morrie chases after him.</context>
      <utterance>Save my place at Oxford. PK exits the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs PK, stopping him.</context>
      <utterance>P.K., goddammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Save my place. Morrie's grip releases.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Halfway down the spout area is a set of six tungsten steel bars called a grizzly which catch all the rocks too large to make it through the funnel mouth to safe haulage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are taken care of by a grizzly, an explosives expert whose job it is to keep the ore flowing, and since when the ore doesn't flow, neither does the money, working the grizzly is a very crucial and therefore very well-paid position. Three months'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? To sign on for a year?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said I was the best you ever taught, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are, boyo. The absolute best.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thomas throws back another drink.</context>
      <utterance>But even the best doesn't survive a year on the bars. Down in that damn tube the luck runs out sooner than later. You may be a genius at reading the rock but you ain't no fuckin' fortune teller.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You worked grizzly a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his hand. It shakes noticeably.</context>
      <utterance>And let me show you what I have to show for it to this day.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's thirteen years after the fact, boyo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BARTENDER comes over and puts another shot in front of Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the lemon soda in front of PK.</context>
      <utterance>One double brandy. One...  lemon soda.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas lifts his glass.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas and PK clink glasses. Thomas knocks his shot back.</context>
      <utterance>On being the best damned blaster ever taught by Ian Thomas. Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender pours another.</context>
      <utterance>Another.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you don't want one?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like the taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taste? You don't drink for the taste.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws PK's attention to the drillers.</context>
      <utterance>Hell's comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches the driller down two more shots of liquor.</context>
      <utterance>Drillers. He's got a powder pain from breathin' too much of that damn gelignite. The pain's bad enough. Mixed with a little alcohol it's fuckin' lethal.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas directs PK towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. We ain't got much time.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they reach the door the behemoth explodes with a roar. He grabs his head and staggers backwards; a mad look comes into his eyes. His three huge frineds rush to grab him. He throws them off as if they were ants. He rips a table out of its bolting to the concrete floor and flings it across the room. The men drinking in the bar, all tough cases, begin to flee. Thomas grabs PK whose eyes stare in amazement as the behemoth struggles against his three massive friends and pulls him out of the bar.</context>
      <utterance>The two most dangerous things you'll ever see in your life, boyo: a hangup of rock that won't blast free on first shot and a driller with a powder headache drinkin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Satisfied with the equipment, PK nods for the box to be closed. ELIJAH, his head man, closes the boxes.</context>
      <utterance>The Africans who come here looking for work are driven by a different desperation--drought, famine, locusts.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>When the boxes are closed the other five men in the crew lift them and follow PK out.</context>
      <utterance>They come and risk their lives to send money back home to the families sitting on the barren farms, starving, waiting for death or rain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PK scales the sheer rock wall of the funnel, his shirt packed with explosives.</context>
      <utterance>Hangups are the worst of it. When the top of the funnel gets blocked up and the ore won't flow.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PK reaches the hangup. He works at taking a prepared parcel of gelignite sticks and jamming them carefully into a crevice. As he does the hangup creaks deeply, shifting, ominous. A few rocks fall. PK freezes, holding his breath.</context>
      <utterance>The only way to unblock it is to set a charge to blow inward. And the only way to do that is to set the charge in mud, which means climbing up to the mouth of the stope and coming face-to-face with the devil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PK finishes setting the charge. He scales down the wall. A large rock is expelled from the hangup and comes bouncing down the sides to the funnel, just missing PK, crashing through the bars below. PK freezes. Elijah holds his breath. The crew in the safty tunnel quakes. Nothing happens. PK comes down the rest of the way. He takes the cordtex rope dangling from the bomb and inserts a fuse. He nods to Elijah. Elijah lights a cheesa stick. He hands the glowing stick to PK. PK waves towards the tunnel. One of the Africans sounds the WARNING WHISTLE. Two blasts followed by two blasts. PK nods for Elijah to be off. Elijah stands his ground.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes the rock doesn't need the provocation of explosives. Sometimes the earth shifts...  a pebble moves...  you talk too loud...  and in the moment before you are turned into something else by fifty tons of rock you understand why it is called grizzly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIJAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK lights the fuse. Elijah takes off like a scared rabbit for the safety of the shaft. PK is right on his tail. The fuse travels quickly toward the bomb.</context>
      <utterance>I wait for you, baas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Happy, the Africans lift shovels and crowbars to clear the bars. As they pass PK they touch him reverentially as one would an icon.</context>
      <utterance>Let's clean her off and call it a night, hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Africans think the longer you survive the luckier you are. And the luckier you are the longer you survive. I know there's something inherently wrong with their logic. Still, I'm beginning to see their point. Especially with less than six months to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOCKO, the bookmaker, enters.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ay, man. If you'd let him win once in a while we could take a little book on it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't care if he wins. He just likes to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why I'm about visiting you. You've come on the board, man. There are odds on your making it or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in your favor, my boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you telling me this, Jocko?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's an omen.</context>
      <utterance>When you come up on the boards, boyo, it's time to bow out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bow out you can't make book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PK, it's not a bet I want to collect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Jocko, how high will the odds go on something like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shorter your time, the higher they go. With you probably ten, twelve, thirteen to one when you're short a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the odds hit the top put me in against all bets for two hundred quid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not come here to solicit your bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that. I appreciate it. But if you don't take it, someone else will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. You're a bleery fool. And I'll be prayin' every night it's the only bet I ever have to pay off on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jocko rises to exit.</context>
      <utterance>And so will I.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should let him win once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasputin says something in Russian as he moves a piece, excited to have taken one of PK's pieces. PK turns and checkmates him.</context>
      <utterance>When he wins it won't be because I let him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasputin laughs, speaks in Russian, and starts to set the board up again. Jocko exits.</context>
      <utterance>Checkmate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear a blast whistle?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIJAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then after a moment the vague sound of a drill leaps through the rock.</context>
      <utterance>No, baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Africans get nervous. They chatter to one another.</context>
      <utterance>I never heard a drill at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK moves forward. The Africans follow him out of the elevator with reluctance.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a ghost. It's just some driller trying to squeeze extra pay. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELIJAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a tremor of fear in his voice. PK follows Elijah's face upwards to a hangup.</context>
      <utterance>Baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the first bloody thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIJAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad sign, baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come on. Let's get it going.</context>
      <utterance>Bad drilling's more like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIJAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK heeds the warning, somberly. He takes the bomb from Elijah and starts to climb the wall. TRACK with PK as he makes it up to the hangup. He quickly seals the bomb and drops the cordtex.</context>
      <utterance>They say juju. Bad magic is in the mine tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK holds his hand out for the cheesa stick. Elijah lights the flare. He goes to hand it to PK. PK notices Elijah's hands shaking. He sees the fear in Elijah's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>She's playing with us tonight. Fuse set? Elijah nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIJAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stay with you, baas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elijah, released from his responsibility, retreats quickly. PK stands holding the flare, a little distracted by Elijah's fear, wondering. Elijah sounds the BLAST WHISTLE.</context>
      <utterance>That's an order.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MUFFLED BLAST comes from the other side of the hangup deep in the stope. PK freezes, confused, and then a SECOND BLAST goes off. The hangups starts to give. And</context>
      <utterance>One... two... three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MINER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead. No doubt about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You give me a fair odds on ten quid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it a sixer and you got me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone else? Six to one he's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MINER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says someone was up there. Blasted it out on PK from the other side?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the driller?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Botha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses a fat wad of cash on PK's bed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, look at ya now, boyo. Up and at 'em in no time. And rich as a fuckin' lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your ticket to ride. Two hundred quid at fourteen to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I didn't make it. I'm a month short.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not according to managment. They cashed you out at twelve months for eleven worked. Last thirty days was bonus. And until someone shows me a calendar reads different, twelve months and a year are one and the same kind of thing. And the bet was for a year. So get yourself mended and get your ass out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jocko grows uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>There's someone I have to see first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to go pressin' it for? You're rich, lad. You're whole. Why do you want to go pressin' it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what? That the man has</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>146.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>blasted so much gelignite he's permanently deranged in the attic? That even the other drillers leave the bar when the man drinks, so crazed does he get. All right. He tried to kill you. But he didn't. You're alive is all that matters. Do us all a favor, boyo. Get out of here. Get on a train and don't come back. We've no liking to be burying someone we're all so fond of.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasputin moves a chesspiece and bellows.</context>
      <utterance>No worries. The luckier you are, the longer you last. The longer you last, the luckier you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASPUTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is ecstatic, bubbling with his joy. Laughter springs from him. Jocko and PK trade a look.</context>
      <utterance>Checkmate! Checkmate!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jocko exits.</context>
      <utterance>There's an end to everything, boyo. Even luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasputin speaks urgently in Russian.</context>
      <utterance>Well I guess this is goodbye, my friend. I'll never forget you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASPUTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK does not respond.</context>
      <utterance>PK. Botha. Nyet, nyet. Nyet, Botha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>147.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grasps Rasputin's bandaged hand to shake it. Rasputin takes him around in a huge bear hug, smothering him. Pk survives, a bit rumpled. He smiles at Rasputin and exits. As he walks away,</context>
      <utterance>Take care, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASPUTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK turns the corner and is gone.</context>
      <utterance>PK. Botha. Nyet. Nyet. PK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DRILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you lookin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Botha. The driller from stope number five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's at the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driller enters his hut. PK absorbs the warning.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't disturb him. There's a reason he's there and we're here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>148.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ja?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Botha the driller in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ja. Always we give him one hour alone before we open. You don't know this because you work at night, but it is the rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK regards them for a moment and then enters the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Ja. In one hour it is pffft. He motions a man falling on his face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Botha does not turn around.</context>
      <utterance>Are you Botha?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ja.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm PK. I worked your grizzly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ja.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Botha turns slowly to reveal his face, swollen with anger and drink. He tears the short sleeve off his left arm, revealing a crudely tattooed swastika.</context>
      <utterance>Why'd you try to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I missed the first time, rooinek.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jaapie Botha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>149.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Botha rises drunkenly. PK backs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember, rooinek.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Botha. It was thirteen years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws back another drink and rushes PK with a roar. PK sidesteps and heads for the door. Botha gets there first and bolts it.</context>
      <utterance>Because of you they expelled me. Because of you my father beat me. Threw me out from the farm. Because of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Botha. We've made a lot of money working together. Let the past be the past.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes PK again. Again PK sidesteps.</context>
      <utterance>You ruined the country, all you rooineks. You come and ruin the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Jaapie Botha. It's hate ruining the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings at PK. PK ducks.</context>
      <utterance>Jaah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boer hate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment the powder headache strikes. Botha bellows, grabbing his head staggering backward. PK runs for the door. As he reaches it a table slams against it, thrown halfway across the room by a powder-mad Botha.</context>
      <utterance>Our country.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Botha feels the punches. He steps back, faltering. PK pursues him.</context>
      <utterance>Want to see the wages of hate?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK hammers away, punching with each word, harder and faster.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Here is what hate gets you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Botha is out on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>For my chicken. For Geel Piet. For Doc. For Mandoma. For Maria.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PK unleashes a final pjnch -- the hardest one he ever threw. It catches Botha square in the jaw. Botha goes over onto his back like a tree falling. The crowd outside screams and yells with delight. Money changes hands. PK collects himself and steps over Botha. He unbolts the door and steps outside.</context>
      <utterance>For Africa.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
