<movie id="479" title="Searchers The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes shift to Martha and hold. Ethan is, and always has been, in love with his brother's wife and she with him.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Aaron...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martha...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan slowly, stiffly swings out of the saddle. Aaron and Martha exchange quick glances... troubled, puzzled. Aaron pastes on an uncertain smile as Ethan comes around his horse toward their side.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's California?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How should I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Mose Harper said...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to his saddle pack, begins unlacing it. Ben and Debbie have inched closer -- half-shy, half-curious. Debbie's dog begins sniffing at his heels. Ethan looks down at them - not unfriendly, just a man not used to children.</context>
      <utterance>That old goat still creakin' around?... Whyn't someone bury him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben nods.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, ain't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy, you ain't much bigger than when I saw you last.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan looks in the direction of the pointing finger.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Deborah!  She's Lucy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy's going on seventeen now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' she's got a beau! Kisses him, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough... Go on inside and help Lucy set the table... You, too, Deborah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin!... Here we've been standing... Ethan, you haven't forgotten Martin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... Mistook you for a half-breed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite... Quarter Cherokee. The rest is Welsh... So they tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've done a lot of growin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Ethan found you squallin' in a sage clump after your folks was massacred...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just happened to be me... No need to make any more of it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, he starts to lead away.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of your horse for you, Uncle Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stops again.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He completes unlacing the pack and takes it -- treating it as though it contained something of value. Martin watches with a touch of resentment: Ethan doesn't trust him. Ethan turns and sees the look. He doesn't care what Martin thinks, nor does he explain. Martin leads the horse off.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates, then grudgingly surrenders it -- conscious of its sorry condition.</context>
      <utterance>Supper'll be ready by the time you wash up... Let me take your coat for you, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just nods, then turns to follow Aaron around the side of the house toward the wash-up.</context>
      <utterance>And... welcome home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clock rattles alarmingly -- the usual preliminary to its striking; and then it bangs out the strokes like a fire-alarm gong. Eight fast clangs.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben! Deborah! Bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've got to help with the dishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight... Ben, put that sword back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a sword, ma... it's a saber!  Did you kill many damYankees with this sabre, Uncle Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many damYankees, Uncle Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin nods and crosses to kiss Martha good night.</context>
      <utterance>Ben!... Martin, he'll sleep in the bunkhouse with you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan doesn't like being called Uncle -- as we must know from the quick look he shoots at Martin. But he acknowledges it.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Aunt Martha... Uncle Aaron...  Good night, Uncle Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben reluctantly puts the scabbard away, turns to Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you tell me tomorrow about the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war ended three years ago, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It did?... Then whyn't you come home before now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ben reluctantly heads out with Martin, Deborah crosses to Ethan's side and studies him gravely.</context>
      <utterance>BEN!... Go 'long with Martin. MARCH!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy's wearing the gold locket you gave her when she was a little girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She don't wear it much account of it makes her neck green.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deborah!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan looks at her gravely.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it does... But I wouldn't care if you gave me a gold locket if it made my neck green or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to where his pack is -- a side table or something -- and burrows into it. Debbie is at his side.</context>
      <utterance>'Fraid I...  Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a gold medal or medallion -- something appropriate to Maximilian of Mexico -- suspended by a long multi-colored satin ribbon.</context>
      <utterance>How about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds it high for mother -- and all -- to see. Martha takes it and reacts at its weight.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! LOOK! My gold locket!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's solid gold... Ethan, I don't think she's old enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha reluctantly surrenders it to Debbie's eager hand. Aaron hasn't missed the word "Mexico" and looks sharply at Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Let her keep it... Just something I picked up in Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, Uncle Ethan...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two girls leave the main room. Martha and Aaron both look at Ethan -- half expecting some further explanation. He turns from them and looks into the fire. Martha begins to clear the table. Aaron gets up, takes a pipe and a spill -- lights it at the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Come along...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What happened to 'em?</context>
      <utterance>Passed the Todd place comin' in...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan turns and looks at her -- still busy with her dishes.</context>
      <utterance>They gave up... went back to the cotton rows... So'd the Jamisons... Without Martha, I don't know... She wouldn't let a man quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha freezes in what she's doing -- listening.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan, I could see it in you before the war...  You wanted to clear out!</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan can't answer, but he takes it as a challenge and almost welcomes it.</context>
      <utterance>And you stayed out beyond all need to... WHY?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You askin' me to clear out now?</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're my brother... You're welcome to stay as long as you got a mind to... Ain't that so, Martha?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha resumes her activity. Ethan crosses to his pack, reaches into it for a leather pouch, brings it back and tosses it onto the table. It lands with a resonant clink. Both Martha and Aaron draw close to the table. (NOTE TO WINTON HOCH: This scene should be dramatically back- lighted.)</context>
      <utterance>I expect to pay my own way...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens a waistline shirt button and hauls out a leather money belt and drops that on the table.</context>
      <utterance>There's sixty double eagles in there... twelve-hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into the belt and takes out a few mint-fresh gold pieces which he slides across the table.</context>
      <utterance>An' twice that in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha picks up one of the gold pieces, staring at the face on the coin: the same as that on the medal -- staring sharply then at Ethan. Aaron is examining another coin with a different interest.</context>
      <utterance>...only these got the late Emperor Maximilian's picture on 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances questioningly at Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Mint fresh... not a mark on 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aaron shrugs and crosses to a barrel chair. He raises the seat and lifts out a pair of old boots, some rags of clothing and then raises a false-bottom lid and drops pouch and money belt into it. Carefully he replaces everything. During this Ethan's attention has gone to Martha's hand, to one cut finger, its wound barely healed. He takes the hand -- gently.</context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods and withdraws the hand.</context>
      <utterance>Cut yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up one of the lamps and starts away toward their bedroom door. Martha looks at Ethan again. His expression is bitter.</context>
      <utterance>Time for bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns obediently and follows Aaron. Ethan looks after them and waits as Aaron opens the bedroom door. Martha goes into it and Aaron follows and closes the door. Ethan crosses to the lamp on the mantel, blows it out. Only the firelight strikes his face as he stares broodingly at the closed bedroom door.</context>
      <utterance>Night, Ethan... Come 'long, Martha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door is opened by Aaron -- holding a lamp and a gun. He is only partly dressed -- pants, boots, undershirt. The bar of light slashes across the faces of Sam and some of the men behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Aaron! Open up!... Sam Clayton!</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend... Come in!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to get you out of bed so early...  Mornin', Sister Edwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Reverend?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lars Jorgensen claims someone bust into his corral last night and run off his best cows...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jorgensen enters -- an angry little man -- closely followed by Mose Harper, who is grinning foolishly.</context>
      <utterance>You mean those pure breds he just bought?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time I raise pigs, by golly! You never hear of anyone running off pigs, I bet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kiowas or Caddoes.</context>
      <utterance>Injuns has 'em... Caddoes or Kiowas...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mose spots Martha and at once whips off his hat and makes her an exaggerated cavalier's bow.</context>
      <utterance>Caddoes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed Nesby enters.</context>
      <utterance>Respects to a charmin' lady, ma'am. ...Respects, respects...</utterance>
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mornin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee's made if you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads for the stove.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee'd be fine, sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes brighten as he looks toward the fire and spots a rocking chair. He shuffles toward it, plants himself and begins rocking and half-crooning to himself.</context>
      <utterance>My bones is cold...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or bumble bees, by golly... I show them dirty rustlers!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin ranges himself next to Aaron and both face Clayton.</context>
      <utterance>Over here, Martin... Aaron...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha sets out cups on the table, begins pouring the coffee. During the swearing-in, Ethan will enter the room from the inner door -- unnoticed by the other men, but not by Martha. And as the scene plays, the audience must always be conscious of the by-play of glances between Martha and Ethan as they face the prospect of being left in this house together.</context>
      <utterance>Raise your right hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are hereby volunteer privates in Company A of the Texas Rangers and will faithfully discharge the duties of same without recompense or monetary compensation -- meaning no pay!... Amen and get your shirt on, will you, Aaron.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't goin' volunteerin' after rustlers without my morning coffee, Reverend... Drink your own!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Ethan advances and calmly appropriates the cup Clayton is reaching for...</context>
      <utterance>From now on, call me 'Captain'!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clayton marks his surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Captain the Reverend Samuel Johnson Clayton!... Mighty impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan sips his coffee and doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>Well... the prodigal brother... When'd you get back?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't seen you since the surrender.  Come to think of it, I didn't see you at the surrender.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe in surrenderin'... I still got my sabre, Reverend... never turned it into any ploughshare neither!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is no time for kaffee-klatch while a man's beef is been run off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha has left the room briefly to fetch Aaron's shirt and vest and stands behind him. Aaron drains his cup.</context>
      <utterance>Injuns, Ethan...  Caddoes or Kiowas... Mose Harper, drinkin' coffee in a rockin' chair. ...ay-eh!</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan -- cup to his lips -- looks over its rim at Martha as Aaron starts to put on his shirt. Their eyes meet briefly, then she looks away. Ethan sloshes the dregs of his cup into the fire -- some of it spattering Mose.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan, countin' on you to look after things while I'm gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sure is goin'... He's sworn in.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Ethan, I ain't sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't argue!... And stay close... Maybe they're rustlers... and maybe this dodderin' old idiot ain't so far wrong...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kind words...</context>
      <utterance>Thankin' ye, Ethan... thankin' ye.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... I'll swear you in...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can forget that...  Wouldn't be legal anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha waits -- intent.</context>
      <utterance>Why?  You wanted for a crime, Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You askin' as a Reverend or a Captain, Sam?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm askin' as a Ranger of the sovereign state of Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a warrant?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fit a lot of descriptions.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks past him then -- at Martha and then at Aaron.</context>
      <utterance>I figger a man's only good for one oath at a time... I took mine to the Confederate States of America...  So did you, Reverend...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Martha again... and then strides out.</context>
      <utterance>Stick close, Aaron...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In confusion, Lucy runs back around the side of the house as Brad -- unrepentant -- grins at his irascible old man and heads for his waiting horse. Clayton chuckles and turns toward Martha, who has followed them out.</context>
      <utterance>Brad!... Is no time for lolly- gagging...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like I'll be reading the lines over that pair before long, sister Edwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mose, last to emerge, bows elaborately to Martha.</context>
      <utterance>Is no time for talking weddings... Better say prayers for those dirty thieves, by golly... running off a man's beef...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men are mounting. Mose nimbly vaults onto the back of his horse -- which he rides bareback, with only a blanket pad.</context>
      <utterance>Grateful to the hospitality of yore rockin' chair, ma'am...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin! Ride me as far as the well!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings her up in front of his saddle. They start away. Ethan is last to ride out. He is watching Martha. He brings a gloved hand up in a salute. She starts to raise her hand but only brings it just above her waist, a fluttering gesture with tremulous fingers. It is the last he will ever see of her alive.</context>
      <utterance>Grab hold!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan reins in -- compressing his lips at the "Uncle." Mose waits.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Ethan!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin' mighty fishy about this trail, Uncle Ethan...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop callin' me 'uncle'... I ain't your uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mose lets out a snickering laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Don't have to call me 'sir' neither... Nor grampaw neither... Nor Methuselah neither... I can whup you to a frazzle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want me to call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Ethan... Now what's so mighty fishy about this trail?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks and all turn at a distant hail from Jorgensen.</context>
      <utterance>Well, fust off...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look! Look!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jorgensen doesn't even seem to hear him. Angrily Ethan whips out revolver and fires into the air. Then he swings his arm in a come-back gesture. He rides out ahead then a short distance and dismounts... and slowly the others follow. We see now, the bodies of a few bulls stiffening in the sun. Ethan goes to the nearest one. A feathered lance is driven into it. He pulls the lance out. Mose comes over beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Call that young fool back!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the lance to Mose.</context>
      <utterance>Caddo or Kiowa, huh?... Ain't but one tribe uses a lance like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brad rides in -- shrill with anger.</context>
      <utterance>Ay-he... Comanch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killed every one -- an' not for food either... Why'd they do a thing like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jorgensen wilts and casts an anguished look back over the miles they have ridden.</context>
      <utterance>Stealing the cattle was just to pull us out... This here's a murder raid...  It shapes up to scald out either your place... or my brother's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama!... Oh please... please no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he too rides. Martin swings his horse back to where Ethan and Mose still are standing.</context>
      <utterance>Jorgensen's place is closest... If they're not there, we'll come straight on!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy!  It's forty miles, sonny... Horses can do with some grain and a little rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comanch generally hits at moonrise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wheels his horse and goes tearing to catch up with the others. Ethan shrugs and stoically takes grain bag to feed his horse. Mose does the same.</context>
      <utterance>Moonrise!... It'll be midnight before... I ain't waitin'...!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan just gives him an angry look and then ruthlessly begins discarding every bit of unnecessary equipment from his saddle.</context>
      <utterance>Wisht it was Caddoes... or Kiowas...  Comanche...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I'll see if I can pick off a sage-hen or two, Martha...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do that, Aaron...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps out. Only then does Martha turn -- and her</context>
      <utterance>Won't go far...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUCY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My, the days are getting shorter!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy frowns at her mother.</context>
      <utterance>Lucy!... We don't need the lamp yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's enjoy the dusk a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind you sweep up them shavin's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aaron stares as the boy shifts a fold of blanket, or whatever, by his side -- to disclose Ethan's cavalry sabre. Aaron smiles and rubs the youngster's head, then sets out across the yard.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Pa...  An' if you see any sage-hens, I'm ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, ma... I been watchin'... Only I wish...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't answer. Lucy comes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>I wish Uncle Ethan was here. Don't you, ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother, I can't see what I'm doing!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buckling on his gun belt, he moves toward the middle of the room, looking around him, taking inventory of his resources. Lucy slowly approaches, biting a knuckle, eyes wide with fright.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, close the shutters.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One shutter closes and the bar of light they were standing in goes out. Martha, Aaron and Lucy are dark silhouettes now against the red beam from another window.</context>
      <utterance>Pa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(calling it)</context>
      <utterance>Where's Deborah?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I couldn't find the shawl...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cautiously swings the shutters open. A pale light filters into the room. We see Martha wrapping the shawl around Deborah.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry, Martha... Moon's fixin' to rise...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to play the sleep-out game... Remember?... Where you hide out with grandma?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's she buried?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(her voice breaks)</context>
      <utterance>And you'll go along the ditch -- very quietly -- like a...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a little mouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the child, but he has to wait for Martha's last embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There!... And you won't come back or make a sound... no matter what you hear? Promise!... No matter what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise... Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Child, child!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't I have Topsy to keep me company?</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no time...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aaron takes the child, swings her out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Here she is, baby... Baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martha would come to the window to look out, but Aaron bars her with an arm and draws back to the side of the window to watch her go... Outside the little dog barks a welcome and presumably starts to follow the girl. Aaron reacts.</context>
      <utterance>Down low -- go!</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog whines but obeys. Aaron continues watching the child's course -- unconsciously imitating her every run and twist... Then he smiles and we may see the brightness in the corners of his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Here dog... here!</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the shutters and turns -- and his arms go around Martha, weeping soundlessly.</context>
      <utterance>She reached the ditch...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be all right, mother... she'll be all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA SWINGS with him and we see Ethan and Mose approaching at the same steady gait.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan!... Ethan!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan doesn't slacken, nearly rides him down.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Ethan... it's me... Martin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin goes sprawling to his hands and knees. Mose continues without slowing.</context>
      <utterance>Out of my way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes running, stumbling after the riders -- desperately calling to them...</context>
      <utterance>Mose! Wait!...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then at the crest of the rising ground, he stops -- We see in the distance the glow of a fire leading from the barns and the hayricks and the house of Aaron Edwards. Martin runs down the slope.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan!... Mose!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He strides back through the main room and out onto the porch just as Martin comes at a shambling run across the yard. Ethan takes a few steps out toward him. Martin would pass him, but Ethan grabs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Lucy?... Deborah? Lucy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin tries to fight his arm free.</context>
      <utterance>You stay out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing for you to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan turns him and drives a brutal right to his jaw. Martin goes down -- out cold. And only now do we understand how merciful the blow was as Ethan looks compassionately at the fallen figure.</context>
      <utterance>Leggo...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he takes off at a stumbling run for the hilltop.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let him go in there, Mose...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs in, looking around him. He sees the little dog, dead on the ground. And then he sees a shadowed something: The shawl Debbie had worn. It is spread out, almost as though concealing a body. Fearfully he stoops and pulls it away... There is nothing there, but the shawl. He drops to his knees, his head bowed, his face tortured. The moonlight is clear on the face of the nearer headboard. It is of weathered wood and the chiselled letters on it read:</context>
      <utterance>Lucy -- Lucy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen and Laurie -- impelled by the same feminine sympathy and interest -- turn to look at Ethan and Martin. The PANNING CAMERA picks them up...Ethan standing dry-eyed, looking at the grave of Martha; Martin -- with bruised lip -- looking out across the plain. Clayton now opens his small, well-worn Bible to a marked page.</context>
      <utterance>...and to Your keeping we commend the souls of Aaron... Martha... and Benjamin Edwards...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan looks at him, angrily, impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>Man that is born of woman is of few days and full of trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He cometh forth like a...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen!... Put an 'amen' to it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amen!</context>
      <utterance>...like a flower and is cut down...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN ET AL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan turns on his heel and walks -- CAMERA PANNING -- to where Ed Nesby has been holding the horses. Brad is already mounting. Mose is there too and Charlie MacCorry. Silhouetted against the dawn light are the rifles in each man's saddle scabbard. Clayton is right behind Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Amen!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young riders spur out.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie--you and Brad ride point! ...Don't get too far ahead...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be obliged if you'd get to the point, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan shrugs his arm free and mounts.</context>
      <utterance>I am... I am... It's just that I know Martha'd want you to think of her boys as well as her girls... And if the girls are... dead... Ethan, don't let the boys waste their lives in vengeance!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ignores her and turns angrily to where Martin is.</context>
      <utterance>Promise me, Ethan!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Martin... Martin...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings into his saddle. Laurie impulsively runs to his side, steps onto the toe of his stirruped boot and pulls herself up to his level to kiss him hard and full upon the mouth. He looks at her dully, as though hardly conscious of it. And she is back beside her mother. Martin rides away after the others.</context>
      <utterance>We'll find them, Mrs. Jorgensen... We'll find them...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie looks at her mother and understands.</context>
      <utterance>I almost hope they don't find them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>63A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MARTIN - Next to last in file. Finally:</utterance>
   <speaker>63B</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ETHAN - His face a study of relentless purpose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another one, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This 'un come a long way 'fore he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's seven we can score up to your brother, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What don't you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Injun's on a raid generly hides their dead so you won't know how many they've lost... If they don't care about us knowin', it only spells one thing... they ain't afraid of us followin' -- or of us catchin' up with 'em either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can back out any time, Nesby.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't say that...  What's he doin' that for...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brad shifts another rock and Looks grimly upon the face (O.S.) of the dead Comanche. Then he spits at it and stands.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to be sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get along...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good does that do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands now and he faces Sam.</context>
      <utterance>By what you preach... none!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flings the scalp down and grinds it into the dirt with his heel... He wipes clean the blade of his knife as he crosses back to his horse. The men mount (those who have dismounted) and they ride off.</context>
      <utterance>But by what the Comanche believe -- now he can't enter the spirit land, but has got to wander forever between the winds... because I took his mangy scalp!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be a buffler...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's horses, I tell ya...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to squirm down the ridge, the others following.</context>
      <utterance>It's them all right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're camped by the river -- 'bout twenty miles from here. Soon's it gets dark we'll circle out so's to jump 'em before daybreak.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what we're here for, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were trying to get the girls back -- alive... We jump those Comanches, they'll kill 'em... You know that!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are we supposed to do?</context>
      <utterance>But... but what are we doin' then?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I had in mind was runnin' off their hoss herd... A Comanche on foot is more apt to be willin' to listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes sense to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about it?... What's a quarter-breed Cherokee know about the Comanche trick of sleeping with his best pony tied right beside him... You got as much chance of stampedin' their herd as...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...as you have of findin' those girls alive by ridin' into 'em... I say we do it my way, Ethan... and that's an order!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look into each other's eyes a moment, then Sam turns to mount... and the others follow. Slowly then they start riding down the slope.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir... But if you're wrong, Captain Clayton, don't ever give me another!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ay-he... They was here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Clayton.</context>
      <utterance>SURE!... They WERE here... Now they're out there... an' waitin' to jump us!...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got any more orders, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move on, slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Just keep goin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brad, who has been looking up ahead, sounds a new warning.</context>
      <utterance>Keep goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were tryin' to surround 'em, you sure succeeded.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far's the river from here, Mose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been baptized, Reverend... yes suh, been baptized, thank ye...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that yell, he drives spurs and cuts sharply at an angle to the converging Indian files -- and every man is with him. In the next instant, the Comanches whoop and give chase.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you better brace yourself for another one... Ya-HEE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they mean to charge us, Uncle Ethan...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We found us an ole buffler wallow...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Criminy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steady, Daniel Boone! You don't want to miss... It makes them think their medicine's stronger than yours...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One Comanche rides a few yards into the water, brandishing his rifle, taunting the white men. A moment later he is joined by a second brave.</context>
      <utterance>Ay-he... That's jest what I tole Joe Powers... That un's gettin' kinda sassy, ain't he, Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Mose slowly bring their rifles to bear -- and then the two shots crack out almost simultaneously. And within split seconds both Comanches fall. The others race away. Sam comes charging over to Ethan and Mose.</context>
      <utterance>Real sassy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't give any order to fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right, Captain... I don't need any formal invitation to kill a Comanch...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he drops behind a rock as, with a wild whooping, the Comanche forces swing from their places of hiding and hit the river. The men open fire, all but Martin, who has frozen, staring wild-eyed at the oncoming Comanches.</context>
      <utterance>You got one now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAYTON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan pulls the gun free and looks out across the river.</context>
      <utterance>Let them bury their dead...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That tears it, Reverend... From now on, you keep out...  All of you!... I don't want you with me... I don't need you... for what I got to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA SWINGS to pick up the figure of Nesby outstretched on the ground, writhing in pain; with Charlie kneeling beside him. The men cross to stand around the fallen man.</context>
      <utterance>No need to shout, mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckon we got to go back -- Ed's shoulder is smashed -- bad!</utterance>
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can make it... just get me on a horse...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No good, Ed... And Ethan's right... This is a job for a company of Rangers... or it's a job for one or two men... Right now we're too many... an' not enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one way you can stop me lookin' for Lucy, mister... An' that's kill me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan glares at them, but has to accept it.</context>
      <utterance>That's how I feel, Uncle Ethan...  Ethan, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... but I'm givin' the orders... You take 'em or we split up here and now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, sure, Ethan... There's just the one thing we're after... finding Deborah and Lucy...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads away, for his horse. Brad and Martin look at each other as the full import of Ethan's footnote strikes home. Then they head for their own horses.</context>
      <utterance>If they're still alive...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod.</context>
      <utterance>You boys got enough shells?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three re-enter the river and slowly start across, with Clayton gravely looking after them. The three riders continue across the river... and the Search Theme resumes.</context>
      <utterance>Vaya con dios.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got to stop sometime... if they're human at all, they got to stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan turns to catch Martin thirstily drinking from his canteen.</context>
      <utterance>Naw... a human man rides a horse till it dies... then he goes on afoot... A Comanche comes along... gets that horse up... and rides it twenty more miles... Then he eats it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy on that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry... We don't even know if Debbie 'n Lucy are with this bunch... Maybe they split up...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brad wheels on him.</context>
      <utterance>They're with 'em -- if they're still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've said that enough!... Maybe Lucy's dead... maybe they're both dead... but if I hear it from you again, I'll fight ya, Mr. Edwards!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll be the day!... Let's ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan thinks he knows why. His face is bleak. But he tries to be casual.</context>
      <utterance>Four of 'em cut out here... Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his mount toward the gap.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take a look... You keep after the others...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want us to fire a shot if...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both can see that.</context>
      <utterance>I... uh... here's where they met up again...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him and each other -- for these are clearly unnecessary remarks and doubly surprising coming from Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Trail leads off there...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd they break off?  Was there water in that canyon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh...? No... no water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right, Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to his horse, mounts. Martin is right beside him and he notes the missing serape.</context>
      <utterance>Huh...?  Sure I'm all right...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say!... What happened to your blanket? Lose it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads out. Brad rides up beside Martin. Again the two exchange puzzled looks. Martin shrugs and the three continue along the broad trace of the Indian ponies into the setting sun.</context>
      <utterance>Must've... Anyway, I ain't goin' back to look for it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin runs to his side as Brad slides off his mount. Ethan moves more slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I saw her!... I saw Lucy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're camped 'bout two miles over... I was just swingin' back when I saw their smoke... I bellied up a ridge an' they was right below me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see Debbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I saw Lucy all right... She was wearin' that blue dress... an' she was walkin' along...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you saw wasn't Lucy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was, I tell you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't look at Brad or at Martin. Brad can't speak -- and then finally:</context>
      <utterance>What you saw was a buck wearin' Lucy's dress...  I found Lucy back there in that canyon... I wrapped her in my blanket an' buried her with m'own hands... I thought it best to keep it from you -- long as I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan wheels on him in shouting fury.</context>
      <utterance>Did they...? Was she...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD!...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They run for their horses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his horse back the way they had come. Martin stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just hope he took some with him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you goin' to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, he rides away. Slowly, reluctantly but helpless to do otherwise, Martin follows.</context>
      <utterance>Get some sleep... Tomorrow's another day...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it. We're beat!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his mount.</context>
      <utterance>No... our turnin' back don't change anything... not in the long run. If she's alive, she's safe... for a while... They'll keep her to raise as one of their own, 'til she's of an age to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you think we got a chance to find her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Injun will chase a thing til he thinks he's chased it enough... Then he quits... Same when he runs... Seems he never learns there's such a thing as a critter that might just keep comin' on... So we'll find them in the end, I promise you that... We'll find them just as sure as the turning of the earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got my letter about your son, Brad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah... Just about this time a year ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It came the day before his... birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen starts to lead the way inside. Martin hangs back.</context>
      <utterance>The Lord giveth--the Lord taketh away...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie rushes past her mother.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't fit to go indoors, miz Jorgensen... These clothes is...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him hard and full on the mouth -- and has no eyes for anyone else. Mrs. Jorgensen looks on with amusement. Martin is just bowled over.</context>
      <utterance>Martie!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And him probably forgettin' all about you!... Probably can't even call your name to mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laurie. And Laurie smiles triumphantly at her mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan shakes his head. She squeezes his arm reassuringly and they start indoors.</context>
      <utterance>The little one?... Debbie?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the shirt, puts it over one arm; she reaches for his long-handled and ragged underwear, runs a fist through a hole in its seat, clucks and shreds it into rags. During this:</context>
      <utterance>Hey... What you doin'...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go takin' that stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and looks at him, matter of fact.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't worth the mendin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you gettin' red-in-the-face for?... I have brothers, haven't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I ain't one of 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a woman, Martie...  We wash and mend your dirty clothes all our lives... When you're little we even wash you... How a man can ever make out to get bashful in front of a woman I'll never know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talk like a feller might just as leave run around nekkid...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she is laughing as she closes the door behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't bother me...  I wouldn't try it in front of pa, though, was I you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen looks up from her darning.</context>
      <utterance>...an' then it snowed and we lost the trail... No need to tell ya all the places we went... Fort Richardson, Fort Wingate an' Cobb... the Anadarko Agency... Trouble is we don't even know which band that war party belonged to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you did all a body could, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got your boy killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go blamin' yourself...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen stands.</context>
      <utterance>It's this country killed my boy!... Yes, by golly!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The speech impresses everyone but Laurie, who probably hasn't heard a word of it.</context>
      <utterance>Now Lars!... It so happens we be Texicans... We took a reachin' hold, way far out, past where any man has right or reason to hold on... Or if we didn't, our folks did... So we can't leave off without makin' them out to be fools, wastin' their lives 'n wasted in the way they died... A Texican's nothin' but a human man out on a limb... This year an' next and maybe for a hundred more. But I don't think it'll be forever. Someday this country will be a fine good place to be... Maybe it needs our bones in the ground before that time can come...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is just the briefest hesitation...</context>
      <utterance>Ma!... Martie's drawers is a sight! Ain't fit for rags!... Would it be all right if we gave him some of Brad's things?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she leads the way briskly, with Laurie following, to a big chest at the far end of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Why...'course it would! They're in the chest...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes to him, her arms piled with clothing; and Laurie a step behind her, holding up a new pair of long- handled underwear -- measuring it with her eyes for holes, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Jorgensen...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out the snip of calico.</context>
      <utterance>Will you look at this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why it's just a snip of calico...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever see it before... like mebbe on a dress Debbie wore?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!... Yes, I remember!... Have they found her, Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the calico snip, places it within the letter and carefully pockets it. He looks broodingly into the fire.</context>
      <utterance>No... not yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie's face is troubled as she turns from him and heads for the grandmother room, carrying the armful of clothes.</context>
      <utterance>...not yet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might at least have left me my pants!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shush!... Time for bed anyway...  Likely these'll need some takin' in... Oh, Martie, you're that gaunted! ...Ma's havin' a turkey for dinner tomorrow and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan opens the door, enters.</context>
      <utterance>Laurie!... Come... come!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wants to kiss Martie but is shy in Ethan's presence and hurries out.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Pa!... Good night, Martie... good night, Mr. Edwards...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night... Laurie...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stoops to remove his boots. Ethan studies him and looks thoughtfully after the girl and at Martin. He takes the letter out of his pocket -- as though he meant to read it -- and then he puts it back decisively. He starts to undress. Martin lies back on his bunk.</context>
      <utterance>Good night...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jorgensen's been runnin' his cattle with my own...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YOUR cattle?... DEBBIE'S cattle! Ethan returns the stare without any change of expression.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's agreed to take you on and share the increase from my herd while I'm gone... I'll be pushin' on tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't stayin'... I set out lookin' for Debbie... I aim to keep on...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because she's my... my...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's your nothin'... She's no kin to you at all!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always felt like she was... Her folks takin' me in, raisin' me like one of their own...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't make 'em kin...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... I ain't got no kin... I'm goin' to keep lookin' that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin throws himself back, turns his face to the wall. Ethan looks soberly at him -- and is sorry for the brutality of his words.</context>
      <utterance>How? You got any horses, or money to buy 'em... You ain't even got money to buy cartridges... Jorgensen's offering you a good livin' here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin... I want you to know somethin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... you want me to know I ain't got no kin -- no money -- no horses -- nothing but a dead man's clothes to wear!... You tole me that already... Now shut your head!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just shakes his head, not looking at her. She lifts the food from the skillet onto a plate and sets it before him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you can do about finding Debbie that he can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head. She crosses to the stove for the coffee pot.</context>
      <utterance>He'll find her now, Martie... Please believe me... I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it is her turn to stare.</context>
      <utterance>That's what scares me -- him findin' her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie has poured his coffee. Now he sips it. She sits at the table with him.</context>
      <utterance>Laurie, I've seen his eyes when he so much as hears the word 'Comanche' ...I've seen him take his knife an' ...never mind... But he's a man can go crazy wild... It might come on him when it was the worst thing could be... What I counted on, I hoped to be there to stop him, if such thing come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'I bought a small size dress off a Injun... If this here is a piece of yr chiles dress bring reward. I know where they gone... Jerem Futterman.' Martin is on his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Futterman!... He's got a little tradin' post on the South Fork o' the Brazos... Laurie, I just got to get me a good horse! Think yer pa would...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish your breakfast...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta catch up with him, Laurie!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on then! Pa's in the barn saddlin' the Fort Worth stud... an' you can take the light gelding with the blaze...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie goes to the front door and throws it wide.</context>
      <utterance>But that's Sweet-face -- your own good horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it and welcome... but don't count on finding me here when you get back... I've been dallying around this god-forsaken wind-scour almost two long years waitin' for you... I ain't cut out to be an old maid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets the jug down, picks up one of the glasses -- so grey and thumb-printed it is almost opaque. Both Ethan and Martin regard it with disgust. Futterman gives a slight shrug, takes the dress and starts to wipe the dirty glass with it. Martin snatches it out of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you come by this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said there'd be a thousand dollar reward.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan looks at him and beyond toward the two men.</context>
      <utterance>You got it with you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reward'll be paid when I find her -- an' if she's alive... Futterman uncorks the jug, prepares to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tilts the jug to his mouth as Ethan reaches for his heavy leather pouch. Futterman watches greedily as Ethan lets a gold piece slide out. He tosses it onto the table.</context>
      <utterance>Man's got a right to expect some kind o' payment... I laid out for the dress an' sendin' you the writin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Futterman puts the jug down. His hand inches -- as though pulled by a magnet -- toward the gold piece.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty Yankee dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan's big hand clamps over Futterman's and he starts squeezing as a man would squeeze a lemon. Futterman's lips whiten.</context>
      <utterance>...an' a man's time is worth somethin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A young buck fetched it in late last summer...  Said it belonged to a captive chile of Chief Scar...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scar? Never heard of any Chief Scar.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither... But this buck claimed he was a big war chief with the Nawyecky Comanches.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scar's band was headin' north... to winter in at Fort Wingate... eatin' agency beef. That's what this buck said... Maybe he lied.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And maybe you lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan stands. Martin follows. Martin takes the dress and folds it carefully.</context>
      <utterance>In that case you won't find her -- and I won't get my thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan and Martin head for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Stay the night if you want...  Cards?... A jug?... If you'd like some company, we got a few squaws on the place...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two plug-uglies stand -- mean ready to do their master's bidding.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget to come back with my thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave. The CAMERA holds on Futterman as he slowly rubs his bruised hand. His henchmen drift toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't yours yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUTTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad manners... He shoulda said 'good- bye.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARTIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acts like somethin's out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS him to where Martin is spreading his blanket some little distance from the small fire.</context>
      <utterance>Smells a change in the weather...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin is a bit surprised as Ethan takes the blanket and spreads it near the saddle -- making the saddle serve as a pillow. Then Ethan tosses a few more heavy pieces of dry wood on the fire, making it blaze up.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't surprise me if we didn't have a frost 'fore mornin'... Here...  Whyn't you bed down closer to the fire, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What's the idea...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spreads his own blanket as Martin wraps into his bedroll, and when Martin turns, he casually arranges the blanket to suggest it is over the figure of a man. During this:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'm gettin' like Mose Harper -- my bones is cold tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan steps back -- and studies the "dummy."</context>
      <utterance>Funny... When we passed through Fort Wingate last winter, we didn't hear mention of any Nawyecky Comanche there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so funny... if you recollect what 'Nawyecka' means...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan studies Martin's back -- the light on him -- and looks around figuring the range of fire.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorta like 'roundabout' -- like a man says he's goin' one place when he means to go just the reverse...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin just grunts and snugs deeper into his blanket. Ethan nods his satisfaction -- sure Martin isn't going to change positions. Then he takes off his hat and boots and uses them to complete the dummy. He picks up his rifle then and quietly walks out of the camp.</context>
      <utterance>You all settled an' comfortable now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan kneels beside Futterman, turns him over, reaches into his pockets -- first one, then another.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks... you did just fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Futterman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just couldn't wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan grins satisfiedly as he straightens and spins the gold piece in the air, catches it and pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>Whatchu doin'?...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Martin is getting the whole picture... and he's mad.</context>
      <utterance>Even got my twenty dollars back... We did all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan is just grinning at him -- completely unruffled, denying none of it.</context>
      <utterance>WE?... You just used me for bait -- staked me out like a... buildin' up the fire... fixin' it so's... I coulda had my brains blowed out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan sobers a little, seems honestly surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Suppose you'd missed!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never occurred to me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Mister Jorgensen...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MacCorry swings off his saddle near the porch, as the door opens and Mrs. Jorgensen comes out -- shawled against the cold.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jorgensen lets the cordwood drop...</context>
      <utterance>Got a letter here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By golly! A letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Miss Laurie...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in, Charlie, come in...  LAURIE!... My land!... Two letters in the one year!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A letter for you, Laurie...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the letter to Laurie who comes over eagerly, takes it and studies the wrapper before opening it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes'm... Figgered it might be the news you been waitin' for... so...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real good o' you to ride all the way over, Charlie... Might at least say your thank you's, Laurie... Declare!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Laurie has no interest in anything but the letter which she is reading skimmingly.</context>
      <utterance>No need to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie looks up then.</context>
      <utterance>Laurie! Don't keep a body just standin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just readin' to see if... Anyway, it's MY letter!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Course it is. Now let's all get comfortable an' set so's we can listen while Laurie reads her letter...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'd better be goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen has been pulling and pushing chairs around and now they all take places. Jorgensen automatically reaches for his glasses on the mantel and puts them on -- even though he isn't going to read the letter. Laurie has been sneaking looks at some of the other pages.</context>
      <utterance>You stay, Charlie... After all, Charlie brought the letter, Laurie... He got a right to listen too!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, all right! Well... Martin says...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the beginning...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dear Miss Laury'... He spells it with a Y instead of an I... E... Wouldn't you think he'd know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares what he spells it? Read the letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks off, looks up -- puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Miss Laury... I take pen in hand to let you know Ethan and me still are trying to catch up with them Comanches the late Mister Futterman told us about...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The late Mister Futterman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means Mister Futterman is dead, by golly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder what happened to the poor man. Go on, Laurie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(her voice fades)</context>
      <utterance>We cut north through Indian territory and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>A WIFE?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks at them - dazed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen, full of sympathy for Laurie, just glares at her husband.</context>
      <utterance>Good! A young man should get married early in life. Right, mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every young man should at least once...Go on, Laurie! Read!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jorgensen is out of his chair and scrambling in the fireplace to recover the letter. He fetches it out, beating the sparks out. The letter is basically undamaged.</context>
      <utterance>Laurie!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie snatches the letter back.</context>
      <utterance>Is no way to treat a letter, Laurie ...Mama maybe you better read it...  My wife was a school teacher, Charlie ...She reads good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie crosses the room, picks up a guitar.</context>
      <utterance>I'll read it...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurie glares at him. He begins chording the guitar.</context>
      <utterance>So he married a Comanche squaw... Haw haw haw!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go... I think I stumbled onto somethin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The name registers with some of the nearer braves. There is a quick interchange of glances, frowning, hostile.</context>
      <utterance>Scar?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you goin' to learn to keep your mouth shut! Come on. Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I just bought a good blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin mounts and the two ride out. The Comanches stare after them suspiciously, resentfully.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I heard back there was that a band o' hostile Nawyeckas came through this way less'n two weeks ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks and both turn as Look rides over the hill on a little spotted Indian pony, with her squaw-bag slung up behind her and her blanket over the saddle. She closes the gap between them.</context>
      <utterance>Think it might be...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look smiles shyly at Martin.</context>
      <utterance>What's she followin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures for her to go back.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I changed my mind... You can keep your blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares and then dutifully wheels her horse. Martin and Ethan face front again. Look wheels her horse again and is right with them. Martin stops - exasperated.</context>
      <utterance>Go on back...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look just sits.</context>
      <utterance>Look... you don't understand...  I don't want it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YOU don't understand, ya chunkhead! You didn't buy any blanket! Ya bought her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got yourself a wife, sonny!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no! Tell her she's got to go back...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look smiles and sets her horse in motion as Ethan moves ahead. Martin's face is a mask of comic despair as he gives up. He is mouthing the words --</context>
      <utterance>And have her whole family after our scalps for floutin' one o' their women?... No sir! Come on, Mrs. Pauley...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Ethan suddenly breaks into song; to the tune of "Skip To My Lou:"</context>
      <utterance>Mrs... Pauley?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got another gal purtier'n you. I got another gal purtier'n you. I got another gal purtier'n you. Skip to my Lou, my darlin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods her understanding, hurries off to fetch a canteen. Martin glares at Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Water!...  Pah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way to train 'em. Looks like Mrs. Pauley's goin' to make you a fine beautiful wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look returns with the canteen, hands it to Martin and kneels beside him. He looks at her sympathetically.</context>
      <utterance>Cut it out, will ya...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Look speaks for the first time. She indicates herself.</context>
      <utterance>Look... I wish I could explain to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she jabbers in Comanche and, at the appropriate time, will point to the sky and imitate a bird flying.</context>
      <utterance>Look?...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin looks blank, but Ethan chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Nay tzare T'sala-ta-komal-ta-name... unt kang-yah Look.  .</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says her name's Wild Goose Flying in the Night Sky... but she'll answer to Look since it pleases ya...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods and smiles and quickly settles alongside him and spreads her blanket over them both. Martin recoils, plants his foot in the small of her back and sends her sprawling. Ethan busts a gut laughing. Martin jumps to his feet, angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Look?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unt osupanet cah-nay Scar?   She stares sullenly, not answering.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands... She indicates Martin. She indicates herself.</context>
      <utterance>Look!  Scar?...  Do you know where he went? And if he has a girl with him... a white girl -- nai-bist pabo taibo...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mah nee-koo-ur?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... not my wife... My...  How do you say sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks gravely from Ethan to Martin. Then, with impassive face, she bends swiftly, picks up her blanket and walks away from them to choose her own sleeping place. The two men don't know what to make of it.</context>
      <utterance>Nami.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me how she could get that pony out o' camp without neither of us hearin' a thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't goin' back to her family, that's certain... not if she took off where the arrow points.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think she means for us to follow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks toward their horses, starts to saddle up. Martin follows.</context>
      <utterance>How should I know... She's YOUR wife!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe we oughta...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, quit it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine...  Ten!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan turns and swings a backhand blow which catches Martin by surprise and fells him.</context>
      <utterance>What's the sense in it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Least, THEY won't feed any Comanches this winter... Killin' buffalo's as good as killin' Injuns in this country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peaceful tribes depend on the buffalo, too....</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips out his shinning knife and strides toward the dead buffalo o.s. Martin looks after him with troubled expression. Suddenly he hears something, borne faint by the wind.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't that too bad... If you feel that sorry for your kinfolk, I'm surprised you didn't take up with that squaw wife of yours...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan stares -- and then the bugle sound repeats and the distant crack of shots, from long miles off.</context>
      <utterance>Listen!... Hear it?... There! Ain't that a bugle... and firing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the two break and run for their horses.</context>
      <utterance>Just hope we ain't too late...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're a widower now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees something clutched in her hand. He stoops quickly.</context>
      <utterance>What'd the soldiers have to kill her for!...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan, who has turned indifferently to leave, pauses. Martin shows him what Look had been clutching -- Debbie's rag doll.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan snatches it, stares at it. Then he turns and runs from the tepee. Martin stares at Look's body, then covers it with a robe.</context>
      <utterance>Look! It's hers, Debbie's...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and then slowly heads out.</context>
      <utterance>So we knew Debbie had been in the village... What Look was doing there -- whether she'd come to warn them, or maybe to find Debbie for me... there's no way of knowing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan isn't thinking of that at all.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta catch up with them yellow legs... Maybe they got her with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start away -- fast.</context>
      <utterance>And maybe they got Scar!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're looking for a girl -- a white girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'd be about thirteen now...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got two around that age...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to wait until we reach the agency... Fall in behind the column...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But couldn't you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep the column moving!... Close ranks there! The officer spurs out to rejoin the column. Martin looks at Ethan, his face alive with hope. But Ethan is just looking stonily along the line of passing prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it was clear to me the hostiles outnumbered us four to one... with all the advantage of terrain...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRESPONDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four to one! What did you do, general? Ethan and Martin enter, stand in the doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir -- we charged!... Gentlemen -- and I hope you will quote me -- I cannot say too much for the courage of the men who followed me into that Cheyenne camp...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheyenne! What Cheyenne?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That camp you hit was Nawyecka Comanche... Chief Scar's bunch...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRESPONDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scar? What a wonderful name!...</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you getting this, Keefer?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRESPONDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan ignores him, still facing the General.</context>
      <utterance>How do you spell that word -- Nawyecka?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Edwards... I'm looking for my niece... she was in that camp when you attacked...</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I know there were some captives recovered...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four of 'em dead... so we were told...</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, the hostiles murdered them as we developed the village...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure they didn't die of carbine shots fired by a bunch o' Yank bluebellies so scared they couldn't tell the difference between a Cheyenne and a Comanche?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keefer!... Put this man under arrest!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keefer coughs.</context>
      <utterance>That'll be the day...  'As we developed the village'... Next time you develop a village, hit it where the fightin' men are... You won't get any headlines for killin' squaws.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I show him the captives, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get him out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...  This way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has seen the light hair and starts crossing the room. Now the madwoman begins her screaming, running from side to side like a trapped animal. Ethan follows Martin into the room, Keefer behind him. Martin comes to a stop, realizing the woman is afraid of him. The two sleeping girls stir, but do not turn.</context>
      <utterance>Debbie?... DEBBIE?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The madwoman crouches behind one of the benches, looking at them with frightened eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be scared, ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin swallows and nods and crosses to the light-haired girl. He reaches a hand gingerly to touch her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't pay any attention to her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the touch, the girl is on her feet, crouching -- one hand, like a claw, drawn back to rake his face. She is unmistakably a white girl, but she is painted like a Comanche woman --her ears red inside, streaks of paint accenting the savagery of her face. Her eyes are frightened, yet full of hate.</context>
      <utterance>Debbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pabo-taibo!  The other girl has risen almost in the same instant -- but more out of fear. She is younger, but painted like the other. She moves to stand behind the savage one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... She's not...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stares at him, then realizes what he has in mind. He fishes the rag doll from under his coat and holds it out to the girl. She looks at it... and we may almost suspect it is rekindling a memory -- but then she spits at it. The other girl laughs. Martin turns away and he's sick.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't sure... Where's that doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was your niece about their age?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not far from it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to realize they're white, isn't it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin nerves himself for the ordeal, turns to follow.</context>
      <utterance>They're not white any more -- they're Comanche!... Let's see the bodies...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan and Keefer move away. As they do, the madwoman -- eyes fixed on the rag doll in Martin's hand -- begins creeping up behind him. Martin is torturedly watching Ethan and Keefer as first one blanket then another is raised -- we will never see the dead. During this:</context>
      <utterance>I don't need you...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stiffens, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to see them all... It might help us identify them... Shot in the head -- flash-burn range... The boy got his skull cracked... Here's the girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin relaxes... and in that instant the madwoman has the doll in her hands. She cradles it and she croons. Martin reaches to take it away. But she calmly sits, cradling the doll, and rocks to and fro, humming a lullaby. He can't take it. Ethan returns.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we only got the one lead -- Scar... And where we begin to look, I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one thing. We recovered a bushel of trinkets in that camp... cheap stuff... trade goods... Couldn't help noticing that most of it was Mexican... Maybe if you could talk to some of those Mexican traders along the border... What do they call themselves?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comancheros...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the breed... Course it might take time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave.</context>
      <utterance>Time's running out... But I'm obliged to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows hard, pauses a moment in her reading.</context>
      <utterance>...so we're setting out for New Mexico Territory in the morning... I am sorry I won't be back for Christmas again this year...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you knittin' that muffler...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the difference!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks almost too obviously at Charlie, which annoys Laurie. Laurie resumes her letter reading:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I just thought it would be a sin and a shame not to let SOMEONE get some good of it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a word crossed out... It looks like 'I wish' or 'I will'...  Anyway... 'I set pen aside in the hope you are enjoying good health and your folks the same... I remain, respectfully...  yours truly, Martin Paulie.' That's all there is. Not a cross on it. Laurie just looks at it. Jorgensen stands, pocketing his pipe, easing the crick in his back. He ceremoniously removes the spectacles and replaces them on the mantel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never find that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads for the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Yours truly...  And he even has to write his full name... Martin Pauley... not even just Martie!...  I don't care if he never comes back!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie hits the guitar a little stronger. Mrs. Jorgensen looks at him -- and the matchmaker is at work.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Laurie!...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie, you'll stay for supper?... Now I won't take no for an answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen smiles and moves about her duties. Laurie has opened the door and is staring out wistfully... and Charlie begins playing and singing a verse from "Skip to My Lou."</context>
      <utterance>Thought of saying 'no' never crossed my mind, Miz Jorgensen... No place I'd rather be than right here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One old boot and a button shoe One old boot and a button shoe...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin shakes his head. They start toward the cantina.</context>
      <utterance>Recognize it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There couldn't be two like that in all the world...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is on his feet and advancing to meet them. As he recognizes them a wide, foolish grin splits his face and his mouth opens and closes in words that won't come out. He grabs and shakes Ethan's arm, then Martin's.</context>
      <utterance>Ay-eh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leggo my arm... You look mangier 'n ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't been too good... No sir, not too good... Gettin' old, Ethan...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were born old...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bienvenidos, senores... Pulque?... tequila?... mescal?... huiskey?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tequila...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lo mismo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin turns back to the bar to take his glass. He finds it empty.</context>
      <utterance>I been helpin' ye, Ethan... I been lookin' all the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He angrily throws a coin on the counter, appropriates the bottle and his glass and heads for a table closer to Estrella. Neither Ethan nor Mose seems aware of his going.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for nothin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the reward still stands...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't want no money, Ethan... jus' a place -- a roof over m' head... a little grub... a bunk to sleep in... an' a rockin' chair by the fire... my own rockin' chair by a fire...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You help me find her, you got your rockin' chair...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear it, Ethan?... Given word?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told ya, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mose winces under the grip. He can't speak, but he looks past Ethan and he points. Ethan turns. Emilio swings his boots off the table and slowly crosses to them. He lets cigarette smoke curl out of his mouth. Then he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Who? Where is he... this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the men study each other, Estrella begins her dance -- and the rhythmic click of the castanets will beat like a metronome. Emilio looks at the bottle on the bar, disdainfully pushes it away and imperiously signals the proprietor to bring something better.</context>
      <utterance>I am this man, senor... Emilio Gabriel Fernandez y Figueroa... at your service...  ...for a price...  ...Always for a price...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Un otra!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin tries to push him away, his eyes still on the girl.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Don Juan... We're on our way...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin breaks free and squares off.</context>
      <utterance>You breeds are all alike -- two drinks an'...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estrella ranges herself alongside of Martin and slips an arm possessively through his.</context>
      <utterance>Take yer hands off'n me... This lady an' me got some things to talk over!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suit yourself... While you're enjoyin' your little conversation, I'll be ridin' out with Senor Fernandez here... The Comanch' medicine country ain't far... there's one camp with a chief named Cicatriz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of him...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and heads out. Emilio, who has come up behind him, gives Estrella a slight smile and bow.</context>
      <utterance>Cicatriz is Mex for Scar... an' he has a white girl in his tepee... Be seein' you...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows Ethan. Estrella swings her body close to Martin and lets her arms slide around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Buena suerte, Estrella... Hasta la vista.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTRELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin blinks to clear away the fog of tequila and desire.</context>
      <utterance>Tu quieres...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin continues out and Mose stands there -- his head rockin' as though he already were in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>'Mind Ethan 'bout my rockin' chair!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Medicine country, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Medicine so strong they believe the feather of an eagle found here can guard a man against bullets...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan and Emilio both look in the direction of his glance.</context>
      <utterance>If you got one handy, now's the time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name - Big Shoulders... His name - He Who Follows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a leading question and Scar knows it. He looks long at Ethan and the suggestion of a smile touches his lips. But he makes no direct answer. He looks instead to Emilio.</context>
      <utterance>You speak pretty good American for a Comanche... Someone teach you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah-we pabbo-tie-bo ee-kee-tay?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pabbo-tie-bo kim te-moo-er.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilio quickly turns and calls to one of his men. Emilio is worried.</context>
      <utterance>That's right... We come to trade... Only not out here...  I don't stand talkin' in the wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the Mexicans comes on the trot, leading in the palomino. Emilio makes a gesture -- giving it to Scar.</context>
      <utterance>Miguel... caballo -- aca!</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scar looks at it greedily, then nods. He'll accept it. He looks at Ethan. Again that faintly contemptuous smile. He signals them to enter his tepee.</context>
      <utterance>Co-bay tabitz-chat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows Ethan into the tepee... and a worried Emilio goes along.</context>
      <utterance>Not likely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the squaws turns -- and even in the shadows we see it is another Indian face. The other does not turn. Scar leans in, blocking the view.</context>
      <utterance>Are those his wives too?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The slightly smaller of the young squaws stiffens but doesn't move. Scar glares.</context>
      <utterance>Two sons -- killed by white men... For each son, I take many scalps...  Mayah-kay zee-eh!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scar's eyes are mocking. He lets his robe slip back from his shoulders, revealing a bare bronzed chest on which -- glinting in the reflected firelight -- is the medallion that Ethan had given Debbie. It is suspended by a chain or rawhide string. Scar touches it.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen scalps before...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan smiles -- and he's still playing poker. He stands... and the others follow. Scar is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>This before?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came to trade, not to admire his collection... Tell him we're going to pitch camp across the crick... Maybe we can talk trade tomorrow. Scar hasn't understood all of it. He scowls and looks at Emilio.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ee-sap! Pabbo-tie-bo ee-sap!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin and Ethan turn to go. Only then does Debbie look swiftly at them and as swiftly away. Martin can't help but pause, but Ethan prods him toward the tepee flap.</context>
      <utterance>Puetze!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk with dignity!  If you gringo heretics have any prayers, say them...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alive... Can you believe it, she's alive... alive... An' we found her...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please!... I, too, am alive... I wish to stay that way. They reach the waiting cargadores and the pack train, surrounded by suspicious Comanches.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They mount and ride out.</context>
      <utterance>Vamanos!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You understand, senores... It is not that I am cobarde... cowardly...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilio nods and mounts.</context>
      <utterance>Don't apologize... You did your job...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fumbles for a pouch, holds it out to Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>He knows you -- who you are -- and why you are here... This I did not understand... or I would not... even for gold, senores... have led you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He digs spurs and rides out. Ethan turns and looks soberly at Martin. We hear the rest of the riders moving away. Ethan and Martin cross the sand and go down slope toward the creek where their horses are waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Take it. I do not want blood money. Vaya con Dios!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You figger Scar means to kill us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got to... All these years, runnin', dodgin', knowin' we were after him... Now we caught up... It's him or us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't he make his move back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks and both wheel as sand slides from the top of the dunes. They look up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... Somethin' tied his hands... maybe hospitality...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unnt-meah!  Both men move closer. She takes a frightened step back, as if to run.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates. She looks long at him.</context>
      <utterance>Debbie... Don't you remember me? I'm Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unnt-meah!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ain't goin'! We ain't goin' without you, Debbie... Ethan, get the horses... I'll try to keep her talkin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? She's even forgot her own language!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Debbie, you're comin' with us! Hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These have been her first words in English... and they bring new hope to Martin.</context>
      <utterance>No... not now... not ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care what they've done to you... what happened...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have done... nothing... They are my people...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your people? They murdered your family!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ee-sap!  White men killed them - to steal cows! I was... little... I ran away... They find me... take care of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Debbie! That ain't what happened! They been lyin' to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie! All white men lie... and kill...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Debbie, think back! I'm Martin... remember? Remember how I used to let you ride my horse? Tell you stories? Don't you remember me, Debbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember... from always... At first I prayed to you... come and get me... take me home... You didn't come...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've come now...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are my people...  Unnt-meah! Go! Go! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin turns as Ethan slowly reaches for his gun. It takes Martin a moment to realize what he is about to do.</context>
      <utterance>Stand aside, boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves quickly then to put himself between Ethan and the girl and in that instant there is the crack of a rifle. Ethan is hit in the leg. It goes out from under him. Martin swings and his gun is out and firing.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan -- NO!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan is on his feet now and limping frantically toward their horses. He shoves Martin ahead of him.</context>
      <utterance>Debbie! WAIT!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They mount and take off, just as the vanguard of the attacking Comanches swings around a point of rock and comes charging toward the creek.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind her! MOVE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on! Get out of here while you can...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan turns and sees what he means. He starts dragging himself to the cave as Martin grabs the rifles from their saddle scabbards, yanks off the water canteens and then drives their horses away. Then he too runs for the shelter of the cave.</context>
      <utterance>Over there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be back...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets an arm under Ethan and hauls him to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>We won't be here... Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stares at him -- and now, perhaps for the first time, he is fitting pieces into the jig-saw puzzle. He shifts closer to Ethan and we see he is preparing to dig out the bullet. Ethan opens his eyes and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Martha... Martha!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He poises the knife.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta open that leg and let the poison out...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fumbles in his shirt pocket, brings out a greasy folded piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin sets the knife down, takes the paper, opens it and slowly reads:</context>
      <utterance>Just in case... Read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'I, Ethan Edwards, being of sound mind and without any blood kin, do hereby bequeath all my property of any kind to Martin Pauley...'  I don't want your property.... 'Sides, what do you mean no 'blood kin?' Debbie's your blood kin...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can keep your will!  I ain't forgettin' you was all set to shoot her yourself... What kind o' man are you, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin shoves him back onto the ground.</context>
      <utterance>She's been with the bucks! She's nothin' now but a...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets to his feet, trembling, and stands looking down at Ethan, his fists clenched at his sides and murder in his eyes. Then his eyes rove to the knife lying on the blanket. He picks it up and he looks again at the wounded man.</context>
      <utterance>Shut your dirty mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he kneels again to open the wound.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you die!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen hurries over, beaming, to admire Charlie.</context>
      <utterance>Here he is, Lars... Combed, curried 'n washed behind the ears!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Charlie, you look real handsome!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clayton -- and the other Rangers -- have been hanging gunbelts on pegs along the wall. Now he shakes out his parcel -- disclosing a green-black frock coat.</context>
      <utterance>You'll see her soon enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, that music sounds so good it must be sinful...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grab a partner, reverend!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, now, a man of my age just can't haul off and dance in cold blood... but if there's any of that wild cherry brandy of yours, Lars...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen glares as he heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Nooo...  Yah, by golly... One jug left... I get it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last winter that man swore up and down there wasn't a drop left -- and me with pneumoney!... Reverend, you'd better start clergyin' again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he sees who they are, and his jaw drops.</context>
      <utterance>Hi!... You're late... hurry...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan... Martie... No, don't get down! ...You can't come in!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says it as though that explains everything.</context>
      <utterance>The Rangers are here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that got to do with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin throws the reins aside and jumps out. Jorgensen grabs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Why, my Laurie's getting married...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Don't you hear me! The Rangers...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin tries to break free.</context>
      <utterance>You been posted for murder... both of you... That trader fella, the late Mister Futterman...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta see Laurie!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go around the side... the grandmother's room... I'll tell her...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads around the side. Ethan meanwhile has climbed stiffly down, slightly favoring his leg.</context>
      <utterance>You better!</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick... hide in the barn, Ethan...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brushes past the little man and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hide? Why would I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evenin'... evenin' Reverend... or do I call you 'Captain'...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Came here for a wedding, Ethan... Until that's over, I reckon 'reverend' will do...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face contorts and his smile is twisted.</context>
      <utterance>And news of our little girl, Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not a little girl any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen her!... She's alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen throws herself against his chest, sobbing. Ethan looks past her at Clayton. And the faces of both men are grim.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen her... and she's alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just stares at her -- very lovely, strangely remote. He suddenly is conscious of his dirty hands, his dusty, worn clothing.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Martie....</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I wrote you a letter... Reckon you didn't get it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One letter in five years... I read it till the paper dried up and the writing faded out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't much of a letter...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it wasn't... You mighta said you loved me... You mighta asked me to wait... At least that'd have been something...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I allus loved you... You know that, without my sayin' it... I couldn't bring myself to ask you to wait... the little I had... not knowin' how much longer until we found Debbie...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sinks onto the bench.</context>
      <utterance>It isn't fair...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't cry, Laurie... I understand how it is... I'll just go 'way...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they are kissing through her tears when the outer door is flung open by Charlie MacCorry. They part as he glares.</context>
      <utterance>You do and I'll die, Martie... I will! I'll just die!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stares at him, then at her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll thank you to leave the room, Laurie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie MacCorry!... You weren't fixin' to marry HIM??</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sure is!... An' don't think your comin' back is goin' to change it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As to that, I don't know, Charlie... We hadn't got around to talkin' marriage...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What right you got to be talkin' marriage to any decent woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're talkin' about that crazy murder charge...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin swings wildly but Charlie is a wily fighter. He side- steps and chops Martin in the jaw and drives him against the wall. Laurie runs between them.</context>
      <utterance>AND other things... Mebbe you thought you was gettin' away with being comical about that Indian wife you took... I bet she wasn't the first squaw you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin gently brushes her aside.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Both of you... I won't have any fighting in this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right... Charlie, let's move outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin nods and unbuckles his gunbelt. The men head outside as Laurie runs to get help.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't wearing no gun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie turns slightly and in that instant Martin springs and drives a straight right at his face -- almost as though there were a knife in the hand. MacCorry stumbles back into Clayton's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant MacCorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this in the line of duty, sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir... pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin waits at a crouch as Charlie comes in, feints his right and crosses his left. It is a hard blow but Martin recovers and waits... Charlie circles and starts to repeat. He feints his right but this time Martin springs in, ducks and -- as the left shoots out -- he grabs the wrist and throws Charlie over his head. What we are looking at, in effect, is a wrestler against a boxer.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, give the boys room...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight fair, son... Use your fists!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that he releases the paralyzed arms just long enough to grab a lock of Charlie's hair and neatly snip it off. He stands then and laughs as Charlie lamely gets to his feet -- easing the tortured arms. Clayton goes to Charlie's side. Laurie moves to Martin's side.</context>
      <utterance>Could scalp him... but I'll just count coup!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right, sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunno... Seems so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie frowns and looks off at where Laurie and Martin are standing.</context>
      <utterance>Well, go get cleaned up and we'll proceed with the weddin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks rather unsteadily away leaving a thunderstruck assembly, murmurous with surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't goin' to be any weddin' -- not till we get a few things cleared up 'round here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>NESBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... it was a nice weddin' party... considerin' no one got married... 'Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Jorgensen puts her handkerchief to her eyes -- letting down now that the guests have gone. Jorgensen crosses to her, pats her sympathetically.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Ed...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads her away. Clayton faces Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Now, mamma!...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to ask you and Martin to ride to the State Capitol with me, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This an invite to a necktie party, Reverend?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan casually reaches into his pocket, takes out a gold coin and spins it.</context>
      <utterance>Captain... Nope, wouldn't say that... Likely you had your reasons for killin' Futterman... Probably needed killin'... I'm speaking as a ranger now, not as a reverend... Fact that all three was shot in the back is the only thing that's raised some question -- that and a missin' gold piece known to have been on him just prior to his demise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin crosses to confront Clayton.</context>
      <utterance>That so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie gets to his feet and he has his gun in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't goin' to Austin, Reverend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're goin' if the captain says you're goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fast hoofbeats sound o.s. -- signalling the approach of a four-man cavalry detail.</context>
      <utterance>Now, now... let's not grow disputatious...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Jorgensen head for the door.</context>
      <utterance>What's that? More company?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice hails from outside.</context>
      <utterance>Kinda late getting here, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello there! Captain Clayton?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Captain Clayton here, Reverend?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant gapes at Clayton's ministerial coat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Clayton.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan chuckles, to Clayton's very obvious annoyance.</context>
      <utterance>You're Captain Clayton?...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Colonel wishes to know how soon you could put a company of Rangers in the field, fully armed and...</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Greenhill's compliments, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on, son... Who's this Colonel Greenhill you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why Colonel Greenhill is Colonel Greenhill, sir... Commanding Officer, Fifth U.S. Cavalry... I'm Lieutenant Greenhill, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... Now what's this your pa wants to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pa wants to know... Colonel Greenhill wants to know how soon you could put a company of your Rangers in the field, fully armed and equipped, for joint punitive action against the Comanches.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JOINT action?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir... We've received information about a band of Comanches under a chief named Scar...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What information?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That maybe he's not far from here -- holed up somewhere, waiting his chance to get back over the border... He raided north about a month ago... ran into more army than he bargained for... Now he's running for cover, for keeps this time...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what makes you think he's in this territory?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday, one of our patrols picked up a man claims he was a prisoner with Scar till only two days ago... He talks crazy but I brought him along... Says he lives here... keeps mentioning a rocking chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he is striding to the door, calling it:</context>
      <utterance>Mose...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MOSE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the old man totters in, half-supported by a trooper -- hollow-eyed, weak, almost delirious.</context>
      <utterance>Ay-he?... Ay-eh?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come f'r my rockin' chai'... ole Mose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Scar, Mose... SCAR?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him about Debbie!... Is she all right, Mose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My rockin' chai'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mose... try to remember!... You were in Scar's camp...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ay-he... Made out I was crazy...  Ate dirt... chewed grass... I fooled 'em, Ethan!... an' I got away...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scar! Where's he holed in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He staggers and this time Mrs. Jorgensen won't be denied.</context>
      <utterance>Seven Fingers... ay-he... Seven...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. JORGENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads him away, at last to his rocker by the fire. During this, Ethan and Clayton have been mulling Mose's answer.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's enough! Here... by the fire... What you need's a good bowl of soup...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven Fingers?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what he told us... but there's no such place on the maps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! Isn't that the Caddo name for where all those canyons branch on the Malapai?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam Clayton wheels on the Lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Caddo or Kiowa... ay-he... ay-eh...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell your pa a company of Rangers -- all fourteen of 'em -- fully armed an' equipped will be in the field by daylight... headin' for the south end of the Malapai. If he can catch up with us, well an' good...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but captain, we can't possibly take the field tomorrow... for your own protection...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lieutenant skedaddles. Sam whirls on Martin and Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Sonny, yonder's a passel of murderers, complete with Texican scalps an' white girl captive... You want to protect us, you just get out of our way... Now skedaddle!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, you an' Martin are hereby appointed civilian scouts -- without pay... Charlie, hightail it to headquarters an' spread the word...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Martin's hands go to his side -- recalling where he left his guns.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads for the inner door to the grandmother room.</context>
      <utterance>My guns...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martie... don't go! Not this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late... She's a woman grown now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to fetch her home...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fetch what home?... The leavin's of Comanche bucks -- sold time an' again to the highest bidder?... With savage brats of her own, most like?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laurie! Shut your mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what Ethan will do if he has a chance?... He'll put a bullet in her brain! And I tell you Martha would want him to!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides out past her.</context>
      <utterance>Only if I'm dead!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they stride out,</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can get within 500 yards... there's a hogback to the south.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many, would you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves as though to mount, but Martin steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Enough to go around... I'd say about a dozen apiece... Mount 'em up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! We go chargin' in, they'll kill her... and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam stares at him, but Martin isn't surprised.</context>
      <utterance>It's what I'm countin' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you are... Only it ain't goin' to be that way... she's alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Livin' with Comanches ain't bein' alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alive... Better she's alive and livin' with Comanches than her brains bashed out...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now son, it's a bitter thing to say, but there's more than your sister at stake here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There sure is! I'm going to tell you somethin'... I wasn't going to speak of it... But I'll tell you now. Did you notice them scalps strung on Scar's lance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>MARTIN NODS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see the third scalp from the point of the lance? Long... wavy hair...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it... And don't try to tell me it was Aunt Martha's or Lucy's...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin stares, quick disbelief in his eyes. But Ethan's eyes hold his and there is no doubting the truth in them.</context>
      <utterance>You don't remember it, but I remember. That was your mother's scalp!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to tell you... but maybe it's your right to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam puts his hand on Martin's elbow -- as though to turn him to his duty. But Martin jerks the arm away.</context>
      <utterance>Now mount up, son...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It don't change it... All I'm askin' is a chance to sneak in there... an' try to get her out before you come chargin' in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you're caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't tell 'em anything, will it! Just a man alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say NO!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan looks long and hard at Martin, then reaches into his shirt for the folded, dirty, dog-eared paper that was his will. Slowly he tears it into shreds.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, son... But at the first alarm, we're comin' in -- and we ain't goin' to have time to pick and choose our targets when we do...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin squats and starts pulling off his boots. He glances up as Charlie MacCorry comes over, an Indian blanket in his hands. He tosses it onto Martin's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It's your funeral...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he grins and extends his hand. Martin takes it -- and they shake as Charlie pulls him to his feet. Martin drops his hat, and then -- at a crouching run -- he heads for the distant Comanche camp.</context>
      <utterance>Here... you fight like a Comanch... Maybe this'll help ya pass as one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam whips off his hat and makes frantic signals to Greenhill to shut up. Greenhill pulls to a canter, puzzled, and rides in.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Clayton... Captain!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on! Whyn't you have your bugler sound the charge while you're at it??</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind... Your pa know you're out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir... Troop's about ten miles back... The Colonel sent me looking for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts away. Greenhill follows.</context>
      <utterance>Well you found me... Good work, son... Good work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's anything I can do, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God forbid... No, son, you flog on back and tell your pa where we're at... and where he's at...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he knows THAT, sir... Can't I stay, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... But keep your eye on me, boy... I'm the hard case you're up against here -- not these childish savages... If you don't hear me first time I holler, you better read my mind... I don't aim to raise no two hollers on any subject at hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREENHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips out his sabre -- to the imminent peril of Captain Sam who quickly shifts out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Sam continues away and the Rangers after him.</context>
      <utterance>Watch that knife, boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then her fingernails rake his hand. He winces and lets go. She screams and tries to leap up. He grabs her. The other squaws wake -- begin squawking.</context>
      <utterance>Debbie... don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debbie sees something beyond him. Her eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>I'm takin' you whether you want to or not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clayton, if you were in my command I'd have you courtmartialed for this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAYTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie just gapes, but Clayton -- grim-lipped -- bends a meaningful glare on someone off. Greenhill looks that way.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, sir... You wounded? What is it, Sergeant -- a bullet or an arrow?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
