<movie id="550" title="Thelma and Louise">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, wait now. I still have to ask Darryl if I can go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Thelma has the phone tucked under her chin, as she cuts out coupons from the newspaper and pins them on a bulletin board already covered with them. We see various recipes torn out from women's magazines along the lines of "101 Ways to Cook Pork."</context>
      <utterance>You mean you haven't asked him yet? For Christ sake, Thelma, is he your husband or your father? It's just two days. For God's sake, Thelma. Don't be a child. Just tell him you're goin' with me, for cryin' out loud. Tell him I'm havin' a nervous breakdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He already thinks you're out of your mind, Louise, that don't carry much weight with Darryl. Are you at work?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm callin' from the Playboy Mansion.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma goes through the living room to the bottom of the stairs and leans on the banister.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DARRYL comes trotting down the stairs. Polyester was made for this man, and he's dripping in "men's" jewelry. He manages a Carpeteria.</context>
      <utterance>Darryl! Honey, you'd better hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damnit, Thelma, don't holler like that! Haven't I told you I can't stand it when you holler in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darryl is checking himself out in the hall mirror, and it's obvious he likes what he sees. He exudes over-confidence for reasons that never become apparent. He likes to think of himself as a real lady killer. He is making imperceptible adjustments to his over-moussed hair. Thelma watches approvingly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Doll, I just didn't want you to be late.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a good day at work today.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want anything special for dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Thelma, I don't give a shit what we have for dinner. I may not even make it home for dinner. You know how Fridays are.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny how so many people wanna buy carpet on a Friday night. You'd almost think they's want to forget about it for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's finally ready. He walks to the door and gives Thelma the most perfunctory kiss on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, it's a good thing you're not regional manager and I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bye, honey. I won't wait up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darryl leaves. We see his Corvette parked out front. As he closes the front door, Thelma leans against it.</context>
      <utterance>See ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma laughs to herself. She goes back into the kitchen and picks up the phone and dials it.</context>
      <utterance>He's gonna shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise comes over and takes the phone out of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning. Why, yes, she is. Is this Thelma? Oh, Thelma, when you gonna run away with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this weekend, sweetie, she's runnin' away with me.  Hi. What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time are you gonna pick me up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kiddin'! Alright! I'll be there around two or three.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of stuff do I bring?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Warm stuff, I guess. It's the mountains. I guess it gets cold at night. I'm just gonna bring everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I will, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And steal Darryl's fishin' stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to fish, Louise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both hang up.</context>
      <utterance>Neither do I, Thelma, but Darryl does it, how hard can it be? I'll see you later. Be ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need the lantern. The place has electricity.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna take it anyway. Just in case.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case there's some escaped psycho killer on the loose, who cuts the electricity off and tries to come in and kill us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, sure, Thelma, that lantern will come in real handy. Maybe we could tow your car behind, in case he steals the spark plugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They load everything into the car. The trunk barely closes. Thelma heaves all her weight against it. They get into the car and pull out of the driveway. As they drive down the street, we hear Thelma let out a long howl. She is laughing and she sticks her arms straight up in the air.</context>
      <utterance>We'd have to. That thing barely makes it down the driveway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise shrieks at the sight of it.</context>
      <utterance>Louise, will you take care of the gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma wonders if Louise is really that naive.</context>
      <utterance>Why in hell did you bring that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise reaches over and takes the gun out of Thelma's purse and holds it in her hand. She tests the weight of it, and then puts it under the seat. Thelma puts the bullets under the seat. They are speeding off down the highway with the RADIO blaring. Louise puts in a TAPE of wild R&amp;B MUSIC.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, Louise... psycho killers, bears... snakes! I just don't know how to use it. So will you take care of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose place is this again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Bob's, the day manager's. He's gettin' a divorce, so his wife's gettin' this place, so he's just lettin' all his friends use it till he has to turn over the keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never had the chance to go out of town without Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come he let you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause I didn't ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, shit, Thelma, he's gonna kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both silent for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he has never let me go. He never lets me do one goddamn thing that's any fun. All he wants me to do is hang around the house the whole time while he's out doing God only knows what.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a pause.</context>
      <utterance>I left him a note. I left him stuff to microwave.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise's jaw tightens. The car speeds up.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you haven't heard anything from Jimmy... yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge semi-tanker carrying gas passes them on the highway and HONKS. The mud flaps are the shiny silhouettes of naked women. There is a bumper sticker on the back that says: "Lick you all over -- ten cents."</context>
      <utterance>...never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is watching herself in the side mirror, pretending to smoke a cigarette. THELMA'S POV OF A SIGN alongside the road that reads "See you in church on Sunday!" Thelma pushes in the lighter and waits for it to pop out. Louise gives her a sidelong glance, but does not say anything.</context>
      <utterance>One of your friends?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much longer is it gonna be? I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another hour of so. We've got enough food for a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never make it... Can't we stop just for a few minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've not gonna get to the cabin till after dark as it is, Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise realizes that Thelma is going to revert to a teenager and continue whining unless she gives in.</context>
      <utterance>Then what difference does it make if we stop? Come on. I never get to do stuff like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, but it's gonna be a quick stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen a place like this since I left Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WAITRESS comes over and drops two menus on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't this fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all wanna drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Waitress leaves:</context>
      <utterance>I'll have Wild Turkey straight up and a Coke back, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me somethin'. Is this my vacation or isn't it? I mean, God, you're as bad as Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just haven't seen you like this in a while. I'm used to seeing you more sedate.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Waitress returns:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've had it up to my ass with sedate! You said you and me was gonna get outta town and, for once, just really let our hair down. Well, darlin,' look out 'cause my hair is comin' down!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright...  I changed my mind. I'll have a margarita with and a shot of Cuervo on the side, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Waitress leaves, a MAN comes over with a chair which he pulls up to the table and straddles backwards. He is in his late-40's, heavyset, his face is shiny in the neon light.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what are a couple of Kewpie dolls like you doin' in a place like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mindin' our own business, why don't you try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise kicks Thelma under the table.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we left town for the weekend 'cause we wanted to try and have a good time. And because Louise here is mad because her boyfriend won't call her while he's out on the road...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just wanted to get somethin' to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress returns with Louise's drink.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you come to the right place. You like chili? They got good chili.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harlan, are you botherin' these poor girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode>MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, no. I was just bein' friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise understands.</context>
      <utterance>It's a good thing they're not all as friendly as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name's Harlan? I got an uncle named Harlan!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlan laughs. Thelma laughs, too, but doesn't really get the joke. Louise does not laugh.</context>
      <utterance>You do? Is he a funny uncle? 'Cause if he is, then he and I got somethin' in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to be rude, but I've got something I need to talk to my friend about. In private.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, I understand. I didn't mean to bother ya. It's just hard not to notice two such pretty ladies as yourselves.  You better dance with me before you leave, or I'll never forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlan leaves, then:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. That'd be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, Louise, that wasn't very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you tell when somebody's hittin' on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what if he was? It's all your years of waitin' tables has made you jaded, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma knocks back her shot of Wild Turkey and holds up her glass to the Waitress to bring her another one. The Waitress sees her and nods. She turns back to face her friend.</context>
      <utterance>Well, just relax, will ya. You're makin' me nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Jimmy still hasn't called yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Givin' him a taste of his own medicine. Asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Louise. I know you're all upset. It's just I'm so excited to be out of the house, I guess.  I wonder if Darryl's home yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if Jimmy's gotten back.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell him to just to get lost once and for all?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both drift off momentarily, contemplating their domestic problems, until the Waitress comes over:</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you ditch that loser husband of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma looks over at the bar where Harlan is grinning at her, making dancing motions. She smiles and waves at him. Her face becomes serious again as she turns back to Louise.</context>
      <utterance>This one's on Harlan.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma's mind goes too fast for her mouth, and the speed at which she speaks can be staggering. Louise is used to it. Louise smiles wistfully at Thelma's assessment of the situation.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy'll come in off the road, you won't be there, he'll freak out and call you a hundred thousand times, and Sunday night you'll call him back and, by Monday. He'll be kissin' the ground you walk on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She again drinks her whole shot of Wild Turkey and holds up her glass, as the BAND strikes up a lively tune. Practically the whole place "whoops" and heads for the dance floor. Louise drinks her shot of tequila and holds up her glass, too.</context>
      <utterance>In the meantime, you said we were gonna have some fun. So let's have some!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma, I'm gonna hit the little girls' room, and then we gotta hit the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise heads off to the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Ready when you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is heading towards the bathroom, where there is a line of at least fifteen women in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>Louise, I'm gonna come with you.  I don't feel so good. She stumbles a step and drops her beer bottle.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise leans against the wall, waiting in line.</context>
      <utterance>Oopsy-doopsy. We need to get you some fresh air, little lady. He steers her towards the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm spinning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlan is leaning close to Thelma's head, and she pulls her head away.</context>
      <utterance>How you feelin' now, darlin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm startin' to feel a little better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her to him and tries to put his arms around her. Thelma pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're startin' to feel pretty good to me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I need to keep walking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. I'm married. I don't feel good. I've been sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlan is pushing himself on her now, and she is beginning to push him away harder.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I'm married, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful. It's okay. I won't hurt you. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Goddamnit, I mean it! Louise is gonna wonder where I am. Let go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise is alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no trace of friendliness in his face now. He looks mean and dangerous. He lets go of her face and pins her arms behind her. He holds both of her arms with one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you hit me! Don't you fucking hit me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his free hand, he reaches down and starts to pull her dress up. Thelma is still struggling and there are tears running down her face.</context>
      <utterance>You just shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt me. Harlan. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns her around, pushing her face down onto the back of the car. He holds both her arms in one hand and continues pulling her dress up over her hips. He starts to undo his pants as we hear the CRUNCH of gravel.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT SHOT of the barrel of Thelma's gun being pressed into the nape of Harlan's neck. Louise's thumb pulls back the hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Louise!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harlan slowly raises his hands in the air, and Thelma darts out, pulling her dress down.</context>
      <utterance>You let her go, you fat fucking asshole, or I'm gonna splatter your ugly face all over this nice car.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise glances at Thelma. Thelma shakes her head no.</context>
      <utterance>Now, calm down. We were just havin' a little fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise starts to back away, but the gun is still close to his face. His pants are undone in the front. She is still backing away with the gun raised. Thelma is inching away as well.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you've got a real fucked up idea of fun. Now turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise lowers the gun and stares at him for a second. Then she turns and walks away. Thelma does, too.</context>
      <utterance>Just for the future, when a woman's crying like that, she's not having any fun!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise stops in her tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Bitch. I should have gone ahead and fucked her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise takes two long strides back towards him, raises the gun and FIRES a bullet into his face. We hear his body HIT the gravel parking lot. LOUISE'S POV. The car behind him is splattered with blood. Thelma and Louise are both silent. We hear the SOUND of the nightclub in the distance. Louise lowers the gun.</context>
      <utterance>I said suck my cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! Louise, you shot him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma runs to get the car.</context>
      <utterance>Get the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma comes careening up in reverse. Louise hops in and Thelma PEELS OUT, spraying gravel. As they speed out of the parking lot back to the road, we hear MUSIC blaring from the nightclub. They hit the main road with tires SQUEALING.</context>
      <utterance>You watch your mouth, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise lifts her hand and notices she is still holding the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Get back to the interstate.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! I... I, which way?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West. Left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise does not answer.</context>
      <utterance>Louise.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise. Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma starts to cry quietly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Thelma! I don't know! Just shut up a minute so I can think.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't we go to the cops? I mean, I think we should tell the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them what?! What, Thelma? What do you think we should tell them?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Just tell 'em what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which part?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of it. That he tried to rape me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only about a hundred people saw you cheek to goddamn cheek with him all night, Thelma! Who's gonna believe that?! We just don't live in that kind of world. Pull over!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise rests her head on the steering wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Louise... Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma doesn't hear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Christ.  Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma looks at her blankly, without answering.</context>
      <utterance>Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma's head moves almost imperceptibly. Louise studies Thelma's face.</context>
      <utterance>I've gotta stop for a minute. I've got to get it together. I'm gonna find a place to get a cup of coffee and I'm gonna sit down for a second. Do you want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, Thelma slightly moves her head in a nod. Louise puts the car in gear and pulls OUT OF SHOT.</context>
      <utterance>Is that yes? Are you up to this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta be inconspicuous. Do you know what that means?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, she twitches more than nods.</context>
      <utterance>It means you don't talk to anybody. You don't draw attention to yourself in any way. Do you understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma nods more firmly now. She understands. VARIOUS POV SHOTS of truck drivers seeing Thelma and Louise wind their way towards the restaurant portion of the coffee shop. They look small and incongruous with the surroundings.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me you understand that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to think this through. We have to be smart. Now is not the time to panic. If we panic now, we're done for. Nobody saw it. Nobody knows it was us. We're still okay. Now all we have to do is just figure out our next move.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our next move? I'll say one thing, Louise. This is some vacation. I sure am having a good time. This is real fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you weren't so concerned with having a good time, we wouldn't be here right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what is that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means shut up, Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at Thelma for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>So this is all my fault, is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress comes and fills their coffee cups. Thelma stands up to go to the bathroom. She grabs her purse from the counter, and the strap catches on her coffee cup and it falls to the floor with a CRASH. All heads turn and look at her.</context>
      <utterance>Just shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Louise.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go to the bathroom. I... Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you identify 'em, if ya saw 'em again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENA</speaker>
      <mode>WAITRESS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hal, I've told you about twenty times, yes, I could identify 'em, but neither one of them was the type to pull something like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're not exactly an expert witness, but what makes you so sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If waitin' tables in a bar don't make you an expert on human nature, then nothin' will, and I could've told you that Harlan Puckett would end up buyin' it in a parkin' lot. I'm just surprised it didn't happen before now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has anybody asked his wife? She's the one I hope did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lena, just cut the bullshit, will ya? Do have any ideas or don't ya? I been standin' in this stupid parkin' lot all goddamn night, and I still got to go file a report before I can go home in time to get back up again!</utterance>
   <speaker>LENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if I had to guess, I'd say it was some ol' gal, some ol' gal's husband. But it wasn't either one of those two. The tall one, the redhead, she left me a huge tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't happen to notice what kind of car they were driving?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a nightclub, not a drive-in, Hal. I don't follow the customers to the parking lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lena gets out of the back of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Lena. Go on home. We might have to call you in for some more questioning.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those girls are not the murderous type.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up and goes into the bathroom. As the door closes behind her, Louise comes up with a handful of change and starts putting it into the phone. She dials a number. It RINGS for a long time. She hangs up and goes into the bathroom. She looks at herself in the mirror. She notices a tiny speck on her cheek. She takes a paper towel and wets it and rubs the spot. She looks at the towel and there is a bright red streak.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'll try later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door of the stall flies open and Thelma comes charging out and heads straight for the door, without even looking at Louise. Louise charges out after her. They head out of the restaurant and, THROUGH THE WINDOW, we see them get into the car and drive away.</context>
      <utterance>Thelma... Come on, Thelma!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna go to the next town and stop. We'll get a motel room. I can rest for a while and then figure out how to get some money. We're gonna need money. Thelma. How much money do you have with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is rummaging through her purse. She finds her wallet and takes it out. Thelma finds some bills stuffed in the change compartment and takes them out. She straightens the money out.</context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, I don't know. Let me look.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she is counting it, one of the bills flies out of her hands. Thelma's not that good at handling money.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty-four dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise has not noticed any of this. She is so intent on her driving.</context>
      <utterance>Umm. Shit. Forty-four dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm cash poor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. We gotta get some money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise did not realize she was doing it.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you unpacking? You said we were just gonna take a nap.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. I'm just nervous. I gotta figure out what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, when you figure it out, wake me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise slams the closet door. Thelma jumps.</context>
      <utterance>Just what the hell is wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you actin' like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are silent for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Actin' like what?! How am I supposed to act? 'Scuse me for not knowing what to do after you blow somebody's head off!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could help me try and figure it out! I gotta figure out what to do, and you could try and help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suggested we go to the police, but you didn't like that; so, frankly, Louise, I'm all out of ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what's the big rush, Thelma? If we just give 'em some time, they'll come to us...! Oh Christ. I'm just not ready to go to jail yet. Why don't you go out to the pool or something and I'll figure it out...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not touchin' that car.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My stuff's in the trunk! God! You care more about that car than you do about most people.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most people just cause me trouble, but that car always gets me out of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The I.D. TECH comes over and looks and shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>I.D. TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose?</utterance>
   <speaker>I.D. TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal makes a face like he suddenly felt a slight toothache. He stares at the guy.</context>
      <utterance>His, I guess...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal takes out a black sharpie and draws a circle around the area of the black smudge and the drop of blood. He shakes his head slightly.</context>
      <utterance>You guess?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANSWERING MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A VOICE interrupts the message:</context>
      <utterance>Hi. This is Jimmy. I'm not here right now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The machine switches OFF.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! I'm here. Hang on a minute!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise! Where are you? Are you alright? Honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm okay. How are you? Long time no see.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louise is still looking at herself in the mirror, as if she's never seen herself before.</context>
      <utterance>Louise, honey... Where are you? You sound funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am funny. I'm real funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in town? This sounds long distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm out of town. I'm in... I'm in real deep shit, Jimmy. Deep shit Arkansas.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise, just tell me what the hell is going on here! I come back, nobody knows where you are. Is Thelma with you? Darryl's been callin' here every half-hour sayin' he's gonna kill you both when you get back, he's goin' nuts. I don't envy her if she is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd y'all go?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fishing. Look, Jimmy... I need you to help me. This is serious. I'm in trouble and I need you to help me. Can you do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a savings account with about sixty-seven hundred dollars in it. Now I know you won't be able to get it out, but I'm good for it. I need that money. Can you wire me the sixty-seven hundred dollars and I'll pay you back? Please, I'm desperate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something real bad has happened and I can't tell you what, just that it's bad and I did it and I can't undo it. Can you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louise sits on the edge of the bed. She is looking at her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Of course! Where? Can't I bring it to you? For God's sake, baby, please, just tell me what's happened, what could possibly be so bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the ring that she wears on her left hand and turns it around backwards to make it look like a wedding band.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, sure... yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wire it to the Western Union in Oklahoma City,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in Oklahoma?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise, let me call you back after I wire it, so you'll know which office to go to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't it go to any office?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, for that much money I have to tell them exactly which office. I know, I've had to have money wired to me on the road. And there has to be a code word or they won't give it to you. I'll have to tell you the code.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll call you back. In an hour. Don't tell Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Call me back. Louise, I love you, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you finish thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise PEELS OUT of the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>I think better when I drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All we know is there were two women in a green T-Bird convertible that turned left out of the parking lot, going real fast. We're trying to get a make on the car, but nothin' yet. So far, we got nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you'd best get something. Even if they didn't do it, it times out that they most likely witnessed it. I want somebody to at least talk to 'em. Put out an APB with a description and see what we get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any reason to believe they've left the state?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's certainly possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go ahead and let the bureau in on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no problem with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody's butt is gonna bar-b-que.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get mad, Louise, but where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oklahoma City. Jimmy's gonna wire me some money, and then...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talked to him?! Is he mad? Did you tell him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't tell him. And that's something we gotta get straight. Darryl's been callin', mad as a hornet, makin' all kinds of noise. When you talk to him, you cannot say anything about this. You gotta make sure everything sounds normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called the asshole at 4:00 in the morning and he wasn't even home. I don't know what he's got to be mad about. I'm the one who should be mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been tellin' you that for the last ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think Darryl's having an affair?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think Darryl is mature enough to conduct an affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you think he fools around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma, I'm going to Mexico. I think I can make it in two and a half days, but I'm going to have to haul ass. Are you up to this? I mean, I have to know. This isn't a game. I'm in deep shit. I gotta know what you're gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know. I don't know what you're askin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is staring down the road. She does not answer. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Don't you fall apart on me. Goddamnit, Thelma. Every time we get in trouble, you go blank or plead insanity or some such shit, and this time... Not this time. Everything's changed now... Now you can do whatever you want, but I'm going to Mexico. I'm going. Are you coming with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he does. Fool around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a pay phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise gets change while Thelma strolls around looking at rubber worms and pickled pigs' feet. Louise goes out to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>'Round the side, by the restrooms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that how you answer the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it. I was afraid I'd missed you. I almost couldn't get a check cashed. It's Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friend of mine, owns a club. Dickie Randall. You'd know him if you saw him. His brother was in your class. Terry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't say what it was for, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, honey. I told him I was buyin' a car. What is it for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. That was good. Where do I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a place called Shaw's Siesta Motel. The address is 1921 North East 23. It's under your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's the mysterious code word?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louise rolls her eyes and tries not to melt.</context>
      <utterance>That's the code word. I miss you, peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her finger down on the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Jimmy. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is walking towards the car. She puts her purse in the front seat. She looks at Louise.</context>
      <utterance>Go call Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call him. Don't tell him anything. Tell him you're having a wonderful time and you'll be home tomorrow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma and Louise look at each other while this sinks in.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I won't be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darryl... baby... Darryl, calm down now, honey. Please don't get so mad. I can explain...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He covers the mouthpiece and watches a play where "his team" fumbles the ball. This only makes him madder. He puts the phone back to his ear in time to hear Thelma say:</context>
      <utterance>Hold on. Hold on a minute, damnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...only for one day and we'll be back tomorrow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you won't. You'll be back today. Now! You get your ass back here, Thelma, now, Goddamnit. Thelma, do you understand me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither one of them say anything for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>That does it! That Louise is nothin' but a bad influence. If you're not back here tonight, Goddamnit, Thelma... well, I just don't wanna say...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up on him.</context>
      <utterance>Go fuck yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma nods her head "yes," but tears continue. Her crying is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Excuse me! Miss, are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma shakes her head "no." She tries to control her tears. She notices how blue his eyes are.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything I can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Thanks. Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma doesn't know what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Would you mind me asking which direction you and your friend are going? I'm trying to get back to school and my ride fell through, so I'm kinda stuck. Are you going my way?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm. I think we're going to Oklahoma City. But I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think you could... I mean, I could help pay for gas. Thelma knows Louise isn't going to like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm. Well, see, it's not really up to me. It's not my car. Umm, we'll have to ask my friend, but she'll probably say no. She's a little uptight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she wants him to come. He starts to walk away from the car.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Maybe we better not ask her. But thank you anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Louise comes out of the store. She sees Thelma talking to this guy and, for one moment, stops dead in her tracks as she takes this in, then continues toward the car. Although her face is basically expressionless, we see that it's possible she might kill Thelma.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we can ask her. That won't hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise, this young man is on his way back to school and needs a ride, and I thought since...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably not a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hitchhiker just nods and starts walking towards the road.</context>
      <utterance>Louise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy does seem really nice and Thelma is really frustrated that Louise wouldn't give him a ride, but decides not to confront her.</context>
      <utterance>Y'all have a nice day. Drive safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise lowers the top and backs the car out. They watch him walk away. Louise pulls out of the parking lot onto the road. They pass the Hitchhiker. Thelma waves.</context>
      <utterance>See how polite he is? He was really nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITCHHIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns around in the seat to continue waving. He smiles and waves. They drive down the road. TIGHT SHOT of the Hitchhiker as the smile fades from his face.</context>
      <utterance>You cheer up now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish we could've brought him with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Darryl say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said "Okay, Thelma. I just wanted to know you were alright. I hope you're havin' a good time. You sure deserve one after puttin' up with me all the time. I love you, honey." Louise doesn't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long before we're in Goddamn Mexico?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't see what it would hurt just to give somebody a ride. Did you see his butt? Darryl doesn't have a cute butt. You could park a car in the shadow of his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm just not in the mood for company right now. Here. Take this map. I need you to find all the secondary roads to Mexico from Oklahoma City. I think we should stay off the interstates. We're too conspicuous.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it looks like we can get on this road 81 that heads down towards Dallas, then cut over to...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to go that way. Find a way that we don't have to go through Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. What? You want to go to Mexico from Oklahoma and you don't want to go through Texas?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how I feel about Texas... We're not going that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Louise, but we're running for our lives! Don't you think you could make an exception just this once?! I mean, look at the map. The only thing between Oklahoma and Mexico is Texas!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma! I'm not gonna talk about this! Now find another way or give me the goddamn map and I will! You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is completely unreasonable on this subject and Thelma is totally puzzled by Louise's reaction but is reluctant to press her further.</context>
      <utterance>No, Louise. How come you never said what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks very shaken up. She keeps her eyes on the road but she's holding the steering wheel so tightly, her knuckles are white. She does not look at Thelma. Suddenly she reaches over and locks her door. Thelma flinches imperceptibly at this gesture.</context>
      <utterance>I... I just... I just don't think it's the place I wanna get caught for doin' something like... if you blow a guy's head off with his pants down, believe me, Texas is the last place you wanna get caught! Trust me! Now, I said, I don't wanna talk about it!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. We'll go around Texas to get to Mexico. This is crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So J.D., what are you studying in school?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Human nature. I'm majoring in behavioral science.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And whaddya wanna be when ya grow up?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise laughs. He has charmed her too.</context>
      <utterance>A waiter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how come you don't have any kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darryl, that's my husband, he says he's not ready. He's still too much of a kid himself. He prides himself on being infantile.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a lot to be proud of.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise and Darryl don't get along.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's puttin' it mildly.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She thinks he's a pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a real piece o' work. I wish you could meet him.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get married real young?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-four isn't young. I'd already been goin' out with him ten years when we got married. I've never been with anybody but Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you don't mind me sayin' so, he sounds like a real asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. is looking down the road, way off in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. He is an asshole. Most of the time I just let it slide.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks down the road and sees a highway patrol car coming down the road towards them. She does not look alarmed but veers off the road into a "rest area" drive that has trees and shrubs that obscure the view from the road. She glides along as the cop car passes on the other side without seeing them. Louise glides right back onto the road as if nothing unusual has happened at all. They realize they have not been spotted. J.D. and Louise look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Better slow down. That's a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you got a few too many parking tickets?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take you on to Oklahoma City, then you'd best be on your way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at J.D. in the back seat and takes the keys out of the ignition.</context>
      <utterance>I just gotta run in for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise gets out of the car and goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>You two better go on and say your goodbyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise Elizabeth Sawyer. Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise turns and sees Thelma crawl over into the back seat with J.D.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'. Nothin' came in today at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing under peaches? Check again under peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN comes up behind Louise and stands close behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, nothin' under peaches neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>JIMMY</mode>
      <context>He drops an envelope in front of her. Louise is startled and turns around quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Did you say Peaches?! Why that's the secret word! Show her what she's won, Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Jimmy! You... Oh my God! What are you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman hands them a key.</context>
      <utterance>Can we get another room? Just put it on my credit card.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Round to the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy! Hello, stranger. What in the world are you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask me no questions, I'll tell you no lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good answer. Same goes double for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. is climbing out of the car, looking very uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Who's your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is J.D. He's a student. We're just givin' him a ride to... to here. Louise said we could bring him here and then he'd have to go. And that's what he's doin'. He's goin'. Aren't you, J.D.?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quickly turns and walks away toward the road.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. Thanks for the ride. You all take care.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. That's him goin'. I love to watch him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy is smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Thelma kinda took to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, come on, gal, I got you a room. You can go on in and take a nice cold shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mind me, Jimmy, I'm just a wild woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always knew that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise shoots Thelma a look. The three of them drive around to the back of the motel. Thelma turns and looks at the road. J.D. is standing there. He blows her a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>A regular outlaw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is taking their luggage out of the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Let me just go in and freshen up for a minute. I need to wash my face, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy helps carry the luggage to Thelma's room. He stops at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, honey. I don't want to rush you. I just wanna talk to you and...  ...be alone with you. I'll just be in my room, 115, you just come on down when you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise smiles at him quizzically as if she can't believe he's acting this way. He turns on his heel and slinks away.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care what you say about him. The boy has got it bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's always got it bad as long as I'm running in the other direction. Don't be fooled, he's no different than any other guy. He knows how to chase and that's it. Once he's caught you, he don't know what to do. So he runs away.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise gets her purse and starts taking out her makeup. She stands very close to the mirror. She is putting on lip liner. Thelma is watching.</context>
      <utterance>Our future.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you gonna tell him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I'm not gonna tell him a thing. The least I can do is not make him an accessory any more than he already is.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is still putting on her makeup, making sure it's perfect.</context>
      <utterance>You are so sweet to that guy, you really are. Imagine not wanting to drag him into this. He is a lucky man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask him to come! It's like I said, Thelma, he just loves the chase.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well boy, he's got his work cut out for him now, don't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put a lid on it, Thelma! It's hard enough as it is. Just let me get this part over with. Now stay here and guard the money. If there's any problem I'm in room 115.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise turns to face Thelma.</context>
      <utterance>I won't wait up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a vision, Louise, a goddamn vision of loveliness, you always are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Have another drink, Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The following eleven roses are held out the door, then Louise is yanked inside and we hear her shriek with LAUGHTER.</context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another KNOCK.</context>
      <utterance>Louise?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Thelma opens the door and there stands J.D., soaking wet from the rain pouring down behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Thelma? It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's kind of looking over towards the road. He's still slightly shy.</context>
      <utterance>I just thought I... I know I'm supposed to be gone, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices looking past her into the room that Louise isn't there. Thelma just stands there looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not havin' much luck gettin' a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I'd better...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...! Um, where ya going?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Nowhere. What are you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Nothin'. Took a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can tell he does want to but doesn't want to say so. So instead he just kind of stands there with a reticent grin on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you wanna use the shower?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I... where's Louise?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's off with Jimmy, that's her boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma pretends like she's had a lot of experience with this sort of thing.</context>
      <utterance>That's lonely for you, I guess. I always think of motel rooms as lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, well, they can be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, my little coconut, what seems to be the trouble here? Tell Daddy everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy, my daddy's still alive and it kind of gives me the creeps when you do that...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise just looks at him for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, just tell me what's the trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy is once again shocked by how serious she is.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy, I'm not gonna tell ya what the trouble is. Someday soon you'll understand why I can't. But I won't tell ya, so don't ask me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, peaches, okay. But can I ask you one thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it have something to do with another guy? Are you in love with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothin' like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise spills her champagne.</context>
      <utterance>Then what?! What, goddamnit, Louise! Where the fuck are you going? Are you just leaving for fucking ever? What, did you fuckin' murder somebody or what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Stop it, Jimmy, or I'll leave right now. I'm not kiddin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both take a second to regain their composure.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I just ask you one other thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy pulls a little black box out of his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Louise the box. She opens it and it is a diamond ring. Louise is flabbergasted.</context>
      <utterance>Will you wear this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you at least see how it fits?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy... it's beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't see that one comin', did ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So whaddya think. I mean... I could... uh... get a job. Of some kind. I mean you've been tellin' me that for years, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why now, Jimmy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise doesn't know how to respond. She struggles for a reply.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause, Louise. I don't want to lose you. And for some reason I get the feelin' you're about to split. Permanently.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy doesn't answer right away. He's trying to see it.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy, we've gone all these years... we never made it work. We're not gonna be able to just... I'm not... What kind of job, honey? Can you see it. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the one... I never made it work. I just... It's not that I don't love you. It's not that. I just never thought I'd be thirty-six years old and I never thought... I don't know what I thought. What do you want, darlin'. What do you want me to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy does not really understand why this is happening.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It doesn't even matter anymore. I just want you to be happy... It's not that I don't love you either. But Jimmy, your timing couldn't be worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you just doin' this to punish me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, the last thing I want is for you to get punished.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps from the dresser and flies across the room landing on the bed, straddling Thelma.</context>
      <utterance>Faster than a speeding green T-Bird, able to leap tall babes in a single bound...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma has not stopped laughing since he came in the room. He is the greatest guy she's ever seen. He is sniffing her neck like a dog.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Could I interest you in some Fuller brushes?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma tries to catch her breath.</context>
      <utterance>Stop, stop, stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. attacks her again.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the great and powerful Oz...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.D.! Just tell me. I know you're not some schoolboy. Now come on, nobody ever tells me shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma gasps.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just some guy. A guy whose parole officer is probably having a shit fit right about now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Parole officer? You mean you're a criminal?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not anymore, Thelma, except for bustin' parole, I haven't done one wrong thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did ya do?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a robber.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a bank robber?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. I've never robbed a bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I robbed a gas station once, and I robbed a couple of liquor stores, and some convenience stores. And that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was just down on my luck and it seemed like somethin' I was good at so I...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean how would you do it? Do you just sneak in real fast or hide out till the store closes or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, honey, that would be burglary. I never got arrested for burglary. Burglary's for chicken shits. If you're gonna rob someone, ya just have to go right on up to 'em and do it. Just take the money. That's robbery. That's a whole 'nother deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. jumps up and picks up a hair dryer and holds it like a gun. He starts acting it out.</context>
      <utterance>Well, first you pick your place, see, then I'd just sit back and watch it for awhile. Ya gotta wait for just the right moment, which is something you know instinctively, that can't be taught. Then I'd waltz on in...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'd say, "Alright, ladies and gentlemen, let's see who'll win the prize for keepin' their cool. Simon says everybody lie down on the floor. If nobody loses their head, then nobody loses their head. You sir... You do the honors. Just empty that cash into this bag and you'll have an amazing story to tell all your friends. If not, you'll have a tag on your toe. You decide." Then I'd split. Simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My gosh, you sure gentlemanly about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always believed if done right, armed robbery doesn't have to be a totally unpleasant experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God. You're a real live outlaw!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may be the outlaw, but you're the one stealin' my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss passionately.</context>
      <utterance>And smooth, boy, you are smooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kinda the best thing that's happened to me in a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. turns out the light.</context>
      <utterance>You're a little angle, you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. Completely.</context>
      <utterance>Louise? I think you are so damn beautiful. I mean that. I always have.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're beautiful too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry darlin'. I'll say I never found you. I'll say anything you want. We'll find a way to get you out of this, whatever it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, Jimmy, did you take a pill that makes you say all the right stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>I'm choking on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, into each other and Jimmy can see that Louise is already gone. Louise is really touched that he asked her that but she knows it's impossible. She is very kind to him.</context>
      <utterance>Honey? Ummm... Do you want me to come with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In her hand she's been holding the ring in the black box. She puts it on the table and slides it back to him. He stops her, suddenly. He covers her hand with his.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... now... it's probably not such a good idea right now. I'll... catch up with you later, on down the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy is trying not to seem upset, so he's completely still. A taxi pulls up outside.</context>
      <utterance>You keep this!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy pulls her to him and kisses her so passionately that employees in the coffee shop look away. A cook fans himself with a spatula. The taxi driver, who can see in, looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Your taxi's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at her hand and Jimmy's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Are you happy, Louise? I just want you to be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy gets up and leaves the coffee shop. Louise watches him go. A WAITRESS comes over and fills her coffee cup.</context>
      <utterance>I'm happy, sweetie. Happy as I can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress chuckles and the other waitresses do too. Louise waves to Jimmy in the back of the cab. The cab driver winks at her. She smiles to herself.</context>
      <utterance>Good thing he left when he did. We thought we were gonna have to put out a fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think you could ever shoot someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think you could ever think of a set of circumstances that would just cause you to haul off and shoot someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could shoot your cousin Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he's an inconsiderate asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking you seriously, Sarah, a stranger?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, honey. I guess it would depend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe if they were trying to hurt you or one of the kids. I'm sure I could shoot someone if they tried to hurt one of the children.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I could too. But... I don't know why I'm even asking you this. It's just... we can't place anybody at the scene but these two gals that everybody swears is sweet as pie. I don't know. I keep hearing words -- impossible -- inconceivable. If just one person would say...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey. Nothing's impossible. You just don't shoot someone like that for no reason. Maybe he was askin' for it. Anyway, somebody's husband probably got ol' Harlan.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what everybody says. Only problem is nobody's husband was unaccounted for that night... Could you shoot Eddie in the face? At point blank range?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go to Little Rock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is shocked by Thelma's appearance.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is studying Thelma closely as Thelma squirms in her seat, barely able to contain herself.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. It got messed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Why? Do I seem different?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, now that you mention it. You seem crazy. Like you're on drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not on drugs. But I might be crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is just laughing hysterically. Louise suddenly understands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, Louise!!! I can't believe it! I just really can't believe it! I mean... whoa!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Thelma. Oh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean I finally understand what all the fuss is about. This is just a whole 'nother ball game!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma, please get a hold of yourself. You're making a spectacle.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Louise, you're supposed to be my best friend. You could at least be a little bit happy for me. You could at least pretend to be slightly happy that for once in my life I have a sexual experience that isn't completely disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I am happy. I'm very happy for you. I'm glad you had a good time. It's about time. Where is he now?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taking a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is getting a bad feeling. She is already standing up putting money on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You left that guy alone in the room?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma has forgotten all about the money.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the money, Thelma?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both leaving the restaurant now. As they hit the door they both break into a full run.</context>
      <utterance>Ummm... it's on the table. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise comes back outside. She doesn't say anything. She is stoic, fighting tears.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit! I've never been lucky! Not one time!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise sits down on the sidewalk in front of the room. Thelma comes and sits beside her. Neither one says anything for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. That little sonofabitch burgled me. I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise shakes her head no.</context>
      <utterance>Louise? Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise has seen the end of the tunnel and there is no light.</context>
      <utterance>Louise... It's okay. Louise? I'm sorry. I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise quietly starts to fall apart. This causes Thelma to leap into action.</context>
      <utterance>It's not okay, Thelma. It's definitely not okay. None of this is okay. What are we going to do for money? What are we gonna buy gas with? Our good looks? I mean... Goddamn, Thelma!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is still sitting on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Stand up! Don't you worry about it. I'll take care of it. Just don't you worry about it. Get your stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise slowly gets to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Damnit, get your stuff and let's get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is hauling stuff out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Move!  Jesus Christ, take your damn time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to leave someone here at the house in the event that she calls in. Someone will be here until we find them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The important thing is not to let on that you know anything. We want to try and find out where they are. Now I don't want to get too personal, but do you have a good relationship with your wife? Are you close with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess. I mean, I'm about as close as I can be with a nut case like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if she calls, just be gentle. Like you're happy to hear from her. You know, like you really miss her. Women love that shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty-eight dollars ain't gonna make a dent, baby girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. You want anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma marches off to the store. Louise puts a tape in the deck and is listening to loud R&amp;B MUSIC. She checks herself in the rearview mirror. She takes her lipstick out and is about to put it on. She makes eye contact with herself and, instead, throws it out the window, closes her eyes and leans her head back on the seat. She's in a world of shit. Thelma comes trotting out of the store and jumps into the car.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Drive!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive! Drive away!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma opens her purse and exposes a bag full of bills.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma shrieks with excitement. Louise is completely stunned.</context>
      <utterance>What? You robbed the store? You robbed the Goddamn store?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise shoots her a look. She puts the car in gear and FLOORS it out of the parking lot. She is still looking at Thelma as if she has completely lost her mind.</context>
      <utterance>Well! We needed the money! It's not like I killed anybody, for God's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Well, we need the money. Now we have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, Thelma!! Shit! Shit! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you get a grip, Louise! Just drive us to Goddamn Mexico, will ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Shit, Thelma! What'd you do? I mean, what did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I just...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>TIGHT SHOT of Darryl's face going deeper and deeper into a state of shock. TIGHT SHOTS of Hal, Max, etc., all looking intently at the screen. VIDEO IMAGE of Thelma boldly ordering cashier to fill her purse with money. As he's loading the purse with bills, she's taking beef jerky from the display and putting it in there, too, while she points the gun at the cashier.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, ladies and gentleman, let's see who'll win the prize for keepin' their cool. Everybody lie down on the floor. If nobody loses their head, then nobody loses their head...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, sir... You do the honors. Just empty that cash into this bag and you'll have an amazing story to tell all your friends. If not, you'll have a tag on your toe. You decide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise throws the map across the front seat at Thelma and FLOORS it.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme see the map.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at the speedometer touching 80 mph and lets her foot off the gas. Louise is looking a little nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Louise, you'd better slow down. I'll just die if we get caught over a speeding ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the first time in my life, I wish this car wasn't green.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure we should be driving like this? In broad daylight and everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we shouldn't, but I want to put some distance between us and the scene of our last Goddamn crime!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooooweee!! You shoulda seen me! Like I'd been doin' it all my life! Nobody would ever believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you've found your calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma howls like a dog and drinks a little bottle of Wild Turkey.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Maybe. The call of the wild!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're disturbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! I believe I am!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to God, she wouldn't tell me one thing! Christ! You oughta try to find that kid that was with 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy is really upset and has to really struggle to control himself.</context>
      <utterance>Just some young guy. Around twenty years old. Dark hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said they'd picked him up along the way. He was a student. But he didn't look right. But he left when they got to the motel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand that you may be facing an accessory charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is serious, son. A man is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know! I'd tell you if I knew! Goddamn! I know something happened, or she wouldn't have left. I'm trying to remember everything! Find that fucking kid. He probably knows something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the plan, Thelma? You just gonna stay drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come ROARING up on a semi-tanker carrying gas. We see their FISH-EYE REFLECTIONS in the shiny tanker. The mud flaps are the shiny silhouettes of naked women that Thelma and Louise saw earlier. The truck is going slower than they are.</context>
      <utterance>Litterbug.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She noses out to see if she can pass, but there's a car coming. The car passes and the truck HONKS. The truck driver's arm comes out his window and waves them past.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, great. This always happens. Whenever you're in a hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they get next to the truck, the truck driver is smiling and waving at them. They smile and wave back. He flicks his tongue at them. Louise screams.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that nice? Truck drivers are always so nice. The best drivers on the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA/LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise FLOORS it and speeds past him.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh!! Gross!! Oh my God! Aw, God!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugh!! Why do they have to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise shivers with disgust.</context>
      <utterance>They think we like it. Maybe they think it turns us on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the guy you saw them with?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, happy day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kiddin' me. They picked up a murderer?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Armed robber.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're flying him here right now. He was picked up this morning for parole violation. They also found about six grand on him, so he probably knocked over something while he was out there. They can drop him by here for questioning. I'm so happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much cash did he have?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to call Darryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To find out if he knows anything. If you think he does, you gotta hang up because it means the police have told him and the phone is probably tapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, Louise, tapped the phone? You think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on! Murder one and armed robbery, Thelma!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murder one! God, Louise, can't we even say it was self-defense?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it wasn't! We got away! We were walkin' away!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't know that! It was just you and me there. I'll say he raped me and you had to shoot him! I mean, it's almost the truth!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both pause for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>No physical evidence. We can't prove he did it. We probably can't even prove he touched you by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then:</context>
      <utterance>God. The law is some tricky shit, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise does not answer the question.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know 'bout all this stuff anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, what do we say about the robbery? No excuse for that. No such thing as justifiable robbery.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Louise!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the nut?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Thelma Dickinson's husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright! She did good! Didn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, son, she's doin' a damn sight better 'n you right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get $6600.00 in cash?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We spoke with a gentlemen today who says he personally delivered very close to that same amount to a Miss Louise Sawyer. Do you know her too?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm, yes. She was driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he took it to a motel in Oklahoma City. He also says that at that time he met a man. He identified you through a series of mug shots. He also told us that you and Mrs. Dickinson seemed "close." Is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might say we had a meeting of the minds, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know that Mrs. Dickinson and Miss Sawyer are wanted in connection with a murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did either of them ever indicate that they might be running from the Law?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that you mention it, they might have been a little bit jumpy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? You're starting to irritate me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal thinks for a moment and then looks to Max.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max agrees and opens the door for the others to leave. He and Hal make eye contact before Max closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Do you mind if I have a word with him alone for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal sits down across the table from J.D. and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>What?! What'd I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. doesn't say anything. They both just sit there for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Son, I gotta feelin' about somethin' and I just wanna ask your opinion. Do you think Thelma Dickinson would have committed armed robbery if you hadn't taken all their money?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. shifts in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Cat got your tongue?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I took it? How do you know they didn't just give it to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal walks over and opens the door and Max and the others straggle back in.</context>
      <utterance>There's two girls out there that had a chance, they had a chance...! And you blew it for 'em. Now they've gotten in some serious trouble, some very serious trouble and for at least part of it, I'm gonna hold you personally responsible for anything that happens to them. I've got no feelin' for you. But I may be the only person in the world who gives a rat's ass what happens to them and you're either gonna tell me every damn thing you know, so there's a small chance I can actually do them some good, or I'm gonna be all over you like a fly on shit for the rest of your natural life. Your misery is gonna be my goddamn mission in life. That's a sincere promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, for one thing, you violated your parole two days out. And you know Judge Hainey. He hates this sort of thing. Once he gets wind of this, he's gonna blow sky high. And then when he finds out that you're a possible accessory to murder and armed robbery, well, I think we can safely place your ass back in the slammer for at least the remaining eight, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Is somebody gonna write this down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Police officers lead J.D. out of the interrogation room, down the hallway. Darryl is watching J.D. closely. J.D. is smirking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dickinson, if you'll just hang on, I want a word with you and then we'll take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like your wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fill her up.  There's a phone right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma and Louise walk to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not kidding, Thelma. If you think he knows, even if you're not sure, hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darryl. It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma! Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darryl still holds the phone in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! All I said was hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma digs in her bag and hands Louise a roll of quarters. Louise gets out of the car and goes to the pay phone. Thelma follows her. She puts the money in and dials. It RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>You got any change?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darryl, this is Louise. Are the police there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DARRYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal comes over and takes the phone away from Darryl. Hal looks at Max who nods, "take it."</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about, Louise?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Miss Sawyer. I'm Hal Slocumbe, Chief Investigator, Homicide, Arkansas State Police. How are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You girls are in some hot water.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're both fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. You wanna tell me what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Maybe over coffee sometime. I'll buy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>No kiddin'. Listen, we gotta go. I'll call you back, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>On hearing this Louise mouths the word "shit" in a very frustrated way. Louise hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Sawyer, I don't think y'all are gonna make it to Mexico. We should talk. Please. I wanna to help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That J.D. kid is a little shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise stops as she is about to get in and faces Thelma who's standing on the other side of the car.</context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd they find out we're going to Mexico, Thelma, how they know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise yanks open her car door, gets in and slams the door and fires up the ENGINE. Thelma hops in quickly.</context>
      <utterance>You told that thievin' little shit where we were goin'?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just told him if he ever gets to Mexico to look us up. I asked him not to tell. I didn't think he would tell anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise careens back onto the road.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?! What's he got to lose? Other than my life's savings, that is. Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise slams on the brakes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I mean I...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise stops yelling for a moment groping for self-control. Thelma looks pitiful.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, Thelma! Let me explain something to you. Right now we have only two things goin' for us. One, nobody knows where we are, and two, nobody knows where we're going. Now, one of our things that was going for us is gone!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stop talkin' to people, Thelma! Stop bein' so open! We're fugitives now. Let's behave that way!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise? Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just past Boise City.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Idaho?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oklahoma, Thelma. We're crossing into New Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always wanted to see New Mexico.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whaddo we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know, Thelma. I guess maybe we could turn ourselves in and spend our lives trading cigarettes for mascara so we can look nice when our families come to visit us on Saturdays. Maybe we could have children with the prison guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma hands Louise a little bottle of Wild Turkey and she drinks it down. Thelma has one too.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not suggestin' that! I'm not goin' back. No matter what happens. So don't worry about me. Louise speeds up.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you kind of a weird question?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of all the things in the world that scare you, what's the worst thing that scares you the most?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean now or before?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I always thought the worst thing that could happen would be to end up old and alone in some crummy apartment with one of those little dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What little dogs?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know those little dogs you see people with?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a Chihuahua?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those, too, but you know those little hairy ones? Those flat-faced little fuckers with those ugly goddamned teeth?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. You mean Peek-a-poos.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Those. That always put the fear of God in me. What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, to be honest, the idea of getting old with Darryl was kinda startin' to get to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, look how different he looks just since high school. It's bad enough I have to get old, but doin' it with Darryl around is only gonna make it worse.  I mean, I don't think he's gonna be very nice about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, now, maybe you won't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always lookin' on the bright side, aren't ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh. It sure is.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always wanted to travel. I just never got the opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look forward for another moment. And then, at the same time, they look at each other, each taking the other one in completely, in this moment. They're saying everything to each other in this moment, but their expressions don't change and they don't say a word. MUSIC plays on the RADIO.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you got it now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look! Look who it is, Thelma. I'll be darned. What's he doin' way out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise passes him and, as she does, he HONKS. They look up and he is wildly pointing to his lap.</context>
      <utterance>Just ignore him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ. I hate this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should have just ignored him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. It's not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is trying to compose herself but cannot.</context>
      <utterance>What? What's not funny, Thelma!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma isn't making a sound. She is stuck in a convulsion of laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, but...  I can't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harlan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What about him?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the look on his face when you...  ...it's not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is still trying to get a grip on herself.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Thelma, that is not...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, he wasn't expectin' that!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is laughing wildly.</context>
      <utterance>Suck my dick... Boom!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma has just crossed the line from laughing to crying.</context>
      <utterance>Thelma. It's not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma leans back just watching Louise. She studies her as if she's never really seen her before. All of a sudden a look of shocked realization comes over Thelma's face. She jerks upright and startles Louise.</context>
      <utterance>I know! They both get quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about it! Thelma, I'm not kidding! Don't you even...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks as if she is looking for a way to flee.</context>
      <utterance>...in Texas... didn't it? That's what happened... Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm warning you, Thelma. You better drop it right now! I don't want to talk about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise's eyes are wild, not seeing, while Thelma now seems completely serene.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Louise... It's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma jumps awake.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Thelma, wake up! Shit! We're gettin' pulled over!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are trying not to panic. They are slowing down, but still doing 70 mph. The patrol car is right behind them.</context>
      <utterance>What! What! Oh shit! Oh no!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do? What do you want to do?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Shit! Let's just play it by ear. He may not know. He may just give me a ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise pulls the car off the road. The patrol car pulls up right behind them. The lights shine brightly in through the windows.</context>
      <utterance>Please, God, please don't let us get caught. Please, please, please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Louise does. The PATROLMAN gets out of his car and approaches their car. He comes to the driver's side window. It is rolled up. PATROLMAN'S POV OF LOUISE smiling up at him. He gestures to her to roll her window down. She does.</context>
      <utterance>Turn off your engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Officer. Is there a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise fumbles in her purse for her wallet, opens it and shows her license.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna let me see your license, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna take it out of your wallet, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does and hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you to slow down. Hell, Officer, I told her to slow down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About how fast was I going?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk to the back of the car. He notes the license plate number.</context>
      <utterance>About a hundred and ten. You wanna step out of the car, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna come with me, please? Walk around and get in the car, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the back?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patrolman gets in the driver's side. He picks up a clipboard and clips Louise's driver's license to it. He picks up the hand mike for the radio and, as he does, a hand with a gun comes in his car window. It's Thelma and she puts the gun to his head.</context>
      <utterance>As far as I'm concerned, yes, ma'am, you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops it.</context>
      <utterance>Officer, I am so sorry about this. Could you let go of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise reaches over and takes his gun.</context>
      <utterance>I really, really apologize, but please put your hands on the steering wheel. See, if you get on that radio, you're gonna find out that we're wanted in two states and probably considered armed and dangerous, at least I am, then our whole plan would be shot to hell. Louise, take his gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am really sorry about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear, before yesterday, neither one of us would have ever pulled a stunt like this. But if you ever met my husband, you'd know why I just can... You wanna step out of the car, please?  You wanna put your hands on your head, please? Louise, shoot the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise SHOOTS the car radio. The cop flinches with each shot.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot the radio!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise fires TWO SHOTS into the police radio. It BLASTS all to hell.</context>
      <utterance>The police radio, Louise! Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise reaches over and takes the keys. She takes her license off the clipboard. She gets out and trots around to the back of the car. Thelma is holding the gun on the Patrolman. Suddenly Thelma FIRES the gun, blowing two holes into the trunk cover.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna step to the back of the car, please. Louise, bring the keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise opens the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Open the trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna step into the trunk, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATROLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, please... I got kids... a wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he's climbing into the trunk, Thelma explains to Louise:</context>
      <utterance>You do? Well, you're lucky. You be sweet to 'em. Especially your wife. My husband wasn't sweet to me and look how I turned out. Now go on, get in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's all the way in and Louise closes the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Air holes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma hops into the car with Louise. They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise pulls the car back onto the road and they drive away.</context>
      <utterance>Hit it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's crazy, Louise, but I just feel like I've got a knack for this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive like hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just not working like this. We gotta do something. It'd be one thing if these girls were hardened criminals, but Jesus, Hal, this is makin' us look bad. I don't know... maybe they're not movin'. Maybe that little creep lied.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got nothin' to gain by lyin'. Nothin' at all. He already got all their money. I just don't know what we're dealin' with here. Anyway, it went out again last night on Nationwide Teletype. Let's just wait it out a little longer. She said she was gonna call back. Let's just sit tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have a whole lotta choice, do we? I can't figure out if they're real smart or just really, really lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cop walks into the kitchen and hands Hal a file that says Louise Elizabeth Sawyer on the outside. He opens it up and starts looking through a personal history. One piece of paper is a case file from Texas containing an incident report of a rape. Stamped across it are the words "charges dropped."</context>
      <utterance>It don't matter. Brains will only get you so far and luck always runs out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise... are we still going to Mexico?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma pauses while she searches for the logic.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then aren't we going in the wrong direction?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I figure if you take a state policeman, shoot up his car, take his gun and lock him in the trunk, it's best to just get on out of the state if you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both quiet for a second. Louise goes a little faster. Thelma is digging through her bag. She hands Louise a piece of beef jerky.</context>
      <utterance>Just asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to see any more beef jerky. I mean the next beef jerky you hand me is going out the window. It's drivin' me crazy. The whole car smells like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good. It's what the pioneers ate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma puts down her bag.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care what the damn pioneers ate. You just keep that shit away from me, now I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't want any more Wild Turkey, either. It's burning a hole in my stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay... I've got some tequila. You want some tequila?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you want it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma starts to dig through her bag again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is rubbing her face. She looks pretty bad. Her hands are shaking.</context>
      <utterance>It's in here somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. I'm gettin' tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise does not really seem alright.</context>
      <utterance>Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've really fucked up. I think I've got us in a situation where we could both get killed. Why didn't we just go straight to the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why. You already said.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I say again?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody would believe us. We'd still get in trouble. We'd still have our lives ruined. And you know what else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy was hurtin' me. And if you hadn't come out when you did, he'd a hurt me a lot worse. And probably nothin' woulda happened to him. 'Cause everybody did see me dancin' with him all night. And they woulda made out like I asked for it. And my life woulda been ruined a whole lot worse than it is now. At least now I'm havin' fun. And I'm not sorry the son of a bitch is dead. I'm only sorry that it was you that did it and not me. And if I haven't, I wanna take this time to thank you, Louise. Thank you for savin' my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Louise, you said the first part. I said all the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me speak to... Slocumbe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Louise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are things goin' out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird. Got some kind of snowball effect goin' here or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still with us though. You're somewhere on the face of the earth?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're not in the middle of nowhere, but we can see it from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear. Louise, I almost feel like I know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. You don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gettin' in deeper every moment you're gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you believe me if I told you this whole thing is an accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do believe you. That's what I want everybody to believe. Trouble is, it doesn't look like an accident and you're not here to tell me about it... I need you to help me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Through clenched teeth, repulsed:</context>
      <utterance>Did Harlan Puckett...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louise thinks for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>You want to come on in?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, certain words and phrases just keep floating through my mind, things like incarceration, cavity search, life imprisonment, death by electrocution, that sort of thing. So, come out alive? I don't know. Let us think about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A FINGER reaches up and presses down the lever and hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Louise, I'll do anything. I know what's makin' you run. I know what happened to you in Texas. Louise's eyes get wide as she hears this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE OF THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has her finger on the lever.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away towards the car. Louise is still standing there holding the phone. Thelma stops and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Louise. Don't blow it. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max, still holding the phone, is surprised by this outburst.</context>
      <utterance>Max. You gotta take me there! I'm... I'm the only one she's ever talked to. I don't want anybody losin' their heads. You know what happens. The volume gets turned way up and the next thing you know those girls are gonna get shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Hal, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Thelma?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna give up on me, are ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna make some deal with that guy, are you? I mean, I just wanna know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Thelma. I'm not gonna make any deals.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise is surprised to be hearing this from Thelma.</context>
      <utterance>I can understand if you're thinkin' about it. I mean, in a way, you've got something to go back for. I mean Jimmy and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thelma, that is not an option.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't know... something's crossed over in me and I can't go back. I mean, I just couldn't live...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both quiet for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I know what you mean. I don't wanna end up on the damn Geraldo Show.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said they're charging us with murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eeuww.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we have to decide whether we want to come out of this dead or alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise STARTS the car. They lurch into reverse then SCREECH forward as they tear off down the road.</context>
      <utterance>Gosh, didn't he say anything positive at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDE SHOT OF CAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as they fly down the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise, do you think we should change cars, get another car?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure... You know how to hotwire a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let me know when you figure it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could call it that. My eyes are open.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. I feel awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise and Thelma both get quiet for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Wide awake. I don't remember ever feelin' this awake. Everything looks different. You know what I mean. I know you know what I mean. Everything looks new. Do you feel like that? Like you've got something to look forward to?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be drinkin' margaritas by the sea, Mamasita.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can change our names.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can live in a hacienda.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna get a job. I wanna work at Club Med.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Yes! Now what kind of deal do you think that cop can come up with to beat that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'd have to be pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both laughing. The car is still flying down the road. The sun is coming higher in the sky now. They come to an intersection in the middle of nowhere. Louise stops and looks at the map.</context>
      <utterance>It would have to be pretty damn good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should head a little further in. There's not that many roads in this state. I want to try to hit Mexico somewhere not so close to New Mexico. They probably wanna kill us in New Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise takes a right turn and speeds down the road.</context>
      <utterance>You're drivin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Louise! Look! Look! See if that's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's him. He's got California plates. It's the same guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pass him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there! You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're fine! How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grrrreat!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn off onto a dirt road and pull to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>Follow us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fresno.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We been seein' you all along the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I been seein' you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise nods.</context>
      <utterance>We think you have really bad manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just wonderin' where you think you get off behavin' like that to women you don't even know. This is not what is supposed to be happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What are you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know good and damn well what I'm talkin' about.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean really! That business with your tongue. What is that? That's disgusting!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, oh my God, that other thing, that pointing to your lap? What's that supposed to mean exactly? Does that mean pull over, I want to show you what a big fat slob I am or...</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that mean suck my dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You women are crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got that right.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is getting a little panicky.</context>
      <utterance>We think you should apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not apologizing for shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you're sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise pulls the gun they stole from the State Patrolman.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Say you're sorry or we'll make you fuckin' sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You probably even called us beavers on your CB radio, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... sure did.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. I hate that! I hate bein' called a beaver, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to apologize or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise looks at his truck off in the distance. She points the gun at it, takes a second to get a bead, then SHOOTS two of the tires flat. The truck slowly sinks as the air escapes from the tires.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise and Thelma look at each other. They both turn towards the truck and FIRE rounds into the tankers until they EXPLODE in a huge ball of fire. The truck driver screams at the top of his lungs. Louise starts the car and starts driving in circles around the truck driver. Thelma and Louise are both howling at the top of their lungs. Thelma is sitting on the back of the front seat with her legs on the dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh goddamn!! You bitch!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise stops the car right next to him.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking bitch! Aaaaaaarrrgghh!!! You're gonna have to pay for that!!! I'm gonna make you pay for that!! You hear me??!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise takes off again and Thelma falls into the back seat. They drive off trailing a huge cloud of dust.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Where'd you learn to shoot like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pull away from the burning wreckage.</context>
      <utterance>Texas... You were right about what happened to me there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's happened, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've gone insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit. Louise... Do you think he saw us?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but let's get off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma puts her seat belt on. Louise floors the car and it streaks off, putting some distance between them and the police car. Thelma looks back at the police car. She looks scared.</context>
      <utterance>Is your seat belt on?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we shoulda made some kinda plan for what to do if we get caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. We're not gonna get caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...requesting assistance. In pursuit of a green T-Bird, 1966 license, seven, one, nine, William, Zebra, Adam...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger. Be advised...  ...armed and extremely dangerous...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far are we from Mexico?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About two hundred and fifty miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do you think that'll take?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that guy?! He was right in the middle of the road!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What d'you think?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We probably shoulda filled up the car before we blew up that truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll probably catch us when we have to stop for gas!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this whole thing was my fault. I know it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one thing you oughta understand by now, Thelma, it's not your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise... no matter what happens, I'm glad I came with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too, sweetie, the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I went a little crazy, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... You've always been crazy. This is just the first chance you've had to really express yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess everything from here on in is going to be pretty shitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbearable, I'd imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess everything we've got to lose is already gone anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile.</context>
      <utterance>How do you stay so positive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louise!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in the hell is that up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise strains to see. Whatever it is, Louise is barreling towards it, the car leaving the ground as they fly through the desert.</context>
      <utterance>Way up ahead!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise starts to laugh and cry at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in the hell is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Goddamn Grand Canyon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it beautiful?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise has tears streaming down her face as she realizes there is absolutely no escape. She continues barreling towards it without slowing down.</context>
      <utterance>It's grand!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God! It looks like the Army!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma starts to laugh. Louise is only concerned with missing the cacti and other obstacles that lie before her.</context>
      <utterance>All this for us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Don't let them shoot those girls. This is too much. They got guns pointed at 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max climbs out of the chopper. Hal sits for a moment and then leaps out and follows Max.</context>
      <utterance>The women are armed, Hal. This is standard. Now you stay calm here. These boys know what they're doin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Arizona Highway Patrol. You are under arrest. You are considered armed and dangerous. Any failure to obey any command will be considered an act of aggression against us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not giving up, Thelma.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's not get caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma is smiling at her.</context>
      <utterance>Go?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, look back at the wall of police cars, and then look back at each other. They smile.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT SHOT - CARTRIDGES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>being loaded into automatic rifle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARIZONA COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...heard they shot a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIZONA COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIZONA COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With his own gun. Put him in the trunk and blew him away...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn off the engine and place your hands in the air!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max goes around Hal and continues walking. Hal jumps in front of Max again and blocks his way.</context>
      <utterance>Max! Let me talk to 'em! I can't believe this! You've gotta do something here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to bother you, I know you're real busy right now, but how many times, Max? How many times has that woman gotta be fucked over? You could lift one finger and save her ass and you won't even do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max lets go of Hal's lapels.</context>
      <utterance>Get a hold of yourself! You are way out of your jurisdiction, now come on! Calm down! Don't make me sorry I let you come!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal is running now and clears the front row of cars. There is a lot of confusion among the officers on the front row. Some shout, some lower their guns to look.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIZONA COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in the hell?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIZONA #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The son of a bitch is in my way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, too, sweetie, the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thelma nods.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise puts the car in gear and FLOORS it.</context>
      <utterance>Hit it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
