<movie id="554" title="This Boy s Life">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Well, I mean it. I'm serious -- I do. You promise and promise, and then you change your mind, just like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait 'til you ask me for something. Just wait. See if you get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said -- for the twentieth time -- if a person promises somebody something, they can't just turn around and take it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, honey, Jesus. Don't start with that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm the mother, and I get to tell you what to do every minute of your life 'til you're eighteen. Seriously, we've got no money. I can't buy you the moccasins.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet if you'd promised Roy some moccasins he'd of got 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No talk about Roy, okay? And ditto the moccasins. We, can't, afford, them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but you did promise...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sue me. Take me to court. Oh, Toby, I know you're disappointed, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack. Call me Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to drive me to an early grave: I'm never going to make Salt Lake City.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously. If a person can't get a stinking miserable pair of moccasins, at least he ought to be able to choose his own name...  ... and I wanna be called Jack!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. And you can call me...  ... Jeanette. Jeanette Marie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're so stupid sometimes,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause. Then Toby speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that poor man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline turns to Toby, her face worried. Then she sees the look in Toby's eyes -- he's ragging her. She grins and gives his shoulder a light, affectionate shove.</context>
      <utterance>I hope to hell this isn't some kind of omen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's this thing work, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes a black light that, uh, causes uranium traces to glow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we just walk along the street and find this glowing uranium?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was everywhere in Moab, they say -- just like gold in the gold-rush days.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we were too late in Moab, and that guy at the office said nobody'd found any uranium in Salt Lake City.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It'll be like heaven on a June day.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that means we'll have the place pretty much to ourselves, huh? Honey, this could be a big break for us. If this works out, oh, just think: we'll get us a house, get rid of this damn Nash Ambassador -- no money worries...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby is instantly awake, excited. Caroline points to a small highway sign and both she and Toby yell out.</context>
      <utterance>Ask me how far we are from Salt Lake City.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE/TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of them are laughing with excitement. Toby claps his hands together once, very hard, and Caroline yells --</context>
      <utterance>Forty-seven miles to go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could have one wish right now -- only one wish -- you know what I'd like? I'd like to burn this damn Nash Ambassador to a crisp.  I'm serious. I hate it. I hate the factory that produced it, and I hate the man who invented it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the mention of Roy's name, Caroline lightly touches the bruise on her right cheekbone. Not enjoying the talk about Roy, she pours the water into the radiator, and speaks directly to the car.</context>
      <utterance>It almost makes me want to see Roy -- he was the only one could make the thing stop overheating.  My God, he was boring. Boring and mean: you sure got crappy taste in boyfriends.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to burn you to the ground.  Let's go get rich in Salt Lake City!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pulling my leg, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I came here to look for uranium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, lady. If you're looking for uranium, why didn't you go to Moab?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We went there, but everybody'd beaten us there. We were too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you came here just on the chance you'd find uranium? Listen, you mind me saying something to you might sound rude? Lady, you got more courage than you got common sense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That mechanic in Colorado said it needed points.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a WOMAN in pedal-pushers and a thin, inexpensive sweater stops. She's vaguely low-class, but friendly and sympathetic.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Don't tell me what I already know. This thing's a bottomless pit. I don't know what to do. No matter how much money I pour into it...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline smiles, then her face changes.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather be whipped with a belt than have car trouble. 'Course these days I don't have to worry about that. My husband got laid off at the mill, and they repossessed the car, so wherever I wanna go, I just have to hoof it, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked, the Woman says --</context>
      <utterance>You don't have a car?  You want this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... uh... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna give our car away?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously. It needs points, and it overheats constantly, but you can have it if you want it, because my hand to God, I can't look at it one more minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the bags out. Get the owner's slip out of the glove compartment. We're rid of this son-of-a-bitch pink and white albatross. You don't mind taking a car with a big dent in the passenger door?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline draws back her leg and delivers a terrific, flat-footed kick to the door, leaving a dent the size of a dish-pan.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, no.  There's no dent there...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby hands the Woman the owner's slip, Caroline gives her the keys.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes there is!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... you really just giving me this car?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of them pick up two bags apiece -- all they have in the world -- and off they go, feeling good.</context>
      <utterance>It's done. It's yours. You got yourself a Nash Ambassador!  Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VICE PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... like to give new boys the benefit of the doubt, but this is the second time in two weeks that you've been in front of me, and I don't like that.  Now I think you better just call your mother and tell her to come down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent, the man continues to hold out the telephone to Toby. Finally he takes it and dials.</context>
      <utterance>She works. She's working.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't me broke their stupid windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, thanks a lot, Mom -- believe them instead of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you care anything about me at all, you'll shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well if you'd stayed married to Dad none of this would've ever happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, don't you put that on my back: I can't make your father call you. I can't make your brother write you. They dumped you. Yes. But it's not my fault.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven. Almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you wake me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline sees that he's trying to make it up to her, and pats the bed for him to sit down next to her. He moves to sit beside her.</context>
      <utterance>I started dinner. The potatoes are frying, and I'm heating up the hot dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold your mother's hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TELEPHONE RINGS and she answers it. When she hears the VOICE on the other end she once again touches her right cheekbone with a finger -- the spot where the bruise had been. She sags back against a wall.</context>
      <utterance>I know you are, honey. Ah, well -- it wasn't fire, and nobody bled, so I guess we're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...  Yes...  Yes, I know...  You're right...  All right, yes... in an hour, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline laughs aloud, then slides down the wall until she's on the floor still laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby groans and falls full-length onto the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>We've got a guest for dinner: it's Roy. He tracked us down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I found me a room, but it's clear the hell and gone 'cross town. And I think I got a job lined up doin' tune-ups in a Texaco station. How you like it at Winstead's?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know where I work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been here almost a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roy doesn't answer. He just wiggles his eyebrows like Groucho Marx.</context>
      <utterance>You followed me around? For a week? Watching?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, Roy does the Groucho Marx. He turns to Toby.</context>
      <utterance>And how did you ever find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like the rifle, Toby? 'Jack,' I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the best present I ever got. I just love it.  I'm going to pretend I'm shooting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't point that thing at anybody or I won't teach you to shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not loaded!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me: anybody or any thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got no bullets, for God's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me speak to you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roy leans back, smiling, and eyes Caroline.</context>
      <utterance>Don't. Toby's still up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her to him, starting to kiss her. She fends him off, looking worriedly toward the room where Toby's light burns.</context>
      <utterance>You are one sweet thing, baby: just the sight of you makes my dick hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again he pulls her toward him; again she turns her head from the kiss. Then it happens. A spasm of anger passes across his face and he shoves Caroline away from him. It's a hard shove, but nothing that could really hurt her. Violence has happened before between these two, and they recognize it. Caroline is immediately on guard, and Roy is apologetic.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, he won't hear anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides toward Caroline, kisses her. This time she accepts the kiss -- feels she has no choice.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, baby, I'm sorry. I didn't mean that. I'm just so glad to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman stops to take a breather, lights a cigarette, pokes her companion.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord, look at the eyes on him -- won't he be a heartbreaker in three, four years?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Bedroom eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You live in the neighborhood, sweetie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over there.  I won't be here long, though, 'cause my dad's coming to get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm gonna live on his ranch in Phoenix. The "Lazy B," it's called.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds like fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two Women exchange a glance. It's obvious the boy is lying.</context>
      <utterance>It is. I've got a palomino horse and a collie, and Dad lets us go on hunts all by ourselves. He gave me this Winchester .22, and last year I shot a mountain lion with it. And Lad -- that's my dog -- found a nest of rattlesnakes one time, and killed all twelve of them...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing home so --  We going someplace?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sure are.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Got any suggestions?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phoenix.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I was thinking of Phoenix or Seattle -- lots of opportunities in both those places.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about your fabulous boyfriends? What about the fabulous, boring Roy? Is he coming, too?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if I can help it. I looked out the window at work today, and he was parked across the street, watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy's so uncool. So boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You liked him well enough last night.  'Oh, Roy, I just love my rifle so much! It's the bestest present ever!'</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's smiling, completely unbothered. Suddenly Caroline laughs, stands up, and begins to close the suitcases. Toby laughs, too.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now? We're going now? What about all the food?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even the canned stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grab the four heavy suitcases and head out the door. Both of them are laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Leave it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, ask him when the next one to Phoenix is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TICKET SELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow morning, eleven forty-five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Seattle?</utterance>
   <speaker>TICKET SELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Leaves in nine minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I've always had a good head for figures, and if I could get my C.P.A. license, I believe we could make a real go of it in Seattle. I'll advertise for roommates, and I bet we find us a real cute house to rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's a big yard, can I get a collie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Oh, honey, I feel a wind at my back: I think this is going to work out good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and if you cut school again I'll just wear you out -- do you hear me? I'm tired of it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>But, Jesus, what a new Toby: he's turned cool. A few months have passed. He now wears T-shirts and jeans which ride way low on his hips. As he walks along, he combs his hair into a duck's ass in back, and forward into a curl at the center of his forehead. He's 1957 hip -- or thinks he is. He strolls on, feeling cool.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah... Toby exits the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Terry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jack. What'd your mom say about skipping school today?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who listens?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go over to Wanda's house last night?  You make out good?  How good?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fucked her 'til her nose bled.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you did! Oh, Wolff, you're rich.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SISTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh look -- it's Elvis, Elvis, and Elvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that piece of high wit, they're out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but does your face hurt? 'Cause it's killing me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lois. Oh, baby, come here -- I got six hot inches just waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, look at her! Look at that body-y-y-y.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um-m-m-m. M-M-M. Oh, Annette, I want you. I want you so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three carry on for a few more seconds.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, babybabybabybabybaby... You make my dick hard!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE OF THEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yum, yum, yum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That belt just makes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does pick up the green, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you say he's getting serious already?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think. He keeps talking about marriage, keeps saying he wants to meet Toby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's it -- three dates and you got 'im good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I want him -- She stops as Toby enters the kitchen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't want who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little pitchers...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's the tough guy who can't be bothered to go to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's nothing -- we were talking about Dwight. I told you about Dwight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a KNOCK on the front door. Toby sticks his head around the door, looking into the living room. A man is outlined against the sunset, only his black silhouette is visible. It is our first glimpse of DWIGHT. Has the man heard him? Toby doesn't know for sure. Caroline brings Dwight into the kitchen. He is older than her, an attractive-enough man. He is well-built, has a full head of brown hair, and very white teeth. Those are his good points. On the minus side: his over- eagerness to please, his nervous smiles and his clothes. He wears two-tone shoes, a hand-painted tie, and a monogrammed handkerchief, folded beyond perfection, in the pocket. Caroline introduces him to Marian and Kathy. Then she introduces Dwight to Toby. Dwight is all smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He the one drives down from the boondocks? The mechanic? Dwight. What a stupid name.  Dwiiiight. Duhhhhwight. Dwight-tah-h-h-h. Dwighttahhhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like coffee before we go? Or a Coke?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I believe I could stand a cup of java.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're Toby.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not Toby?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he wants to be called 'Jack.' It's so silly... ever since he read Jack London.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kathy and Marian think it's pretty funny. They laugh. Caroline smiles. Toby just stares.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll call him anything he wants.  I always say people can call me anything they want, long as they don't call me late for supper!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Jack, you like school?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He might like it if he ever went there and tried it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, have another cookie, Marian -- keep your strength up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to just yank that nasty tongue of yours out by the roots.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son's decided to try to drive me into an early grave. Truly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dwight takes a swallow of the coffee. His eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>You straighten up and be polite, you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who made this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did...</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marian puts a cigarette into her mouth. Dwight jumps up, pulls a velvet case from his pocket and extracts a mono- grammed Zippo. He snaps open the top of the lighter against his leg, and holds the flame in front of Marian's face. She lights her cigarette. Then Dwight perform the Zippo drama in reverse. What a conversation stopper. Finally, Kathy speaks to Toby.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, well, all I can say is that you people are pretty lucky to live in a house where -- oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you're invited up to Dwight's next week for Thanksgiving.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby sits up, eager.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, you'll love it. Great air, great water. For scenery, all you have to do is step outside your front door and open your eyes. And there's a turkey shoot Thanksgiving Day. Your mom said you might like it, so I signed you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I can shoot my Winchester? Great! I bet I could be the one to get the turkey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to be polite to Dwight this weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said 'Okay,' didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, c'mon, maybe the weekend'll be fun... maybe Concrete will be pretty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Welcome to beautiful Concrete!</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Concrete, my favorite town.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And stop that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I could kill you as free as I could eat a bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A car stops and through a window, we see Dwight. Caroline turns to Toby.</context>
      <utterance>Ditto.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby stops the buck-toothed thing and speaks normally.</context>
      <utterance>Please be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her face strained, Caroline leans over for a closer look. The salmon swim in slow, stunned circles, some with an eye missing or hanging by a membrane, a hideous sight.</context>
      <utterance>They always show you salmon fighting to get upstream, but they never show you what they look like when they get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pitiful. Awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Toby and Caroline move to the passenger side of the car, Toby speaks so Dwight can't hear:</context>
      <utterance>They'll spawn, and then they'll die. They're dying now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline has to fight back a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I hope to hell it's not an omen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three children exit the house. SKIPPER, a pleasant boy who is average in every way, is 17. NORMA is 18, slow- spoken and sensual, Toby cannot take his eyes off her. The third is PEARL, two years younger than Toby. Pearl has a bald spot the size of a dollar, high on the side of her head.</context>
      <utterance>All the houses are converted Army barracks, made into duplexes --</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Let's see here. Kids, this is my pretty friend, Caroline Wolff, and her boy To...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops at an extra, no-particular-purpose, nondescript room furnished only by two easy chairs and a card table.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, so that was the living room; over here is the kitchen -- I plan on getting all new fixtures in here -- and down that hall are the three bedrooms and the bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He searches, can't think of how to finish the sentence in any impressive way. He gives up, finishes weakly:</context>
      <utterance>This is sort of a lounging area.  You know, just in case you want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skipper snorts with laughter, but cuts it off when Dwight gives him a look. Toby, trying to be good, bites his lip to keep from laughing.</context>
      <utterance>... lounge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And over there's where I work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They glance at each other.</context>
      <utterance>How about you guys? You like it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little isolated, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that isolated.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pretty isolated, though.</context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe not that isolated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, there's plenty to do in Concrete if you kids would take a little initiative. When I was growing up we didn't have T.V. -- we used our imaginations. We read the classics. We played musical instruments. You show me a bored kid, I'll show you a lazy kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you played an instrument, Dwight. What do you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skipper and Norma glance at each other, then look away. Caroline takes a cigarette from her purse. Again Dwight jumps to her service: we are once more treated to the mini-drama of Dwight unsheathing the Zippo from its velvet case, opening the top on his pants leg, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Sax. Tenor sax.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the school here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't one. We go to Chinook.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chinook High.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a few miles downriver.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come off it -- it's not that far.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In spite of the fact that he's eager for this day to go well, Dwight's bottom teeth begin to show.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I clocked it: thirty-nine miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all shut their pie-holes. The six walk in a tense, uncomfortable silence for five full beats. Then Pearl tries to help out:</context>
      <utterance>Ah, you'd bellyache if the goddam school was in your fugging back yard. Just shut your god- damn pie-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody seems to care.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in fifth grade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Turkey shoot' is just a figure of speech.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no real turkey?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's just regulation paper targets. It's a test of skill.  And, Jack, I just found out yesterday that they won't let kids shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you said I could!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby starts to argue, but Caroline touches his arm.</context>
      <utterance>I know, but they got it all screwed up somehow and told me wrong at first.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dwight, you did tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't make the rules, Caroline. If I made the rules, I might make different ones, but I don't make the rules.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolff. Caroline Wolff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you want to enter? I think it's against the rules.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that sign says this is an N.R.A. club, and I'm a dues-paying N.R.A. member. That gives me the right to participate in the activities of other chapters.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline just smiles. The Man shrugs, takes her money and writes down her name.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be the only woman shooting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That second-place trophy ain't bad, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was for you, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you were a member of the N.R.A.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little behind in my dues -- Thirty-six years behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What gives?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom won the turkey shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, boy. Now we're in for it -- he thinks he's some kind of big hunter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he killed a deer once.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>That was with the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're okay. What's that bald spot on Pearl's head? Ugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some sort of infection.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all nice, but Dwight keeps rushing me, keeps talking about marriage. And I don't really want to get married -- not now anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine with me.  I wish you would've stayed married to Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>God.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't wish Duke back on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That woman he married? Is she really rich?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like King Midas. Okay, look, we'll go back to Seattle and see how things go. I've been thinking about taking a course in stenotyping. A court reporter's pay is real high. Kathy got engaged, so either I find us another roommate or I've got to make some more money. And this stenotyping thing sounds just right. This could turn out good, honey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terry Silver takes a long slow drag on his cigarette. The other boys glance at each other: they don't buy it.</context>
      <utterance>I mean I blew it off, man -- I blew his fuckin' turkey's head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a .22.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' A. Winchester .22. Pump.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wolff, you are so full of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't believe me -- see if I care.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby takes a drag on his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>All a .22 bullet would do is make a hole in his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One bullet, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby nods. Silver and Taylor howl with laughter. Furious, Toby says "Fuck you" over and over. He pulls out a rat-tail and scratches the words "FUCK YOU" onto the soft paint of the bathroom wall.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh, I see -- you hit the turkey more than once. While he was flying. In the head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline takes out a cigarette. Then everybody jumps as Toby yells and jumps up knocking his chair over backwards.</context>
      <utterance>... exactly what I wanted for my dress. It's a Simplicity pattern, and I'm pretty sure I can make it myself. It's got big puff sleeves...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby grabs Caroline's lighter, and begins to imitate Dwight: saying, "Oh!" and "Oh, yes!" and Oh, my!" and "Here, let me!" and "I'll do that!" It's a mean, accurate imitation of Dwight. All three women laugh in spite of themselves. Caroline keeps saying "Jack, that's enough," and Marian says, "Dwight's not that bad." But they can't help laughing. Toby offers the other two women a light, then offers a broom, the back door, and the refrigerator a light.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He violated the school property and flouted the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you say that in English?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wrote obscene words on the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you do it?  He didn't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wrote obscene words on the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What obscene words?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fuck you.'</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Shippy looks stymied. There is a pause.</context>
      <utterance>That's one obscene word.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mrs. Wolff, Jack's teachers, like him but they think he's fallen in with the wrong kind of friends.  Is that nicotine stain on your fingers?  I hope not. Let me tell you a story: I started smoking in college. Two packs a day. I ate 'em.  One night I went to have a cigarette and lo and behold, the pack was empty. I went downstairs and started to rummage through the garbage cans. But as I reached down -- I mean, right down into a garbage can -- I suddenly thought, 'Whoa. Hold on right there, Buster.' I went back to my room and to this day I haven't smoked another cigarette.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shippy looks puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>After that, every day I saved the exact amount of money I would've spent on cigarettes. In three years, I put it all together, and you know what I bought? I bought myself...  ... a Nash Ambassador. Caroline gives a bark of laughter. She brings out a handkerchief and coughs, as if she has a cold. Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SHIPPY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, back to the point: I think two weeks' suspension.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what shall we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since Duke and I got divorced, you're a different boy. I know he never calls you and I could kill him for it -- but that's how Duke is. And Gregory's in Princeton now, so I guess...  So what shall we do? Because this isn't working.  We barely have enough money, Kathy's moving out, and on top of it all, you've gone wild. You lie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don'...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So, you tell me what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you do. You steal from Marian's purse -- I just can't handle you anymore, and it scares me. I don't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With peculiar intensity, Caroline speaks in a soft, odd voice:</context>
      <utterance>I can be better. I will be.  And I hate the way I am anymore! I don't know why I do it!  What about that stenotyping thing you were gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands for a few moments as if listening for a far-off sound.</context>
      <utterance>It won't happen. It won't happen. It won't happen. Things aren't going to turn out well, things aren't going to start looking up, and it's never going to be like heaven on a June day. There is no uranium. There is no stenotyping. There is no C.P.A. license. There isn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I talked to Dwight: after Christmas, he wants you to come up to Concrete and live with him for a few months -- go to school there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, just give me away to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you two can get along, if it works out, then I guess he and I might get married.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the two stare at each other.</context>
      <utterance>I can't think of anything else to do. But first I want your approval.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline nods, turns away.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I put in both your sweaters. You wear them now, the nights are so chilly up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to go if you don't want to, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.S. we hear a KNOCKING and Dwight's cheery voice.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay. I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I am, you lucky people!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight swerves deliberately to hit the animal. There is a sickening THUMP, and Dwight stops. As he backs up:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look: is that a raccoon or a beaver.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go get it -- the pelt's worth fifty bucks, minimum.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing's probably got rabies...</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little sick to my stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sick to your stomach? A hotshot like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a hotshot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That right, Jack? You a performer?</context>
      <utterance>That's what I hear. I hear you're a real hotshot. Come and go where you please, do what you please. Isn't that right? Yeah, regular man about town. Performer, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight keeps glancing from the road to Toby, and back again.</context>
      <utterance>That's a goddamned lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's one thing I can't stomach, it's a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you are. You or Marian. Is Marian a liar? She says you're quite the little performer. Is that a lie? You tell me that's a lie and we'll drive back to Seattle so you can call her a liar to her face. You want me to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you must be the one's a liar, right?  And you're a performer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guess? You guess? Let's see your act. Go on. Do your act.  I'm waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Toby shakes his head, and then gasps as the CAR SKIDS hideously close to the cliff's edge. Dwight is oblivious to the danger.</context>
      <utterance>Do me. I hear you do me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight holds out the velvet-covered Zippo, driving with one hand, and the car is all over the road. Dwight puts the lighter back into his pocket. The car slows a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I hear you're good at doing me. Here. Do me with the lighter. Go on. Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hotshot. You pull that hotshot stuff around me and I'll break every bone in your body. You understand me?  You're in for a change, mister. You got that? Huh? You got that good?  You're in for a whole 'nother ballgame.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be in Miss Graham's class?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, is she nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's okay. She's pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate changing schools.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of changing, I had a talk with Jack on the way up here, and he says he wants to be a better boy. And that's good, 'cause things weren't going well for him in Seattle: the police actually came to his house to talk to Caroline about him. Uh-huh, the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Criminal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So here's what I think: I think idle hands are the devil's workshop, and so I found our Jack a little something to do.  I picked up two barrels of horse- chestnuts in the park. You can spend your evenings hulling 'em. And I enrolled you in the Boy Scouts, and you've got a paper route, starting Monday, every afternoon from three to six-thirty -- pays fifty-five bucks a month. What d'you say? Toby glances around the table, he is subdued.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.  I want to be... better.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I like to hear. Okay, you guys get these dishes cleaned up. Let's show Jack how we do it in Concrete.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MISS GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Of course I prayed -- and did God care? He cared as much as on the air a bird had stamped her foot and cried, "Give me".' Now. What is the tone of this short poem?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it religious?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- even though it talks about God, I wouldn't say it was religious.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MISS GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause. Finally, Toby raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well, closer, maybe. But no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's angry, sort of bitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the front of the room, a tall, thin, effeminate boy, ARTHUR GAYLE, turns to look at Toby and holds the gaze for three full beats, then turns around and faces the front. What the hell does it mean?</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Jack. Bull's-eye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>55 E) (NIGHT) Dwight introduces Toby at a Scout 55 meeting. All the other boys have on Scout uniforms. 55 F) (DAY) Toby is on the utility porch husking the 55 horse chestnuts. His hands are now orange. Pearl stands in the doorway watching him work. Norma appears beside Pearl. Norma's face turns sympathetic.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Mom, Thanks for the birthday present. It fit fine. You don't have to worry so much. I'm okay here. The weather is nice, and I like Scouts a lot. Dwight took us all to see Bridge on the River Kwai. I liked it. So things are all right with me, except for stupid Pearl, who I hate. Don't worry all the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby doesn't answer. The two girls move away. Toby sighs, and picks up another chestnut. 55 G) (DAY) Toby, keeping an eye on the door to make 55 sure he's unobserved, reaches under the mattress of Skipper's bed and pulls out several billfold-sized black and white pornographic photographs. The hair styles of the women in them are decades old. Toby takes the photographs into the bathroom, shutting the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>You remind me of that boy in the fairy tale who had to spend twenty years sifting sand to find a golden needle. Remember that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Toby, Just a note before going to bed. Dwight tells me that the two of you are getting along like a house afire. I'm so glad. I wanted this to work out for you. You left your sock cap here. Do you need it...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby takes out his comb, combs his hair a bit, then holds it out to Pearl, an exaggerated look of innocence on his face.</context>
      <utterance>That's no fair. You make me sick. I don't know why you have to live here, anyway. Daddy says we should think of it like you were a charity kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl covers her bald spot with one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna comb your hair, Pearl?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl is on the verge of tears. There are THREE TREMEN- DOUSLY LOUD FLAT-FOOTED KICKS against the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Probably you do, since you've got such pretty hair. I know if I had hair as pretty as yours, Pearl, I'd comb it all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Pearl opens the door revealing a beaming Dwight holding two dishpans piled high with snow. We see through the doorway that the sun is shining and there isn't snow anywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Open the hell up! I got us a treat!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna have snowcream!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody laughs.</context>
      <utterance>... heard there was a fresh snow this morning, so I drove up to the mountains. I stopped in a field where it was all clean. I was finished packing it up high when somebody said...  This's private property, in case you're interested.  I turned around and there was this woman...  Yechh! Ugliest woman I ever saw -- ugly as a madman's ass she was. And frowning on top of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ugly as a madman's ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say to the ugly woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody laughs again. They eat in silence for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't say nothin' -- I ran.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get you a Scout uniform, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I join the Girl Scouts?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight takes out a magazine entitled Boy's Life. He hands it to Toby.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting one for me, too. Don't believe in doing anything halfway. If you're serious about the Scouts...  ... then I want you to do it right. We'll do it right together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got you a subscription to this. I'll take the price out of your paper route money.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy's Life?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby opens the book at random, reads from it.</context>
      <utterance>It's the official Scout magazine. Tells about what it means to be a Scout, what kind of boy you need to be, and, oh, about merit badges and stuff like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Suggested good turns a Scout can do: assist a foreign boy with some English grammar. Help put out a burning field. Give water to a crippled dog.' I could do those.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby nods, enthusiastic, happy.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, yes, you could. You're a bright kid. I want this Scout thing done right, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not. Cut down Skipper's old stuff, and he's twice as big as me -- I'm gonna stay home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Now get out here.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna shit and fall back in it -- that's all you're gonna do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut your pie-hole.  You look fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look like an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You act like an idiot, you look fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you'd get me a new uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I'd try to get you a new uniform. Beside, this one is new -- new to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look at the sleeves and how it hangs down between my legs!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh piss and moan -- all you can do is piss and moan.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, piss and moan -- I notice you're all jazzed up in new stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't have second-hand uniforms in my size.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby throws himself down on the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, pull the other leg, it's got bells on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight picks up the copy of Boy's Life and thumbs through it, He reads:</context>
      <utterance>And what're you gonna tell Caroline this weekend? You gonna say you wouldn't join the Scouts because... him didn't wike his widdle uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight looks at Toby expectantly. Toby hesitates, then gives up.</context>
      <utterance>'No boy given over to dissipation or negativity can stand the gaff. He quickly tires and gives up. He is the type who usually lacks courage at the crucial moment. He cannot take punishment and come back smiling.'</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby walks outside. Dwight follows.</context>
      <utterance>All right, but this stinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hotshot, you don't know it yet, but me and Concrete are in your blood. We're going to make a man of you yet -- and in years to come you'll thank me. You'll remember me. Me and Concrete.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I missed you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look good. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight comes around the car, kisses Caroline, and the three head into the house.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said to hell with the budget and bought a roast. I made dumplings -- God, what's wrong with your hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just juice from some chestnuts -- it'll wear off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so. My, your hair's short.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's done him a world of good to be up there with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we have us some pretty good times. Don't we, Jack? Have us some good times? Toby, not looking away from the radio, nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go to the Scouts together every week. He's got a good start already on merit badges...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is it in Concrete?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>School?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>School's school. My grades are okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't been in any trouble?  Good. How're you and Dwight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He made us all snowcream, like he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you've got your eyes out of focus. Look at me. Now, are things all right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You swear? You act odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, good. I'd feel awful if it hadn't worked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told Dwight I'd marry him. In two weeks. I don't know what else to do. I mean, he's been helping me with the rent since Kathy left. And you need a father. I think it's the best thing all the way around -- what d'you think? There is a pause as they look at each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's the best thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline smiles, smooths his hair, then goes into the house. Toby continues to walk. Suddenly, he spins around and tears out toward the house. By God, he'll tell her just what's been going on. He bangs through the front door and up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's the best thing, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes another sign.</context>
      <utterance>Hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes another sign.</context>
      <utterance>Food.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes another sign.</context>
      <utterance>Want.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes another sign.</context>
      <utterance>Great mystery.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father. He stares silently at himself in the mirror.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He imitates Elvis -- moves his hips slightly and sings a few notes:</context>
      <utterance>Now that's a song. Not all this Elvis Presley shit. Elvis sings about like I do brain surgery.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight gives Toby a flash of his teeth and Toby smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>'... uh-huh-huh, my blue suede shoes.'</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin painting. After only a few strokes, though, Toby looks doubtful.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get this place ready for Caroline.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so white.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a good deal on this paint.  It'll darken up when it dries.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I like it. It looks clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight's face changes. He has an idea.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it makes everything else look so dark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of stands out, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you could say that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline draws him up to her, and they kiss. Then Dwight turns Caroline on her side, away from him, pre- paring to enter her. Caroline makes a small sound of protest, turning back toward him.</context>
      <utterance>M-m-m. There's not a straight line on you -- everything's curved.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dwight, not like that. Not this time -- not tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I want to see your face while we make love.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>like that way.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no -- I just don't... uh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you don't like to make love face to face?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't like it. I can't handle it -- I don't like to see the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight murmurs an assent. Caroline is appalled.</context>
      <utterance>You mean ever?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's grotesque...</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Caroline turns back away from Dwight. He shifts down on the bed a few inches, again preparing to enter her.</context>
      <utterance>Look, you can get it doggie-style or you can get it laying on your side -- those are your only choices. This is my house, and I get to say. Wherever McGinty sits is the head of the table, you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline's eyes are red and swollen. Dwight turns ON a RADIO, sips his coffee, and chats with Norma. Toby gives Norma's rear-end an appreciative glance, then comes up behind Caroline, speaking sotto voce:</context>
      <utterance>Happy Wedding Breakfast!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's the bride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bride doesn't want to chat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, Toby waits for some response to his teasing, but there is none. She turns away and sits at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the bride is sure snotty this morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>OSCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur Gayle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a homo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sure walks like a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And runs like one and talks like one and throws like one. Probably takes a pee like one too -- just squats right down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He smarted off to me the other day -- told me I was a bourgeois.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the frig's a bourgeois?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OSCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call him a sissy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>OSCAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just see what he says.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time Arthur is next to them. Smiling a superior smile, he stops and glances at all three of them as if they were just the oddest things he's ever seen. Then his eye falls on Toby's yellow hands.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my, my -- look at all that yellow: Didn't your mama teach you to wash your hands after you pee?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's what I like -- an insult with some originality. Did you just make that up? Just now? So clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take a long walk off a short pier?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of Toby's friends laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but has anyone ever told you your breath would gag a maggot?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two things happen instantly: the superior smile vanishes from Arthur's face, and Toby's friends exchange a single expectant look: "Here it comes."</context>
      <utterance>Well, at least I'm not a great big sissy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur's words are not angry anymore. Toby's worn out too...</context>
      <utterance>Take it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I take it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby glances at Oscar and Jimmy. Their faces are gleeful but he doesn't care what the hell they think.</context>
      <utterance>No, say 'You're not a sissy.'</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur immediately turns and walks away, but Toby ignores them and walks away in the opposite direction, delivering his hated newspapers.</context>
      <utterance>You're not a sissy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't do it, you know. I won't be a referee between the two of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who asked you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You both do. You do. Just by coming home like this you ask me to take your side when he raises hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the answer's 'No.' I'm going to make this marriage work. No fights.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline refuses to argue. She picks up a piece of material and holds it up to the window to see if her choice of color was a good one.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, the bride is calm. Who the hell cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... seems like this place is so ugly. Seems like everywhere I look there's something... ugly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who won?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, well, uh... he's the one can't see out of one eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot damn! You actually gave little Lord Gayle a black eye?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't black yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it was all puffed up?  Then it was a shiner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd it start?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight hoots with laughter and slaps his leg.</context>
      <utterance>I called him a sissy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he sure's hell can't sue you for slander. That boy fights for the pink team. Did you make him cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... he was just ready to. I called him a big-assed, squat- to-pee sissy.  I'd have won bigger except he hit me when I wasn't looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He dry-gulched you. Now that's your fault. You gotta keep your guard up. There's no excuse for getting dry-gulched. I'll show you a couple moves after supper that'll leave Miss Arthur Gayle wondering what month it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it was real hot out, okay? And there were these horse turds laying all over the place. I picked one up and went up to him, but not acting tough, okay? Acting more like, 'Oh gee, I'm so scared, please don't hurt me.' Sort of like this: Dwight slumps his shoulders, drops his chin, and looks up through his eyebrows, a simpering expression on his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight goes on, relishing the story.</context>
      <utterance>So I say, 'Excuse me, but what's the problem?' And he starts in on me again, blah, blah, blah, and I jam a horse turd right into that big mouth. Then I give him a sucker punch in the breadbasket, and he goes down like a...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you'd show me how to dry-gulch somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning, Dwight lunges at Toby and swings the side of his arm toward Toby's throat. Toby dodges wildly, falling backward over a box of sports equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Now you can always kick somebody in the balls, but I like this one better: What you do is hit 'em in the throat with the side of your forearm. You wait 'til -- hah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's dry-gulching. Hit 'em in the throat, but do it before they're expecting it. Now you try.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I'll hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally Toby gives a half-hearted "Hah!" and swings the side of his forearm toward Dwight's throat. Dwight catches the arm easily.</context>
      <utterance>But I might.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Toby hesitates, again he says "Hah!" and gives a lukewarm swing at Dwight's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Come onnn. You're not trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby's eyes flare up, then he lowers his head, biting his lip, sniffling a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Well, don't go all shy and delicate on me -- you're as sissy as little Miss Arthur Gayle. Yeah -- I'll just call you 'Little Miss Jackie Wolff.' Ooh, my, yes -- Hello, Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning, Toby lunges at Dwight, screaming "HAH!" trying for the man's throat. Caught off guard, Dwight stops the main force of Toby's arm, but is slammed onto the ground stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, Jesus Christ, if you're gonna --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight manages a grin, but he is not happy to have been bested.</context>
      <utterance>You just about got dry-gulched, my man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest of the word is jerked out of her as Dwight turns her onto her side, away from him, and proceeds to make love again in his favorite manner.</context>
      <utterance>I know you may think this is silly, Dwight, but it seems like... I don't know, like an emblem or something. I want to be able to see your face when we make love. How else can we be cl --</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You just don't know what's good, Sugar. You're too tense. You just relax and Dwight'll take you on a little trip. Okay? You'll have a good time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but ask him again, why don't you? I hate it so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked him a week ago, I asked him this morning -- he wants you to keep the paper route.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then make him give me the money. It's mine, I earned it. It's $220.00 already.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't. He says he'll keep it for when you really need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair. I ought to be able to have my own money.  But it's mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remind me of a baby bird -- you know those frantic little things with their mouths wide open, wanting, wanting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least ask him about my gym shoes again. I can practice barefoot but for games I gotta have shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a referee. I won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we know, we know: the bride won't argue. The bride won't raise her voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you what the bride will do: the bride will get up and walk over there and slap hell out of the bride's son. Now does the bride's son want his face slapped?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I hate it here! I wish we could just get up and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline points to the sink.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have another 'get up and go' left in me! You understand? I'm telling you I've hit a god- damn wall. I can't run anymore. Now this whole thing isn't perfect for me, either... let me impress that on you real strong, okay? I don't wake up singing every morning. But I'm going to make this marriage work -- I won't join in any fights, you got that? I won't even raise my voice!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See those two roses? He picked them for me on his way home last night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma appears in the kitchen door, wearing her cap and gown. She strikes a pose.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to concentrate on the good stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma snaps her fingers and goes back to her bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>What d'ya think? I think I look like a fool.  Who cares? Six weeks to graduation, and California, here I come!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline turns her attention back to the curtains.</context>
      <utterance>Seriously: you have to concentrate on the good stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I know damn well you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About some things, yeah. Not about this. You're a goddam hog, and I proved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know Skipper didn't eat it? Or Norma? Or Pearl?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told all three of them to stay away from this candy for twenty- four hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how do you know I even ate any?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I counted them. You hogged down eleven chocolate covered cherries since yesterday afternoon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline and Skipper enter, carrying throw pillows and materials.</context>
      <utterance>So that makes you a hog. I just wanted to establish that fact, and now I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Mr. Hotshot Hog and I've just been establishing some facts, and what we come up with is this: One, he's a pig who gobbles down everybody's candy; two, he lies about it; three, he lays around on his lazy ass day and night reading, reading; and four, he's not getting any ten-dollar gym shoes. That's about what we've come up with so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skipper leaves the room. Caroline sits down, begins to try various materials as coverings for the pillows.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you ever take up for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline doesn't even look up. She threads a needle and begins to sew. Whilst Dwight paces around the room.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you ever help me straighten that boy out?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All he does is read or listen to records or sing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sick of that shit! And when he isn't singing, he's watching T.V.  And don't say you don't 'cause when I come home I always put my hand on top of it to see if it's warm, and it always is. This is the news, kid -- I'm wise to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, big, big deal, who cares, and as long as we're passing out news here, I don't want to do my paper route anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you don't -- big lazy candy hog like you'd rather lay on his ass and read, wouldn't you? Let me tell you something: you're gonna deliver those papers if I have to walk behind you with a horsewhip ever' step of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then give me the money I earn!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, no. I'm putting that in the bank for you for when you really need it -- cuss me now, thank me later.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby stops suddenly. He looks at Dwight for a beat or two, and then speaks in a different tone:</context>
      <utterance>Mom, won't you at least make him let me have the shoes for gym? How can I play basketball without gym shoes? I'm the only one who --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight glances at Caroline, who still looks at her sewing.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the shoes, is it? Or the candy. It's me, isn't it? You just can't stand the fact of me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight stops short as Caroline says one word.</context>
      <utterance>I, well, no, it's not that -- I just want you to be well-behaved. Your rich daddy 'Duke' doesn't care anything about you, and so somebody's got to train you, and one of the things you've gotta be trained about is not to be a hog and eat everybody's candy like a --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight and Toby glance at each other nervously. What is this?</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I. Will. Not. Referee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight and Toby grab their caps and hotfoot it out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Jack, I think you've made your mother nervous, so why don't we just go on to Scouts and let her rest?  You lay down and rest awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastard. Swallow that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give my pud a big squeeze while you're at it, why don't you? Toby and the life-savers on either side of him laugh a bit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like my dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smart, too -- he can talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure -- I just about believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As PEPPER BARKS TWICE:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pepper -- what's on a tree?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As PEPPER BARKS ONCE:</context>
      <utterance>Bark! Way to go, Pepper -- pretty smart. Oh, I was wondering, Pepper -- I wanted to ask you something: how's the world treating you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rough! Yeah, I know what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's dumb. A little funny, though. How come your dad never comes to meetings with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a dad. Never did. I sprang full-blown from my mother's forehead. You want to walk home with me and Pepper?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure -- compared to a ride home with Dwight, it'll be like heaven on a June day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My real parents would probably have given me an elegant name, too. I say 'real parents' because I suspect I'm a foundling. Somebody royal -- or at least very, very beautiful had me and gave me to my poor but honest mother.  Tell me more about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day of my life feels like a mile on the Bataan Death March.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew I'd like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you point at me that day?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're an alien. You don't belong in Concrete any more than I do. This place would like to kill us because we're different.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, Arthur. That's a little dramatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think so? You know what chickens do if one chicken's born with a little difference? With a few black feathers on its head, say? They peck at the black spot 'til the chicken's dead -- they can't stand the fact that it's different. Now we're both different. Your difference is something other than...  ... my difference...  But we're both aliens here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't exactly feel like an alien. I've got friends here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and they're fools. And you act like a fool when you're around them. A prediction: if you stay in Concrete, you'll wind up working at the A&amp;P -- either that or you'll go on a rampage with a hunting rifle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and you'll wind up a recluse that everybody says likes to dress up in his mama's old clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, maybe, but no matter how many times I have to repeat: my primary goal's to get out of Concrete.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur and Toby laugh. As they walk on, though, Toby's face is thoughtful.</context>
      <utterance>Burma-Shave!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you wanted a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A collie, though. Not this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Go get ready for Norma's play.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he's yours. You paid for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Dwight doesn't answer. Toby waits, then shrugs and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>What d'you mean I paid for him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Winchester's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A champion.</context>
      <utterance>This dog is pure-bred Weimaraner.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're purely out of luck, aren't you, 'cause that rifle's on its way to Seattle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my rifle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, want in one hand and shit in the other -- see which gets full first.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Dwight, that Winchester was mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Champ's your dog. Jesus, I trade some old piece of crap for a valuable hunting dog, and all you can do is piss and moan.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not pissing and moaning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you aren't. You can just make your own deals from now on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment Caroline doesn't respond. Then she nods her head.</context>
      <utterance>Dwight traded my rifle for a dog. He says the dog's for me, but it's some stupid dog he wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby nods. Caroline heads inside, loaded for bear.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Okay, Dwight. You stay here. Don't come inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get his rifle back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline calmly SMASHES another PLATE on the countertop.</context>
      <utterance>But that dog's a champion!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get his rifle back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he finishes the sentence, Caroline SMASHES a GLASS on the countertop.</context>
      <utterance>Am I supposed to go clear to Seattle just to get...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get his rifle back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline picks up a bowl.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, woman, I don't even know the guy's last name.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline exits leaving Dwight, Norma, and Pearl with their mouths open.</context>
      <utterance>All right, all right. The guy's supposed to send the A.K.C. papers. When he sends 'em, I'll know his name and address, and I'll go get the god-damn rifle back. Jesus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby gives her a dirty look, but Caroline's smile makes Toby grin.</context>
      <utterance>'Course, having seen that dog, I wouldn't suggest you hang by your thumbs 'til those papers come. I mean, that dog is ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice -- I haven't seen a real smile out of you in a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom, can't we leave here? I hate it so much. You don't like it either -- all you do is stick your head in a sewing machine night and day. Let's just leave and start over someplace else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Start over.' Do you know how many times I've started over, sweetheart? I don't want to do it anymore. This is as far as I want to go. This place. I have to make this work somehow. We do. You're fourteen now -- you have to help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But me no buts, honey. I told you: I've hit a wall. And besides, it's not so bad here, if you just try to --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say 'look for the good stuff,' I'm gonna get Dwight's 30/30 and shoot myself!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously, though: give the place a chance. Give him a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Just great. What a life: I gotta live with Dwight... I got a sissy for a new best friend...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got no rifle... I got no gym shoes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In spite of his disappointment over the rifle, in spite of all that Caroline had said about staying with Dwight, Toby is happy to see Caroline completely back to her old self again, joking with him. He grins and, with the palm of his hand, he gives her shoulder a gentle shove. She returns the gesture. And the two of them sit on the steps, staring into the twilight.</context>
      <utterance>Well, look on the bright side... You got a dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He looks up just in time to see a flashlight fly through the air toward him. He catches it. Dwight stands in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Heh Hotshot!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight switches the room light off.</context>
      <utterance>If you can tear yourself away from your pedicure, I want you to fetch me some of that paint from the attic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is now too soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your car in the ditch back there?  How'd you do that, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feeling better?</context>
      <utterance>Your mother said you were sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, good. Get some sleep, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I slept about four hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause:</context>
      <utterance>Must've needed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, by the way, you didn't happen to hear a funny pinging noise in the engine, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What engine?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was downtown with Champ a few minutes ago, and I met a guy who recognized him. Said he'd seen my dog this very morning. Told me an interesting story of how he and the dog happened to meet. What d'you think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Dwight is across the floor and onto the bed. He straddles Toby and slaps him across the face with the left hand then the right, again and again. Toby holds a forearm protectively across his face. Dwight holds both Toby's hands with one of his and, slaps the boy's face again and again. Finally Toby manages to get his right hand loose. He slams his forearm across Dwight's throat. Dwight rears back, choking and gagging. Toby throws off the covers and tries to run. Still choking, Dwight grabs the back of Toby's hair and forces the boy's face down against the mattress.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PSYCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ag-Hhh! Gorilla blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Psycho, shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's hot for Wolff.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, look -- there goes Carol Baumgarten. Ain't she sweet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't do her any good, though -- Jack's saving himself for Rhea Clark.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what he said about Rhea? Said even the inside of her arm turned him on. You slay me, Wolff. She is pretty though.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is general laughter, mixed with groans.</context>
      <utterance>I'd sure like to eat Rhea Clark's pussy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause. One more story. Nobody has much of a reaction.</context>
      <utterance>... So the S.O.B. had been on my back for a week at work, okay? Sayin' I stole his wrench, an' poured oil all over his tools, as if! Anyway, he went just one step too far with old Dwight, okay? Spat on the floor as I walked by. I turned around and walked back to him, acting so dainty and humble and scared, you know, all innocent -- and the minute he took his eyes off me, BLAM, I dry gulched him! I shut his water off good! Never gave me another second's grief to this very day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard Kennedy on the news again tonight -- I don't know: I hate the Democrats and the Republicans, but then once in a while somebody comes along who doesn't seem like...  ... a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kennedy -- the senator from Rome.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gives me hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what he gives you, and it sure as hell isn't hope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true he is attractive! And it may just be those white teeth that I respond to. But I don't think so.  I'm going to work for his campaign.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brief silence. Suddenly Caroline leans across the table and speaks to Dwight in a loud, exaggerated disappointed whine:</context>
      <utterance>No. Too many Republicans in this town. They hear my wife's working for the Democrats, they'll take their cars someplace else to be fixed. Bad idea. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Rickyyy!  Oh, Ricky-y-y! Please let me come down and work at the club!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you treat me like Lucy, I'll act like her. I'll be working for Kennedy's campaign.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight looks around.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be through in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left the lid off the damn toothpaste again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angered, but keeping his voice low. He pushes Toby's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dwight, is that the best you can come up with?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still Toby doesn't respond -- Dwight reaches out and pinches the skin on Toby's waist, hard. Toby still doesn't respond, when Dwight begins to twist it. Toby spins around, eyes blazing.</context>
      <utterance>This is my bathroom, and I say about the toothpaste, got it?  Huh? Have you? Huh? Now if you lived with your daddy Duke and his rich wife, maybe things'd be different, but he's not here now, is he?  Oh, Duke? Duke, are you here? Dukie? Oh, how sad -- Duke's not here. Oh, boo hoo!  My bathroom. I get to say. Got that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't pick this up yesterday -- congratulations, you got nothing higher than a C.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signs the grade card, saying, "Presto."</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm psycho! I'm retarded!</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get caught some day.  You act more like those morons you hang around with every day. Aghhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hears you do that, you're dead. Hey, lemme copy your math homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I'll show you how to work the problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you I'm thirsty, you offer me a sandwich thank you and fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jaaack!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it back you don't act like Psycho, you act like Dwight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it. He's winning. I do act like him. I feel like him sometimes. I've gotta get out of this place or I'm a dead one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but you've said that for two years.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it. I may go live with my brother Gregory in Princeton.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That brother Gregory?</context>
      <utterance>You mean the brother Gregory in Princeton who never calls you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wrote me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he asked you to live with him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But I'm going. Or maybe I could go to a prep school like Gregory did. Like my dad did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about your grades? And what would you use for money?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Dwight owes me over twelve hundred bucks! If I hadn't let him keep my paper route money, I'd be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Toby is angry. He stands up, moves to another seat.</context>
      <utterance>If the dog hadn't stopped to pee, he'd have caught the rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby falls into another seat, then, pulls his head back and bangs it against the window. Then does it again, harder.</context>
      <utterance>I think Dwight was right about you I think you fight for the pink team.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody in your family ever even been in a Corvette, let alone owned one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait and see if I don't get one. I'm gonna move down to Seattle, get a job at Bendix and drive a 'Vette to work every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My uncle can have any car he wants. He makes big bucks as an electrician.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? How big?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hundred seventy-five a week, take home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PSYCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshitter!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even the supervisors at Bendix don't make that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others all laugh at Chuck. Toby has reached the group and stands on the lip of the large wooden platform that they are on and listens while leaning on a large hook.</context>
      <utterance>So how are you ever gonna make enough to drive a 'Vette then, fuck-face?</utterance>
   <speaker>PSYCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna drive a T-bird, someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' I'm gonna own a Corvette if I have to hold up the Bendix payroll to get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others all laugh at him. Toby regards them with a sneer.</context>
      <utterance>Me. I want to eat a big red-haired pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Losers. What a bunch of losers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you calling a loser, fuck-face?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of you.  You're gonna drive a Fairlane just like your daddy does.  How you ever going to drive a Thunderbird when you're a janitor like the rest of your family?  An' you can forget being an electrician, you can't even pass tenth grade math.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well fuck you. Who died an' made you King Shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>PSYCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're no better than us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby topples over and falls down a bank of rubble. The other burst out laughing and hooting. The CAMERA MOVES off them and CRANES DOWN to a spread-eagled Toby's face. The LAUGHTER ECHOES around the building. Toby begins to laugh, but it soon turns to bitter tears.</context>
      <utterance>I know that, Psycho. That's my point: Ha, ha, ha. You guys are my buddies. You guys are my pals. And my dear old dad's called Dwight.  Welcome to Concreeee...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called Gregory at Princeton.  He's sending me applications for prep schools. I need you to take me to Seattle to take some entrance exams.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would a prep school take you with, uh, your school record?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to get out of here, Mom. I've got to. I've got to get away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are the tests?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't let you have the Buick.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard. I think I did okay. I'll know Monday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My application forms must've come today, and he threw them away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I thought I was helping him -- thought I'd save him some trouble 'cause he's got no chance of getting into some fancy prep school.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've always got your nose pressed up against the bake shop window, don't you, Dwight?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel like everybody else is inside, and you're stuck on the outside. It turns you mean. It turns you ugly. And one day do you hear me, Dwight? One day all that ugliness is going to snap back and hit you in the face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? You work right in the office -- nobody'll ever know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised you'd want help from anybody who fights for the pink team.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking you to help me, man. I got word yesterday that I did really well on those tests -- but that's not enough. I've got to cheat and lie -- but I don't care: this is my one chance to get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Why should you get to be the one? Why not me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could leave too, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur turns and swishes away. Toby pats the manilla envelope, turns back to the saw. Suddenly he jerks, looks down, and sees that the ring finger of his left hand is spurting blood. Toby says a mild, astonished "Hey," and sinks to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>No, I've grown progressively fond of Concrete. I think I'll stay here all alone and dress up in my mama's old clothes sometimes -- like you said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come help me stuff envelopes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do some this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I need to take them with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be in in a minute. Let me finish this article.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that last school will come through.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby gets up and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, or maybe he'll get a contract in the mail asking him to be a singing star on T.V.  Well, he's got about as much chance of one as of the other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We only take boys who really want to work hard. Is that you?  I'd want you to start evenings now, and I'd want you all summer -- no vacations.  Food service work isn't easy. It's not something that comes to you in a year or two. So. You think you have what it takes to be an A&amp;P management trainee?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what I've got.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight sighs with irritation at the interruption of his listening pleasure, and turns UP the VOLUME on the record.</context>
      <utterance>I can't find where this green piece goes -- it's gotta be grass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go off without eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exasperated that conversation is continuing when he's trying to listen, Dwight reaches over, presses his hand down on the arm of the record player, then SCRAPES it back and forth on the record. It's a violent action, and it makes a GROTESQUE SOUND. The NEEDLE BOUNCES around on the scarred record. As the three of them stare at him, Dwight speaks calmly:</context>
      <utterance>I'll get a sandwich after work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight rises, walks outside into the back yard. Then the TELEPHONE RINGS. Pearl answers it, listens, then says,</context>
      <utterance>I was trying to listen to a record.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the receiver out to Toby, whispering, "Are you Tobias?"</context>
      <utterance>"Yeah, he's here,"</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby hangs up, turns to Caroline, quietly:</context>
      <utterance>Hello? All right. Tomorrow, then. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline upsets the puzzle getting up to hug Toby.</context>
      <utterance>It's Hill School -- the last one I applied to. They haven't accepted me, but they're sending somebody up to interview me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Yeah, I enjoy my classes, especially the ones that are advanced, but I've been feeling a little restless lately. It's hard to explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're probably bored. Not being challenged. Your application was very good, Toby, but we have many boys who want to go to Hill. Not everybody is comfortable at a prep school.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I would be. My father and brother went to prep schools.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Howard is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Deerfield and Choate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. Well, maybe you'd like it. Hill was difficult for me, though -- classes were hard, and the boys seemed cold -- interested in money and social position.  And I hated those snowy Pennsylvania winters! But then in my last year, something changed. The guys in my class grew close, so close that I still think of them as a second family.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want that. I do, and --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch moves toward the back of the store toward the area where Toby sits. Toby inches down a bit farther into the booth. Arch stops at a sunglass rack five feet from Toby and tries on a couple of pairs.</context>
      <utterance>... so she said, 'No, I don't want you to do that,' and I said 'Oh, baby, let me get down and grovel on it.' I mean, I ate her pussy 'til my tongue was calloused, and then...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arch decides to let the sunglasses go. He and Psycho move toward the front of the store, he talks about pussy. Toby exhales.</context>
      <utterance>... so anyway, she went off like a Roman candle -- I mean that woman can scream. I said, 'You liked that, didn't you, baby?' I said, 'You liked the old Arch Cook special, didn't you?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>Toby, boys at Hill talk roughly sometimes too -- you'd have to be ready for that. I can see you've had sort of a sheltered life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From O.S., we hear Dwight's voice, and Toby goes rigid.</context>
      <utterance>You seem like a fine boy, and I'll give you a good report tomorrow. But there are lots of boys applying, and we'll just have to wait and see whether --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Both Mr. Howard and Toby turn to see Dwight, wearing his coveralls, ten feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Ohh, it's the Hotshot Boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight turns and enters the drugstore.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's the guy who thinks he knows everything. Thinks he's so smart, but fella, what you don't know would fill a book.  General Motors makes shit cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's, uh, that's this guy... he's a mechanic... did some bad work on our car... It's not much of an explanation, but Mr. Howard seems to buy it. He says goodbye to Toby, gets into his car, drives away. Toby stares after him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby gets a jar of mustard from a cupboard, but it's empty, so he tosses it on top of the trash can, gets a new jar and starts to open it. Dwight enters.</context>
      <utterance>He said they're gonna give you two thousand three hundred dollars a year and it costs two thousand five hundred dollars... so you gotta come up with the other two hundred. Great, huh?  I'm making hot dogs -- I'll make one for you. Can you put mustard on some bread for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight makes himself a drink, takes two large swallows, then turns to Toby.</context>
      <utterance>What're you doing home so earl... Oh! Toby he got that scholarship -- two thousand and three hundred dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby won't rise to the bait, and Dwight falls silent, he, looks around and sees the jar of mustard on top of the trash.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, leopard. I say, 'Hey, leopard.' I know you, leopard -- I can see those spots you can't change.  Thinks he can go to some fancy prep school and fool everybody. Not a chance. I know a thing or two about a thing or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who threw that away?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it was empty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Empty? That look empty to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks empty to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight pushes the jar against Toby's eye, leaving mustard stains on the boy's face.</context>
      <utterance>It looks empty to me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby jerks his head away, not answering. Dwight slams down the jar of mustard, grabs Toby by the back of the hair and forces his face down against the mustard jar.</context>
      <utterance>Look again, hotshot. Is it empty?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it wasn't empty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly he stands up and faces Dwight.</context>
      <utterance>Now. Was it empty?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwight slaps Toby across the mouth and the battle is on. As Pearl stands frozen, Toby lunges at Dwight, they grapple and stagger around the room. GLASS SHATTERS, the kitchen table CRASHES over, and their feet STAMP and SHUFFLE but Toby is a wild man. Even though he has only one good hand. He lands a blow between Dwight's eyes that bangs the man back against the wall. Dwight grabs the pan with the hot water from the hotdogs, flings it at Toby. Most of it misses. Again they grapple. Toby manages to throw Dwight down, then grabs a broom that has fallen to the floor, presses it against Dwight's throat, using his good hand and one knee. Dwight's mouth gapes wide, his eyes bulge, and he jerks himself frantically trying to dislodge Toby, but Toby hangs on like grim death. Desperate, Dwight grabs Toby's bandaged hand, bringing it close to his own face, and bites the stump of Toby's injured finger as hard as he can. Toby and Pearl scream simultaneously. Pearl in horror, Toby in pain. Pearl runs into her bedroom. Toby reels back in pain, holding his freshly-bleeding hand. Dwight takes his chance, grabs Toby by the throat, forces him down onto the floor and begins to choke the boy. Toby's eyelids begin to flutter. He's losing consciousness.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toby manages to stand up, Caroline speaks to both of them.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from him or I will kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the scholarship and he went nuts. He's crazy, and I'm leaving.  I'm leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me my paper route money, and you'll never have to see my face again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not so much that you're disappointing -- it's that you're consistently disappointing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fancy, fancy talk -- fancy talk for a whore. I know a thing or two about a thing or two. I got friends in this town that tell me things, and I found out some man down at that campaign headquarters found you a job in Washington, D.C. Gonna run off with him, aren't you, Miss Whore?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Liar. Miss Whore Liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving, Mom. You can leave, too. You don't have to stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't, do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could leave with you, couldn't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you could!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could just walk right out that door, couldn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline takes a deep breath, a weight has been lifted.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you could!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God... the lightness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Dwight, why do you want me to stay? You don't even like me, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look again, Dwight -- I'm already gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline and Toby are at the door, run across the yard and down the street. Dwight stands in the doorway, yelling:</context>
      <utterance>... you two've always sided in against me, always thought you were better than me. I tried. I did the best I could. What about me? Am I supposed to just crawl off in a ditch someplace and die? I've always been the nigger. Everybody's nigger. Ever since I was little.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me? When is it ever Dwight's turn for some consideration? What about me? I'll tell you one thing -- you'll remember me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, oh man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, oh man, oh man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's great. And you got the scholarship! Congratulations, honey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline's smile becomes fixed during Toby's speech and she begins to regard him oddly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm out! I'm outta here! Maybe I'll crash and burn, but it's a chance, so I'm gone! I'm history, Histoire. Nobody's gonna tell me what to do now, nobody. I'm free as a bird. Sayonara nest.  Heaven on a June day!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, heaven on a June day...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say about you having a job in D.C.?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Helen found me something in a real estate office, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline's eyes well up, and she lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>So now you can go! Oh. Oh! I am so damn glad to get out of this place! I'll be in 'fourth form.' Doesn't that sound great? And if you get a two-bedroom place in D.C., I can come for vacations and summers. I'm out. I'm out!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As sad as she is, Caroline smiles...</context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, don't cry -- he's not worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She holds Toby at arm's length and studies him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then clutches him to her fiercely. Smiling, the two walk on through the sunny afternoon, singing softly to each other.</context>
      <utterance>My you've grown, haven't you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you'll be all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on the bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I borrowed money from everybody I know -- it's the two hundred you need for the tuition, and an extra fifty. Buy yourself a blazer. Oh, God. I'll miss you. I'll write you. You sure your hand's okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline puts her arms around Toby, kisses his cheek hard, then whispers something into his ear. When Toby speaks, his words are full of love:</context>
      <utterance>Get on the bus, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline gets onto the bus, the DOORS CLOSE, WHOOSH and the bus pulls away. We see Caroline's face at a window. As the bus recedes, Toby turns and walks in another direction. His face is shining, incandescent with happiness. He breaks into a wide grin.</context>
      <utterance>I know that, Mom. I've always known that.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
