<movie id="555" title="Thor">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a loud BANG followed by muffled CURSING from below. Jane offers a hand down to ERIK SELVIG (60) who emerges as well, rubbing his head.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-- watch your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. So what's this "anomaly" of yours supposed to look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little different each time. Once it looked like, I don't know, melted stars, pooling in a corner of the sky. But last week it was a rolling rainbow ribbon--</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>GENTLY TEASING</mode>
      <context>Jane reigns in her excitement. She tries for dignity. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 1A.</context>
      <utterance>"Racing "˜round Orion?" I've always said you should have been a poet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Intern DARCY LEWIS (20) hands Jane a bottle of Champagne and a pair of gloves through the window. Jane passes it to Selvig to hold while she pulls on the old gloves -- too large and masculine for her small hands. He starts to unwrap the foil, and she stops his hand with an excited grin.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Darcy. Pass up the bubbly and my gloves, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until you see it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane's grin fades to a sad smile.</context>
      <utterance>I recognize those. Think how proud he'd be to see you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two stare out at the sky expectantly. A long beat while they scan the skies. Nothing. Jane's worried. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 2.</context>
      <utterance>The benefit of the doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Darcy calls up from the front seat.</context>
      <utterance>It's never taken this long before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I turn on the radio?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worried, Jane heads back down into the vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, if you like rocking out to KFRM, "All agriculture, all the time."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shows him a complicated CHART she's drawn in the book, tracking occurrences and patterns.</context>
      <utterance>The anomalies are always precipitated by geomagnetic storms.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Something catches Darcy's eye out the driver's side mirror. She adjusts it. In the distance, ODD GLOWING CLOUDS form in the skies over the Northeastern end of the desert.</context>
      <utterance>The last seventeen occurrences have been predictable to the minute... I just don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane SHUSHES her, leafs through her notes. The bottle of champagne begins to vibrate.</context>
      <utterance>Jane?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights and equipment in the SUV begin to FLICKER around them. The computer monitors SQUELCH with static. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 2A.</context>
      <utterance>There's got to be some new variable... Or an equipment malfunction...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The champagne bottle starts to RATTLE noisily now as it shakes more violently. Jane and Selvig notice. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 3. They watch it curiously, pressure building up inside it, when the cork EXPLODES out of it. Champagne goes spewing everywhere -- over equipment, over Jane.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think there's anything wrong with your equipment...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy points out the window. Jane and Selvig look out. Over the desert --</context>
      <utterance>I think you want to see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASSIVE CLOUDS OF RAINBOW LIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Churn in the sky. The three stare, dumbfounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy. Shatner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your "subtle" aurora?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No-- yes! Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>5 INT. SUV 5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane grins, thrilled, pumped with adrenaline.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thought strikes her.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't this great?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're seeing it too, right? I'm not crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SUV lurches.</context>
      <utterance>That's debateable. Put your seat belt on! 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 3A.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You've gotta get us closer so I can take a magnetic reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right! Good one!  Oh God, you're serious...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want those college credits or not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the credits. I'll intern at Burger King.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane grabs the wheel, jerks it hard the other way. They struggle for control, when the headlights fall on --</context>
      <utterance>Saving our lives!</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Directly in their path, stumbling through the winds. Darcy slams on the brakes, Jane turns the wheel hard to avoid him. The SUV swerves -- but too late.</context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 5.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that was legally your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy heads back inside the SUV as Jane, concerned, kneels next to the man. Selvig hovers, protectively. She gently turns his head to the light, and we see him clearly for the first time. He is magnificently handsome, long blonde hair flowing around his classically sculpted features. She cups her hands around his face, as if willing the life back into him.</context>
      <utterance>Get the first aid kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, he GROANS, and she's startled, then relieved, as his eyes flutter open. She looks deep into his confused, azure eyes, which at last focus on her own. Locking onto them. For a moment, they each forget to breathe. The connection is broken as Darcy returns with the kit. She freezes when she sees how gorgeous the man is. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 5A.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, big guy. Do me a favor and don't be dead, okay? Open your eyes and look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flustered Jane smooths her hair and sits back on her heels. She looks up at Selvig. Back to being a scientist.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Does he need CPR? Because I know CPR.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode>DREAMILY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--are beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--are dilating. That's a good sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We still have to get him to a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>HOPEFULLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After we get a reading on the storm?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane sighs and nods, regretfully watching the storm EVAPORATE above their heads. A thought strikes her.</context>
      <utterance>Immediately, Jane.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange puzzled looks, as we move up through the last glowing remnants of the storm, and into:</context>
      <utterance>Where did he come from?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We pull away from the planet, widening, past other worlds, cosmic debris -- leaving first our solar system, then our galaxy.</context>
      <utterance>Questions, they've always asked questions -- this race called man, on this planet they call earth. Passionately longing to know how they are connected to the heavens. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 6.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We pull back until we see it -- YGGDRASIL. Immense, sprawling, like a quasar or a nebula twisted into the vague shape of a TREE, its branches of glowing energy stretching out into the black void of space.</context>
      <utterance>In ages past, they looked to us as gods, for indeed so many times we saved them from calamity. We tried to show them how their world was but one of the Nine Realms of the Cosmos, linked to all others by the branches of Yggdrasil...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We move in through Yggdrasil, until we reach what looks like a galaxy, slowly spinning before us.</context>
      <utterance>...the Worlds Tree. Nine Realms in a universe of wonder, beauty, and terror that they barely comprehended.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We move through the galaxy's mists and astral matter, then over and up, through a band of prismatic color to reveal what's on the other side:</context>
      <utterance>But for all their thirst for knowledge, they let our lessons fall into myth and dreams. Where did he come from? He came from us, the proudest race of warriors the Worlds have ever seen. He came from this -- the greatest Realm the universe has ever known.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came... from Asgard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think he's ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks he is. He has his father's confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll need his father's wisdom.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin reacts.</context>
      <utterance>And his humility?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Have faith in your sons.</context>
      <utterance>Thor won't be alone. Loki will be at his side to give him counsel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin stops, notices HIS HAND SHAKING. It seems to be out of synch temporally with the rest of the world, leaving a trail as it moves. He stares at it determinedly, concentrating, trying to stop the strange event through the force of his sheer will. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 8. Finally, the occurrence subsides, his hand normal once more. A worried Frigga covers his hand with her own.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but Thor's still a boy. He could be a great King...</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - QUIETLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...if we only had more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For once, our son needs something we cannot provide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can fight it a little longer...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her cheek.</context>
      <utterance>No. You've put it off too long! I worry for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've destroyed demons and monsters, devastated whole worlds, laid waste to mighty kingdoms, and still you worry for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her close, and they kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Not today. Now come kiss your king... while I'm still king.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 8A. The cup smashes, the alcohol causes the fire to glow intensely -- and, for a moment, brightly lit, and seen full length, like a King to be, is THE MIGHTY THOR. He proceeds down stops, past camera, and down the center of the Hall. We follow from behind and see at the other end, massively shadowed on one of the great banners, the shape of two great horns. As Thor approaches, the horn shapes move, and then, from the shadows at the side, emerges LOKI, wearing his horned headpiece. Like Thor, he is dressed for a great ceremony. They stand by a brazier at the foot of steps that lead up to the crowded throne room.</context>
      <utterance>Another!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>TO THOR</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 9.</context>
      <utterance>Nervous, brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever known me to be nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was the time in Nornheim...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant approaches with another goblet of wine for Thor.</context>
      <utterance>That wasn't nerves, brother. It was the rage of battle. How else could I have fought my way through a hundred warriors and pulled us out alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I recall, I was the one who veiled us in smoke to ease our escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant stifles a laugh. Loki notices, doesn't like it. He gestures towards the goblet in the Attendant's hand. EELS pour over the sides of the goblet, slithering out and across the terrified Attendant's hand. He SCREAMS, hurls the goblet to the ground. Loki chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Some do battle, others just do tricks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki gestures to the writhing eels on the ground. They turn back to spilled wine, the illusion shattered.</context>
      <utterance>Loki...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that was just a waste of good wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant isn't so sure. Thor dons his EAGLE-WINGED</context>
      <utterance>Just a bit of fun.  Right, my friend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 9A.</context>
      <utterance>Nice feathers.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't really want to start this again, do you, Cow?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was being sincere!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're incapable of sincerity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks his brother in the eye, all pretense lost.</context>
      <utterance>Am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor searches his brother's face, sees no trace of irony. He's either speaking from his heart or he's a very, very good liar. Maybe both. Thor puts an appreciative hand on his brother's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I've looked forward to this day as long as you have. You're my brother and my friend. Sometimes I'm envious, but never doubt that I love you. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 10.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two brothers take in the moment a beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give us a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor makes the final adjustments to his ceremonial wear.</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear the blast of a CEREMONIAL HORN.</context>
      <utterance>Like a king.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki casts him a wary look.</context>
      <utterance>You go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki heads inside the palace without his brother.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be along. Go on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to the Maidens)</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, love.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 10A.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The giddy Maidens eagerly raise their hands. HOGUN stands staring ahead grimly, his hands folded in front of him, amidst the hustle and bustle of the ATTENDANTS and the ceremony preparations going on around him. A HELPFUL ATTENDANT approaches him and starts to polish his armor. Hogun turns his head, gives him a look. Intimidated, the Attendant quickly backs away. From behind, we see a WOMAN IN CEREMONIAL ARMOR take off her SWORD and set it on a table, then her SHIELD, then several HIDDEN DAGGERS and small, yet intimidating WEAPONS. We reveal that it's SIF, looking radiant. She eyes the weapons on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Now who'd like to polish my sword for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll miss you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope this goes quickly. I'm famished.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>FEIGNED DISBELIEF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you attached to that pretty face of yours? Because one more word, and you won't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others laugh, save Hogun. Fandral turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>My, we are hungry, aren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hogun stares at him grimly.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, Hogun. Smile. You can do it. Even you, Hogun the Grim. Just one smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, half a smile. Look, forget the smile, just show some teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fandral, is it true the famous Warriors Three are ready to meet any challenge?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name it, Lady Sif.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 12.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your mouth shut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right to be nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm not nervous!</context>
      <utterance>Why does everyone keep saying that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may be able to fool the rest of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but never you. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thor, just remember that you have something even the great Allfather never had.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Me for a mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frigga leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Now don't keep your father waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sitting atop his throne, clad in full ceremonial armor. He holds his spear GUNGNIR before him. Any trace of weakness in him is gone now. He exudes all the power and majesty of a Ruler of Asgard. Frigga joins him at his side. He looks around the hall, casts a glance over to the Warriors. Thor is nowhere to be seen. Odin looks to Loki. Loki shrugs. Odin isn't pleased. A murmur spreads through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 12A.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif realizes the truth, shakes her head in disapproval.</context>
      <utterance>He said he'd be along.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to make an entrance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if he doesn't show up soon, he shouldn't bother. Odin looks like he's ready to feed him to his ravens.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, at the back of the hall, up the steps from the lower level --</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't worry. Father will forgive him. He always does. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 13.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gungnir. Its aim is true, its power strong. With it I have defended Asgard and the lives of the innocent across the Nine Realms since the time of the Great Beginning. And though the day has come for a new King to wield his own weapon -- that duty remains the same. Thor Odinson, my heir, my first-born.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 13A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 14.</context>
      <utterance>So long entrusted with this mighty hammer, Mjolnir. Forged in the heart of a dying star, from the sacred metal of Uru. Only one may lift it. Only one is worthy. Who wields this hammer commands the lightning and the storm. Its power has no equal -- as a weapon, to destroy, or as a tool, to build. It is a fit companion for a King.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Crowd and the Warriors Three start to shiver and rub their limbs for warmth in the increasingly cold air of the hall. Thor turns back to face his father. Odin looks upon his son with pride. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 15.</context>
      <utterance>Today I entrust you with the greatest honor in all the Nine Realms. The sacred throne of Asgard. I have sacrificed much to achieve peace. So, too, must a new generation sacrifice to maintain that peace. Responsibility, duty, honor. These are not merely virtues to which we must aspire. They are essential to every soldier and to every King.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thor Odinson, do you swear to guard the Nine Realms?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you swear to preserve the peace?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Do you swear to cast aside all selfish ambition and pledge yourself only to the good of all the Realms?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin hesitates, noticing a strange sight before him. ICE creeps across the surface of the large banners around the hall, making an eerie CRACKING sound. Thor, his comrades, and the crowd see it too.</context>
      <utterance>Then on this day, I, Odin Allfather, proclaim you--</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - REALIZING</mode>
      <context>The far-off sounds of a BATTLE echo in the depths of the palace below. Sif and the Warriors Three reach for their weapons, as Thor races from the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Frost giants...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Destroyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>AWED</mode>
      <context>Odin steps in behind the Asgardians, as the Destroyer sets the Casket back on its pedestal. It moves back to its post, the faint, FIERY GLOW extinguishes within it. Fandral looks around the Vault, ill at ease.</context>
      <utterance>I thought it was but a legend.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been inside the Vault before. It's said the Tesseract was once held here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>AWED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Tesseract? I thought that was but a legend too!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin surveys the destruction.</context>
      <utterance>Shush!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 16A.</context>
      <utterance>The Jotuns must pay for what they've done!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have paid with their lives. The Destroyer did its job, and the Casket is safe. All is well.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"All is well?!" They broke into the Weapons Vault! If the Frost Giants had stolen even one of these</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know why they--</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>INTERRUPTING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Casket of Ancient Winters belonged to the Jotuns. They believe it's their birthright.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you hadn't taken it from them they would have laid waste to all the Nine Realms!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a truce with Laufey, the Jotun King.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin turns to Sif and the Warriors Three.</context>
      <utterance>He just broke your truce! We must act!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor's comrades exit. Odin eyes Thor, as Loki watches.</context>
      <utterance>Leave us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what action would you take?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>March into Jotunheim as you once did, teach them a lesson, break their spirits so they'll never dare try to cross our borders again!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 16B.</context>
      <utterance>You're thinking only as a warrior!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was an act of war!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the act of but a few, doomed to fail.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got this far!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 17.</context>
      <utterance>We will find the breach in our defenses. It will be found, and it will be sealed.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As King of Asgard, I would--</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor sees in his father's face that he's pushed this as far as he can. He backs away, then leaves, pushing through the doors so hard that they SLAM backwards behind him. Odin watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>You are not King. Not yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg surveys the overturned tables and food, aghast.</context>
      <utterance>Redecorating, are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this -- ?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you they'd cancel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg looks about the floor, despairing.</context>
      <utterance>We thought that was just you being your normal cheery self.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor strides away from them to the far end of the hall. Loki calmly moves towards him.</context>
      <utterance>All this food -- so innocent, cast to the ground. It breaks the heart!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 18.</context>
      <utterance>It's unwise to be in my company right now, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said I was wise?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was to be my day of triumph.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will come. In time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>ADMITS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's any consolation, I think you're right. About the Frost Giants, about Laufey, everything. If a few of them could penetrate the defenses of Asgard once, who's to say they won't try again. Next time with an army?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, exactly!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor considers this, looks at his hammer, a gleam in his eye. Loki can guess what he's thinking, grows concerned.</context>
      <utterance>But there's nothing we can do without defying Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... stop there! I know that look!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the only way to ensure the safety of our borders.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's madness!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madness? What sort of madness?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing! Thor was making a jest!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 19.</context>
      <utterance>The safety of our Realm is no jest. We're going to Jotunheim.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thor, of all the laws of Asgard, this is one you must not break. Loki looks on, intrigued by the proceedings.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't like a journey to Earth, where you summon a little lightning and thunder and the mortals worship you as a god. This is Jotunheim.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if the Frost Giants don't kill you, your Father will!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father fought his way into Jotunheim, defeated their armies, and took their Casket! We'd just be looking for answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor sizes up his friends, smiles. He proceeds to make his case with enthusiasm and charismatic conviction.</context>
      <utterance>It is forbidden!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Fandral.</context>
      <utterance>My friends, have you forgotten all that we've done together?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who brought you into the sweet embrace of the most exotic maidens in all of Yggdrasil?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>TO HOGUN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who led you into the most glorious of battles...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG/HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Sif.</context>
      <utterance>You did. / You did.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who proved wrong all who scoffed at the idea that a young maiden could be one of the fiercest warriors this Realm has ever known?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>QUICKLY</mode>
      <context>The others exchange concerned looks, realize there's no convincing him.</context>
      <utterance>True. But I supported you...  My friends, trust me now. We must do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki looks startled.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. You're not going to let my brother and me take all the glory, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are coming with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I will be at his side.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course! I won't let my brother march into Jotunheim alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 20.</context>
      <utterance>And I.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I. The Warriors Three fight together.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fear we'll live to regret this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're lucky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must first find a way to get past Heimdall.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will be no easy task. It's said the Gatekeeper can see a single dew drop fall from a blade of grass a thousand worlds away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he can hear a cricket passing gas in Niffelheim.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jest not! He heareth all!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg, terrified, calls out to the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Getting past him should be simple enough now, since he seems to be letting Frost Giants sneak by under his nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki rejoins the group as Thor leads them onward. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 20A.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive him! He meaneth no offense!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor, Loki, and the others trade looks.</context>
      <utterance>You're not dressed warmly enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The freezing cold of Jotunheim. It will kill you all in time, even Thor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>He fixes his eyes pointedly at Fandral.</context>
      <utterance>You think you can deceive me? I, who watch all? I, who can sense the flapping of a butterfly's wings a thousand worlds away?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 22.</context>
      <utterance>Or can hear a cricket passing gas in Niffelheim? Fandral looks gob-smacked.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki goes into damage control.</context>
      <utterance>That was just a bit of a jest, really...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be mistaken. We're not--</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>STEPPING FORWARD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For ages have I guarded Asgard and kept it safe from those who would do it harm. In all that time, never has an enemy slipped by my watch -- until this day. I wish to know how that happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor walks past Heimdall as the Gatekeeper lets the group pass. Volstagg walks beside the frustrated Loki, needles him.</context>
      <utterance>Then tell no one where we've gone until we've returned.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened? Your silver tongue turn to lead?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg and Fandral share a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Get me off this bridge before it cracks under your girth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be warned. I will honor my sworn oath to protect this Realm as its Gatekeeper. If your return threatens the safety of Asgard, Bifrost will remain closed to you. You'll be left to die in the cold wastes of Jotunheim.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no plans to die today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heimdall inserts his sword into the control panel, and the apparatus of the Observatory starts up.</context>
      <utterance>None do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All is ready. You may pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't you just leave the bridge open for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To keep this bridge open would unleash the full power of the Bifrost and destroy Jotunheim with you upon it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor starts towards the Bifrost, turns back to the others, grins. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 23A.</context>
      <utterance>Ah. Never mind, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others join him at his side, then step towards the Bifrost. Their bodies stretch towards the maelstrom, changing shape, as if every atom of their being is being elongated by the pull of it. In an instant, they're jerked off the platform and inside the vortex.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Don't be bashful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With an effort, Thor pulls the burly warrior back onto the ice and, tremendously relieved, he proclaims:</context>
      <utterance>Come on, big fella. Up...!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This belt! This belt is now my lucky belt! I will never remove it! Even when bathing!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor and the others turn and stare out in horror and wonder at the frozen alien wasteland before them. The whole planet is a massive flattened ring of jagged ice, slowly breaking apart. Huge CHUNKS OF ICE calve away from its outer edges and float off into space. The planet's icy surface cracks and melts as far as the eye can see. The ruins of a Jotun city lies in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>You bathe?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shouldn't be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too late now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor ignore him, heads off. Loki looks around, anxious.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, it's not. We could turn right around, hop back to Asgard, share a mug by the fire. Could be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor turns back to his brother.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we should wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 25.</context>
      <utterance>To survey the enemy. To gauge their strengths and weaknesses from a distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm liking that. Gauging, surveying. Particularly the distance part.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor heads on. Reluctantly, the others follow.</context>
      <utterance>We know all we must. It's time to act.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just got to swing his hammer...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels good, doesn't it? To be together again, adventuring on another world?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adventuring? Is that what we're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you call it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freezing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starving.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whining.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others groan.</context>
      <utterance>How about a song to lift our spirits?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 25A.</context>
      <utterance>No, not that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't make us sing again!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I have to listen to Volstagg's singing voice one more time, I'll fall on my own sword!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The party reaches the edge of the city -- its ancient structures of jade and ice melting and crumbling, ravaged by warfare long ago. A TEMPLE lies before them, across a central plaza.</context>
      <utterance>Well, now I'm on board. She and Thor share a grin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor leads the others onwards towards the central plaza. Loki reluctantly follows. They don't notice as SHADOWY FIGURES move in the shadows of the structures nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Hiding. As cowards always do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="62">
   <speaker>JOTUN SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Jotun's voice itself sounds like cracking ice. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 26.</context>
      <utterance>What is your business here, Asgardian?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I speak only to your King. Not to his foot soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOTUN VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Thor turns towards the source in a balcony of the temple, where LAUFEY sits, veiled in shadow, behind a cascading waterfall. The Jotun King is ancient, noble, powerful -- too proud to reveal even a hint of the years of suffering he and his people have endured.</context>
      <utterance>Then speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Laufey, King of this Realm.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I am--</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know who you are, Odinson. Why have you brought the stench of your blood into my world?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laufey stands, sizing up Thor, tries to piece this together.</context>
      <utterance>I demand answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You "demand?"</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did your people get into Asgard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif and the Warriors Three exchange a puzzled look, disturbed by the Jotun King's words.</context>
      <utterance>The house of Odin is full of traitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do not dishonor my father's name with your lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 27.</context>
      <utterance>Your father is a murderer and a thief. He stole what was ours, and left our world in ruins. We have the right to reclaim the Casket.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laufey laughs, cold, mocking.</context>
      <utterance>Not when you'd use it to make war against other Realms.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why have you come here? To make peace? You long for battle. You crave it. I see you for what you are, Thor Odinson. Nothing but a boy, trying to prove himself a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor takes a step towards Laufey. The other Jotuns step in front of Thor, blocking his path. We finally see the Frost Giants now -- terrifying, blue-skinned, standing eight feet tall. Loki moves next to his brother and quietly implores him.</context>
      <utterance>This boy has grown tired of your mockery.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thor, stop and think. Look around you. We are outnumbered.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know your place, brother...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laufey steps out of the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>You should listen to his counsel. You know not what your actions would unleash.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor simmers. Loki speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>But I do. Go now, while I still allow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look to Thor imploringly. Thor stares Laufey down a beat -- then relents. He turns to leave. His comrades breathe a sigh of relief and follow, when a Frost Giant nearby mutters under his breath. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 28.</context>
      <utterance>We will accept your most gracious offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOTUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor stops in his tracks. Loki goes white. He knows what's coming.</context>
      <utterance>Run back home, little princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In one quick move, Thor pulls Mjolnir, swings it, and KNOCKS the Jotun clear across the plaza. The Asgardians reluctantly draw their weapons, gather into a circle around Thor. Volstagg looks around at the angry Jotuns approaching them.</context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ICE forms on the Jotuns' bodies, creating a FROZEN ARMOR around them, extending off the ends of their arms like SWORDS. One Giant does so directly in front of Fandral.</context>
      <utterance>Silly hammer! Has a mind of its own!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor leaves the circle of Asgardians, swings at another Frost Giant. His comrades form another circle around him, separating him from the Jotuns, as he whirls his hammer around once and catches it with a cocky grin. He's enjoying this.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hoping that's just decorative.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fandral calls to Volstagg and Hogun.</context>
      <utterance>Next!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? What move, do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we use "The Norn's Revenge."</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this close range? I think "The Alfheim Lunge" is a better move.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>DISGUSTED</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 28A.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe if they were three feet tall! No! How about "The Randy Valkyrie"?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor takes out yet another Frost Giant, then all hell breaks loose as the Asgardians and Jotuns begin to battle. A Jotun backs Hogun up against a wall of ice. As the Giant hurls an ice blade fist at him, the grim warrior swings his mace over his head, embedding it into the ice wall, and hoists himself up, dodging the Giant's blow and leaping over him. Hogun takes out a second approaching Frost Giant, spins back, dodges a swing from the first, then pounds the Jotun with his mace. Nearby, Sif expertly stabs one Jotun after another with her double-bladed staff. One knocks her viciously to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki backs away from an approaching Jotun, finds himself at the edge of a deep crevasse. The Giant sees he's vulnerable, swipes at him. But the Jotun's arm passes right through him. The Giant stands there, confused, when THE REAL LOKI comes out from behind a structure and shoves the Giant into the crevasse below. The false Loki dissipates into nothingness.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't treat me like a lady, I won't act like a lady! She takes out the Jotun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to the battle. Two Jotuns come at him from either side. He lets two daggers fly, felling both Giants at once. Laufey nods to one of his guards -- a massive Jotun BRUTE. The Brute leaps down from the balcony, icing himself up, then punches his giant fist into the ice beneath his feet. It's a long-range attack, causing PILLARS OF ICE to explode out in front of Hogun, sending the grim warrior flying back. Across the plaza, Thor easily dispatches some Jotuns.</context>
      <utterance>Pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees the Brute coming at him. The huge Jotun lands a tremendous blow, sending Thor back across the ice. Thor rises, grins. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 28B.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! At least make it a challenge for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He throws Mjolnir with all his strength, knocking the Brute head over heels. Thor raises his hand. Mjolnir slows in mid-air, then flies back to his grasp.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's more like it!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sif takes out a couple Frost Giants, but she's knocked to the ground by another. It raises its weapon above her. Hogun sees Sif in danger. He pulls a HIDDEN KNIFE from his sleeve and hurls it at Sif's attacker, hitting him square in the chest. The Jotun falls dead.</context>
      <utterance>Ugly and stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg grapples with a Frost Giant, getting a couple good hits in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad I taught him how to do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Frost Giant fights back, but Volstagg manages to grip in a headlock just as another comes up on him from behind. Volstagg fends him off, then turns the first one loose.</context>
      <utterance>You may want to put some ice on that!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Volstagg launches his mighty belly at the Jotun and sends him flying. Another Jotun grabs Volstagg, squeezing him tightly and sending him crashing to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You may be taller, but I'm wider!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Volstagg recovers and fights on. The Jotun grabs Volstagg's bare arm. The warrior's skin begins to freeze from the Jotun's grasp, a BLACKNESS spreading from it, necrotizing Volstagg's flesh. The warrior SHOUTS in pain. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 28C. Volstagg head-butts the Frost Giant, shattering the Jotun's ice helmet and dropping him to the ground. Winded, he takes a seat upon one of the fallen Jotun's bodies to catch his breath. As the battle rages around him, he opens a secret compartment at the end of his weapon, takes out a small FLASK. Volstagg grimaces in pain, sees his blackened skin. He yells to his comrades.</context>
      <utterance>It's not too late for you to surrender.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He takes a swig, enjoying the brief respite, then rejoins the battle. Volstagg stabs his blade in a Giant's chest, but the sword stops mid ice layer. The Giant delivers a bone-breaking blow to Volstagg's face, and the warrior drops to one knee. Sif sees Volstagg in trouble and rushes towards him. In one quick move, she leaps up and off of Volstagg's back, using her boot to plunge Volstagg's blade deep into the Giant's chest, standing atop him as he falls backwards to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let them grab hold of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, my lady. But I nearly had him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby, a Frost Giant forms a BARRAGE OF ICE BULLETS, hurling them at Sif. Sif raises her shield barely in time, as the bullets go pinging and ricocheting off it. She races into the group of Frost Giants who attacked her and takes them out. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 29. A Frost Giant touches a pool of standing water. It FLASH- FREEZES Hogun's feet to the ground. Volstagg notices, hurries over, dispatching Jotuns as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg swings his weapon, wildly hacking at the ice around Hogun's legs to free him. Hogun looks down, suddenly worried, as Volstagg's blade cuts deep -- and perilously close to hacking into Hogun's legs.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch the legs!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>REALIZING</mode>
      <context>Volstagg chips away at the ice more carefully, finally freeing Hogun's feet. Fandral sword fights with a Frost Giant.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fandral lunges at the Giant. The Jotun knocks his blade away.</context>
      <utterance>You really think your icicles are a match for Asgardian steel?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fandral moves on him again, but the Giant grabs Fandral's sword and snaps it in half.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fandral fights the Giant with his broken sword. The Jotun then lunges at Fandral, who ducks just in time, grabs hold of the Giant's sword and redirects it, stabbing the Giant through with his own weapon. The Jotun staggers back, then reaches down and swipes at a pool of water, sending up a spray that freezes in mid-air, forming into an ICE STALAGMITE. It impales Fandral, rendering him helpless. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 29A. Loki races towards the impaled Fandral, throwing daggers and felling Frost Giants as he goes. He reaches the nearly- unconscious warrior, when other Jotuns approach. He fights them off. Volstagg looks across the plaza and sees the impaled Fandral.</context>
      <utterance>Could we stop just a moment while I get another sword?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries to his wounded comrade.</context>
      <utterance>That's unfortunate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may need a bit of help. Not a good look, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just try not to bleed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the face?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg begins to pull the bleeding Fandral off the ice stalagmite. Loki plunges two daggers into the chest of one of the Frost Giants. The Giant grabs hold of Loki's gloved wrists. Loki pulls his hands free of the gloves, which are still in the Giant's grasp, revealing Loki's skin beneath. The wounded Jotun sees his chance, grabs hold of Loki's bare arm. Loki looks at his arm, prepared for the worst. But instead of the blackness of necrotizing flesh, Loki's arm turns BLUE -- like the Frost Giant's own skin. The blueness spreads painlessly up Loki's arm. He stares at it, confused. The Frost Giant is thrown as well, distracted by the unexpected phenomenon. Loki takes advantage of the distraction, KICKS the Giant. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 30. Thor continues fighting, his blood lust rising. He taunts the Jotuns around him.</context>
      <utterance>Flawless.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But when he hurls his hammer to take out a Jotun, the Frost Giants seize the opportunity. A group of Jotuns swarm Thor from all sides, keeping him separate from his weapon. Mjolnir falls to the ground. A Frost Giant desperately struggles to lift Mjolnir off the ground, to no avail. Now free, the wounded Fandral looks relieved as Volstagg slings him over his shoulder, and the warriors start to leave. From his balcony, Laufey looks upon the battlefield, decides it's time to pull out the big guns. He touches a wall of the palace. An ENERGY WAVE sweeps from his touch, across the wall of the palace, and down to the ground below. The Asgardians hear a foreboding CRACK OF ICE below their feet.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look down, suddenly filled with dread when they see shadowy figures moving in the ice -- dozens of JOTUN WARRIORS awakening beneath the surface, rousing to join the battle. Loki turns to his brother, who battles a group of the Giants. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 31.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it could! Might be an early spring!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor, still without his hammer, fights his Jotun foes mercilessly, a man consumed by blood lust. Loki sees the look on his brother's face -- the savage thrill of the heat of battle.</context>
      <utterance>Thor, we must go!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are too many of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others hesitate. Jotuns break up through the ice all around them.</context>
      <utterance>I can stop them!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Thor ignores his comrades, continues fighting.</context>
      <utterance>Thor!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, the group flees back toward the inner edge of the planet as the Giants break up through the ice and give chase. Thor battles valiantly, but there's just too many of them. The Frost Giants swarm him from all sides now, as he disappears beneath a pile of blue flesh and ice. After a</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Thor done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Jotuns race towards the Asgardians, they open their mouths wide and breathe out an ICY FOG. The swirling mists quickly engulf the fleeing Asgardians before them. The Asgardians stand in the mist, unable to see. Hogun takes a step back, the ice cracking beneath him. They dare not move, for fear of falling through, into the void below. Thor sees he's put his friends in even greater danger. He raises Mjolnir high, SUMMONING THE WINDS. They lift him off the ground and carry him across the frozen wasteland to his comrades.</context>
      <utterance>Likely killed us all!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki raises his arms, concentrates, the mists dissipating. But as they do, the Asgardians see before them the faces of the Frost Giants. And there are HUNDREDS of them -- too many, even for a Thunder God.</context>
      <utterance>Loki, we have to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>TO LOKI</mode>
      <context>Thor realizes that he and his comrades are as good as dead. The Giants move in for the kill, when they hear a deafening ROAR. A hole in the sky opens up, and the Bifrost blasts down onto the inner edge of the planet. Out of the maelstrom comes the sound of THUNDERING HOOVES, and, to the shock of all, tearing across the frozen wasteland comes --</context>
      <utterance>Actually, could you bring the mists back, please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laufey. End this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 33.</context>
      <utterance>Your boy sought this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unseen by Odin and the others, Laufey starts to form an ice blade at the end of his arm.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. These are the actions of a boy. Treat them as such. You and I can stop this before there's further bloodshed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin looks grim, determined.</context>
      <utterance>We are beyond diplomacy now, Allfather. He'll get what he came for -- war and death.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning, Laufey swings his ice blade at Odin, but Odin is quicker. The Allfather brings his spear down upon the ice. Laufey and the nearest Jotuns go falling backwards in a wave, the ice cracking beneath their feet. The other Frost Giants turn tail and run. Thor watches the fleeing Jotuns with delight.</context>
      <utterance>So be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now! We'll finish them together!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin raises his spear. The hole in the sky opens, the Bifrost energy blasting forth from it. The Bifrost envelops the Asgardians, yanks them off the ground and up through the hole. The vortex closes behind them as all falls silent. Laufey stares up after them contemptuously.</context>
      <utterance>Silence!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you bring us back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 33A.</context>
      <utterance>Do you realize what you've done? What you've started?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 34.</context>
      <utterance>I was protecting my home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin turns to the others.</context>
      <utterance>You cannot protect your friends. How can you hope to protect a kingdom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - RE: FANDRAL</mode>
      <context>Sif, Volstagg, and Hogun hurry to help Fandral out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Get him to the healing room!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>There won't be a kingdom to protect if you're afraid to act!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever the cost, the world must know that the new King of Asgard will not be held in contempt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pride and vanity that talks! Not leadership! Have you forgotten everything I've taught you? What of a warrior's patience, cunning?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While you wait and be patient, the Nine Realms laugh at us! The old ways are done. You'd stand giving speeches while Asgard falls!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a vain, greedy, cruel boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole world seems to stop at Thor's words. Odin falls quiet. When he speaks again, there's something terrifying beneath the calmness of his words.</context>
      <utterance>And you are an old man and a fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 34A.</context>
      <utterance>A fool, yes! I was a fool to think you were ready. Loki takes a step towards Odin imploringly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Allfather plunges Gungnir into Observatory's control panel. The turret turns, the Bifrost energy building along with Odin's rage. It FIRES, as the Bifrost opens at the end of the platform, creating a portal behind Thor. Odin turns angrily to his son.</context>
      <utterance>Thor Odinson... You have disobeyed the express command of your King. Through your arrogance and stupidity, you have opened these peaceful Realms and innocent lives to the horrors of war.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Odin RIPS a disc off Thor's chest.</context>
      <utterance>You are unworthy of this Realm...</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He rips away Thor's cloak.</context>
      <utterance>...unworthy of your title...</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Odin extends his hand towards his son. Mjolnir goes flying from Thor's grasp into Odin's hand.</context>
      <utterance>...unworthy of the loved ones you've betrayed. I hereby take from you your powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A FINGER OF LIGHTNING comes off the hammer and hits Thor, disintegrating the right arm of his armor and part of the chest piece.</context>
      <utterance>In the name of my father...</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Another strike disintegrates the remainder of Thor's armor, including the cape and torn-away disc on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>...and of his father before...</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Odin thrusts Mjolnir before him and -- with a CRACK OF THUNDER -- Thor is hurled backwards into the open Bifrost and disappears in the vortex. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 35A. Odin holds Mjolnir in his hand, stares at it bitterly. He closes his eyes, lost in contemplation, whispers something quietly.</context>
      <utterance>I cast you out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - WHISPERING</mode>
      <context>RUNES appear on the side of the hammer, as if carved into its smooth surface. The runes linger for but a moment, then disappear. Suddenly, Odin turns and hurls the hammer into the Bifrost.</context>
      <utterance>Whosoever holds this hammer, if he be worthy, shall possess the power of Thor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CUT TO BLACK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat, we hear familiar voices.</context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 36.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that was legally your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the first aid kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, big guy. Do me a favor and don't be dead, okay? Open your eyes and look at me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>TO SELVIG</mode>
      <context>They exchange puzzled looks when Thor GROANS again. He sits up abruptly, and Jane topples backwards in surprise. Thor staggers groggily to his feet, then turns and offers Jane a hand up. She takes it hesitantly, and he easily pulls her up. She can't help but marvel at his strength.</context>
      <utterance>Where did he come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor searches the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, thanks. Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hammer...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane notices something on the ground around them. She shines her flashlight down at the sand. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 36A.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we can tell you're hammered. That's pretty obvious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He joins her at her side and sees it. A faint, discernible pattern is etched into the sand. They exchange a look. Amazed and excited, Jane hurriedly takes out a camera and snaps some photos of the runes. A breeze begins to blow them away.</context>
      <utterance>Erik... look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to move fast before anything changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 37.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pulls out a light meter, holds it up, takes some readings, jots them down in her notebook. Selvig looks at Thor, who stares up at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>We need soil samples, light readings, everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane kneels and quickly scoops up a soil sample in the cannister.</context>
      <utterance>Jane, we need get him to a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig looks uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Not right now. It'll take too long. County's an hour away. We'll drop him off after we're done here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - RE: THOR</mode>
      <context>Thor stares up at the stars, shouts up at them angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Look at him, he's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father! Heimdall! I know you can hear me! Open the bridge!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you and Darcy take him to the hospital, I'll stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor turns to the others, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>You expect me to leave you alone in the middle of the desert?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group is intimidated by his fervor.</context>
      <utterance>You! What world is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig touches Thor's shoulder. Thor shoves him off, grows agitated, belligerent. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 37A.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, my friend. We're going to get you some help.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy reaches into her fanny pack, pulls something out of it. Jane looks on, concerned. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 38.</context>
      <utterance>Where am I?! Answer me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erik, just back away...</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in the desert outside the town of Puente Antiguo.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Realm?! Alfheim? Nornheim?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy raises a TASER at him. Thor looks at the weapon, unsure what to make of it.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... New Mexico?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dare threaten Thor with so puny</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nurse painstakingly types it into the computer, one key at a time. Jane watches as Thor is wheeled out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>He said it was "Thor."</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>SPELLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T-H-O-R. And your relationship to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never met him before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until she hit him with the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grazed him, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and we tasered him, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>SYMPATHETIC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must have been quite the spat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't know him. I just want to make sure he's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to need a name and contact number.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane Foster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>J...A...N...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 39A.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches over Jane's shoulder and hands the Nurse his business card.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, for God's sake...</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 40.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Let's go. Selvig, Darcy, and Jane head out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor SLAPS the syringe away angrily, starts to sit up.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Just taking a little blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you attack the son of Odin!</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two ORDERLIES race over, try to hold Thor down.</context>
      <utterance>I need some help!</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to help you!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls one of them off, smashing against a wall. Now a couple SECURITY GUARDS and MALE NURSES join the fracas, all struggling to hold Thor down. Medical equipment goes flying, furniture overturned.</context>
      <utterance>Then bring me a healing stone, you savages!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, they force him back down onto the gurney. Thor looks shocked and amazed that he's actually being overpowered by this small group. The NURSE injects him with a sedative.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this guy on?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're no match for the Mighty-- Thor struggles a beat, then passes out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 40A. The Townie approaches something at the center of the crater. We don't see what it is, but it bathes him in an otherworldly, BLUE LUMINOUS GLOW. He reaches for the object, tries to lift it, but can't. He redoubles his efforts, strains with all his might, with no luck. He takes off his hat, fans himself, stares at the mysterious object. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 41.</context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darcy, when you're done, take the soil samples to Professor Meyers in geology. Remind him, he owes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We might want to perform a spectral analysis.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the offer Jane's been waiting for. She gets up, inserts the piece of equipment she's been working on into a rack-mounted server.</context>
      <utterance>I flew all the way out here -- might as well make myself useful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what would be really useful? Do you still have that friend at LIGO?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was more than a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you call in a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 41A.</context>
      <utterance>You don't think this was just a magnetic storm?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm right, their observatory must have picked up gravitational waves during last night's event.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane heads over to a computer monitor. Selvig follows.</context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning these anomalies might signify something bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane indicates the footage on the monitor. As the last of the Bifrost cloud disappears into the night sky, there appears to be a blister in space, bulging out in convex and covered with stars.</context>
      <utterance>How "big" are we talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the lensing around the edges is characteristic of an Einstein-Rosen Bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were a science major.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig shoots Jane a confused look. Jane shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Political Science.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was the only applicant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>TO DARCY</mode>
      <context>Darcy stares blankly.</context>
      <utterance>An Einstein-Rosen Bridge -- a "theoretical" connection between two different points of space-time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>TO DARCY</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 41B. Selvig looks skeptical. Jane prints out a frame-grab off the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>A wormhole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jane indicates the print-out showing the constellations seen through the "bubble" in the clouds.</context>
      <utterance>Erik, look... 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 42.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spreads out a STAR CHART, barely able to contain her excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But not our stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Darcy pulls another frame-grab of the Bifrost footage from the printer and hangs it on the wall, when something in the image catches her eye.</context>
      <utterance>This is the star alignment for our quadrant, this time of year. So unless Ursa Minor decided to take the day off... those are someone else's constellations. Selvig's intrigued, in spite of himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane and Selvig examine the photo, amazed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jane walks away, we REVEAL the photo. Inside the Bifrost funnel cloud is a FIGURE -- the vague, but unmistakable shape of a MAN.</context>
      <utterance>I think I left something at the hospital.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you have done this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand what he set in motion? He's taken us to the brink of war!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But banishment? You would lose him forever? He's your son!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 43.</context>
      <utterance>What would you have done?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would not have exiled him to a world of mortals, stripped of his powers, to suffer alone. I would not have had the heart for such cruelty!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is why I'm King.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, too, grieve the loss of our son. But there are some things that even I cannot undo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can bring him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. His fate is in his own hands now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, only relatives can visit patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>THINKING FAST</mode>
      <context>Darcy stifles a SNICKER at this, as the Nurse looks doubtful.</context>
      <utterance>But... I'm his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 43A.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you didn't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant I barely know him anymore. The man he's become. He's changed. I mean, what woman really knows her husband, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMISSIONS NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of us, dear. He's in Room</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>51 INT. JANE'S SUV 51</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane starts the car, frustrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typical. I just lost my most important piece of evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see what he did in there? I don't know if finding him is the best idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know what that thing was, and he may have the answers. We don't have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out her taser and a can of mace.</context>
      <utterance>Oo-kay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we're just going to spend the rest of the day looking for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane puts the car in reverse and backs up, when --</context>
      <utterance>However long it takes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks up at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry. I swear I'm not doing that on purpose. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 45.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blue sky... one sun... This is Earth, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you may have hit him with the car one time too many.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>TO THOR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get you some clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should never have let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was no stopping him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least he's only banished, not dead. Which is what we'd all be if that guard hadn't told Odin where we'd gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki stares at his arm.</context>
      <utterance>How did the guard even know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 45A.</context>
      <utterance>I told him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 46.</context>
      <utterance>I told him to go to Odin after we'd left. Though he should be flogged for taking so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told the guard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saved our lives! And Thor's. I had no idea Father would banish him for what he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loki, you're the only one who can help Thor now. You must go to the Allfather and convince him to change his mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others exchange glances, torn. Loki has a point. He leaves the room. Hogun stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>And if I do, then what? I love Thor more dearly than any of you, but you know what he is. He's arrogant. He's reckless. He's dangerous. You saw how he was today. Is that what Asgard needs from its King?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He may speak about the good of Asgard, but he's always been jealous of Thor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True, but we should be grateful to him. He did save our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others turn to the usually quiet Hogun.</context>
      <utterance>Laufey said there were traitors in the House of Odin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it every time you choose to speak, it has to be something dark and ominous?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look to Hogun, understanding the implication.</context>
      <utterance>A master of magic could easily bring three Jotuns into Asgard.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 46A.</context>
      <utterance>No! Surely not!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 47.</context>
      <utterance>Loki's always been one for mischief, but you're talking about something else entirely.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else could elude Heimdall's gaze with tricks of light and shadow?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ceremony was interrupted just before Thor was named King.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go to the Allfather.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell him what? "Oh, by the way, we think your son just betrayed the throne. And do us a favor. Bring back Thor. There's a good fellow!"</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's our duty. If any of our suspicions are right, then all of Asgard is in danger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Loki turns, sees Odin hurrying into the room, the Destroyer goes motionless, the latticework rejoining before it. Odin eyes Loki with dismay.</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I cursed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki sets the Casket back upon its pedestal, his body quickly returning to its normal form and color. He stares at his father.</context>
      <utterance>No. Put the Casket down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin doesn't answer. He looks suddenly weary, burdened. Loki sizes him up, realizes the truth.</context>
      <utterance>What more than that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Odin looks him in the eye. He can deny it no longer.</context>
      <utterance>The Casket wasn't the only thing you took from Jotunheim that day, was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Loki is sent reeling by the revelation.</context>
      <utterance>In the aftermath of the battle, I went into the Temple, and I found a baby. Small for a giant's offspring -- abandoned, suffering, left to die. Laufey's son.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He desperately struggles to make sense of it all. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 48A.</context>
      <utterance>Laufey's son...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You were knee-deep in Jotun blood. Why would you take me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were an innocent child.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>You took me for a purpose, what was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we could unite our kingdoms one day, bring about an alliance, bring about a permanent peace... through you. But those plans no longer matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I am no more than another stolen relic, locked up here until you might have use of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you twist my words?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have told me what I was from the beginning. Why didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are my son. My blood. I wanted only to protect you from the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I am the monster parents tell their children about at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It all makes sense now. Why you favored Thor all these years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 48B.</context>
      <utterance>Listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin's body begins to shake, he lifts his hand. It starts to move out of synch temporarily, leaving a trail, the effect of the Odinsleep approaching. Loki doesn't notice as Odin tries to fight it off.</context>
      <utterance>Because no matter how much you claim to "love" me, you could never have a Frost Giant sitting on the Throne of Asgard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki strides away towards the exit.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Odin starts towards him, when the enormous mental, emotional, and physical strain of recent events finally takes its toll. The effect of the Odinsleep consumes him. His entire body now moves out of sync with the rest of the world, leaving trails behind him as he staggers backwards. Odin falls back against a wall, his face contorting in a scream. He collapses to the stone floor. Loki, shocked, hurries to him. He takes Odin in his arms, calls out.</context>
      <utterance>Loki!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guards!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EAGER TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He yells to the driver.</context>
      <utterance>This'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EAGER TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The townsfolk watch as the pick-up's engine ROARS, then STRAINS, its wheels spinning futilely, until finally the rear of the truck, along with the back wheels and axles, break off and go flying. People dive out of the way. The PICK-UP DRIVER sticks his head out. He is STAN "THE MAN" LEE. He looks back, shocked. The townsfolk laugh, the party continuing. They don't notice as --</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let 'er rip!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane turns away. Thor emerges from the back room, holding a t-shirt.</context>
      <utterance>You know, for a crazy homeless guy, he's pretty cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor heads over to Jane's work area, starts fiddling with the equipment there with interest. Jane hurries over to put a stop to it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, sorry I tased you!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads him away from the work station. Thor holds up the t-shirt. On the front, it bear a sticker which reads: "HELLO, MY NAME IS DR. DONALD BLAKE". Thor looks at it, puzzled. Jane rips the sticker off. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 52.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me... excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor stares at her a beat.</context>
      <utterance>My ex.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're the only clothes I had that'll fit you. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor turns his attention to the pictures of the Bifrost on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>They will suffice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor studies the frame-grabs with interest. Jane points to his form in the Bifrost photo.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. Now tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He glances at it, dismissive.</context>
      <utterance>What were you doing, in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone stares at him. Selvig seems to recognize the word. Jane opens her notebook, quickly writes the word down. Thor moves close to her, eyes the notations and drawings within the book, curious.</context>
      <utterance>What does anyone do in the Bifrost?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane starts to get uncomfortable with Thor standing so close to her, looking over her notations. She quickly closes the book.</context>
      <utterance>The Bifrost...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly is the Bifrost?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>IGNORING HER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This mortal form has grown weak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked him to be honest with you from the beginning. There should be no secrets in a family.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why did he lie?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki takes this in, stares at Odin.</context>
      <utterance>He kept the truth from you so that you would never feel different. You are in every way our son, Loki, and we your family. You must know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - RE: ODIN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can speak to him. He can see and hear us, even now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 53.</context>
      <utterance>How long will it last?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. This time is different. We were unprepared.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never get used to seeing him like this. The most powerful being in the Nine Realms lying helpless until his body is restored.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki takes her hand. She's grateful, wipes tears from her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>But he's put it off for so long now, I fear...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki sits there, uncertain how to react, uncertain how he really feels.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good son.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki looks to Frigga, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>We mustn't lose hope that your father will return to us. And your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What hope is there for Thor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki looks troubled by the revelation. He rises, heads for the exit, when they hear the clatter of ARMORED FOOTSTEPS hurriedly approaching.</context>
      <utterance>There's always a purpose to everything your father does. Thor may yet find a way home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Einherjar kneel before the shocked Loki. Another EINHERJAR enters, holding Gungnir before him. He kneels before Loki, offers the spear to him.</context>
      <utterance>Thor is banished. The line of succession falls to you. Until he awakens, Asgard is yours. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 53A.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki reaches out tentatively, then takes it. He likes the feel of it in his hand. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 54.</context>
      <utterance>Make your father proud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks her in the eyes, staring, intrigued. Jane gets flustered, looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Now tell us exactly what happened to you last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe start with how you got inside that cloud.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane shoots her a withering look. Thor downs a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>And how you could eat an entire box of Pop-Tarts and still be this hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This drink. I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor hurls the empty mug at the ground, SHATTERING it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's great, isn't it? Isabela makes the best coffee in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CALLS OUT</mode>
      <context>ISABELA ALVAREZ (60), the diner's proprietor, glares at Thor from behind the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Another!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Izzy. Little accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>IN SPANISH</mode>
      <context>Isabela turns to a WAITRESS and starts venting quickly in Spanish. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 54A.</context>
      <utterance>Yo voy a pagar la taza.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELA</speaker>
      <mode>IN SPANISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that? The first time she brings a man in here, and he's a lunatic!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't understand. The other patrons stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was delicious. I want another.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you should just say so!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just did.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean ask for it. Nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant no disrespect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, then no more smashing, deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 55. A few TOWNIES, looking bedraggled, enter and take a seat at the counter. We recognize them from the crater. (Among them is the Drunk Townie Jake, who is not presently drunk.)</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Pete. Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNIE PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabela pours them a couple cups of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>The usual, please, Izzy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You missed all the excitement out at the crater.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane and Selvig overhear this, exchange a look, turn to the Townies with interest.</context>
      <utterance>What crater?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNIE PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're saying some kind of satellite crashed in the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were having a good time with it till the Feds showed up, chased us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, did you say there was a satellite crash?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And I had my hands all over it.</context>
      <utterance>Yep. They said it was radioactive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE JAKE</speaker>
      <mode>REALIZING</mode>
      <context>Thor, unconcerned, prepares to dig into the giant pile of pancakes. Darcy is amazed by the sight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm probably sterile now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy whips out her cellphone.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, this is going on Facebook.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - TO THOR</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 55A. Thor looks puzzled as she SNAPS a photo of him and his massive stack of food.</context>
      <utterance>Smile!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did the satellite look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor springs to his feet, heads over to Drunk Townie Jake, and pulls the Townie around to face him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothing about satellites. But it was heavy. Real heavy. Nobody could lift it. This gets Thor's attention. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 56.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor grins, his spirits soaring, as he quickly strides out of the diner.</context>
      <utterance>About twelve miles east of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't bother! Looked like the whole Army was coming in when we left!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to stride determinedly down the street. Jane walks with him.</context>
      <utterance>Twelve miles east of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To get what belongs to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now you own a satellite?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not what they say it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever it is, the government seems to think it's theirs. You intend to just walk in there and take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 57.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. He stops walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you take me there now, I'll tell you everything you wish to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy looks to the others.</context>
      <utterance>All the answers you seek will be yours, once I reclaim Mjolnir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane studies Thor. He looks sincere. She's nearly swayed,</context>
      <utterance>"Myeu-muh?" What's "Myeu-muh?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her aside. Thor can tell that Selvig doesn't much care for him.</context>
      <utterance>Jane.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - TO JANE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what we saw last night. This can't be a coincidence. I want to know what's in that crater.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm talking about him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about the crater.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's promised us answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's delusional! Listen to what he's saying! "Thor." "Bifrost." "Mjolnir." These are the stories I grew up with as a child!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just be driving him out there, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, she nods. They head back over to Thor and Darcy.</context>
      <utterance>It's dangerous. He's dangerous. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 58.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I can't take you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand and kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>I understand. Then this is where we say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor bows slightly to each of them.</context>
      <utterance>That's... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads off down the street. Selvig looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Jane Foster... Erik Selvig... Darcy. Farewell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig and Darcy turn and start to go. Jane looks after Thor as he walks away down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Now... let's get back to the lab. We have work to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friends... you haven't heard? I am now Ruler of Asgard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Odin?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father's fallen into the Odinsleep. My mother fears he may never awaken again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif and the Warriors Three exchange a look. Loki notices.</context>
      <utterance>We would speak with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif covers quickly.</context>
      <utterance>She has refused to leave my father's bedside. You can bring your "urgent" matter to me, your King.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 60.</context>
      <utterance>We would ask you to end Thor's banishment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif and the Warriors Three trade looks, not liking any of this.</context>
      <utterance>My first command can not be to undo the Allfather's last. We're on the brink of war with Jotunheim. Our people must have a sense of continuity in order to feel safe in these difficult times.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of us must stand together, for the good of Asgard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif and the Warriors Three bow their heads and exit. Loki stares after them.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agents ignore her as Agent Coulson approaches.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Foster, I'm Agent Coulson, with</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care who you work for, you can't do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane. This is more serious than you realize. Let it go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it go?! This is my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here investigating a security threat. We need to appropriate your equipment and all your atmospheric data.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instead of answering, Coulson gives her a check.</context>
      <utterance>By "appropriate" you mean "steal?"</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws the check to the ground without looking at it.</context>
      <utterance>This should more than compensate you for your trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't just pick up replacements from RadioShack! I made most of that equipment myself!</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'm sure you can do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 61.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm sure I can sue you for violating my constitutional rights!</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to walk away, but Jane blocks his path. She is fully herself, fueled by outrage.</context>
      <utterance>We're the good guys, Ms. Foster.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are we! We're on the verge of</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSTANDING SOMETHING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane holds up her notebook.</context>
      <utterance>extraordinary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Coulson gestures to a nearby AGENT, who promptly plucks the notebook out of Jane's hands and adds it to the pile he's carrying. Jane is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Everything I know about this phenomenon is in this lab and in this book, and no one has the right to take it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets into a car. The cars and trucks pull away.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for your cooperation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 62.</context>
      <utterance>Years of research, gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They even took my iPod.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your back-ups?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look around! They took our back- ups. They took the back-ups of our back-ups.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just downloaded, like, thirty songs on there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>TO DARCY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you please stop talking about your iPod?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one knows much about them. But I knew a scientist -- a pioneer in gamma radiation. SHIELD showed up, and he was never heard from again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm getting everything back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to let them do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, let me contact one of my colleagues. Dr. Pym has had some dealings with these people. I'll e- mail him and see if he can help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annoyed, Selvig thinks.</context>
      <utterance>They took your laptop, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>PET STORE CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, we don't sell horses. Just dogs, cats, birds.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Thor hears a CAR HORN. He turns to the open door. Across the street, Jane calls to him from the Pinzgauer. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 63.</context>
      <utterance>Then give me one of those, large enough to ride. The Pet Store Clerk looks confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still want a lift?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks amused by her excitement.</context>
      <utterance>I've never done anything like this before! Have you ever done anything like this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Many times. You're brave to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They just stole my entire life's work. I really don't have anything left to lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're clever. Far more clever than anyone else in this Realm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"This Realm?" Why do you talk like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane laughs, catches herself.</context>
      <utterance>You think me strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Just a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good strange or bad strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, sees him staring at her. She's lost in his gaze, distracted, when the PINZGAUER LURCHES. She quickly turns her eyes forward, regains control of the car.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not quite sure yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She glances back at him. He's confident, determined.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll see soon enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks at her, charmed by her persistence.</context>
      <utterance>You promised me answers. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 63B.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you seek -- it's a bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bridge? Like an Einstein-Rosen Bridge?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>More like a rainbow bridge. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 64.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I hope you're not crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor shrugs out of his jacket and hands it to her.</context>
      <utterance>That isn't a satellite crash. They would have hauled the wreckage away, not built a city around it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to need this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thunder RUMBLES overhead. She stares at him intently and takes his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Why?--</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to her, already knowing that Jane may disobey his request.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here. Once I have Mjolnir, I will return what they stole from you. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 64A.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Look what's down there! You can't just walk in, grab our stuff, and walk out!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before she can react, he starts heading towards the crater. The first drops of rain begin to patter into the dust. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 65.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to fly out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Thor is already headed towards the crater.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Techie hikes a thumb at another monitor, SQUELCHING with static. It shows an SAR shot of the area, laid over a terrain map.</context>
      <utterance>Feed from the keyhole. Can barely penetrate the cloud cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He gestures towards the hammer. He checks a computer.</context>
      <utterance>Tech's barely working as it is, with all the interference that thing's giving off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we've got a commercial aircraft coming in right over us, Southwest Airlines Flight 5434.</utterance>
   <speaker>SITWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reroute it, like all the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 65A.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Can I get the passengers some free drinks for the trouble? Sitwell glares at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SHRUGS</mode>
      <context>The Techie types into the computer, when he notices something on another screen, holds up a hand.</context>
      <utterance>It'd be a nice gesture.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points at the screen. Through the haze, it shows a THERMAL IMAGE huddled beside the fence.</context>
      <utterance>Hold a sec... we got something outside the fence, west side...</utterance>
   <speaker>SITWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeLancey, Jackson -- check it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>V.O., ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>His voicemail BEEPS. She talks quietly, urgently.</context>
      <utterance>You've reached Dr. Erik Selvig. Please leave me a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More sounds of MAYHEM come from the base.</context>
      <utterance>Erik, okay, first of all, don't worry. I'm perfectly fine, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>But if you don't hear from me again, you might want to come out to the crater site and look for me. I kind of did what you said I shouldn't do. Thanks. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor grins.</context>
      <utterance>You're big.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fought bigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 70.</context>
      <utterance>I can't just leave him there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darcy points at an illustration of Thor's hammer in the book.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't see what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane looks at the illustration in the book, turns to Selvig knowingly.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Myeu-muh!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>RE: BOOK</mode>
      <context>Selvig grabs the book from them, quickly closes it.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you find this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane is unconvinced by this. She knows he wants to believe.</context>
      <utterance>In the children's section. I wanted to show you how ridiculous his story was.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the one who's always told me to chase down all leads, all possibilities?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking about science, not magic!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magic's just science we don't understand yet. Arthur C. Clarke.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wrote science fiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The precursor of science fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In some cases.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's really an Einstein-Rosen Bridge out there, then there's something on the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 70A.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Advanced beings could have come through it before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They give her a look, surprised by her unexpectedly insightful input. Darcy shrugs. Jane points at her, grateful for the support.</context>
      <utterance>A primitive culture like the Vikings might have worshipped them as deities.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 71.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Exactly! Thank you! Darcy beams.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane, if you do this, you'll find yourself in a situation that I won't be able to get you out of this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane looks grateful. Selvig looks at her, sees there's no stopping her. He sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not easy to do what you did. You made us all look like a bunch of mall cops. That's hurtful.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Thor sits silently.</context>
      <utterance>The men you so easily subdued are highly-trained professionals, and in my experience, it takes someone who's received similar training to do what you did to them. Would you like to tell me where you received your training?</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Still no answer. Coulson leans in close to him.</context>
      <utterance>Pakistan? Chechnya? Afghanistan? Then again, you strike me more as the soldier of fortune type. What was it, South Africa?</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certain groups pay well for a good mercenary. Especially HYDRA. Coulson waits for a response, but gets none.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 72.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coulson leaves the room. Thor lowers his head.</context>
      <utterance>One way or another, we find out what we want to know. We're good at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Thor looks up, shocked to find Loki standing there, dressed in 21st century attire.</context>
      <utterance>I thought he'd never leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loki? What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happened? Tell me! Is it Jotunheim? Let me explain to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor stares at him, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Father is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The implications of Loki's words dawn on Thor -- he's responsible for his father's fate. Loki draws close to him, looks in his eyes, consolingly.</context>
      <utterance>Your banishment, the threat of a new war, it was too much for him to bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mustn't blame yourself. I know that you loved him. I tried to tell him so, but he wouldn't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 73.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - THEN</mode>
      <context>Thor stares ahead, falling deeper into the abyss.</context>
      <utterance>It was cruel to put the hammer within your reach, knowing you could never lift it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The burden of the throne has fallen to me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come home?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truce with Jotunheim is conditional upon your exile.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But couldn't we find a way to--</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor nods, lowers his head, beaten.</context>
      <utterance>Mother has forbidden your return.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is goodbye, brother. I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sorry. Loki... thank you for coming here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coulson enters the room, but seems to take no notice of Loki.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing could have stopped me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fare well, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks up to see that Loki is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Good-bye? I just got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 73A.</context>
      <utterance>Now. Where did we leave off?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Donald Blake?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Donald Blake. He's part of our team.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig.</context>
      <utterance>You have dangerous coworkers, Dr.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Troubled, not dangerous. He was distraught when he found out that you'd taken all of our research. It was years of his life, gone! He got depressed, started drinking, and... well, you know the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. You mind if we take a moment to verify his identity?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Techie at a computer nearby runs the name.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can understand how a man could go off like that. I mean, a big, faceless organization like yours, coming in with their jack-booted thugs and stealing private property...</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...is how he described it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>That doesn't explain how he managed to tear through our security.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the Techie's monitor, a DMV record from the State of New York pops up reading "DR. DONALD BLAKE". The license photo is indeed a picture of Thor -- the one Darcy took with her cellphone. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 75. The Techie hits a button, and a graphic reads, "SHIELD SECURITY ANALYSIS IN PROGRESS." Coulson eyes the screen. After a beat, he turns back to Selvig.</context>
      <utterance>Steroids. He's a bit of a fitness nut. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 74A.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says here he's an M.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is. That is, he was. He switched careers and became a physicist. He's quite brilliant, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Coulson thinks, sizing Selvig up -- then smiles. He turns to an AGENT nearby.</context>
      <utterance>If you would just release him to me, I promise to keep an eye on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Techie looks to him, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Release Dr. Blake to Dr. Selvig here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - TO SELVIG</mode>
      <context>Selvig shakes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure he stays in town for the next few days in case we need to talk to him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks up, unsure what the hell is going on. Selvig pulls Thor to his feet, gives him a warm hug.</context>
      <utterance>Donny, Donny, Donny! There you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He leads the bewildered Thor out the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be all right, my friend. Come on, I'm taking you home. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 75A.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep him away from the bars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>TO SELVIG</mode>
      <context>Selvig drops his cool demeanor.</context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig and Thor climb into the SUV. As they drive off, Coulson turns to the other two agents -- GARRETT and CALE.</context>
      <utterance>To get a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 76.</context>
      <utterance>Follow them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me why I shouldn't kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've come alone and unarmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To what end?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To make you another proposition.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode>REALIZING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're the one who let us into Asgard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laufey lashes out, grabs Loki around the throat, but Loki calmly stands his ground.</context>
      <utterance>My men are dead, and I have no Casket. You are a deceiver.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blueness spreads across his face, as Laufey and the guards stare in shock. Loki grins.</context>
      <utterance>You have no idea what I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Laufey releases him. Loki's body turns back to normal. Intrigued, Laufey sizes up his son. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 76A.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the bastard son. I thought Odin had killed you. That's what I would have done. He's as weak as you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This gives Laufey pause.</context>
      <utterance>No longer weak. I now rule Asgard, until Odin awakens. Perhaps you should not have so carelessly abandoned me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 77.</context>
      <utterance>Or perhaps it was the wisest choice I've ever made. I will hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laufey studies Loki's face.</context>
      <utterance>I will conceal you and a handful of your soldiers, lead you into his chambers, and let you slay him where he lies. I'll keep the throne, and you will have the Casket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When all is done, we will have a permanent peace between our two worlds. Then I, the bastard son, will have accomplished what Odin and Thor never could.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asgard is finally ours.</context>
      <utterance>This is a great day for Jotunheim.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laufey considers the proposition.</context>
      <utterance>No. Asgard is mine. The rest of the Nine Realms will be yours, if you do as you're told.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUFEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki turns to leave. As he goes, the slightest trace of a smile crosses his face.</context>
      <utterance>I accept.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 78.</context>
      <utterance>What troubles you, Gatekeeper?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I turned my gaze upon you in Jotunheim, but could neither see nor hear you. You were shrouded from me, like the Frost Giants who entered this Realm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps your senses have weakened after your many years of service.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki sizes him up, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Or perhaps someone has found a way to hide that which he does not wish me to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tell me, did Odin ever fear you?</context>
      <utterance>You have great power, Heimdall.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he is my King, and I am sworn to obey him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Just as you're sworn to obey me now. Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki heads out of the Observatory. Heimdall stares after him. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 78A.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Then you will open the Bifrost to no one until I have undone what my brother has started.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems Darcy's a terrible intern, but a talented hacker.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for what you've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't thank me. I only did it for Jane.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in love with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This registers with Thor.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not! Jane's like a daughter to me. Her father and I taught at University together. A good man, but he never listened.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig eyes him with interest.</context>
      <utterance>Neither did I.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you're really delusional, and I really don't care at this point. I just care about her. I've seen the way she looks at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to you, I mean her no harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause, then Thor nods. He takes a drink. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 80.</context>
      <utterance>Good. If that's the case, then I'll buy you one more drink, and you'll leave town tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig watches him keenly. This is a different Thor than he's seen before.</context>
      <utterance>I had it all backwards. I had it all wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a bad thing, finding out that you don't have all the answers. That's when you start asking the right questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the first time in my life, I have no idea what I'm supposed to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor nods.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone who's ever going to find their way in this world has to start by admitting they don't know where the hell they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>An intimidating DRUNK TOWNIE nearby sizes up Thor. He is one of the Townies from Isabela's Diner who saw Thor earlier. He approaches, belligerent and looking for a fight.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I know you, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor doesn't like where this is going.</context>
      <utterance>You were in the diner with that hot girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He laughs. Thor is annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't mind her doing a little research on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 80A.</context>
      <utterance>I have no quarrel with you. But she's a lady. You should be more respectful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig looks to Thor, concerned that he's going to lose it. But, to his surprise, Thor remains unaffected by the Townie's baiting.</context>
      <utterance>And you should shut the hell up, princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not fight him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it'll be easy to kick your ass. Selvig stands, steps between the two men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Selvig HEAD-BUTTS the Townie, knocking him out. Thor's impressed. Selvig downs his drink, then hurls his glass aside, SHATTERING it on the ground. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 81.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, please. Let's keep our heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - TO THOR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erik!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>TO THOR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Thor enters, he BANGS Selvig's head on the doorway. Selvig GROANS.</context>
      <utterance>He's fine. Not injured at all. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 81A.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 82.</context>
      <utterance>We drank. We fought. He made his ancestors proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor moves through the small trailer carrying Selvig, like a bear lugging another bear, smashing into things along the way, until he finally sets Selvig down on Jane's bed. Selvig awakens groggily and looks up at him through bleary eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Put him on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't believe you're the God of Thunder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Thor grins, pats him on the cheek. As Selvig drifts off to sleep, Thor pulls a blanket over him. Jane watches, stunned by their friendship, impressed by Thor's tenderness. Thor turns back to her, looks around.</context>
      <utterance>But you ought to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane suddenly becomes self-conscious. She starts cleaning up the mess around her.</context>
      <utterance>These are your chambers?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor picks up a sock off the floor. She snatches it from him, puts it away.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's more of a temporary living space, really. I don't usually have visitors in here. Actually, never...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we go outside?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come up here sometimes when I can't sleep. Or when I'm trying to reconcile particle data. Or when Darcy's driving me crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Thor looks at the night sky, filled with stars. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 82A.</context>
      <utterance>I come up here a lot, now that I think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you're safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been very kind. I've been far less grateful than you deserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins, then reaches into his pocket and pulls out her</context>
      <utterance>I also hit you with my car a couple times, so it kind of evens out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She takes it from him, surprised and grateful.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was all I could get back. Not as much as I promised. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down and opens the notebook eagerly, then stops, a harsh realization clouding her face. Thor notices.</context>
      <utterance>No, this is good. Thank you. This means I don't have to start from scratch...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHIELD, whatever they are. They're never going to let this research see the light of day.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must do this. You must finish what you've started.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor moves beside her, opens her notebook, turns to the page which bears a sketch of the Bifrost. He takes the pen from the notebook, begins to add to the sketch, leading from one point to another in space.</context>
      <utterance>Because you're right. It's taken so many generations for your people to get to this point. You're nearly there. You just need someone to show you how close you really are. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 83.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We recognize that Thor is drawing the branches of Yggdrasil as she looks on, amazed and intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- your ancestors called it magic. You call it science. I come from a place where they're one and the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is how my father explained it to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>They look at each other. She nods. They smile. This is going to be a long night.</context>
      <utterance>Your world is one of the Nine Realms of the Cosmos, linked to each other by the branches of Yggdrasil, the Worlds Tree. Now, you see it every day, without realizing. Images glimpsed through -- what did you call it?...  ...this Hubble Telescope. So, Nine Realms...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fandral moves to throw the platter in the fire, but Volstagg pulls his weapon, stopping him.</context>
      <utterance>Our dearest friend banished, Loki on the throne, Asgard on the brink of war, yet you manage to consume four wild boar, six pheasant, a side of beef, and two casks of ale. Shame on you! Don't you care?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do not mistake my appetite for apathy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it, both of you! We all know what we have to do, we're just too damned afraid to do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode>DECIDES</mode>
      <context>Hogun starts to pull the delicate HEALING STONES from the fire, carefully putting them into a POUCH at his side.</context>
      <utterance>We must go. We must find Thor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's treason, Hogun.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hell with treason, it's suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>SUDDENLY NERVOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, shh! Heimdall may be watching! It's said he can hear--</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, we know!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An EINHERJAR GUARD enters. They tense.</context>
      <utterance>Thor would do the same for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>EINHERJAR GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg quickly drains his flagon of ale.</context>
      <utterance>Heimdall demands your presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 84A.</context>
      <utterance>We're doomed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane joins them at the card table with a couple more plates. She and Thor sit with the others and start to eat their breakfast, looking like a little family.</context>
      <utterance>You're very welcome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want an update.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT CALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them he's eating eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cale glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Scrambled or fried?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT CALE</speaker>
      <mode>INTO COMM-LINK</mode>
      <context>We'll keep you posted.</context>
      <utterance>Target is eating eggs, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>RE: MUG</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Excuse me a moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it, looks at it curiously, then smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>To replace the one I broke. Please forgive my behavior. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 86A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I may, I'd like to come back for more of your "coffee."</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and walks away. She stares after him, smiling, and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She could do worse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Heimdall, less us explain--</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four exchange nervous glances.</context>
      <utterance>You would defy the commands of Loki our King, break every oath you have taken as warriors, and commit treason to bring Thor back?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but--</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group looks puzzled. What did he just say?</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you'll help us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Heimdall leaves them alone in the Observatory. The others exchange puzzled looks. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 86B.</context>
      <utterance>I am bound by honor to our King. I cannot open the Bifrost to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Complicated fellow, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sif glances at the control panel, notices something.</context>
      <utterance>Now what do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others turn to see HEIMDALL'S SWORD stuck into the control panel. They exchange a grin. They have an ally. Sif hits the controls, and the Bifrost apparatus fires up.</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 87.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fifteen miles due northwest.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir. We got massive energy readings out of nowhere, then they just disappeared.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go take a look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must have landed nearby. It's time to put our tracking skills to work. Spread out. Check the sand for indentations of his boot prints.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The winds would have blown them away by now. We should look for signs of a campfire.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points behind them to the town of Puente Antiguo in the distance -- the only visible sign of civilization -- and to Hogun, who has already started walking towards it. Volstagg and Fandral trade looks, their egos bruised.</context>
      <utterance>Or we could just start there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The party tromps towards the town.</context>
      <utterance>It's worth a look, I suppose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy just stares, standing frozen. The Asgardians head off.</context>
      <utterance>There you go, lad!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it just me, or does Earth look a little different to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has been a thousand years...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Volstagg sniffs, smells something.</context>
      <utterance>Things change so fast here. You leave for a millennium, and it's like the whole neighborhood's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we should split up.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT GARRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a Renaissance Faire in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT CALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before they can, Volstagg rises up behind them, smashes their heads together. They're out.</context>
      <utterance>Call it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to go, then sees their bag of fast food on the ground. Intrigued, he pulls out a cheeseburger and takes a bite. He likes what he tastes.</context>
      <utterance>Never cared for spies.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exquisite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EINHERJAR GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki reacts. He knows who's responsible.</context>
      <utterance>My liege, the Warriors Three and the Lady Sif have gone missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Loki, how did you get the Jotuns into Asgard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think the Bifrost is the only way in and out of the Realm? There are secret paths between worlds to which even you with all your gifts are blind. But I have need of them no longer, now that I am King.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 90.</context>
      <utterance>And I say, for your act of treason, you are relieved of your duties as Gatekeeper. And you are no longer a citizen of Asgard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heimdall raises his massive sword, strides towards Loki. Loki reaches out and, with both hands, takes hold of something invisible, hovering in mid-air before him. As it quickly fades into view, we realize what it is --</context>
      <utterance>Then I need no longer obey you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor happily races over and greets his comrades. Jane, Selvig, and Darcy watch the Asgardians from across the room. Jane looks concerned. Selvig and Darcy eye them with wonder.</context>
      <utterance>My friends!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 91.</context>
      <utterance>Who are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Selvig looks pointedly at Volstagg's massive gut.</context>
      <utterance>Lady Sif and the Warriors Three. Surely you've heard tales of Hogun the Grim, Fandral the Dashing, and I, Volstagg the Svelte?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, perhaps I've put on a little more muscle since I was here last.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would have been a thousand years ago? Northern Europe?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor grins, lays a hand on Volstagg's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly! Those lovely herring people. They worshipped us!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friends, I've never been happier to see anyone. But you should not have come.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane reacts to the news of Thor leaving.</context>
      <utterance>We're here to take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I can't. My father is dead because of me. I must remain in exile. The other Asgardians exchange puzzled looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor reacts to the revelation.</context>
      <utterance>Thor... your father still lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHIELD AGENT</speaker>
      <mode>RE: DESTROYER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that one of Stark's?</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coulson grabs a megaphone, steps forward, calls out to the Destroyer.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. But the guy doesn't tell me anything. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 93.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We hear the HUM of the Destroyer's fiery energy power up inside.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! You're using unregistered weapons technology. Please identify yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As the SHIELD Agents scramble for cover, a blast of energy from the Destroyer EXPLODES a vehicle. SHIELD agents return fire.</context>
      <utterance>Incoming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave this town now. Get yourself and your friends to safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Asgardians look to Thor.</context>
      <utterance>I must stay and fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still a warrior, and I will fight by your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're but a mortal now. You'll get yourself killed!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 94.</context>
      <utterance>Or one of us, trying to protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks at the townsfolk around them, all oblivious to the oncoming threat.</context>
      <utterance>The best thing you can do is get the mortals to safety and leave the battle to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>TO SIF</mode>
      <context>Sif looks surprised. Thor turns to Jane, Selvig, and Darcy.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor, Jane, Selvig, and Darcy start to herd the crowd of Townsfolk off the streets, as the Warriors Three and Sif head across town, towards the Destroyer.</context>
      <utterance>Help me clear the streets. I'll let none of these people die this day.</utterance>
   <speaker>124 OMITTED 124</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 95.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries off. The Warriors Three continue towards the behemoth.</context>
      <utterance>Keep him distracted.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think? "The Svartalfheim Twist?" "Kiss of the Hag?" "Face Full of Boot?" Volstagg grins eagerly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Flying Mountain." Hogun and Fandral groan.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not "The Flying Mountain!" It threw out my back for a year last time!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, it'll work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>TO VOLSTAGG</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 96A. Volstagg takes off running at full speed. As he catches up to his comrades, Hogun and Fandral grab him on either side, and with all their Asgardian might, hurl the voluminous warrior into the air at the black metal behemoth.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 97. The Destroyer is unable to react quickly enough, as Volstagg SMASHES into the creature. It looks like it might actually work for a moment, but the Destroyer stays on its feet. It lifts Volstagg into the by the scruff of his neck. He shrugs apologetically. The Destroyer savagely HURLS him at Hogun and Fandral, smashing into them, when --</context>
      <utterance>For Asgaaaaard!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She and Thor hurry to his side. He's losing blood, going into shock.</context>
      <utterance>Erik!</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode>TO JANE</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 98. Jane takes his hand as Thor spots Hogun's pouch of healing stones lying in the middle of the street. He makes a break for it, dodging through the flaming wreckage, then grabs the pouch and races back. He opens the pouch to find the fragile stones crushed and useless. He pours the contents out in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Leave me!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amidst the useless powder, he finally finds one stone still intact. Thor tosses the pouch aside, holds the stone over the end of the iron rod.</context>
      <utterance>Come on... give me one!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the stone begins to glow, Thor crushes it. Jane looks on, amazed, as the glowing powder falls upon the piece of iron, dissolving it, heading downwards, until it reaches Selvig's wound. The powder heals his wound completely. Thor looks down the street, sees his wounded friends still lying there, as Selvig sits up in utter astonishment. He reaches through the hole in his shirt to touch his healed flesh.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane turns to Thor to find he's gone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really starting to like him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go, while you can!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the others...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 98A.</context>
      <utterance>You can't help them now. Your job is to survive. She struggles to sit up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I will die a warrior's death. Stories will be told of this day-- He gently takes her shield from her.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At last, she nods. Thor spots Volstagg lying unconscious, with Hogun and Fandral lying nearby. Thor makes his way towards them. Volstagg is barely breathing. Thor tries to pull him to safety, but it's no use. He won't budge. He rouses Hogun and Fandral.</context>
      <utterance>Live and tell those stories yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - RE: VOLSTAGG</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We can still fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor looks at them, grins.</context>
      <utterance>But not win. Move Volstagg, or he'll die!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The two Warriors reluctantly grab their fallen friend and drag him away from the battlefield. After they go, Thor turns to back to the Destroyer, then tosses Sif's shield aside. He strides down the street towards the behemoth, completely defenseless.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, my friends. I have a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 98B.</context>
      <utterance>Brother... for whatever I have done to wrong you, whatever I have done to lead you to do this, I am sorry. But these people have done nothing to you. They are innocents. He continues towards the Destroyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor reaches the Destroyer, extends his arms. The Destroyer hesitates, sizing up the defenseless Thor, then swats him with its enormous arm. We hear the sickening CRACK of breaking bones as Thor goes flying. Thor lands in a crumpled, broken heap in front of Smith Motors, before Jane, Selvig, and Darcy. The wounded Asgardians watch helplessly from down the street, a look of horror on their faces. Jane tries to rush out to Thor's aid, but Selvig holds her back.</context>
      <utterance>Take my life, and know I will never return to Asgard. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 99.</utterance>
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her into Smith Motors. A RAVEN flies overhead, watching the scene --</context>
      <utterance>Jane, no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how can you speak our language?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor calls up to the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Your language? Ha! Silly girl, you're speaking ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heimdall! Open the Bifrost!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He would open it if he could. I fear the worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we're trapped here forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to Darcy, turns on the charm.</context>
      <utterance>Then I suppose we'd best start settling into our new lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Darcy enjoys the attention.</context>
      <utterance>Are all earth maidens as fair as you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor shouts back up to the sky.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heimdall!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the Bifrost EXPLODES down from the sky. Thor grins. The mortals look on, amazed. Fandral turns to Darcy. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 102A.</context>
      <utterance>Primitive. Good enough for hunting small game, I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He joins the other Asgardians at their side. Thor turns to Coulson.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, my love. These things happen. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 103.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know this, son of Coul. You and I, we fight for the same cause -- the protection of this world. From this day forward, count me as your ally.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you return the items you have stolen from Jane Foster.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane shoots him a look. Coulson quickly continues.</context>
      <utterance>Not stolen. Borrowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COULSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor takes Jane's hand, kisses it tenderly. She looks at him, her eyes filled with the fear that she may never see him again.</context>
      <utterance>You'll get your equipment back. You're going to need it to continue your research... which, after today's events, SHIELD would like to fully sponsor. If that's all right with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her in his arms, kisses her passionately. Thor and the Asgardians leap into the Bifrost.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever fate lies before me, you are part of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks to Odin.</context>
      <utterance>I swear to you, mother, they will pay for what they've done today. I will end the Jotun threat, now and forever!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki savors the moment, but it's short-lived, as Thor bursts in. He's thrown by the scene before him -- Odin safe, Laufey and two Jotuns dead, Frigga regarding Loki with pride and respect. Stunned and delighted to see Thor, Frigga beams.</context>
      <utterance>And I will make you proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to Thor and hugs him, but Thor's eyes remain fixed on his brother. Loki looks at Mjolnir in his brother's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Thor!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Found its way back to you, did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frigga picks up on the tension building between her sons.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frigga looks to Loki, alarmed and confused.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell her? How you sent the Destroyer to kill our friends? To kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 106.</context>
      <utterance>It must have been enforcing Father's last command.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Always have been.</context>
      <utterance>You're a talented liar, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good to have you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor hurries to the ice, raises his hammer to SMASH through it to get to the controls frozen within. Before he can, Loki fires Gungnir. The blast hits the ice in front of Thor, blasting him back across the floor. Loki steps down from the ice as Thor staggers to his feet. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 107.</context>
      <utterance>All these years, and no one's ever dared to use it as a weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't stop it. The Bifrost will build until it rips Jotunheim apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why have you done this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To do what Father never could. To destroy their kind forever. When he awakens, he'll see the wisdom of what I've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't! You can't kill an entire race!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this newfound love for the Frost Giants? You, who would have killed them all with your bare hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So have I. Loki hits Thor across the face with Gungnir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He swings Gungnir at Thor again. Thor catches it in his hand, rears back his hammer as if ready to return the blow, but instead takes to the air and flies past Loki, back towards the frozen controls. Loki spins around, aims Gungnir, and fires a blast which immobilizes Thor in the air. He hangs there, suspended.</context>
      <utterance>Fight me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the throne really worth what you've done? What you would become?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a gesture of Gungnir, he flings Thor to the ground. Thor rises to his feet, turns to Loki.</context>
      <utterance>I never wanted the throne. I only wanted to be your equal. Now fight me! 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 108.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not fight you, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not your brother. I never was.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loki grins.</context>
      <utterance>Loki, this is madness...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He FIRES Gungnir at Thor. Thor dodges the blast, rolls to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor doesn't answer. Loki laughs, realizing he's right.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to you on earth that turned you so soft? Don't tell me it was a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>That did it. Loki and Thor rush at each other. They and their weapons collide. The two battle -- Loki unleashing years of pent-up rage and jealousy, Thor having no choice but to defend himself.</context>
      <utterance>It was. Perhaps when we're finished here I'll pay her a little visit myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SELVIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 108A.</context>
      <utterance>Jane?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 109.</context>
      <utterance>Something's wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thor steps over to the side of the Bridge, sees Loki looking up at him desperately.</context>
      <utterance>Thor! Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki's fingers start to slip. Thor reaches down to grab his brother's wrist, but his hand passes through Loki's. Just then, the REAL LOKI materializes behind him. Thor whirls around as Loki STABS him in the chest with Gungnir. Loki lifts Thor into the air, impaled on the spear, and hurls him across the bridge. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 110. Thor, bleeding, rises to his knees. Loki strides up behind him to finish him off, when Thor swing his hammer around. It passes through him. Instantly, another Loki appears next to him, Thor swings his hammer, but that too is an illusion. Loki after Loki appears, Thor futilely swinging at each one, never making contact. Thor falls back to his knees. The Lokis grin as their raises their spears, encircling him.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was always more clever than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Thor raises his hammer, rising into the air, summoning lightning. A massive bolt strikes Mjolnir, then channels outwards, splitting up, striking each one of the Lokis. All of them dissipate into nothingness, save one -- the real Loki -- who's sent flying back across the Bridge, Gungnir knocked from his grasp. Thor steps over to his fallen brother, lying dazed on his back. Loki winces, prepares for the worst, when Thor steps away. Loki opens his eyes, tries to stand, but can't. He looks confused, then sees what the problem is -- Mjolnir rests atop his chest. Struggle as he may, Loki can't lift it off. He's pinned to the ground. Thor looks about him desperately -- at the Bifrost firing towards Jotunheim, gaining in strength, at the surge of energy moving through the Bridge. He's at a loss of what to do. Loki watches him smugly.</context>
      <utterance>Yet still not clever enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With all your strength, what good does it do you now? Thor knows Loki's right. He's powerless to stop what's happening. He looks down at the Bridge beneath his feet, VIBRATING from the force and speed of the Bifrost energy feeding into the Observatory. Then he gets an idea. He realizes what he must do -- and what he must sacrifice. Thor extends his hand towards Loki, summoning Mjolnir. The hammer goes flying to his grasp. Loki looks confused. 4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 111. Thor raises Mjolnir in the air. Clouds form above him, thunder RUMBLING. Lightning arcs off of his hammer, as he channels the power of the storm into it, then -- He strikes Mjolnir down upon the Rainbow Bridge. The blow is massive, causing a rumbling along the whole bridge, shaking the Observatory itself like an earthquake. A crack appears where the blow struck. Loki rises to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Look at you, the Mighty Thor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Thor lifts the hammer again, brings it down harder. BOOM! The crack grows bigger. The Bifrost energy starts to stream out from it. Loki thinks fast.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOKI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Loki grabs Gungnir, runs towards him, ready to pierce Thor through the back.</context>
      <utterance>If you destroy the Bridge, you'll never see her again!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Summoning every bit of strength he has left, Thor raises Mjolnir one last time, drawing lightning to it from all sides, and brings it down with a final, terrible blow -- KRAKABOOM! The Bifrost SHATTERS, rainbow energy EXPLODING out of it. Both Loki and Thor are hurled into the air by the force of the blast. A wave of destruction moves forward along the Bridge towards the Observatory, breaking it apart as it goes. The Observatory RIPS ITSELF APART. As Loki and Thor fall together, Thor grabs hold of one end of Gungnir, while Loki still clutches the other. They both fall towards the MASSIVE WAVE of Bifrost energy which spews out from the broken Bridge. They're an instant from being blasted by the destructive force of the energy, carried away by the current, pulverized by the debris, when --</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But it's too late. Odin and Thor can only watch as Loki falls into the rushing torrent of Bifrost energy. It carries him away, along with the debris of the Bridge and the Observatory, disappearing out of sight. Odin pulls Thor up onto the Bridge. Drained, Thor falls back into his father's arms.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 113.</context>
      <utterance>...and then, with a mighty bellow, I flew at the great metal beast and laid it low...</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that another way of saying you fell on your huge a--</utterance>
   <speaker>VOLSTAGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, falling down was a tactic. Lulling the Destroyer into a false sense of security!</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hogun points to Volstagg.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I was the one who had to drag your enormous carcass off the battlefield. That makes me the real hero. Doesn't it, Hogun?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other gathered Asgardians laugh. Volstagg and Fandral look to Hogun. The grim warrior gives just a trace of a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Big stomach.  Big mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANDRAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frigga sits nearby, lost in thought, her face betraying the sadness she struggles to conceal. Sif notices, approaches Frigga, bows her head.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how about that? A smile! I'd say that calls for another drink! They laugh and raise another round.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frigga takes Sif's hand appreciatively.</context>
      <utterance>My Queen. I am so sorry for your loss.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to Thor, who's unable to enjoy the merriment around him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Sif.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>4th BLUE REVISIONS 03-26-10 113A.</context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frigga sees the trace of regret in Sif's face as she looks at Thor with new feelings. He rises and leaves the hall.</context>
      <utterance>He mourns for his brother. And he misses her. The mortal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIGGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will need his friends now more than ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frigga understands, puts her arm around Sif gratefully.</context>
      <utterance>I will always be at his side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be a wise King.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will never be a wiser king than you. Or a better father.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have much to learn. I know that now. But some day, perhaps, I will make you proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>ODIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Odin leaves, Thor consoled by his words.</context>
      <utterance>You've already made me proud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heimdall turns, gazes out towards Earth.</context>
      <utterance>Can you see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIMDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane inserts the flash drive into the device.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He would have come back if he could.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane hits a switch on the device. Suddenly, a 3-D HOLOGRAPHIC PROJECTION bursts to life over the device, bathing the two women in its glow. We recognize what it is -- YGGDRASIL, in all its beauty.</context>
      <utterance>I know. But if he can't get here on his own...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
