<movie id="560" title="Thunderheart">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Nice tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start walking briskly toward the loading dock.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get too attached.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They mount steps.</context>
      <utterance>Ya got the paper?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're my hero, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heroes ain't supposed to shake. I'm shakin', man, look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop at the door of a service elevator and Carl breathes. Expanding his chest, exhaling. Ray adjusts Carl's tie for him, his collar. He speaks quietly. Quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Breathe, Carl. Four, nice, deep ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone stops us going in, we're with the Bowen-Hamilton Textile Company. We have rug samples.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rug samples.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl nods. Ray hesitates, adjusts his own collar and enters the service elevator. Carl follows. Door closes.</context>
      <utterance>We are one-dimensional, boring peddlers of fine carpet, Carl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look who's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray walks up to the counter. Carl lingers, fidgeting. Ray sets his briefcase on the counter and click-clicks it open. The Hispanic fence man looks inside, and begins pulling out stacks of treasury checks.</context>
      <utterance>Louis, my man, what's happenin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clean ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gestures to Carl and he nervously sets his briefcase on the counter, fumbles with the first latch. The second. He flips it open. The fence man casts his eyes down at a neat cache of Grade A Treasury. A lot of it. Then his eyes rise to Carl.</context>
      <utterance>Immaculate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENCE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ya got there, seventy-five thousand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred and ten. Count it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>BLACK MAN</mode>
      <context>The fence man pushes an intercom button and yells into a speaker.</context>
      <utterance>Have the girl count it, we can't sit around here countin' bonds, we got things to do here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl startled, does an almost effeminate dip down to one knee, but that knee is swept out from under him, slapping him flat onto plywood where he is instantly frisked down by the fence man who is wielding a 9 mm handgun. But the white collar criminal is more stunned by the fact that -- Ray is walking across the floor with his hands in his pockets over to the Mr. Coffee. He pours one, and adds some milk. Turns and watches the bust while opening a packet of Sweet n'Low.</context>
      <utterance>F.B.I.! Get your face on the fuckin' floor! MOVE!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slam dunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray rests his weight against the coffee station, takes a careful sip. Carl is yanked to his feet by the fence man and he stands there, looking at Ray, baffled. Completely shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Beauty. Beauty...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Larry, what the fu-- Larry. That's not even your name, is it? What's your real name, you fucking scumbag?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coffee in hand, Ray walks briskly toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't have one, Carl. I have a number, man. Just like the numbers on those treasury checks. You stole from your own country, Carl. Shame on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns. Louis takes a few steps toward him, putting his gun back in his waistband.</context>
      <utterance>Sugar Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stands frozen, holding the door knob, and digesting what are apparently influential words.</context>
      <utterance>They want ya Home. Upstairs wants to see ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray just stares for a moment. Then hurries out the door. Carl, being arm-gripped by two agents and photographed like a trout, gazes bewildered at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure ya spell my name right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just spent four months together... I thought he was my friend... what the fuck, man?  He had dinner at my mother's. CAMERA FLASHES at him, an agent on either side, striking a natural pose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>INTERCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SA Levoi, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seated, at the far end of the table, engrossed in the deep spread of information, SA (Special Agent) FRANK COUTURE is about to break the record for longest single ash on the end of a cigarette and the smoke forces his eyes into tight, concentrating, slits. "COOCH" as they call him in the Bureau has seen thirty years in some rough "provinces". He has survived the Hoover era and is a legend in the Sessions era but survival has honed an edge. An edge with a touch of ironic cop humor. Ray enters, walks into a firm shake.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Tully.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want a coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sits nervously across from Cooch who looks up from the photos and studies the younger man through reading glasses and cigarette smoke, and he looks at him like he doesn't know who the hell he is or why he's sitting there.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, no. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Levoi, Cooch. Raymond Levoi, Criminal Division.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch sticks his cigarette in his left hand, shakes with his right.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah -- right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray this is --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY / TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank Couture.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUTURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The handshake is still locked. Cooch is still squinting at the younger agent. Ray obviously knows something about Agent Couture.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tully leans back in his chair, crosses his legs casually.</context>
      <utterance>It's an honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray's enthusiasm suddenly deflates.</context>
      <utterance>Ray, we're taking you off the street. We need you out in South Dakota.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>South Dakota...  Did I do something unsatisfactory, Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks completely baffled now, swinging a look from Cooch to Tully.</context>
      <utterance>No, Ray. You're gonna have to blame that on your grandmother.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting bloodline you have, Ray.  French, Scots-Irish, Italian, ...and one-eighth American Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sioux Indian, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not that sure. Yeah, I think --</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods, looks from Tully to Cooch. What's going on here?</context>
      <utterance>-- yes, Teton Sioux. Father's side.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, there's been a homicide out in an area known as The Badlands. Indian Reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the first. There's been several. And our field office in Rapid City is getting a lot of heat... none of the investigations have turned up jack shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The main problem is, Ray, these people are extremely distrustful of outsiders, non-Indians. Relations have not been amicable.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tully straightens the edges of a bureau memorandum.</context>
      <utterance>Different culture. Hard to penetrate. The Indians don't like white cops poking around. And that's why we're in a position where we have to bring in an American Indian agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With an Indian representative out there, we hope to keep hostilities dormant; this is a COINTELPRO, Selective Operations Unit, and it'll be easier on Agent Couture if you can gain the people's trust and maybe --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woh, excuse me, Sir... I see what you're saying... I've got a little Indian blood, that's true. But --  I am not an... an Indian. I can't just go in and --</utterance>
   <speaker>TULLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Ray lowers his eyes to the photos.</context>
      <utterance>-- your father was part Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know him, Sir. He passed away when I was six.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks up at Cooch. Another uneasy beat. Cooch lights a cigarette as if lighting a cigarette was a science.</context>
      <utterance>Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sits before the files and photos, looking unsure. He has come to garner a promotion but has just been sent to The Graveyard. Or in the FBI argot, Indian Country. Tully pivots his leather chair in a full circle and slaps an assignment folder down in front of the young agent.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, Ray. As long as the people have proof that we sent them one of their own, no one's gonna ask you to weave baskets or make it rain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch opens a folder that sits between them, and taking his eyes off the road for a dangerous five seconds, locates some photos, and hands them to Ray. Ray's expression tells us they are not pretty.</context>
      <utterance>Eight murders in less than a year. All of them Indian. All of them unsolved. Is the law a non-entity out here or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are two agents who went into a reservation a few years ago to serve a warrant. They were executed at close range. That one there is a police officer killed by the Mohawks up in Canada more recently.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray considers this as he looks out at the unfamiliar terrain while on the RADIO, a D.J. speaks in LAKOTA LANGUAGE. Ray... back at Cooch, studying his face.</context>
      <utterance>The agents who have worked out here say its like going into Nam. Unfamiliar terrain, foreign language, foreign customs... and you never know when you might walk into a few rounds. They hold a lot of old anger for the white man out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you in Nam?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray smiles, sets the AC on high.</context>
      <utterance>Airborne. That's where they used to get us agents from. Now we get 'em from Carnegie-Melon, Ivy League. Accountants and computer whiz-kids. Yuppies with guns.  That's scary shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch throws a quick look Ray's way. And a smile. He appreciates the sting of a right off a left.</context>
      <utterance>Not as scary as a Hoover man with a computer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, hey. J. Edgar would've loved you. He'd love anybody who joined the bureau to, what was it? "To enforce the laws of my country and protect her interests"?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crashed my file?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray has finished his sandwich. He wipes his hands on a kerchief while taking in the sight of chalky buttes cramming roadside.</context>
      <utterance>No. I consulted it. We're going into Indian Country, I wanna know what kind of individual is covering my ass. Don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch looks at Ray, amused. He likes this guy. And then he notices a look of growing consternation on his partner's face.</context>
      <utterance>You've been in the bureau for thirty years. You survived The Hoov, the Black Panthers and Abscam. I don't see any bullet holes. That's good enough for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who found him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch studies the body from where he stands. Sherman hands a file over to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Indian kids. Hunting fossils.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I think Agent Levoi and I can proceed from here. What are your call signals?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PX-10 and 11. Anything we can do to help you out, just radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agents start back through the Badlands. Ray is already squatting a safe distance from the body, covering his nose with a kerchief while looking in the file. Cooch takes a bended knee on the other side of the body. Flies buzz on and around the corpse.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Thanks, Guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch makes a note then slowly circles the body. He holds a hand out to Ray and the younger agent turns the file over.</context>
      <utterance>Leo Fast Elk... Thirty seven... single... Member of the Tribal Council.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gets closer, swats at Flies with the folder.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like Fast Elk wasn't fast enough to outrun that load. What do you make of the damage?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six rounds. 357.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks up impressed. Cooch rises and walks off gingerly, scanning the surroundings.</context>
      <utterance>That's what it looks like, doesn't it? But that's what a ten gauge, choke-bored, shotgun will look like when it hits your lower back from five feet away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody was serious about doing this guy, that's for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch is standing ten feet away, staring at the ground. Ray walks over, carefully. He follows Cooch's frown down at the twisted layers of earth.</context>
      <utterance>Ray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse hawks his eyes onto a big rock, a full second before Ray steps out, his .45 drawn but held at ease. Crow Horse slowly raises his arms as Ray moves up to him, studying him.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taking ol' Leo somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo's been out here too long, man. I'm taking him to ceremonial burial.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a restricted area.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray frisks the Indian, finds an old leather wallet, and then a gun. A .38.</context>
      <utterance>Check him out, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice piece. You come back here to cover your tracks, Geronimo? What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't Geronimo.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch walks around to the front of Crow Horse, and studies him.</context>
      <utterance>I think maybe you guys got off the wrong exit, yeah? This is the Bear Creek Indian Reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know where I am. I'm on federal land, doing a federal investigation, and if you don't wanna cooperate you can take a ride in a federal car, and spend the rest of the day in a little room, answering federal questions. It's your call. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a full blood Oglala Sioux, born and raised on this reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a wise-ass. Ray check his wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. A long, dead of South Dakota, Badlands pause. Cooch turns and looks at Ray who holds up the open wallet, revealing a badge. Like Cooch's it shines in the sun.</context>
      <utterance>-- a fucking cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch stands staring at the Indian... then takes a few steps over to Ray and grabs the wallet. He examines it. Then looks at Crow Horse and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Walter Crow Horse. Tribal Police.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indian cop has plenty of time to get up on his own but he kneels there, tauntingly, waiting for Ray to help him. Ray walks over and offers a hand. Crow Horse takes it, and pulls himself up, looking square into Ray's sunglasses. Cooch walks over and hands the officer his wallet, and his .23. Crow Horse takes the items, eyeing the older agent.</context>
      <utterance>He's a fucking cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the wire ya was comin'. You're the Indian official, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray does a take but quickly recovers, meeting Crow Horse's scrutinizing gaze. Crow Horse nods to Ray, and Ray nods back in case it's the Indian thing to do. Crow Horse nods again. Ray nods again.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, that's Ray, here. Ray, uh...  Ray... Little Weasel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo's gotta get to burial, Brother. He's gotta make the journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What journey?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stares at Crow Horse, uneasy. The wind sings through the Badlands.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo has to take the journey, Cooch.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have to give Leo a refund. Because he's gotta go to the M.E. In case you don't know, Officer, violation of the Major Crimes Act on --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- an Indian Reservation is within the jurisdiction of the Federal Bureau of Intimidation. I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse says something in Sioux to Ray. Ray just stares.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said when can Leo be taken to ceremony?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse is staring at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>After we've completed our investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks offended. Cooch puts a hand on Crow Horse's shoulder and walks him toward his beat-up motorcycle.</context>
      <utterance>That's a nice suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody must be doing something somewhere in your jurisdiction, Officer Crow Foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse turns and looks at Ray. Ray is quick this time.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't gonna cut his hands off and send 'em to Washinton, are ya? They done that to one of our girls once. Leo did quillwork, he's gonna need his hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo's gonna need his hands, Cooch. He does quillwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Leo's retired from quillwork for the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Respect the dead, Hoss. Because when --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- did you understand me when I said that --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- violation of the Major Crimes Act on an Indian Reservation is within the jurisdiction of the Federal Bureau of Instigation. I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse appears to be getting on his bike when suddenly he moves like a cat and lays his knife to the dead man's head. He cuts away a patch of hair.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch and Ray stand there, watching Crow Horse mount his bike and push off down a nasty slope back through the Badlands. He starts his motor. It dies. Then starts again.</context>
      <utterance>His mother needs a piece of his hair. It's for the Keeping of the Souls Ceremony.  Has to be kept for four days.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keeping of the souls. Do they still burn their dead or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Cooch look off across the Badlands, as far out of their element as they can be.</context>
      <utterance>Beats the hell outta me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young agent smiles, amused, starts to enter the bar but --</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Ray. You're gonna have to wait in the car. I'll bring you out a cheeseburger.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ray spins quickly, paranoid about entering. But the man calling to them is -- An Indian himself. TRIBAL PRESIDENT OLIVER CLEAR MOON, a small man in his late fifties who peers out at the agents through fat bifocals. He wears a straw cowboy hat, red windbreaker and his hair is cut short, or "bobtailed" as the Indians say. Clear Moon is walking away from a parked pick-up truck, toward the white men, eyeing the two with deep curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch discreetly peeks into a folder as he walks toward the man</context>
      <utterance>You made it. Was-te.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be... President Clear Bone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is pointing his long, skinny finger at Cooch.</context>
      <utterance>Clear Moon.  Moon. You must be the Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's Ray here. Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps pumping Ray's hand, looking into his face with great admiration. Cooch looks on with amusement.</context>
      <utterance>It's about time they sent us one of our own. Was-te.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clear Moon has not released Ray's arm as he leads them to a string of seedy motel units across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Things are no good here. It is like war zone. We need an official who understands what is good for the Indian people. Who knows Indian way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were staying on the reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Rooms thirteen and fourteen are on Indian land.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry? I have some nice raw kidney in the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm set, Sir. I'm set.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Clear Moon guides them through the front door of room 13. Ray looks over his shoulder threateningly at Cooch who winks and pats his back.</context>
      <utterance>He's starving, Mr. Clear Moon. Get him some raw kidney. He hasn't had any Indian food in days...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE LOCAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young local bends down behind the Indian while another shoves him, sending him tripping over the bent man and onto his back in the dirt.</context>
      <utterance>Where you goin'? Back to the res?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE LOCAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MORE LOCALS come out from the bar, beers and drinks and interested in what's going on.</context>
      <utterance>What ya doin'? You drunk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I can't walk across the goddamn street without some breed-ass fallin' all over me? And then Cooch shoves the Indian with all his might back across the road. The locals resume their fun, and Cooch looks at a local man and shares a chattering laugh that makes Ray do a serious take.</context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indian ends up stumbling back toward Ray, and Ray catches him this time. The man maintains a perfect vacant expression and keeps acting as though nothing of the sort is happening. But he is dizzy, and exhausted, and Ray keeps him from falling. Cooch looks at Ray. Their eyes meet. Ray shoves the man forward. This time, instead of catching him, the local on the receiving end, hauls off and punches him in the face. The Indian drops. Cooch runs in, grabs the Indian under the arms and drags him back to his car.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out now, he wants a kiss, Ray, wants a kiss --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves him behind the wheel as the locals crowd around. They don't see Cooch throw the wheel stick in drive, and lean into the man's ear.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, skin, get your ass back on your sacred land. Get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch slams the door, and kicks it, and the vehicle lurches forward. A beer can clanks off the rear window, and rolls clanking into the middle of the road. Ray stands there with the locals as they all watch the car drive off across the reservation line. Cooch, belly sticking out of his unbuttoned shirt, and a breathless smile on his face, heads to the bar without breaking stride. This man has done "underground" before.</context>
      <utterance>Get outta here. Drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what type of salesmen are you gentlemen anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liquor. We heard they like their drink on the reservation, and we were gonna see if we couldn't unload some surplus on the way to Nebraska.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now keep that between us, Dennis, cuz I don't know what kinda Johnny Law they got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BROOKS, a small, older man with a feed store cap and a clean cowboy shirt, comes over with a beer and a pensive look on his face. He pulls up a chair and positions himself at the end of the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Brooks, come over here. I want you to meet a coupla fellas from Denver.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liquor salesmen. Be nice to them, maybe they'll give you a sample of some of that gin you like.  He likes that Russian shit that --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ain't liquor salesmen. They're</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brooks, what's a perceptive fellow like you, doing in a joint like this? Let me buy you a glass of some of that Russian shit you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FBI? What you investigatin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A murder. On the reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again. Figures, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never find out who did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You underestimate me, Brooks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You underestimate these grass niggers. They're killing each other. That's all they do. Get drunk and kill each other. Then cover for each other. Who gives a damn really as long as they stay on their reservation. You ask me, the government shouldn't care one particle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how in your big cities, you got your niggers and you got your Puerto Ricans? Well out here we got Indians. That's just the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch laughs good-naturedly. Ray smiles. But Brooks looks offended.</context>
      <utterance>The only good Indian is a dead Indian, does that old adage still hold true out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That set-to you saw out front, was nothin' more than a message we were sendin' to the sonsabitches that are divertin' water from the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray catches this. Glances a look off Cooch who works on a cold draught beer.</context>
      <utterance>We got rights. We got a ranch just up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men shake their heads. Get quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Did any of you gentlemen know Leo Fast Elk?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fellas are here to investigate a Indian crime, you should keep to Indian land, and talk to them, not us. But you wanna drink here and shoot stick here, that's your right, and we respect that.  Come on, Son, we're up on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch shakes his head, distracted, and the two locals leave, enroute for the pool table. Ray watches them go, curious.</context>
      <utterance>You fellas wanna play doubles?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water. Worth killing for out here, I'd think.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the plate numbers off everyone of these cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch looks at Ray, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>I already did.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop in front of their rooms and Cooch pulls a small tape recorder from his waistband. A micro-cassette recorder that he examines in the dim door light.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECORDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch shuts it off.</context>
      <utterance>-- out here we got our Indians. And that's the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Ray the recorder.</context>
      <utterance>By the time you get to the main village, sun'll be up. I want you to fraternize. Socialize. Penetrate. Infiltrate. Eat some raw kidney, and get these Indians talking. I'm gonna Powwow with Big Chief Clear Moon and find out more about Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch starts for his room but in a long, exaggerated country step as he breaks into the HANK WILLIAMS tune that has all but driven him insane inside the joint. Ray watches him go, and cracks a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning. I'm looking for Hobert- Buffalo-Dreaming...  Hobert Standing-Buffalo-That-Walks-- The door closes. Locks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stands there for a moment then lowers himself to look through the huge hole in the door.</context>
      <utterance>--Dreamer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tattered chair is pushed against the door, covering the hole. Ray stands up, turns on the steps. And before he can let out a flustered sigh, he spots something across the dirt road. Something that makes him remove his shades, look again. Whatever it is, it doesn't make him happy, and he is hurrying across the road.</context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wind whistles and moans through the Badlands as Crow Horse continues feel tracking.</context>
      <utterance>Ray Little Weasel. FBI. I like the way ya sneaked up on me. Must be Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray draws back.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse lowers his face to the ground and blows some scattered dust out of a print. Lightly lays his fingers inside</context>
      <utterance>You're steppin' on sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.  Hey, you, listen up --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse checks out another track.</context>
      <utterance>-- Leo wasn't killed here. He was dumped here. Out of a vehicle. Bald tread. Muffler held on with baling wire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse rises, points down the road.</context>
      <utterance>The man you want... stepped outta the car, dragged Leo out, laid him down. Then walked over here and made a circle in the earth with a stick. I can't find the stick. He stuck an eagle plume in the circle, got back in his car, dustin' his own prints with a pine bough for about six feet, but he missed a print, right here, see. He got in his car and went Hell- bent-for-Holy-Sunday outta here. He ditched that pine bough three miles across the flat, in the Little Bear River, it floated down to Thundershield Gap. The car hit paved road, and was outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is frowning at the big Indian, trying to get a fix on this</context>
      <utterance>The killin' was done where Leo's mother lives. But he was driven here into these Badlands.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big sonuvabuck. Based on the depth of that print, pressure releases... I'd say he goes two-ten, two-fifteen --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Well, maybe two-seventeen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trying to tell me you can read all that from a track?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not just a track. You gotta listen to the trees, man. To the leaves. To this sand, you FBI's kicked all up. You gotta listen to the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right? Well, listen to this: drag your ass. This is a restricted area.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is the home of the Oglala Sioux and I want the dog-fucker who killed Leo. Whether you get him or I get him, I just want him. Shit's been goin' on too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got no jurisdiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got no know-how. About Indian Way. Or about Jack Shit for that matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're not aware of this, Crow Horse, but I just flew in from a place called the Twentieth Century where we have such things as electrostatic tracking methods, psycholingusitics, DNA fingerprinting; I don't have to crawl around with the scorpions and talk to the fucking trees to get answers. Leo was killed right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back to the M.E., take a look inside Leo's exit wounds and tell me how chicken feed got in there. Trust me, there ain't chickens in the Badlands. His mother's place is --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- his mother never lived here. She was from up in North Dakota.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talkin' his spiritual mother. Maisy Blue Legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His spiritual mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To us Indians, our spiritual relatives are as close as family. I've got seven mothers on this reservation. Sisters. Brothers. You ain't one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God. Now listen to me, asshole. I'm giving you a break. But if my partner finds out you're here, you're gonna be reading rat tracks in Sioux Falls Maximum Security.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse walks back up toward the road. Ray lets him leave then crouches where Crow Horse was, begins looking at tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Easy. Easy... I'm goin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ray turns, and sees Crow Horse perched on a high bank -- the one Ray came down -- and he's in a tracking stance.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Little Weasel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray just stands frozen, blown away. Crow Horse rises, dusting off his hands, and heading to his vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>You weigh one sixty-three, yeah? Not a beer drinker. You're one of these tofu and pilaf characters. Pack your gun, under your coat -- left shoulder. But you got backup; a little .32, .38 maybe, in a ankle holster that gives you a right foot drag, Shoes are too tight at the toe but, man, they look cool. And that's what counts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indian turns. The wind moans. Ray scrutinizes him, deliberating.</context>
      <utterance>Crow Horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse grins and waves, and ambles away. DOWN IN</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs... Blue Legs? Can I ask you a few questions --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- go away. Leave us alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She mounts the metal steps. Ray is losing her. He gets a foot on the bottom step, and attempts something he does not want to do.</context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, Please --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Halfway through the screendoor, Maisy turns and looks at the young man in suit and shades.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Blue Legs. I'm Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maisy lowers her bifocals, studies him. Then walks in, slaps the door shut, and locks it. A towel hung as a shade folds down. Ray lingers at the bottom of the steps.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he walks around the side of the trailer, looking at the ground. In the gaping space between the trailer blocks, and the grass, there is much junk stored, and Ray kneels to look. He is drawn to a pair of cowboy boots, caked with dried mud. He picks up a boot, looks at the sole, then touches the mud. His fingers break through the hardened crust and come back moist and blue. He looks at this sniffs it. There is a tense, water-torture like tempo coming from the old pump where water barely drips onto a hub cap in the dirt. Ray sets the boot down. Goes to grab the other boot and -- a WESTERN DIAMOND BACK RATTLER coils out from the shade of the boot, RATTLING and HISSING from white mouth and three- inch fangs, and Ray has done a backflip and roll, slapping his shoulder holster and pulling lead and BLAM! BLAAAM! he unloads two, and the reptile is so dead, there's not even enough snake left to make a truck-stop key chain. He kneels there, flushed in the face, holding his breath and double-clutching his gun. The SHOTS ECHO through the Badlands like the aftermath of dynamite. From inside the trailer, he can hear CRYING. A low moaning. Praying softly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then his RADIO CRACKS IN.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Mrs. Blue Legs! It's okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>COOCH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>X21, give me a 20.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black Tail District, X22. You ready for this? Leo wasn't killed in the Badlands. I... I found the location.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maisy Blue Legs place?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got one up on ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>I've got the doer. I know who he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me at base. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks down at the dead snake, still rushed from it, and he hurries out of there.</context>
      <utterance>Cooch. You're my hero.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON - FILE PHOTO: a raging fire and six long-haired, fist-raising Indians, yelling at the camera.</context>
      <utterance>One of the leaders of the Warriors of All Red Nations. Militant organization. He hands an open file over to Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The progressive Indians don't like them because they want everybody to go back to the old Indian ways, and the old way Indians don't like them because they use violence to get attention.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White eagle feather through the circle. That's their symbol.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray shuffles through more of the same with great interest.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They obviously wanted it to be known that they offed Leo. Some kind of statement.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch takes a long, tight breath then turns around in his seat, coming up with an M-16. Ray lifts one of his own. He looks out the car window.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy Looks Twice put Leo's head through a glass door of the tribal offices three months ago. And threatened him several times since. President Clear Moon and the regional FBI feel he made good on that threat.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just like five minutes alone with the motherfucker who hung that flag upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, Cowboy. No vendettas on my ship. Now: remember what I told you about Nam? Watch the grass, watch the trees, watch the shit house, be on your toes, and if we get committed, don't hesitate to empty that sucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch whacks a top clip into the M-16. Ray slams a clip in his.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Car doors open in skillful silence.</context>
      <utterance>It's show time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy drops boot camp fast. Cooch moves up on the sweat lodge, looking quizzically at it, trying to figure out how to open it. He grabs a canvas flap at the front and after a moment's hesitation and a look at Ray, he tears the flap away. A BLAST OF 200 DEGREE STEAM explodes forth and Cooch dances back, throwing up his rifle.</context>
      <utterance>On the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>GRANDPA SAMUEL REACHES, a rail-thin Sioux elder, appears through the steam like a vision. Bent in the tiny doorway, he searches out the interruption. Cooch aims the M-16 at the old man.</context>
      <utterance>Mitakue Oyasin!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandpa Reaches crawls out first, ignoring the "Hands on your head" order from Cooch. His eyes move back and forth between the two agents. FIVE MORE INDIANS, from 16-45 come out, looking confused. Cooch makes the towel-wrapped men spread out in a line. The old man is speaking to the others in LAKOTA, and Ray steps up to him, cuts him off.</context>
      <utterance>This is the FBI! Come on out of there nice and slow. Let's move it! Hands on your head!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The archaic figure just looks through him. Starts to walk away. Ray takes his thin arm. He locks eyes with the old man. Slowly, he obeys, raising his hands and laying them on his head. From the lodge, the last man emerges. It's Crazy Horse reborn out of the burning sage. JIMMY LOOKS TWICE is in his mid- thirties -- big, well over two-hundred pounds. But lean. His braids fall nearly to his hips. His face is handsome but at the moment, twisted in a full-blood's scowl.</context>
      <utterance>Hands on your head, Sir. Come on, come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James Looks Twice?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks Twice shoots hawk-like black eyes onto Ray.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. What are you doing here? This is a religious ceremony you're desecrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're FBI, James. We just need to ask you a few questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are in the middle of a sweat lodge ceremony. Do you drag people out of your churches when they're in the middle of prayer?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch takes a careful step behind Jimmy and cuffs him. Looks Twice speaks to the others in LAKOTA, and they disband, heading to a shade arbor where their clothes hang. As Cooch starts marching Looks Twice toward the house, Ray keeps an eye on the departing. One of them stops halfway to the fence and turns. Grandpa Reaches looks at Ray with eyes that have seen one hundred and one hard years in Indian Country.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a walk, Jimmy. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he follows Cooch and the cuffed Jimmy to the house.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. You can all go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just wanna take a look around your place, Jimmy. We're not here to bust your balls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this about?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your good friend Leo Fast Elk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I killed him? Cuz he was an apple? Well, let me tell you something about Leo, Man --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy doesn't answer. He glares with hatred into Cooch's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>-- don't "man" me, Jimmy. Where's the key?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray steps up, gets ready to throw a frontkick at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Ray, use the federal master key.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his hands cuffed, he can only jerk his head toward a big hole in the wall down near the foundation. Cooch quickly drops to a knee and checks out the hole.</context>
      <utterance>No. Don't do that. Don't deface the property, man. The key's in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch reaches in, probes.</context>
      <utterance>Inside... in the coffee can.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something horrifying happens so fast, Cooch has no time to react. Whatever has taken his arm has done so with such force, his body jolts like he's touched raw voltage. The South Dakota BADGER rips through his leather jacket -- we get a glimpse of its striped face and yellowed teeth -- through his shirt. Through flesh, and deeper, GROWLING insanely while COOCH HOLLERS in shock tries to pull free and -- Jimmy Looks Twice spins from the porch with a skillfully executed back kick, knocking Ray off the step and to the ground. The Indian bolts like a deer into the darkness. Ray rolls in the grass, throwing his M-16 up. He hesitates. But only for a moment before FIRING and decimating the corner gutter, a junked car, several trees. But no sign of Jimmy. Cooch falls back in the grass badly mauled. His arm has been ripped open down to the bone.</context>
      <utterance>There's no coffee can in --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray starts toward Cooch.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus... Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray takes off, crashing through weeds, into a stream, wading through mud. He throws his flashlight left and right. He crosses the river, shines the light in a field of wild sage. Nothing. He runs like a sprinter, looking everywhere. But as he enters an --</context>
      <utterance>Get him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assault on federal officers. Suspect has left the area. One officer down. Issue a Fugitive Alert immediately. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has the officer been shot, X-22?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the officer's been bitten by a fucking badger, okay? Get a Fugitive Alert fucking now! Over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an easy man to track, Ray. Ya walk like a penguin with a hard-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right? What are the trees saying today?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray soaks sweat off his forehead as he eyes the Indian on this one. He sees himself in the polaroid shades.</context>
      <utterance>They're sayin' that nobody's gonna talk to you cuz they don't give away one of their own. But they did say there's somebody way across the Little Walking River who wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sent me to find ya. He says he's got information.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray quickly leaves the porch.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandpa Samuel Reaches. Heavy duty medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse nods slowly, looking at Ray in a very serious manner</context>
      <utterance>Medicine. As in medicine man?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does he wanna see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse stops walking, making Ray do the same.</context>
      <utterance>Good question. Hardly sees anybody anymore. Hasn't left this place in twenty years. Did you bring some tobacco?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray reaches into his shirt pocket and fishes out a pack of Marlboro. Crow Horse glances at it, and shrug-nods. They continue on toward the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>When you go see an elder, you always bring some tobacco as a gift.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks puzzled. Crow Horse laughs bull-wild as Grandpa takes up a fly swatter and takes out a big horsefly. The old man begins speaking Indian again.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to know if you ever watch the Cookie Monster. He says the Cookie Monster is not to be trusted -- a trickster.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse turns a questioning look at Ray. Ray doesn't flinch.</context>
      <utterance>He says there's something wrong with Big Bird -- he's crazy,  He says you stopped the Inipi ceremony last night...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he is not unhappy with you because he knows you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse stops translating suddenly even though the old man continues speaking. Crow Horse looks concerned, and ASKS A QUESTION IN LAKOTA. We don't know what he's asking but the tone is absolute amazement. This question triggers an exchange between he and Grandpa, the old one getting angry. Grandpa wins.</context>
      <utterance>He says he saw you in a vision some time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray's brow is drawn tense as he stares at the old Indian, absorbing the translation. Grandpa speaks more fervently now, incorporating Indian sign. Each time Grandpa does the hard Sioux HAND SLAP, Ray blinks.</context>
      <utterance>I guess he had this vision some time ago, in the Moon of the Popping Trees -- uh, back in the winter. He says you come from Wasi'cu city in the East but that your people... way back... are of the Minniconjou Sioux. But you yourself don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man has taken a long wooden stem and a red stone bowl from a beaded pipe bag. He joins the two together then begins offering a pinch of tobacco to the Four Directions. While this goes on, Ray fidgets.</context>
      <utterance>He says he knew you'd be coming to Bear Creek. He was told. It is the will of Tunkasilia -- the grandfather that you come here. He says let's smoke the caanunpa the sacred pipe, symbol of truth. So that there will be no lies between us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he smoke in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man is offering the pipe to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Sacred herbs. Tobacco. Don't worry, we don't smoke no Mexican agriculture in The Pipe. That's a white man's myth. This is a sacrament.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Grandpa. The old man offers the pipe again.</context>
      <utterance>Mltaku Oyasin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray takes the pipe, looks at it... then passes it to Crow Horse. The big Indian takes it from Ray, giving him a long eye, then offering the pipe to The Directions before smoking. Crow Horse puffs hard, eyes closed, then slowly releases some smoke upward. Ray watches it climb and fade. The old man then takes up an old turtle shell rattle. He speaks.</context>
      <utterance>You don't smoke with him, it means you're hiding something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes the rattle very slightly, moving it in front of Ray. He speaks just above a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>He says Wakan. Sacred. Five hundred year old turtleshell rattle, passed down from the Grandfathers. Heavy duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray smirks.</context>
      <utterance>He says, it is good. The Spirits are here. The Spirits want to know what you're doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse asks the old man in Lakota. No answer. The pipe is back to grandpa, and he offers it to the Directions, to the Earth then upward before smoking himself. He begins to speak again. Passionately. In long glottal Sioux sentences, adding sign, fingers crossing, brushing an arm, a slap here and there, He is working himself into an excited state, and Ray keeps looking at Crow Horse, very interested in the old man's answer. Finally Grandpa's breath comes up short and wheezing, he ends his oratory with a solid hand slap.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him I'm trying to find the man who murdered Leo Fast Elk. Ask him if he knows where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he doesn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse ignores him. Grandpa speaks again. More hand language. The old man is staring at Ray while whispering to Crow Horse. He strokes his badger claw necklace. Crow Horse looks at Ray and seems hesitant to translate this new piece of information.</context>
      <utterance>He just did the Gettysburg Address in Sioux. What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandpa smiles toothlessly. Ray who has his driving glasses in hand, lifts them to say "these?" but Grandpa sees it as an accepted deal, and swiftly removes his necklace. He holds it out. Ray slowly, hesitantly surrenders his sunglasses, and takes the necklace. Crow Horse bursts into laughter and so does Grandpa, enjoying a good trade. He draws a hand through the air in a sort of horizontal karate chop, meaning done deal. Ray looks confused. Out of his element. And out of his shades. Another fly gets snagged on sticky tape.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... Grandpa likes to trade; no one stops by here without gettin' stuck in the old Indian barter. He, uh... he likes your shades.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was he saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Because he was talking to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse stops walking and eyes Ray, deliberating.</context>
      <utterance>Does he know something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old man saw an owl. Over there in the dry wash. Last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silent moment. Ray tries to figure out what he's missing here.</context>
      <utterance>He saw an owl.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stares vacantly.</context>
      <utterance>The owl is a messenger. When one shows itself to a Sioux... it means someone's gonna die. The owl told him about Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The owl told him about Leo. That's incredible. I guess we just broke the back of this investigation, didn't we? Evidence doesn't get any harder than that -- not for my money. Is there anyway we can seduce this owl into Federal Court?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He also said "listen to the water."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to the water. Listen to the owl. He also said, don't trust the fucking Cookie Monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse KICK STARTS his bike and burns off down the drive Ray feels the presence of the old man, standing behind the busted screen door. Just watching.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to your DNA finger-printin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHASING HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The veterans just stand under the flag, solemn, looking at Chasing Hawk. The flag undulates soundlessly.</context>
      <utterance>What is that that you honor there, uncles? After all the Wasi'cu country has done to you, after all he still does to you, you honor that flag?! That flag has been desecrated by the United States, because they have not honored what that flag represents!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASING HAWK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To them, we are the Bank of America. Whenever they get into a little difficulty, they go to The Bank, withdraw a little land, withdraw a little oil --</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE THE ARBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the four FBI agents stand, watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anderson Chasing Hawk. Second in command behind Jimmy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magedelana Eagle Bear. Eagle's claws and a bear's balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ray watches her, someone approaches in a less hostile manner. It is President Clear Moon, looking very upset. He holds the hand of a LITTLE GIRL, dressed in traditional dancing garb. He approaches Ray.</context>
      <utterance>She keeps an AR-15 assault rifle in her truck. And she'll use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Clear Moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clear Moon gestures for the little girl to run off. He leans in close to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Our police are afraid of them. Please get them out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to kill me next. That's what I hear. These new Indians are destroying everything. Our people are a quiet people.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clear Moon is looking past Ray at the Warriors. They are approaching the agents, and Clear Moon looks at Ray with great concern.</context>
      <utterance>They can lead us to Jimmy. Just let them go. We're tightening the net on him. We know he's on the reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he slowly retreats to his lawn chair under the arbor. Chasing Hawk, Maggie and the other Warriors strut up to the agents. All but one who is bound to a wheelchair. We've seen RICHARD YELLOW BIRD, the big Cheyenne who wears a Red Power baseball cap, an earring, and thick bifocals -- in one of the file photos. His arms are plastered with tattoos.</context>
      <utterance>Help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warriors make a show of not acknowledging the FBI presence. They have walked over here just to walk by them. That is there statement. But Yellow Bird stops cranking the wheels of his chair and stop: long enough to look up at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Jimmy? We thought he'd be dancing today.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even the agents crack grins at this bit of Indian wit. All but Ray who just stands there, arms folded across his chest, considering the crippled activist.</context>
      <utterance>Are you the Washington Redskin?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird sits there, staring up at him through thick glasses But then Maggie Eagle Bear takes the handles of Yellow Bird's wheel chair. She looks at Ray with eyes that are choke- cherry black, eyes that look right through him. He returns the glare. And then she pushes Yellowbird forward and leaves the feds alone. Ray turns to Cooch who is lighting a cigarette, and concentrating on the movements of this group as they wander under the arbor, visiting people. LAKOTA SINGERS start up.</context>
      <utterance>Say hello to Richard Yellow Bird, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, get to Jimmy's place and keep it tight. I'm gonna get a tail on his Warriors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>X22. Read.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a pick-up truck. No plates. Subject -- Indian -- entering suspect's house. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sets his radio down, unclips the leather guard on his handgun. Picks up the Big Mac.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Ray. I'm coming in. If he starts to leave the area, move in. And hold him. Over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray maneuvers in Quantico fashion, keeping the rifle on the Indian's back. The Indian drops what he's holding. And turns around. It's not a he. We've seen her before. At the Powwow. Maggie Eagle Bear. Her hair is pulled back tight, braided. Ray moves in toward her, surprised at first, but still cautious</context>
      <utterance>FBI, freeze, Motherfucker -- drop it, drop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does what he tells her. As Ray moves in on her, he notices an INDIAN CHILD sitting in the passenger seat, looking out into the highbeams, frightened. Ray toes Maggie's legs out wider, frisks her one-handed, pats down her boots.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around, put your hands on the roof of the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the Indian FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie turns around, looks Ray in the eye. He looks self- conscious in the cowboy hat.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is looking down at what she dropped. A bundle lying in the grass. He bends down, starts to untie it.</context>
      <utterance>The people are glad they sent you. They usually send in guys who come at ya with highbeams, screamin' "drop it, Motherfucker", stick a gun in your face, frisk ya down. Even if ya got a child with ya. No, it's good to have ya. It's gonna be was-te times on the res.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE BUNDLE -- an eagle skull, tobacco strings, sage, sweet grass, and several white eagle feathers.</context>
      <utterance>I was gonna warn ya about messin' with somebody's medicine bundle but I forgot you know all about that stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Jimmy's?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna catch him. He can shape-shift into different animals. Bear. Elk. Porcupine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that like an hereditary thing, Magdelana, or can one take classes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy didn't kill Leo. Why do you wanna do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tried to kill him twice before. That's a good place to start don't ya think? Leo was on the other side, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Leo was an apple, that's right. Red on the outside, white on the inside. And Jimmy hated him. Kicked his ass a coupla times. But he didn't kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the FBI. That's your job, isn't it? Ya know how many of our Warrior brothers got killed out here? I never saw any investigating then. Why now? What's going down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Fugitive Alert for a murder suspect. Before somebody else gets a shotgun blast in the spine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray doesn't have a clue as to what this radical bullshit is about.</context>
      <utterance>Try the Fort Laramie Treaty. All over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. You and I can stand here in a culture clash til the sun comes up, talking about what's right and what's wrong. You're from the reservation. It's a different world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If this information doesn't throw Ray, the use of his first name does.</context>
      <utterance>I'm from Minneapolis. Fifth Street. I did four years at Dartmouth before I ever set foot on this res. So I know about the other world, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is holding the medicine bundle. He deliberates, then hands it over. She takes it with careful hands, casting a somewhat surprised look up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Are you gonna keep that medicine bundle or are you gonna respect its power?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie gets in the truck, starts it up. She looks out at him, studying him. Trying to figure him out. HEADLIGHTS are coming fast from down the main road.</context>
      <utterance>When you see Jimmy, tell him the sooner he turns himself back into a human being and gives himself in... the sooner we back off this reservation. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandpa Reaches says you come from heavy Indian blood. I used to think Grandpa was gettin' senile. Now I know he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie drives forward, turning down another little wagon road, and bumping into the black night only moments before, Cooch's Le Baron pulls in. SA Miles and Sherman's vehicle pull in behind it. The regional feds fall in behind Cooch, everyone, packing rifles.</context>
      <utterance>Move it, Magdelana.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns, nodding. An FBI van pulls in from the other direction and FOUR AGENTS empty out, wearing FBI windbreakers and heavily-armed.</context>
      <utterance>Ray, you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we got, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just Eagle Bear. I questioned and released her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch nods. The agents form a tight unit out below the upside down flag.</context>
      <utterance>She talks a lot of shit. We're not doing our job. Jimmy's innocent. "What's the FBI really doing here." Some shit about the Fort Laramie Treaty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She took something from the house. What she called a medicine bundle. Most likely Jimmy's.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave it back to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray reaches inside his pant leg, down around his boot and carefully removes a white eagle feather. He gingerly tucks it in a plastic bag.</context>
      <utterance>If it is Jimmy's, she's taking it to him. We'll have a runner. But I borrowed a little mojo...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sherman and Miles, take off. Cooch, an impressive master of COINTELPRO, now turns to the van squad.</context>
      <utterance>Way to go, Raymond. Miles, take that to lab. Sherman, I want you to go back to base and produce some written material. Something that indicates that our girl Maggie is leaking information to us. And make sure that material finds its way into the hands of the Warrior Movement.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The van squad moves toward the house, leaving Cooch and Ray alone in the highbeams that light the yard.</context>
      <utterance>You gentlemen missed that medicine basket. Go back through the house, and make sure you missed nothing else. And lay some wire, too. Let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good goddamn work, Ray. Let the salmon run. Let 'em run Upriver.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why we setting Eagle Bear up as an informant?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch bends down near the road, touches the dirt.</context>
      <utterance>Her own people start to suspect her, it creates discord from within. The Warriors don't know who to trust, they start infighting, and Jimmy loses his support. Ray nods, impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her oil pan is shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cooch. What's the Fort Laramie Treaty?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch wipes the oil on a handkerchief as he rises, smiling playfully at Ray. He starts back toward his car. Some sort of bird is COOING in the night.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I don't know. You tell me. You're the Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks up at the upside down flag. Then watches Cooch walking way.</context>
      <utterance>Get a tail on her, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cooch.  Where the fuck did they send us?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch, standing there with his glasses on and his right arm bandaged, looks tired, too. He gets in his car. In the yard, Ray starts for the van, the res dog, trying to follow. He chases it away. And then as he gets closer to the van, he looks up to investigate the COOING SOUND.</context>
      <utterance>A long way from home. You be careful out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be mad. That was just an old traditional gesture that means hello, how are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray executes a hard, slapping, "up your ass" gesture.</context>
      <utterance>I see. Forgive my cultural ignorance.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse bursts into laughter in his raspy, staccato laugh. He walks off a few steps, picks up a spent shell and pitches it. His laughter simmers and he gets serious.</context>
      <utterance>Have a nice day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy didn't do it, Ray. I checked it out. You can stop taggin' my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's your sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY AND CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spiritual sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse fingers an eagle feather that hangs from his hat band.</context>
      <utterance>Gotchya. We just nailed a genetic match between the eagle feather left at the murder site and one in Jimmy's medicine bundle. It came from a white eagle. Same bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So did this one. Wambli is a rare and sacred creature. When someone finds a dead one, the feathers get around the res. We share everything. A lot of power in the eagle feathers. But you think that's bullshit too, don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse stares, a little surprised.</context>
      <utterance>-- Leo Fast Elk was sitting in the outhouse at Maisy Blue Legs when a car pulled into the yard. He came out, approached the vehicle then saw that the man behind the wheel was Jimmy. He tried to get back into the trailer, but the car came highballing at him. He started running for the open grass. With the car moving, Jimmy hung his shotgun out the window, took aim -- missed once, hitting the shitter -- fired again, and severed Leo's spine. Leo fell, rolled, and came to a stop in the grass. And some chicken feed. Stale chicken feed with four days mold.  Electromagnetic printing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was-te. 'Cept for one thing. Jimmy Looks Twice was nowhere near there. Ya see, when Jimmy was twelve years old, his mother and father was killed in a car wreck right down there near Elk Mountain.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see the connection.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray absorbs this with great interest.</context>
      <utterance>The connection is, it did a head number on him. He's petrified of cars. Won't drive. I've known him all my life, and he's never gotten behind the wheel of a vehicle. He rides passenger and he rides horses, and that's it. The man that shot Leo down was behind the wheel of a moving car.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not solid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray lets a pent-up sigh escape.</context>
      <utterance>You want solid? That one, single, print he left in the Badlands -- the one the FBI missed and then stepped all over -- it belongs to a man who walks heels first. Like a white man. Jimmy has a serious Ind'n walk -- ball of the foot first. The man who murdered Leo walked like a Wasi'cu.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse chews this over, unable to hide a nagging frustration. He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You're saying a white guy did it...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of them stand there, thinking this over. Ray takes out his notebook and starts writing. Crow Horse walks away, turns to face the propped up targets.</context>
      <utterance>When Leo was dumped out there in the Badlands, he was dropped on his back. Our man made an effort to turn him over, onto his face. It's an old Ind'n belief that if a dead man is turned face down, his spirit won't leave. And in the killer's case, it won't come back and jump all over his shit. That's an Ind'n thing a white man wouldn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To punctuate, Crow Horse slaps leather, draws his .38, and begins blasting at the milk bottles. He hits the bank. A tree. One of the posts. But not a single target. When he is done, he looks over his gun, disappointed. Starts reloading. Ray starts laughing, looking at the missed targets</context>
      <utterance>And that's the way it is. Write it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Crow Horse, sees that he's serious, and follows him toward his motorcycle.</context>
      <utterance>You laugh all you want, Breed. Sunset tonight, I get my man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse turns toward Ray, and creates a long dramatic pause.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Crow Horse. I'm listening. I'm listening to the trees, to the stones. Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he hauls his bulk onto his motorbike.</context>
      <utterance>Damned if I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse winks at Ray as he slams the kickstart. To no avail.</context>
      <utterance>But the Old One. He did a Yuwipi ceremony last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old man? He's gonna tell you who killed Leo?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go catch Jimmy, Ray. Really. He's gettin' away. Go ahead, go get him. I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hey, those are my sunglasses you're wearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Crow Horse nails his kick start. The BIKE ROARS alive and the Indian works the throttle hard, leaving gravel and black exhaust. Ray stands there, drifting between logic and instinct. He looks at his watch, then starts at a slow, thoughtful shuffle toward his car.</context>
      <utterance>Grandpa traded with me.  Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Crow Horse, searching for a hint of lightness. But there is only great reverence as he watches Ray blow smoke upward.</context>
      <utterance>He says, back behind Red Deer Table, where the Elk-People-used-to-live... there are strange creatures from another world who eat stones... and who will kill anyone who crosses into this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray smirks as he passes the pipe to Grandpa. Crow Horse looks nervous. Grandpa offers the pipe to the directions and then disengages the bowl from the stem. He speaks again. Crow Horse translates.</context>
      <utterance>He says, in the Yuwipi ceremony last night, he saw you... going back into the land beyond Red Deer Table. I was with you. But that was all the Spirits let him see so he doesn't know if you were killed or not. But he thinks you probably were.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandpa leans closer to Crow Horse and whispers some Lakota.</context>
      <utterance>Go to the land where the Elk-People- used-to-live and you will find the answers you came here looking for. But you must go as two. That is the vision. I have spoken. And this is so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Crow Horse, nervous.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to trade.  He likes your watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that,  It's a Rolex.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Grandpa is already holding out something to offer. It is a cigarette. Grandpa offers it again.</context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse tells the Old Man. Grandpa speaks Indian.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, this is --  -- this is very, very expensive. It's --  Tell him this is an expensive watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray buries his hands in his jacket pocket. No way. Crow Horse signs to Grandpa "no." Grandpa gets up, crosses between the two young men, up to the TV set. He turns it on.</context>
      <utterance>He says, you need to go on Indian time. He says your watch is ruining your life anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red Deer Table, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me: heavy duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They step into the yard and Ray stops, turning to Crow Horse</context>
      <utterance>Heavy, heavy duty. Taku Wakan. Wanagi Spirits. It's one of those few places we'd never go to as kids. Still don't. Some of the old people say Crazy Horse is buried back there. We have to go Ray. Together. Like his vision.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walter. When I fill out my 302, do I say that evil spirits are killing everybody on the reservation?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- no. No offense to the old man. I appreciate you trying to help. But I put my ass on the line coming out here, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you expect to hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Native American myths and legends. I'm with the FBI, Walter, remember? Not National Geographic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you call myths, we call our history.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not real.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's real to you? Wall Street? Capital Hill? Now they are myths.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't be dicking around here. That's all I'm saying. I don't carry crystals, I don't wanna come back in another life. I just wanna do my job, and do it right, and get the fuck outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse drives "Indian" home with a hard finger in Ray's chest. Ray knocks his hand away, explosively. Crow Horse is ready.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't no Indian. You're a Sal Mineo Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The old man is standing at the top of the steps. Ray and Crow Horse are YELLING OVER EACH OTHER, and hands are up.</context>
      <utterance>Knock it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stands there, one hand up in defense, another poised to throw a punch. Bewildered, he stares at the old Indian holding onto the porch railing.</context>
      <utterance>Will ya knock it off? You're actin' like a couple of old women.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For cryin' out loud. Knock it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He speaks English.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only when he's really pissed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Grandpa goes back in, screendoor slapping shut behind him. Ray is just staring, his jaw dropped. Crow Horse starts laughing. Harder than he has yet, and Ray starts walking toward his car in fuck-this steps. He gets into the car, closes the door and looks out the open window at Crow Horse. The Indian moves first.</context>
      <utterance>Come inside. Watch TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray lifts his arm off the door, and springs his middle finger up at Crow Horse. He holds it there for a long moment just looking at the big Indian.</context>
      <utterance>Don't accuse nothin' of not bein' real, Little Weasel. Cuz the only thing around here that ain't real is you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care of yourself, Walter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray checks the time on his watch then guns away. Crow Horse stands there, watching him go. Eventually he shuffles back toward the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>Likewise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SA SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch taps some ashes into an empty coffee cup. They sizzle in cold residue.</context>
      <utterance>We've gotten word that Jimmy has been trying to hook up with Maggie Eagle Bear... but some of the Warriors have been sending word to Jimmy that she may be an FBI operative. So he doesn't know where to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo. It's working.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's out of room. All the reservation exits have been watchdogged. We got him. I give it twelve hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agents all look at Ray. A pin can be heard falling to the cheap carpet.</context>
      <utterance>Well we better use those twelve hours to apprehend the right man.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The right man? Talk to me, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch nods, lights another smoke, intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>Whoever dusted Leo, dusted him from the driver's seat of a moving car then drove those eight miles to the Badlands. Jimmy Looks Twice has never been behind the wheel of a car. It's a known fact out here that he's petrified of driving. His parents were killed in a car wreck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not very solid.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was also a print found in the Badlands that indicated diagetic locomotion. Heels first. Jimmy's walking pattern doesn't match. He has a distinct Indian walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SA MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAUGHTER. Except for Cooch who just stares at Ray, digesting what he has said.</context>
      <utterance>Indian walk? You been smoking hooch in the peace pipe, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sherman looks at Cooch.</context>
      <utterance>They don't smoke hooch in The Pipe, Miles. They smoke something called kinickinick, it's like a tobacco.</utterance>
   <speaker>SA SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're right about X21 being a Washington Redskin, that's for sure. What else, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys want a soda?</utterance>
   <speaker>SA MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, a Coke. You buying?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Ray's buying. Sherman? Coke?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch nods to Ray and Ray follows, gathering up some paperwork He looks determined as a terrier.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... no. No, Cooch, I'm working on a coffee here. Indian walk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Genetic ditto on evidence found at the site with evidence you found in his belongings. An incontrovertible motive. And definite footprints on Jimmy Looks Twice at Maisy Blue Legs house.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did we get that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today. And now you -- there's a dog in the van --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I know. I fed it, and I can't get rid of --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't sent here to go off on your own detail, Ray. You were sent here to assist in a Selective Operations Unit. These regional agents are inept -- that's why they were sent out here to The Graveyard, to Indian Country. I need you behind me, Ray. Not pulling against me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not trying to pull against you, Cooch. I've just been having nightmares about the way Leo was killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your first homicide, that's gonna happen, Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanna make sure no one else gets done in that way because we were in bed with the wrong doer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray studies him with a smile building. Cooch shrugs, sips some soda.</context>
      <utterance>Ray. I never get into bed with somebody unless I know for sure. Just the way I was raised.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Alright...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods, starting for the van.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, alright, alright -- fuck you -- give a yuppie a badge and he wants to take over the world. Go get a tail on Eagle Bear, and stay with her. Cuz Jimmy's gonna show. And I want you to make the collar.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns. Cooch looks at him for a time. It is a warm look.</context>
      <utterance>Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll sleep around a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Cooch.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gets in and pulls the dog out. The dog sits at roadside, tilting its head at him, confused. And he pulls out. It runs after him.</context>
      <utterance>And get rid of the dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastards...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I could think of was... not here. I don't wanna eat it on an Indian Reservation, three thousand miles from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns around in his seat, looking off across dry land.</context>
      <utterance>He's out there. He's out there playing Sitting Bull with us. I want the motherfucker so bad I'm getting a bleeding ulcer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It may have been Maggie's way of saying "get off my ass."</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's that subtle?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eagle's claws and a bear's balls that's what her profile says.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's running now, too. These fucking people like to run, don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does. Ray is turned around in his seat, staring off into the distance.</context>
      <utterance>-- Cooch. Woh. Stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tread matches. It's the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Excited, Ray walks off, scanning the area.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray picks up a handful of stones, sifts them in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>But this doesn't make any sense, Ray. If it's just been sitting in this dry wash for seven days... why the hell didn't we find it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch watches him slosh shoes first through a rut where the water shimmers a foot deep or less.</context>
      <utterance>Because this isn't a dry wash.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns, shucking up mud.</context>
      <utterance>It's the Little Walking River.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it was full of water when I drove by here three days ago. Full. I mean... a river.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray doesn't hear Cooch. He stares past the SAC at the long wide chasm, wet in some places, arid in others, and what he hears must be an echo in his head.</context>
      <utterance>The Little Walking River. You're right. This is part of it. So whoever sunk this car didn't compensate for drought. Goddamn.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch is listening to a TRANSMISSION across his radio and he walks off a few feet, exchanging information with the</context>
      <utterance>Listen to the water...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Little Weasel, Federal Bura of your Imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ. You're hammered. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right about the old man. His power's long dried up. He's supposed to be a medicine man but he won't go see the people. He says we changed, and we don't listen. Well, he don't go out and talk no more. I haven't had a drink in three years but I just turned my sobriety chip into that man behind the bar, and this Hoss is gettin' watered.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut the shit. You shouldn't be in here, Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuz I'm a skin?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuz you're a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell me. You tell me who went to the B.I.A. -- Bureau of Indian Annihilation and said I was messin' with your case, man. I don't give a goddamn about your case.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse shimmers his black eyes onto Ray.</context>
      <utterance>And I don't give a goddamn about whether you wear a badge or not, Crow Horse, but I didn't cut you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still after Jimmy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found prints at Blue Legs' place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray just looks vacantly at Crow Horse. Crow Horse resents the vacancy.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Jimmy's prints are there. But they cross over Benjamin Black Star's prints. And he wasn't there until six o'clock the mornin' after to get eggs from the chickens. So Jimmy wasn't there til the next day. Follow?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Look, man... you better bust Jimmy and get out before somebody shoots up more than your car next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time I'll be ready. You get the word to who ever it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray doesn't blink.</context>
      <utterance>I can't, Hoss. I don't talk to FBI's.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you was sent here cuz you're a good cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse leans toward Ray and speaks more quietly.</context>
      <utterance>No. I was sent here cuz I'm Indian. And a good cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is fuming. He can't believe what he's hearing, what's being insinuated, but he's giving it thought and it's getting him angry. He smashes a hand down on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You ever think that maybe you was sent here cuz the FBI's need one good reason to take out the entire Warrior Movement. And what better reason than one of their men, gettin' blown away on the res. A low-rent, expendable public servant sent in to take a bullet for his country.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sick of your shit --</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Standing over the booth is a long, tall RANCHER'S SON. Rangey with red curly hair tucked under a BLACK HILLS CLASSIC cap, and arms built by tractor work. And behind him, TWO OLDER RANCHERS fall in. And ANOTHER YOUNG MAN, grinning with amusement. Ray and Crow Horse look up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sick of the two of ya timber niggers spewin' off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, we don't speak United States.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCHER'S SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I do. Get the Jesus up, and get the Jesus out or I'm gonna go out to my truck and come back with my hardware.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woh, hold on there, Jack, you're --</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCHER'S SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray realizes now that they think he's Indian, too. Crow Horse sees this revelation and complicates it by suddenly speaking LAKOTA to Ray. The rancher grabs Ray by the cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>-- don't "jack" me, Squanto. I'll bury your lazy ass right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCHER'S SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray decks him. Backhands him in the solar plexus then, lays a burner of a Quantico roundhouse to his ear, knocking him across the bar, over a mop and bucket and into sawdust. The others start to fall at him but someone has jumped in, holding them back, and sticking himself in the way. It is Brooks. The old timer Ray met his first night here.</context>
      <utterance>I'm talkin' to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No, you butt holes! He ain't skin! He AIN'T SKIN!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rancher's son who is coming back with a broken beer bottle, slows his step and shifts his eyes from Brooks to the young fed There is a lot of heavy breathing. But no talking just yet. The young rancher eyes Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah he's In'dn. Miniconjou Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCHER'S SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray just stands tense, staring at him. And it's strange. Because he hasn't really looked like he has any Indian blood up to this moment. But dressed the way he is, and his eyes glaring, face drawing tense, he might pass for a breed although that's probably the Italian. But Ray doesn't answer the question. Crow Horse starts laughing. Drunkenly.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't Indian?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER RANCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so damn funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's just that the cavalry used to always threaten the Lakota. The cavalry ain't around anymore. The Lakota still are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCHER'S SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse rises and walks unsteadily across the floor, leaving the bar. Brooks is whispering to the others, apparently about who Ray is. The bar man comes up to Ray, holding a tray, on which sits a shot and a beer. Ray looks at it for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I got no trouble tellin' where you come from, Fat Red.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAR MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray knocks the tray out of his hand, spilling beer and whiskey all over the bar man and the locals around him. And he walks out, leaving the locals confused.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. On the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No plates. No registration. Serial numbers removed. And all prints washed off by the river. That's great. This is turning out to be a walk in the park, do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before he hangs the radio. IT CUTS BACK IN.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray. X22.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read, Cooch.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember that upside down flag back at Jimmy's house? Somebody took it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray seethes quietly as he drives.</context>
      <utterance>They took it down, set fire to it, and threw it on the doorstep of room 13 at the Buffalo Butte Motel. Your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray keeps driving.</context>
      <utterance>We traced the number of the truck that dumped it, and it belongs to one Maggie Sanders, also known as Maggie Eagle Bear. She's been all over the res, riling up the traditionals, telling them not to break, and to keep Jimmy in hiding. She's a problem now. And she's yours. Get her off the reservation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they all right under here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two-hundred and sixty-seven men, women, old people. And little ones like you. Many killed running along that road you see there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were they runnin' to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A place called The Stronghold.  They died for a dream. But you live. You are their great-great grandchildren and you live. We have to honor their dream. Of protecting the Mother Earth. And being proud of being Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie smiles at the boy.</context>
      <utterance>My mother told me that they call us Indians cuz Columbus was lookin' for India when he discovered our country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHILDREN LAUGH. All but one boy, who isn't paying attention. He is staring up at a hill, off in the distance. MAGGIE'S POV: on the hill, a figure stands, hands in his pockets, hair blowing in the wind. Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, let me tell you something, Henry: just be glad he wasn't looking for Turkey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're praying at the grave. Do you wanna join us? A long silence. The voices carry in the wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at him. They lock eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No, Maggie. But you're gonna have to join me for a ride. I'm taking you to Rapid City.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if exhausted by the thought, Maggie sits down on the bluff, looking out at the children who are still singing the song. As she speaks, she begins digging her fingers in the earth. Ray stands over her.</context>
      <utterance>So much power. I see it in your eyes. This... hunger for power. Or for what you think is power.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You burned an American flag today. And left it for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You desecrated it, it had to be burned.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I desecrated it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie lifts herself onto her knees and looks down into the small hole she's dug. She picks up a little pine cone.</context>
      <utterance>You forced an innocent man to run like an animal. You've tried to poison my people's hearts against me with your manipulation, with letters I never wrote... you've been watching me eat, work, raise my family... wash myself in the river. And now you're here, arresting me at a sacred place.  In your eyes, that's power.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie rises, dusting off her hands. She looks him in the soul.</context>
      <utterance>So I plant this tree for you. And I take all this stuff that you've laid on me and my people, and I put it in this hole with this pine cone.  And I bury it. Cuz ya know what it is, Ray? Bullshit. And shit is fertilizer.  And The Mother will turn your lies into something that lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray just stares at her, struggling with what he's feeling, what he's hearing. What he's supposed to be feeling. Silence hangs between the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>That's what power is, in the Indian way.  Take me to Rapid, Ray. I'm the enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at him, considering. Then toward the long dark silhouette of a mountain range across the plains.</context>
      <utterance>If I told you... that I think Jimmy's innocent... but I'm in over my head... would you believe me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While she looks off at Paha Sapa, Ray stares at her profile.</context>
      <utterance>See those Black Hills out there, Ray? When the people lost the land in 1868, the government took everything but those hills. They allowed us to keep those Black Hills, to live there. Signed a treaty. Until they found gold. Then they told us we had to leave because of National interest. They broke that treaty. Anyone who fought or spoke out against it, wound up dead or in jail. And the people wound up here. On a reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Ray with an ironic smile, and she catches him transfixed.</context>
      <utterance>While up there, in the Black Hills... they carved the faces of four presidents.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your relatives must've taught you something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NO.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie starts giggling.</context>
      <utterance>My father never told anybody he had Indian blood. But he still used a few Indian words around the house. He called me Washee. Said it meant... good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wa-shee is like... a dumpling. Like tallow we put in stew. I think he was calling you chubby boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie is laughing as she looks back at the children who are no longer singing. Ray reaches inside his jacket and takes out five polaroids. He shuffles them as he ponders. He hands one to Maggie who has caught herself opening up too much to the Wasi'cu.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at the first photo and says nothing. She hands it back quickly. Ray won't take it.</context>
      <utterance>You ever see that car before?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's it belong to? Maggie ignores him. Ray studies her reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie is looking away. She picks a long blade of grass and smoothes it in her hands. Ray looks at her a moment longer then rises, dusting off his jeans, and standing there. He thinks for a long moment, pinches the bridge of his nose, then looks out at the Black Hills, pensive.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, Maggie...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie watches him go. Looks away. Then watches him again.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't see you today, Maggie.  Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stops. She stands on the bluff, her hair riding the wind and her eyes searing. And then her lips do something that might qualify as half a smile. A sense of humor rising up through anger. Survival humor. Ray looks at her for a long moment. And then he walks on, leaving her there.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye... Wa-shee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone who fought or spoke out against it... wound up dead or in jail. Ray looks out the window toward the monument.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exhausted, Ray lays his head back on the seat, and lets a long, constricted breath free. THUNDER ROLLS like the slow, deep roar of some giant bear up in the hills. He opens his eyes, looks out the window. POV: rain is coming down, and Maggie is getting the children into the back of her truck. She helps them get a tarp over their heads. Then as Yellow Bird pulls himself into the cab of the truck, she hefts the wheelchair and two boys load it in. She gets in, starts up, and rolls off down the sloping road.</context>
      <utterance>That was 1868, Maggie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I... I fell asleep. I can't believe it. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never turn your radio off! I thought I was gonna find you scalped! Damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Cooch. I lost Eagle Bear --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cooch runs to his car. Ray fires the car's big engine and takes off behind Cooch who is driving a fed Chevy. CRAZY</context>
      <utterance>-- never mind Eagle Bear. We've got Jimmy nailed. Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandpa looks at Sherman, ignores him, looks back at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Where is he, Sam? Where's Jimmy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With RADIO TRANSMISSIONS crackling through the house, Cooch comes back down the hall, and heads to the door.</context>
      <utterance>He's a medicine man, Ray. The "spiritual leader" of the Warriors. That right, Sam?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray starts to follow but he sees Sherman pick something up from near Grandpa. The 500 year-old turtleshell rattle. Grandpa's eyes widen slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Trailer's clean, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been the one making it rain like that, out there, Sam?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, put that down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you make Jimmy outrun an M-16, Sam?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sherman drops the turtleshell rattle on the linoleum floor. Then drives his heel into it, CRUSHING the fragile turtleshell. Ray grabs him and slams him into the tin wall. Miles gets between them, grabbing Sherman.</context>
      <utterance>Sherman!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOOKS TWICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another fed, pushes his face into the mud, cuffs him behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>Brother, the old man told me about you. Listen to me: what was Leo trying to tell me? He wanted to meet me at Maisy --</utterance>
   <speaker>FED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With two FIVE MAN SWAT TEAMS swarming the area, and six agents pushing Jimmy toward a car, Cooch stands there in the pouring rain, looking relieved. Ray stands near him, looking abhorred.</context>
      <utterance>Save your speeches for prison, Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray watches Jimmy as he is shoved into the back of Miles and Sherman's car and driven away. He is twisting around in his seat to look at Ray. Desperately. The SWAT teams disband, return to their vehicles.</context>
      <utterance>Damn. That's one hard running Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch heads to his car and Ray starts shuffling toward his as if he is dared by it all. He is looking at the trailer and there on the rickety porch is Grandpa. He comes down the steps slowly, holding his hat on against the wind. He watches the cars pulling out. Ray walks over to him, looking sick.</context>
      <utterance>It's over, Ray. I aged five years. But it's over. At least I'm gonna look like I'm ready for the advisory desk. Let's go get a beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And after a moment of locking gazes, he starts for his car,</context>
      <utterance>Look... I'm not who you think I am.  I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns.</context>
      <utterance>Out back that way... is a placed called Wounded Knee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man is speaking with conviction. With power.</context>
      <utterance>I was one years old there when our people were shot down. My mother hid me in the snow in a blanket. One of those killed was a Holy Man called Wakiyan Cante -- Thunder Heart. They killed him while he was running for The Stronghold. It is his blood -- the same blood that spilled on the grass and snow at Wounded Knee -- that runs through your heart like a buffalo. Ray frowns, disturbed by this story.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stands, almost paralyzed, digesting this. He turns and looks into the old man's sharp eyes. Grandpa has closed his eyes, and as he is pulverized by the rain, he turns his face toward it and from way down in his belly, he begins to SING IN LAKOTA. And it is too much. Too weird. He wheels and hurries to the car. Gets in, and beats a fast path out of the old man's lonesome patch of land. BLUE HEAT LIGHTNING knifes the sky. THUNDER ROLLS, and rumbles into POOL BALLS --</context>
      <utterance>Thunder Heart has come. Sent here to a troubled place to help his people. That's what I am told. Maybe you're right and I am mistaken. Your mind is young, mine is old. If so, so be it. Ho Hecetu Yelo. I'll speak no more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch throws a mock punch at Ray and he mock blocks, tired. He musters a smile. But he isn't all there.</context>
      <utterance>Buffalo burgers and cold beer, Raymond. Don't worry about the sign out front... you don't have to be Indian anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods. Cooch lets a few agents walk past, LAUGHING. He speaks quietly.</context>
      <utterance>You have a fever. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen: when we get back tomorrow, you're gonna find Tully laying a promotion on you. S.A.C. He wants to prove that his yuppie agents are making good. He's offering you New York. Tell him you want Atlanta.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray tries to break a smile again. Cooch cups his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Cuz I want New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch stares at Ray. The younger agent looks like he indeed has a fever.</context>
      <utterance>Cooch. They sent us out here because the place was being neglected. Now, all of a sudden, there's two five man SWAT teams out there tonight. Bell Huey choppers flying all over the place. Federal occupation to catch one guy. Why, Cooch? What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch hurries across the rain-swept street. Ray steps inside and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>National security, Ray. Get some sleep. Tomorrow, we fly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sticks his open badge, gold eagle wings, near the crack. The door closes. Then unlatches and opens. Yellow Bird sits there in his wheelchair, tiny tobacco bundles in his lap. He's been tying them.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Richard Yellow Bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pivots his chair to allow Ray room to enter.</context>
      <utterance>The Washington Redskin. Thought you'd be gone by now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be a bitch getting around in that wheelchair. How long you been in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I got a iron pipe put across my knees, man. Fight with three wasi'cus, ya know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At Sioux Falls Pen?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that was Leavenworth. This --  was Sioux Falls. What ya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray walks across the room, his eyes on a covert mission.</context>
      <utterance>Leavenworth a tough joint?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever try solitary confinement?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Can't say that I have, Richard. Richard do you know why I'm here?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Washington sent ya. I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird stares at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Washington sent me, Richard. They sent me here because this whole thing has been fucked. Do you know what I mean when I say this whole thing has been fucked, Richard?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird looks at Ray, strangely, shaking his head. Ray starts to look like maybe the game's not working. Like maybe this doesn't add up. But --</context>
      <utterance>An arrangement was made between you... and us. Do you remember that arrangement?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray lets a tense breath out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here, ain't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for long, Richard. You got early parole under the stipulation that you would help us in a situation, and you didn't deliver.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sits in a busted chair, reaches down to his ankle holster and pulls out a .38. He holds it, resting it on the arm of the chair. He strains to look out through the boarded window. Yellow Bird fidgets in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up out of the chair, Richard.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with you people? Why do ya have to fuck with my head all the time? I came through, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up out of the chair, and walk toward the backdoor, Richard.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get thrown in solitary until I don't know my own fuckin' name, and then you people tell me I can beat nine years if I help you. I helped you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird stands. He takes a step forward. Limping. He's got leg problems but he can walk. Heels first. And bowed. But he can walk. He is shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Get up!</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said I'd never see FBI again, and I'm livin' with you fuckers. I don't feed ya information on the Warriors, it's back to the pen. I don't do this, back to the pen. Your word against my word. Against a con Indian's word. I really got a chance, man, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sent me here, Richard because they said you didn't hold up your end of the arrangement, and I have to transport you back to Leavenworth.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck, man? What do you people want? I did what you wasi'cu's told me to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird wheels.</context>
      <utterance>Leo Fast Elk... is alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. No fuckin' way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is trying hard not to reveal his horror at this confession, at this understanding of the machinery. He sits there with his gun, blinking away sweat that beads at his brow. Yellow Bird is weeping in a highpitched voice that doesn't match his great bulk.</context>
      <utterance>I blew his back out with a buffalo gun, that's how I know! Now you're gonna say I didn't, so you can throw me back in solitary?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The men who came to see you at Leavenworth. The one's who made the arrangement... who were they? Maybe I can talk to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miles. Three other suits. That's all I know 'em as -- suits. Were you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turned Leo over on his face. But the coyotes must've turned him back over, man, cuz his spirit is out. It's out, and it knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about spirits? You ain't no In'dn.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo knew something heavy and was trying to tell Jimmy. But you must not know how serious it was or you would have delivered. Do you realize what Leo could have told Jimmy?! Do you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took him out before he got the chance. He didn't say nothin' about Tashka Sha. And now his spirit is in the dirt. Forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Tashka Sha, speak English, speak English!</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray grabs onto these words, rolls them silently on his lips And now Yellow Bird is getting suspicious of the fed.</context>
      <utterance>Red Deer Table! What's with you, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Wait -- what are you doin'? You ain't a FBI. You ain't the law. Let me see your -- Ray snaps out his gun, straight-armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird jumps back, raising his hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the fucking law!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep talking, Yellow Bird...</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then HEADLIGHTS pierce the gaps in the boarded windows. Yellow Bird collapses against the wall, bangs his head off it. He lets a long, pained, cry escape from under his breath and he begins a slow slide down the wall, to the floor. Ray peers out the cracks in the boards.</context>
      <utterance>All I know... is I did what I did... and I ain't in solitary, gettin' pumped up with downer, gettin' beat to shit. But I tell you what, Suit. Take me back. Cuz I can't take this shit no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLOW BIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gets up, putting his gun away and heading to the door. He stops and looks back at the Indian, sitting on the floor, clutching his knees, staring into the kerosene flicker.</context>
      <utterance>Man, I don't know who the fuck I am no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yellow Bird looks at him, his glasses foggy, his face contorted And Ray leaves.</context>
      <utterance>You and me both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps knocking. Nothing. He hurries back down the steps, starts around the back of the house and something attacks him, leaps at him from the dark, knocking him off his feet, into the grass. Hits him again. But as quickly as he falls, he rolls, throwing up his hands and blocking a savage kick aimed for his face. He traps the boot, twists it and drops the attacker onto his back. In a matter of seconds, he is on top of the man, sticking his gun in his throat. He grabs a flashlight from his jacket and shines it in the man's face. Crow Horse. Breathing like a wild animal.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five-hundred year old turtleshell rattle...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crow Horse, listen --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Maggie? Where'd ya take her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nowhere. I'm trying to find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got Jimmy. Let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crow Horse, listen. You have to come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? So you can get rid of me, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse lies there, breathing heavy. Ray on top of him, still clutching his gun.</context>
      <utterance>No. So we can do what the old man said. Red Deer Table, Walter. We have to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods, concentrating. After a time:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe the old man's visions are still strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they come in dreams, these visions?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Dreams. Sometimes durin' sickness. Vision quest. Sweat Lodge. Ya never know when.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Crow Horse doesn't respond, Ray looks over and finds him staring. He looks back to the road. And when he looks back at Crow Horse, he is still staring at him.</context>
      <utterance>Just before we caught Jimmy... I had a dream that I was being chased. And I was running with other people. Old- fashion Indian people. I got shot in the back. Like Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At Wounded Knee. I mean, that's where I was, and that's where the dream was. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were running with the old ones. At The Knee. Heavy duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was just a dream, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sonuvabuck! What's with you, Man? Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse looks out the window as if to avoid Ray who is confused by the Indian's smoldering. After a moment, Crow Horse looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'. Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had a vision. You had yourself a vision. A man waits a long time for a vision. Might go his whole lifetime and never get one. And along comes some instant Indian with a Mastercard and brand-new shoes, has himself a vision.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a full-blood Oglala.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've driven a long way. Where is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it was just a dream. Ya know, just one of them, what do ya call 'em, fitful dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse feels better. He looks out the window, nodding. But it doesn't last long.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Fitful dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You had a vision. You got sign from the old ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you want me to do?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray brakes. Crow Horse is looking past him. Ray turns. The spectacular mesa that we have admired with every sunrise, looms massive now that we are under it. Moonlight falls on it. And the HEARTBEAT DRUM pulses from it.</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sweeps the light along, walking faster, and then something frightening occurs. Something... some unseen thing snags him by the leg, sucking him into the Earth with a horrible GUSHING</context>
      <utterance>Ain't prayer flags, that's for sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Oil?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uranium. Test holes. Somebody came in from the Nebraska side, and did some shotgun testin'. They're gettin' ready to suck this baby dry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we're doing here. National interest. National security. Only this time it's not gold. It's uranium.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're standin' on broken treaty ground, Ray. This ain't supposed to be here. It'll poison the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leo knew about it. Tried to tell Jimmy, get the Warriors involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they took care of Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray goes to another hole and sticks his arm in up to the elbow, sniffs the solution.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to the water... the river keeps goin' down then rising again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something strange in the moonlight. COYOTES. Some forty yards away, on a flat stretch of stoney ground. Six Coyotes, dancing in the shadows of rock formations. MOVING IN ON THEM as Ray walks forward, they circle... scatter... run back... circle again. Look straight at Ray, eyes glowing. And run.</context>
      <utterance>They're drainin' our water table. That's our life, man... Ray is looking past Crow Horse at --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looks down in disbelief.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray steps back, his boots squishing in solution and sealant and soiled water. He covers his mouth, stopping himself from getting sick. And then he explodes, YELLING.</context>
      <utterance>No. No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Clear Moon's house?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse crosses the street. Ray sits there, and he looks almost hurt by this statement. But he is the white man. But he is Indian. He lets a long breath escape, rubs at a temple. He takes out a smoke. Tries to light it. His hands are shaking too badly. But he gets it lit, and sits tense, looking in his rearview.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's time to beat the drum. You better wait here. He don't trust the white man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Shit's comin' down. He's callin' council fire. All the old chiefs and the warriors, too. I gotta be at Grandpa's place in two hours. We need to get the tribe together. We need to block this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse looks at Ray who stares dead ahead.</context>
      <utterance>What we need... is Richard Yellow Bird.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was a rare case of a brother getting a break in the courts. We did an honorin' song for him and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse snakes around toward the rear of the shack. Ray knocks at the front door. It is unlatched and it creaks open a little. Ray pushes it open and sees --</context>
      <utterance>He's looking at a few hundred years in Leavenworth. He's not gonna come out without a fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray reaches inside the car and lifts the handset. He takes a breath before pressing it to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>X21. Read. X21...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>X21. Come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Crow Horse who looks equally spooked. The agent clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Ray. What's your 20?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long, unnerving pause. No response from the other side.</context>
      <utterance>Reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing on the reservation?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray holds the handset down at his side, looking over the top of the car toward the Black Hills.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on my way back in. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray. Ray, don't let go now, Man. Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go to the council fire. I'm going back in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray swings in behind the wheel, starts the car, and barrels off recklessly down the rutted road, leaving Crow Horse behind.</context>
      <utterance>Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Le Baron is already out to where sight reaches farther than sound and silent white dust mushrooms skyward.</context>
      <utterance>Ray!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Cooch. When he speaks, his voice is dry.</context>
      <utterance>Couldn't sleep, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch crosses the room, and picks up Ray's jeans which look like they went through a sandlot tackle match in a mud hole. Ray tucks his clean shirt in; watching Cooch.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch walks up to Ray slowly and takes his face in his hand, turning it toward lamp light to study the bruise along his left eye, a residual from a Crow Horse hook.</context>
      <utterance>I had to finish something with Crow Horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods, and Cooch slowly breaks a smile. An insecure smile but a smile just the same. He starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>That's where you were. You had to go back and have it out with the Indian law...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch laughs in amusement and Ray's face crinkles into a grin as he lowers his eyes, wiping a paper towel over his face. And then, suddenly, Ray lunges at Cooch. He slams the Agent in Charge against the hollow wall, and holds him there. His eyes wild.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking hot head, we can get in trouble for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me what we were doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch suddenly explodes, throwing Ray off of him and sending him reeling back against the sink. He points a finger at his charge.</context>
      <utterance>We're running a cover-up and you didn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever put your hands on me again and you'll be doing the books for a baitshop in the fucking Everglades, Mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't tell me about Red Deer Table --</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- what the hell is Red Deer Table?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch's eyes go frighteningly cold. He can't believe what he's hearing.</context>
      <utterance>What is it? It's genocide, that's what it is. It's a Pay Zone for some U.S. corporation and a Dead Zone for the people here. Uranium, Cooch.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray says nothing. He just stands there, against the sink, breathing like a fighter against the turnbuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ. What are you doing? What the hell were you doing out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was a Selective Operations Unit, Agent Levoi. There is classified information pertaining to our national security. You don't question that, you don't go digging into that shit -- that's insubordination. Jesus Christ --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- if they mine uranium there, these people will have no place left to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were sworn in on the Constitution to protect federal matters, Ray. I don't know about uranium, I don't know about Red Dog Table -- all I know is we did our job. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We neutralized anybody with a voice. Leo, Jimmy... Eagle Bear. Anyone who was standing in the way of the land. Is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns to the sink, turns the faucet on to get some water on his face. The water only trickles into the basin.</context>
      <utterance>No. We neutralized enemies of the United States. Anti-American radicals who have killed federal officers out here!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray leans on the sink, watching the water start to spurt free. He shuts it off. Turns to look at Cooch. And it is then the door opens -- some knocking after the door is already opened -- and SA Miles enters.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Ray. You think I don't like the Indians? Not true. These were noble people but their day is gone. They're a conquered nation. They want all of America back but they can't even keep the garbage out of their own front yards. It's sad, Ray. But it's just the way it is. We have to function as a colonial police force out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gentlemen ready -- hi, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray doesn't turn from the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we're ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stops dead. Beholds the Tribal President who wears a western cut jacket and a strained expression behind his smile. He hole a hand out to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, there you are. The Sioux.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEAR MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stares at him, speechless. Horrified. What is he doing here? What about the council fire? Ray somehow nods. Then walks on to the Le Baron. Cooch gets behind the wheel of the car that Clear Moon sits in. Clear Moon's eyes follow Ray to the car.</context>
      <utterance>You got the troublemakers off our land. Good, Was-te.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse rolls his eyes toward the FBI agent. He has a gash behind his ear, and pink sand clings to the blood. He lifts his head, tries to form words.</context>
      <utterance>Crow Horse!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't no Council Fire, Brother. Clear Moon...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Come on. We gotta get off the reservation or we're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hoka Hey. It's a good day to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gets an arm under the big Indian, helps him up out of a jagged crevice.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit, let's get outta here,</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandpa...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray starts to get back in then hesitates. He looks out across the plains to see -- THREE FED CARS in the distance, fast approaching, dust rising. Ray gets in quickly.</context>
      <utterance>He hasn't left this place in twenty years. They got him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a renegade agent, Cooch? He gets off the reservation...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Cooch gets back in the car, drives off.</context>
      <utterance>-- he's not getting off the reservation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got us sealed. What are we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>We're going for The Stronghold.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Crow Horse exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>Ray. Can you hear me? You are fucked. There's no way out of this. If you won't listen to your own laws, then listen to this:  This is President Clear Moon. This nation does not want your sympathy. You cannot use this reservation as a sanctuary. Stop where you are now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you are trying to do is futile, Raymond. You have nothing. Nothing. Ray picks up the mic as he cranes to keep an eye on the rearview.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yellow bird... is gonna sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECORDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell do you know?  I blew his back out with a buffalo gun, that's how I know. And now you're gonna say I didn't and put me back in solitary?! Ray keeps the tape running into the radio as he drives through rugged Badlands. Crow Horse, stunned by the voice, eyes Ray as the tape rolls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse turns, sees what Ray is looking at. POV: The Stronghold -- a narrow opening in hulking rock formations. Large enough for a car to get in, and keep followers out.</context>
      <utterance>Walter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. The Stronghold. Get us in there, we got a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>just ahead, the earth is gone. A wavering heat pond turns out to be a crevice and they nose down into it, burying the front end in sand and rock. WINDSHIELD SHATTERS.</context>
      <utterance>We're in there. We're in there --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ray. Come forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray refuses to move.</context>
      <utterance>No way, Cooch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooch slowly, lets the bullhorn fall. Then the rifle. He looks back at Sherman who does the same, and all the way down the line, everyone dropping their arms under the threat of a lot more guns from above. And now Ray walks forward, collecting his gun. Anderson Chasing Hawk, one of the Warriors, runs down to Ray, breathless.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Cooch. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHASING HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray notices that Cooch is staring at him, hard. He shakes his head slowly. Strongly.</context>
      <utterance>All the exits are blocked. There's two more fed cars tryin' to get in. And some press.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chasing Hawk takes off, running, and Cooch watches in consternation. Ray just stands eye to eye with him, holding his ground.</context>
      <utterance>Let the press through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray nods, encouraged as they walk along. His eyes follow the helicopters.</context>
      <utterance>The people are already talkin' about their vote for a new tribal prez. They wanna vote for Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the water...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bought her some time, Kola. Ain't never gonna be over... but you bought her some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the dusty, dented Le Baron and stand there, looking at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Some Indian time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crow Horse offers a hand to Ray. He takes it in a white man's shake then follows Walter's cue into the Indian "allies" grip and slap. They hold it there, looking into each other's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Indian time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray ponders for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Where ya gonna go, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have to see what the visions say about that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray shrugs. Crow Horse discreetly gestures below his belt.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't have another vision...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray cracks a smile, a long time coming.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take care.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stands looking at him, searching for words.</context>
      <utterance>If you ever need a place to come back to and listen to the trees a little... we'll be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray goes to get in his car. But he sees someone sitting across the street on the trading post porch. The old man. Ray considers him for a moment then walks over. They lock eyes. Grandpa stares at Ray as if he's never seen him before, and then arcs a brow. He touches his sleeve at the wrist. Ray rolls his sleeve back to reveal his Rolex. Grandpa smiles and Ray strips it off. He hands it to the old man and his face crinkles into caliche earth. Grandpa holds the watch up in the light, admires it then puts it in his shirt pocket. He moves a flat hand through the air in the "done deal" sign language. Ray, a little surprised that he gets nothing in the trade, returns the smile and walks away. He gets to his car and wipes away two inches of dust from the broken windshield.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't no word in Sioux for goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE TRADING POST PORCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>where the elders sit, watching the dust blow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROW HORSE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will be here.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
