<movie id="563" title="Tin Cup">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo quickly pays Dewey and more quickly takes money from the losers. It's fast-paced, inane, time-killing gambling. Tin Cup looks over.</context>
      <utterance>Number one is the winner! Dewey has the winner. Pays five to two!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The regulars flap dismissive palms and mutter in the negative as they turn back to Romeo and the action at the bug lights.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you shitheels ever get bored?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup leads the regulars inside.</context>
      <utterance>... 'Cuz I got a riddle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The regulars silently look at each other, reluctant to reveal the heft of their brains.</context>
      <utterance>Takes about two ounces of brains to figure it out. Anyone think they got a brain with two ounces of brains in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Chrissakes, boys! A little self-confidence from the players' gallery. We ain't talking long division.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much we gotta lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to liven things up, Earl? That's a hell of an idea. Say everyone puts in twenty bucks and the pot goes to whoever solves the riddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to get the riddle, Tin Cup?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey. I'm the one asking the riddle. I already know the answer. I don't getta guess. Although... We could say if I get to five hundred bounces and no one gets the riddle, I get the pot. And I know what you're thinking. It's an impossible riddle. Well, It's not. It's an easy riddle. And if somehow by the grace of fluke luck I win, and you all don't agree it was an easy riddle, hell, I'll refund your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL, CLINT &amp; ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in... We're in... Count us in... etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup begins bouncing a ball on the face of his wedge.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, a man's driving down the road with his son and they get in a crash. Two ambulances come and take the man and his son to different hospitals. Son goes into the operating room, the doctor looks at him and says, 'I can't operate on this boy. He's my son.' How's that possible?  The clock's ticking boys...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father didn't sneak back in, right? He's still at the other hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That eliminates the most plausible theory in their minds. The men think harder.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't 'Star Trek,' Earl. No one beamed him aboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... if the father married the son's daughter --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a family riddle, Earl. Think clean thoughts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>4.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The regulars puzzle some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give us a little hint.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>All heads turn to take in the arrival of:</context>
      <utterance>The doctor's a woman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup misses the ball he's been bouncing, breaking the spell. The regulars wait for Tin Cup's response.</context>
      <utterance>The doctor is the son's mother. Feminists pose the riddle to reveal how deeply our sexual stereotypes run.  I take it you're a feminist?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, I've been called a lot of things -- but no one's ever saddled me with that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The regulars snicker, enjoying her one-upmanship.</context>
      <utterance>You might try being saddled sometime -- the smell of leather, the sting of a whip...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a humble golf pro...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I have a seven o'clock lesson.</context>
      <utterance>You're Roy McAvoy the golf pro? I pictured something... different.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I had a Doctor Griswold</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first thing you gotta learn about this game, Doc, is it ain't about hitting a little white ball into some yonder hole. It's about inner demons and self-doubt and human frailty and overcoming all that crap. So... what kinda doctor'd you say you were?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a psychologist -- in layman's terms call me a neo-Jungian, post- modern Freudian, holistic secularist.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins unpacking one of her bags, pulling out every golf gimmick on the market -- swing aid straps to pull your elbows together, a ball pendulum that hangs from your hat, a metal contraption for your feet, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inner demons and human frailty are my life's work. I used to practice in El Paso but I've moved here now...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're those?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ordered these from the Golf Channel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That stuff's a waste of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands there with contraptions coming from every limb.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure there are excesses and repetitions here, but I believe in the gathering of knowledge and I figured, well, there must be some truths about the golf swing illustrated by these devices -- and that you'd help me sort through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have dozens of golf videotapes, too... And a golf watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She deposits all the golf gimmick devices in a pile.</context>
      <utterance>Take it off. All of it. Now! You're a smart woman, for Chrissakes -- don't you know the work of charlatans when you see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I can always tell when someone is lying to himself, but I'm quite susceptible and frequently wrong when that person lies to me.  That stuff cost me over 200 dollars --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tees a ball, hands Molly her driver and steps back.</context>
      <utterance>Then it's 200 dollars of shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly takes a pitty-pat swing and whiffs, and mutters under her breath with the ease of a longshoreman.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Take a swing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, fuck...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly unloads a mighty second swing. The club head bounces off the mat. The ball sits untouched.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you talk like a golfer --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fuck...' 'Shit...' these are highly technical golf terms and you're using them on your first lesson -- this is promising.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup takes the club from Molly, motions for her to step back, tees up a ball, and rockets a drive into the night.</context>
      <utterance>Awright, wise ass, show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her back the club and tees up another ball. Molly just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup takes a deep breath -- this is his speech.</context>
      <utterance>Impressive. Y'know, I tend to process things verbally. Can you break down into words how you did that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'What is the golf swing?' -- by Roy McAvoy.  The golf swing is a poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes a love sonnet and sometimes a Homerian epic -- it is organic and of a piece, yet it breaks down into elegant stanzas and quatrains. The critical opening phrase of this song is the grip, in which the hands unite to form a single unit by the simple overlap of the smallest finger...  ... held lightly, a conductor's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>8.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>baton.  Lowly and slowly the clubhead is pulled back, led into position not by the hands but the body which turns away from the target, shifting to the right side without shifting balance. Tempo is everything, perfection unobtainable, as the body coils, now to the top of the swing, in profound equilibrium. And then a slight hesitation, a nod to the gods...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A nod to the gods?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the gods, yes... that he is fallible. As the weight shifts back to the left pulled now by powers inside the earth -- it's alive, this swing, a living sculpture -- and down through contact, always down, into terra firma, striking the ball crisply -- with character -- a tuning fork goes off in your heart, your balls -- such a pure feeling is the well-struck golf shot -- And then the follow through to finish, always on line -- The reverse 'C' of the Golden Bear, the steelworker's power and brawn of Carl Sandburg's Arnold Palmer, the da Vinci of Hogan, the unfinished symphony of Roy McAvoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What's unfinished?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a short follow through -- my swing can look unfinished.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some say it's because that's the best way to play through the winds of West Texas... and some say it's because I never finish anything. You can decide. The point is every finishing position is unique as if that is the signature left to the artist, the warrior athlete who,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>9.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly stares back, exhausted and intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>finally and thereby, has asserted his oneness with and power over the universe by willing a golf ball to go where he wants and how and when, because that is what the golf swing is about...  It is about gaining control of your life, and letting go at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez Louise...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is only one other acceptable theory of how to hit a golf ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid to ask. What's the other theory?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grip it and rip it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While I appreciate your poetic sensibility, Mr. McAvoy --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me Roy, Molly...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me Dr. Griswold...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tin Cup does. She tees it up.</context>
      <utterance>Roy... but at this point I think I'm more of the 'grip it and rip it' school. Hand me the driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waggles the club head, then takes the club back.</context>
      <utterance>Waggle it, Doc, don't forget to waggle.  Waggle... the club head...  ... it's a little relaxing ritual...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, lets the club fall.</context>
      <utterance>Let the Big Dog eat!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Big Dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The driver, the number one wood --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, woods are metal -- don't worry about it -- and the driver's known as the Big Dog and I'm just saying to turn him loose, let 'er rip, let the Big Dog eat!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swings. Tops the ball. It goes ten feet.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is, without a doubt, the stupidest, silliest, most idiotic grotesquery masquerading as a game that has ever been invented.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am, that's why I love it.  And if you hit one good shot -- if that tuning fork rings in your loin -- you can't wait to get back. She cracks one dead solid perfect out into the night. It felt great and she knows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the Big Dog ate something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did the tuning fork ring in your loin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't go that far.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always quit on a good shot. We'll call that lesson number one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her speech is delivered without judgement or rancor, so matter of factly that he's disarmed.</context>
      <utterance>If you're such a legendary striker of the golf ball as everyone says, then why are you, at your age, out here in the middle of nowhere operating a barely solvent establishment, ducking the I.R.S., collecting a few pathetic dollars to buy your next sixpack -- when you're capable of so much more?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I'm chocked full of inner demons?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads off to the parking lot. He stares.</context>
      <utterance>No, you're chocked full of bullshit --  Same time next week?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you mean I should try 'being saddled' sometime?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you being literal or was that some kind of Freudian type deal? Molly? Doctor?  What kind of saddle?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A class act there, boys -- probably the first actual `lady type' female ever seen on these premises --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, boss -- we got the Corpus Christi dog track on the dish --</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone's glued to the set. A greyhound race comes on from a remote Texas track on the gulf.</context>
      <utterance>This is yer dead mortal cinch lock bet with Do-reen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free money, boys, what does Doreen know about the fine art of Greyhound breeding?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All she knows is she likes the three dog 'cause his name is Pride of Odessa 'cause she's from Odessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How deep we in?</context>
      <utterance>Get ready for Oddessa-lation, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gave her twenty to one --</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only fifteen to one on the toteboard --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I got every other dog in the race. I'm just getting even with Doreen -- I'm not trying to clean her clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how much you stand to lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve thousand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said to shoot the wad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes on the monitor -- the dogs break.</context>
      <utterance>I said get even, Pod. I didn't say shoot the wad. We better see that three dog rolling on his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The starting box opens -- "THERE GOES THE RABBIT" -- the three dog breaks slow and trails down the front stretch.</context>
      <utterance>Except... if he breaks slow, he won't get creamed...</utterance>
   <speaker>REGULARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The one dog veers wide, going into the escape turn, annihilating the field. Dogs fly ass over teakettle like bowling pins, and --</context>
      <utterance>Three dog's dying, T.C.... easy money...</utterance>
   <speaker>REGULARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three dog clears the pileup, untouched, hugging the rail. It has a ten length lead as it moves down the backstretch and past the toteboard. The race is over -- the three dog wins. Deathly silence. Somebody flips OFF the TV. Finally, in a lame attempt to lighten the moment, Romeo speaks --</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Roy, you were saying you felt a little flutter for this doctor lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I was saying that... just before I was interrupted by... bankruptcy -- a development that the 'Doctor Lady,' as you call her,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We lost everything, boss! We owe Doreen twelve thousand bucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I been dating too many big-haired blondes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them big-haired blondes are a lot smarter 'n us...  ... how we gonna pay her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo doesn't realize the truth in his own response.</context>
      <utterance>You underestimate me, Romes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bad habit I picked up from knowing you so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>TURK</speaker>
      <mode>THE BOUNCER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tin Cup, Doreen's looking for ya --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the strip joint.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure she is...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they pass the stage, even the Naked Dancer interrupts her moment with a bunch of guys offering dollar bills --</context>
      <utterance>Busy man, Courtenay, busy man --</utterance>
   <speaker>NAKED DANCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tin Cup! Hi, sweetie!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And backstage they go, easily waved through by another bouncer. They come up to a dressing room door. And knock. A voice from inside.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, honey -- lookin' sweet...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That better be you, Roy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doreen...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking particularly lovely this evening -- This is nicer than the leopard suit --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut the horseshit, guys. So... the one and two dogs always run wide and the three dog always breaks slow, so I figure there's gonna be a big ol' pile of fur at the turn and the three dog's gonna tiptoe around it and walk on home... I was right.  You owe me twelve thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We going to pay you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>16.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tin Cup squirms as Doreen babbles a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're going to pay me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tin Cup finally digs into his coat pocket and produces some official-looking papers. He hands them to her.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know I finally got rid of the leopard suit thing -- it was so retro, y'know... it's not easy being a post-modern stripper...  So... twelve big ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doreen leans forward to examine the papers. She looks at Tin Cup with surprise.</context>
      <utterance>There. With equity and inventory it's worth twelve grand... more or less.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is how you think you can settle up? By deeding me your driving range?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only on condition you don't sell right away, and me'n Romeo keep our jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in the world would I want with your stupid driving range?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, Doreen can only stare dumbly at Tin Cup, caught off guard by this unexpected turn of fortune. Then she starts to consider the idea more seriously.</context>
      <utterance>Equity, inventory, cash flow... not to mention an enhanced stature in the community, and prepaid membership in the Salome Chamber of Commerce.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are your labor costs?  Payroll, Roy. What do you pay</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>17.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>your help?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see... the tractor kid gets five bucks an hour. Romeo, he gets ten cash --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you pay yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doreen nods in a way Tin Cup finds threatening.</context>
      <utterance>Myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hit golf balls all day... when you're not breaking for beers or corn dogs or to gather the guys and lay bets on which crow flies off the fence next.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're referring to my managerial salary?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, he sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm referring to every nickel you snatch out of the till and every bag of beer nuts you lift from the rack, is what I'm referring to.  I'll say it's worth ten and you still owe me two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still got two grand to pay off. And I can't see my new salary of seven bucks an hour plus lessons getting it done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But your clubs are your livelihood.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CAR HORN SOUNDS from outside.</context>
      <utterance>Well the hood ain't too lively at the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo opens the door, and steps outside.</context>
      <utterance>Whoever it is, tell 'em I'm in Houston on business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo steps outside to greet Simms. Warily.</context>
      <utterance>David Simms! What you doing in town?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo is evasive.</context>
      <utterance>Romeo! It's been awhile. Is Tin Cup around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's on business in Houston... You supposed to be out playin' on the golf tour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>whatever.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you tell him I'm in town for my big charity best-ball tournament, and I got a spot for him when he comes back from...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a spot for Tin Cup? I thought you hated him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romeo! You wound me. I'm fond of the guy, going way back to our days at University of Houston, when we won all those titles together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms won't be drawn into this adolescent competition -- he's too comfortable with himself and his success.</context>
      <utterance>He says he carried you on his back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have much craft back then -- just a little native ability. Roy's a great ball- striker....</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup suddenly appears in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>I want to win my own tournament, and he can help me if we can manage to behave like grownups together. Tell him that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the catch?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no catch. I put together a tournament with an elite field and a half-million dollar purse, and I'm tired of seeing all the money head out of town.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then make more birdies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you on my team.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't that friendly a guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're playing Cottonwood where you once shot fifty-nine, where you can shoot sixty-five in your sleep 'cuz you know every bump on every fairway, every subtle break on every green --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You an' me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup can't quite believe this offer from his old nemesis but there aren't many options out there. He grabs Simms's hand and starts pumping it, gushing with enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>Me an' you -- like the old days.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Well, put 'er there, partner! These two homeboys are gonna show the world what golf in West Texas is all about!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup wilts like a time-lapsing daisy. His hand falls free of Simms's. Words fail him.</context>
      <utterance>No, Roy. I didn't mean I want you to play with me. I just want you to caddie for me, read my putts, club me, that kinda stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caddie? Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I got a network to cover --</context>
      <utterance>I can't bring a guy in off the street to play in my tournament. It's a big-time event, corporate sponsors, thirty dollar tickets...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay you a hundred for the loop, five percent of any earnings --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the hell outta here! Take your goddamn color coordinated corporate sponsored soul and get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms heads to his car.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, just thought I'd offer you some work...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simms!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms nods in agreement, and exits. Tin Cup stands there with Romeo, feeling humiliated.</context>
      <utterance>We'll take the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>POV SHOT - SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>drives away down the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That man stands for everything I hate in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean like... success?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I told you, it was more'n you had in the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>STADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms swivels his head around to look at Tin Cup.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... I had to go for it after your caddy said he could get home from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms looks away, at the shot he's facing: a two hundred fifteen yard carry over water. He looks back at Tin Cup, shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta hand it to you, Roy. For fifteen holes you've seemed to grasp the concept here: I'm trying to win and your job is to help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five percent of your earnings does numb the gag reflex.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the seven iron. I'm laying up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can make that shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The smart play's to lay up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These fans didn't pay thirty bucks to watch a tour star lay up on a short par five.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sitting on a two shot lead with three to go, and my partner's in his pocket. Suddenly, par's a good number. Gimme the seven Iron.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms reaches for the seven iron. Tin Cup clamps a hand over the club.</context>
      <utterance>No way. You're going for the green. These fans paid good money to see golf shots they can't hit, not golf shots they feel shitty about themselves for having to hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirteen years on tour and you're still a pussy. Hit the fucking one iron, Dave.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms removes Tin Cup's hand from the seven iron and grabs the club, stepping up to address the ball. Tin Cup mutters to the gallery.</context>
      <utterance>Thirteen years in a driving range and you still think this game's about your testosterone count.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the remark summons gallery voices suddenly urging Simms to go for the green. Simms motions for Tin Cup, as</context>
      <utterance>Two-fifteen to carry, and the tour star's laying up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>24.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>if reconsidering.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you're gonna editorialize, do it on the other side of the ropes. I got no qualms about firing your ass right here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms steps back to his ball with the seven iron, and: 16 Stadler's still standing back where he hit the shot into 16 the lake. MICKELSON and GARY McCORD, the other team in the pairing, are there with him. Romeo, Stadler's caddie, stands just behind them. McCORD (to Mickelson) I know you could knock it on from here, I'm just saying that caddie's been drinking muddy water if he thinks he can.</context>
      <utterance>Fire me? Hell, I should fire you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the players look at Romeo as: Simms dumps his seven iron shot safely down in front of the water to a smattering of polite applause. Simms tosses the club back to his bag as Tin Cup retrieves the divot. And:</context>
      <utterance>He can.</utterance>
   <speaker>STADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms looks several yards back where Stadler is still standing with McCord and Mickelson.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dave! We in a hurry?</utterance>
   <speaker>STADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause I just bet McCord and Mickelson that your caddie could knock it on from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to win a tournament, pardo.</utterance>
   <speaker>STADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But I'm getting five to one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here ya go. Take a hack at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stadler waves his arms to summon a cheer from the gallery. Tin Cup puts down Simms's golf bag.</context>
      <utterance>Balls versus brains, Roy. You hit that shot, just keep walking, 'cuz your ass is fired. Tin Cup mulls over the warning, as: STADLER, McCORD, MICKELSON Come on, Roy! Your fans are calling!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he heads over to where Stadler and the others stand waiting.</context>
      <utterance>How you gonna fire me in front of all these people? Especially when I knock it on the green.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>26.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gary McCord moves toward the camera and takes the microphone. McCORD Peter, I've done a little background here -- this unfolding disaster's a driving range pro named Roy McAvoy, who everyone calls Tin Cup. Locals claim he he was a pretty good college lick and knocked around the mini-tours... 20 Tin Cup steps up to hit the shot. McCord lowers his 20 voice. McCORD ... but I guarantee you, he's about to suffer brain arrest. He's thinking about the cameras and the gallery and the water, and all that gray matter between his ears is turning to goo... and incidentally, Stadler's got it booked at ten to one... Tin Cup swings, and: 21 The CAMERA PICKS UP the ball arching high and true off 21 the club. It lands on the green. The CROWD ROARS... and the roar becomes deafening as the ball rolls three feet from the pin. KOSTIS AND McCORD He's not that good... he's definitely not that good... (etc.) 22 BACK TO the course -- a scuffle's breaking out. 22 David Simms helping some guy over the gallery rope. Simms walks the guy back to his golf bag... and now Tin Cup understands what's happening, and:</context>
      <utterance>break for a side bet, here --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a hike, Roy -- the loop's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup reaches for the bag. The guy holds onto it. They wrestle briefly, as Simms sighs with fatigue and looks for a marshal.</context>
      <utterance>You can't fire me. How can you fire me? I just knocked it stiff from two fifty. Gimme that bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup gives up wrestling when he sees a couple marshals approaching. He turns his anger on Simms.</context>
      <utterance>Security!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup goes after the bag again. The guy still hangs on. The marshals arrive, and begin to wrestle with Tin Cup. He goes berserk... a WWF battle royal.</context>
      <utterance>You just hit the shot that took you out of the money. Welcome to life on the tour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORGE MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A brief highlight of Tin Cup, going crazy, wrestling with the marshals and replacement caddie.</context>
      <utterance>And finally Sports Machine brings you a bizarre incident...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>MALE LAUGHTER greets the shot, and:</context>
      <utterance>Driving range pro, Roy `Tin Cup' McAvoy...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tin Cup! You made the news!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had it all to do over, I'd still hit that shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The look comes over your face, you would bury yourself alive to prove you can handle a shovel. Tin Cup looks over at Romeo for signs of an implied pejorative. But Romeo's just washing and scooping balls... and looking badly in need of perspective.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Romeo looks over... and he decides that Tin Cup is the one in need of perspective.</context>
      <utterance>You know why I'd still hit that shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cuz it's the only way you can beat David Simms. 'Cuz you never got over that he is on tour and you are not. 'Cuz you get that look on your face...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo nods, holding his peace.</context>
      <utterance>No...  I'd hit it again because that shot was a defining moment. And when a defining moment comes along you define the moment or the moment defines you. I did not shrink from the challenge. I rose to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup cringes at the memory, then moves for the high ground.</context>
      <utterance>1981, Fort Washington Golf Club, Fresno, California, final round of the Tour Qualifying School...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was playing to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A defining moment when you tried to hit the same impossible cut</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>29.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>three wood into the wind from a hilly lie -- four in a row out of bounds -- until you finally pulled it off and tapped in for a thirteen.  When a twelve woulda got you on the tour! That was a defining moment and the definition was shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greatness courts failure, Romeo. That's why most people, in their whole lives, never ever reach for the brass ring, never know when to dig deep and try for the impossible shot...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup tosses down another Maalox cocktail.</context>
      <utterance>You're right about that, boss, but sometimes... sometimes... par is good enough to win.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a business proposition. I'm offering you my winnings from all them tournaments this summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In exchange for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She dances away from him, not exactly sold on the idea. She dances back to him, reclines a leg on the partition, and moves her face opposite his.</context>
      <utterance>My driving range back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy, I'm not as dumb as my hair makes me look.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She twirls off. He chases her, beer and entries in hand.</context>
      <utterance>They ain't all strictly minor league. One of 'em pays almost two grand!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait, Doreen. You gotta do the math, and you gotta look at how good I'm playing. I hit the shot of the tournament at the best-ball. They put it on national TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MUSIC comes to an END. The club is momentarily silent.</context>
      <utterance>And what does that tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what does that tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It tells me you took an unauthorized day off. Next time it happens, you're fired. In the meantime, I'm putting in a time clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not punching in no time</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I early?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. McAvoy, I can appreciate that you have a fairly laid-back, relaxed lifestyle -- but I have hours to keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tees a ball for her and steps back. She's staring at him, half-amused.</context>
      <utterance>A former paramour once ascribed my fluid sense of time to being born under the sign of Pisces -- something about floating through the universe --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You amuse me, Roy. But I'm the only woman in America born after World War II who thinks astrology is a crock of shit.  Now let's see if the Big Dog'll eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm waggling...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly addresses the shot. Her stance is rigid, overly</context>
      <utterance>Set up to the ball like I showed you last time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves around behind her to reposition her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Quit trying to wring that club's neck, Molly. Show it a little warmth and compassion...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, this game's about trust and touch and letting go. So while I'm subtly enhancing your technical prospects, why don't you tell me all about your personal life...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup's hands move down to square her hips. He's discreet and professional.</context>
      <utterance>It's none of your fucking business, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your boyfriend's a golfer -- that's my bet -- and he's why you're taking this game up. Hell, I probably even know him --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>DAVID SIMMS steps onto the range.</context>
      <utterance>Get your hands off her ass, Roy. And, as Tin Cup's hands recoil in alarm...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, sweetie...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not him...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crushed and bewildered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's taking her to Miami for the fucking Doral! How am I supposed to compete with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you are having a bad week.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must think I'm such a nothing, such a loser... a lousy driving range pro living in a Winnebago, making five bucks an hour plus lessons.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She don't know you live in a Winnebago.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reflects deeply while Romeo shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she sure as hell knows I ain't taking her to no Doral for massages and mimosas all weekend. I gotta do something with my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta rise to a level worthy of the women that think I'm a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you could go out and win The Open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romeo, that idea has promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We talking about the same tournament? The U.S. Open? The Biggest golf tournament in the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not just the biggest golf Tournament in the world; the most democratic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it's open. Anyone's got a shot at it. You just gotta get past a local and a sectional qualifier, and unlike Doral or Colonial or the A.T.T., they can't keep you out. They can't ask you if you're a garbageman or a bean- picker or a driving range pro whose check is signed by a stripper. You qualify, you're in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then you pay out of your own pocket to go there and get all nervous and intimidated --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's intimidated? I just told you I'm gonna win the damn thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't got the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got every shot in the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mental game. The head game.</context>
      <utterance>I said you don't got the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suggesting I err on the side of excess?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always go out to shoot zero. Sometimes you pull it off. But you can't play like that at the Open. You win by taking what the course gives you. You win by being humble, which you aren't, and patient, which you never will</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>35.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup comes over to the couch, sits down, and puts an arm around Romeo.</context>
      <utterance>be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, since you're the authority, How'd you like to teach me how to be what I ain't and never will be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't ever listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This time'll be different. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, man. Right now you don't even got the money to get your clubs out of hock.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... my sticks may be in a pawn shop, but I got a rake and a hoe at the range.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo removes an old golf bag from the trunk. It contains a rake, a hoe, a baseball bat, and assorted garden tools.</context>
      <utterance>Let me get this straight -- you're going to play me for four hundred dollars with those?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll give ya two a side... I got the title to my car as collateral.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in that piece of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's cuz you think of it as transportation, Boone. Think of it as bragging rights. Think of yourself sitting around the bar crowing to your buddies about the Cadillac you won off Tin Cup McAvoy.  They'll forget all about the Winnebago you lost to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No mullies, no gimmes, no bumping the ball -- And he rips a drive down the fairway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup selects the baseball bat from his golf bag. Romeo hands him a pink ball and Tin Cup shows it to Boone.</context>
      <utterance>Nutted it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be playing a Pink Lady today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup moves over to the tee markers.</context>
      <utterance>That little pink fag ball supposed to rattle me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he tosses up the Pink Lady and fungoes it long and straight down the fairway.</context>
      <utterance>Not unless I knock it by you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boone knocks an iron onto the edge of the green.</context>
      <utterance>Yep, I caught this thing way the Hell on the toe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive for show, putt for dough, big shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boone's a little rattled by Tin Cup's insouciance.</context>
      <utterance>Did you hear that, Romeo? Boone was being profound! He has revealed to me the essential mystery of golf! Drive for show, putt for dough...  Louisville Slugger, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got Boone shakin' already --  Front left bunker's your best angle to the pin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses up the ball and fungoes a lazy fly ball.</context>
      <utterance>Front left bunker -- plugged lie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup holds up a hand like a gallery marshal requesting silence.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see a legitimate swing. No scooping.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand, please. Gallery, please, stand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>38.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>positioning the blade at an odd angle. He hacks at the ball with an unorthodox chopping motion. The ball pops up in the air, lands on the green, releases and rolls up a foot from the hole. Boone's jaw drops. Tin Cup hit an impossible shot with utter ease and facility.</context>
      <utterance>He addresses the ball, choking down on the hoe,</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup trades Romeo the shovel for the rake, takes the pin out of the hole, and pool cues the putt home. Par. Boone looks at his own sixty-foot putt and he knows he's just been had... utterly, embarrassingly, and thoroughly. Without a word he counts four hundred dollars from his roll and drops it on the green.</context>
      <utterance>I'll finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the hell off my course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, swami, your job is to teach me patience and humility, not to advise me on my love life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head up the street under a collonade toward Tin Cup's waiting Caddy.</context>
      <utterance>No. My job is to get your head straight so you can qualify for The Open, much less win it. To get your head straight you got to forget about the doctor lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not all my thinking occurs below the belt. I actually stand for a few things beside where my next romantic interlude is coming from.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup blinks silently a moment, feeling slightly cornered.</context>
      <utterance>Then you got no problem telling the doctor lady you can't teach her no more till after the Open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo responds with a Spanish curse.</context>
      <utterance>That would make an issue of something that ain't an issue. Besides, I'm focused.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, this is my quest!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhh... your quest... chingaso...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where I stand up for all the little guys everywhere who've had their fill of soulless robots like David Simms --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He may be a soulless robot but he's a rich, happy soulless robot with a beautiful doctor lady girlfriend who's got you by the huevos --  Besides, how is getting into the U.S. Open gonna change what she thinks about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll prove to her that I'm not who she thinks I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you are who she thinks you are! Look, I don't bet on a horse with a hard-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard-on?! Hard-on?! Hard-on?! Here, touch me, feel --  I don't feel nothing! Here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, ever since I let her dump my ass she just can't resist kicking me in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should treat her more like a lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After she ran off with that Dallas banker?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did that after you let her dump you. It wouldn't kill you just once to tell her she's beautiful, she can dance, she's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>41.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romeo... are you sweet on Doreen?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of deep sighs. Two losers with fluttering hearts.</context>
      <utterance>No more'n you are for that doctor lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, Romeo, just great... just when I need you to be my friend and coach, you go get all gooey about one of my ex-girlfriends who just happens to be our boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody comes to me for help on their love life about women is already too far gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a golf image relaxes them into their comfort zone.</context>
      <utterance>I don't recall asking you for advice.  Women are tougher to figure out than a feathered one iron from a tight lie --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually if you open the club face a hair and play it off your back foot --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Romeo... I wasn't really seeking golf tips...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all I'm good for -- but you can count on me for that, at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far off the back foot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Golf is so much easier than life.</context>
      <utterance>'Bout three balls...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ready to charge forth in pursuit of my mythic destiny and I can't get time off work to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no expert, but it seems to me that the `pursuit of a person's mythic destiny' is not the sort of thing that a person needs to get off a five dollar an hour job in order to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm stuck. Buried. My life's a plugged lie in a kakuyi bunker with a tight pin position on a green with a stimp meter reading of thirteen.  I need help. I need advice. I need counsel...  I need a shrink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know no shrinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the doctor lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't ask advice about the woman you're trying to hose from the woman you're trying to hose!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hose?! Hose?! Get your mouth outta the gutter! This is a matter of the heart!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't do anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup slips into the main office while Molly consoles the weeping woman.</context>
      <utterance>I know... I know... wait in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy... are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need therapy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do? I mean... to do it ... therapy... I mean, how do I start doing... it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs and plunges in.</context>
      <utterance>In parlance you might understand, just kick back and let the Big Dog eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, let 'er rip...  Suppose there's this guy. He's standing on the shore of a big, wide river. And the river's fulla all manner of disaster, like alligators and piranhas and currents and eddies, and most people won't even go down there to dip a toe. But on the other side of the river's a million dollars, and on this side of the river there's a rowboat. I guess my question's this: What would possess the guy on shore to swim for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He's a hell of a swimmer, see. His problem's more like... why's he always gotta rise to the challenge?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a juvenile idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand what I mean by the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're talking about you and what you like to call your inner demons, Roy, that human frailty you like to blather about, not some mytho-poetic metaphor you come up with in a feeble and transparent effort to do yourself credit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'mean you're gonna make me feel lousy? I came here to feel better -- what kinda therapy is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have any inner demons. What you have is inner crapola, inner debris -- garbage, loose wires, horseshit in staggering amounts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't just some jerk driving- range pro who drinks too much booze and eats too few vegetables.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're being defensive -- cut to the chase and tell me why you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'm smitten with a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. Is she smitten with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you asked her out?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's seeing a guy. I don't know how serious it is, but the guy's a real horse's ass, in my opinion...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you shared your heart with this woman -- maybe asked her out to dinner -- then it would force these issues out in the open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid she'll say no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh... so what you're saying is that all your speeches about swimming across the shark infested waters are really just about your golf game -- not about your personal life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I didn't know we were gonna get into my personal life!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is therapy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, jeez, I know, but I didn't think it was that kind of therapy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you expecting? Ann Landers?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's rather simple. Those risks that you love to take on the golf course, the risks you talk so passionately and poetically about -- you need to apply those risks to your personal life with the same passion.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should ask this woman out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should risk coming right over the top and snap-hooking it out of bounds left.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Risk hitting it a little thin and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Godsakes, Roy, that's enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S'okay...  Look, just walk up to this woman, wherever she is, look her in the eye with those big beautiful green eyes of yours, let down your guard and don't try to be smooth or cool or whatever -- just be honest and take the risk -- you can do it! Tin Cup rises with new confidence. He does several deep breathing exercises, trying to work up the courage. She stares at him. And he walks right up to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Griswold -- I think I'm in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>47.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the moment I first saw you I knew I was through with bar girls and strippers and motorcycle chicks, and when you started talking I was smitten and I'm smitten more every day I think about you -- and the fact that you know I'm full of crapola only makes you more attractive to me because usually I can bullshit people but I can't bullshit you and in addition, most women I'm thinking about how to get into their pants from Day One but with you I'm just thinking about how to get into your heart -- Molly was clue-less. She just stares.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stunned, eh? So what about dinner and we can talk about `us' and if we have a future and how to drop that horse's ass boyfriend of yours --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy, slow down --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I just hit a eight degree driver off a cart path here, I'm staring eagle in the face --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup is knocked off his horse. Into deep rough.</context>
      <utterance>This is a terrible mistake!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm acting from the heart so I can't make a mistake?! Right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong. Aw, shit...  I am one horrible shrink... jeez... I didn't know you were talking about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's frustrated and at a loss for words.</context>
      <utterance>Would your advice have been different?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crushed, Tin Cup heads to the door, stops and turns.</context>
      <utterance>Session's over. You better leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna qualify for the U.S. Open and kick your boyfriend's ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. She just sits there.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you think of me, you should know that your boyfriend hates old people, children, and dogs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup hits another shot, totally focused.</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd it go with the doctor lady, boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she was a par three, I'd'a made a nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stroke and distance, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo backs off to let the man practice, and Clint asks:</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clint turns and nods approvingly to the rest of the regulars.</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills. His divots got to look like dollar bills. 'Course Moe Norman hits divots like bacon strips 'cuz he come over the top, but that's gettin' too technical for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They murmur approval, but Earl catches Clint's eye and jerks his head at Tin Cup, indicating Clint isn't doing his job as group spokesman. Clint takes a step forward.</context>
      <utterance>See that, boys? He's hitting dollar bills. Tightening his game.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This remark penetrates Tin Cup's concentration. He turns with a smile to the regulars.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, something us shitheels want you to know, Tin Cup, is uh, well, we been to see Doreen, and we told her we'd stage a customer's strike if she didn't give you time off to win the Open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You perverts did that for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We believe in you, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup looks at the beaming faces of the regulars and smiles broadly.</context>
      <utterance>And if you get past the local qualifier, we gonna sponsor you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with big smiles, they move each other back so as not to mess up Tin Cup's concentration. And he pulls out another ball, mutters dollar bills, and hits another perfect shot.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, boys -- a man couldn't have better friends. Now move the hell back and shut the fuck up. You're messing up my concentration.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A KNOCK at the door. He's startled.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Debt collection? Process server?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>51.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens -- Molly enters. He's surprised but well- settled into his bath of cynicism.</context>
      <utterance>Ex-flame? Jesus, I'm clean.  Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you've got a beautiful swing --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And big, beautiful green eyes -- I'm a beautiful guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came here to apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I counseled you, you did exactly what I said, and I just... poured cold water over your effort.  I didn't get it. I'm a terrible shrink, probably... I should've never got out of real estate -- actually I should never have left Ohio for that cowboy in Armarillo -- have you ever been to Amarillo?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cowboy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not as romantic when you're actually with one -- a wrangler, y'know -- so of course the oil man in Dallas looked great after that -- I don't know what I was thinking... That's when I went to the gulf and ended up in, well, trailer sales and then all those condos in Corpus Christi -- the bottom fell outta the market and I needed a new gig --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new gig?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Therapy. I took all the classes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>52.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm licensed, y'know.  Oh God...  Mind if I smoke?  Anyway, I'm flattered you asked me out. I can't accept because I am involved with David and I haven't seen any evidence that he treats old people, kids or dogs badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a little carried away, I guess. I shoulda just layed up, made my par, and moved on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I want to propose something -- as long as you understand this is professional -- we're not going out together --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tee it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can help you with the mental aspects of the game. You've got Romeo to be your swing doctor, I can be your head doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you said you were a lousy shrink?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah... I'll improve.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got no money to pay for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll trade my services for golf lessons and help you through the qualifying. If you get into the Open, well, you're on your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be with David.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. A deal. It's the best they can do.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STARTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The regulars applaud and whistle and shout way too many "You the man's!" as Tin Cup steps onto the first tee, followed by his Sancho Panza, Romeo. Tin Cup is feeling on top of the world, at his cocky best.</context>
      <utterance>... the next group... Roy McAvoy, Salome, Texas... who will be playing with...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya feelin', boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm feelin' like par's a bad score, podnuh -- fifty-eight's within the realm!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, the doctor lady's here --</utterance>
   <speaker>POV SHOT - MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>standing not far from the regulars.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't I tell ya? She's gonna be your guru partner. You handle my swing mechanics and she handles my brain mechanics.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long as you keep your dick out of it --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>then...</context>
      <utterance>Me an' the 'big guy' have an understanding. He's gonna lie low till I get in the Open -- then...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Big Dog'll eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup steps up to the tee, a couple quick limber</context>
      <utterance>The Big Dog'll hunt, that's for sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have to help him keep his head on straight --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can, you be the first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does have the occasional tendency towards self-destruction it seems.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup waves and motions to his team.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't occasional and it ain't no tendency -- it's a fact of life that he gonna blow sky high, it's just a matter of when and how fast can the pieces be put back together.  Behind that twinkle in his eyes is nitroglycerin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Tin Cup uncoils a mighty drive with an elegant stroke, fully confident and smooth. The gallery applauds.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet in the gallery! A man's trying to do his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly leans to Romeo just before they all head down the fairway and confides --</context>
      <utterance>Got my 'A' game with me today, folks... you're in for a real treat!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find him mildly attractive when he's obnoxious and arrogant like this --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>49 He nails a two iron straight as a string. 49</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>50 He rifles another drive into the stratosphere. 50</context>
      <utterance>Nutted it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>51 Putt after putt drains into the jar. 51 52 CLOSE ON the SCOREBOARD -- The red numbers (under par) 52 are going up quickly as every shot he hits is dead, solid perfect. Minus one, two, four, five, seven...</context>
      <utterance>Ben Hogan? Who's he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLINT/EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the man, Tin Cup! You the man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They bugging you, boss -- I can shut 'em up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way I'm swinging today,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>56.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Romeo is handing him a two iron.</context>
      <utterance>nothing bugs me -- except insufficient applause.  Gimme the lumber.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think two iron's safer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo looks warily down the fairway of a tight dogleg left par five.</context>
      <utterance>I said I want the Big Dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tight par five, out of bounds left... you don't want to hit driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going left of those trees. I'm going over those trees... with a little draw. That way I get home in two. That way I'm putting for eagle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need eagle to qualify! You need to get used to playing smart -- no mistakes wins the Open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup reaches for the driver. Romeo shifts the golf bag beyond Tin Cup's reach.</context>
      <utterance>Qualify? I want the course record! Now gimme the lumber!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You think I'm full of shit?</context>
      <utterance>You not going to listen to me? You don't care I'm trying to help?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna get penalized for slow play if you don't give me that fucking driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a head case, boss, always were, always will be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly an OFFICIAL steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's ask the head doctor. Dr. Griswold?  Dr. Griswold, should I hit the Big Dog or the two?</utterance>
   <speaker>P.G.A. OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soliciting shot selection advice is a two-stroke penalty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust your feelings, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup looks at the two halves of his driver, curbing his anger, not giving Romeo the satisfaction of a reaction.</context>
      <utterance>... Go ahead. Hit the driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I changed my mind. Gimme the three wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't clear the dogleg with a three wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo pulls out the three wood, snaps it over his knee, and tosses the halves on the ground next to the driver halves. Tin Cup turns with amusement to his playing partners, lest they think management has lost the upper hand with labor.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup reaches for the two iron, studies it a moment, frowns, and then: He snaps it over his knee. He dumps these halves on the ground with the halves of the driver and three wood.</context>
      <utterance>Guess I'm going with the safe shot, boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>58.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romeo stares, aghast. Tin Cup merely shrugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo warily hands Tin Cup the three iron. Tin Cup looks at it, frowns, then: He snaps it over his knee and tosses it on the ground. Molly leans over to the regulars.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I fan that two iron. Better gimme the three.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this normal behavior for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches in amazement as --</context>
      <utterance>The word 'normal' and him don't collide in the same sentence too often.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the three iron halves with the other halves, and steps past Romeo and sequentially yanks all but the seven iron from his bag. He snaps them over his knee, one by one, citing the crimes of each club with mounting absurdity and ire.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I catch that three a little thin...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps the putter in half and dumps it in the pile of</context>
      <utterance>And I've hooked my four iron...  ... and hit flyers with the five...  ... and shanked the six...  ... and skulled the eight...  ... and fatted the nine...  ... and chili-dipped the wedge...  ... and bladed the sand wedge...  ... and then there's Mister Three-putt...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>59.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, he reaches for the last club in his bag, the seven iron. The regulars hold their breath, thinking this is the end of Tin Cup's Open bid. But... Tin Cup smiles and caresses the seven iron affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>broken clubs at his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the tee, drops a ball, and hits it down the middle with the seven iron.</context>
      <utterance>But the seven iron, I never miss the seven iron. It's the only truly safe club in my bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You happy, Romeo?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo turns and starts walking away.</context>
      <utterance>No, boss, I'm tired... my life's too short to spend it watching you fall apart. I done it too many times.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this? You're quitting? First sign of adversity, you're quitting?  Anyone want to bet me I can't par in with a seven iron?  Doc? Take the bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy -- just shut up and hit the ball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>19TH HOLE WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beer for everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A toast is raised to their king, and Tin Cup eats it up.</context>
      <utterance>You the man, Tin Cup!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, boys, what'ya think was my best shot -- the seven iron on twelve, the seven iron on fourteen, or maybe it was the bunker shot on eighteen which, to my recollection was a -- seven iron? Much laughter. This is the Tin Cup they love.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You definitely the man!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd I do, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You failed miserably.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! I parred the back nine with a seven iron, I qualified for the regionals, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your job is not just to qualify for the Open, it's to prepare for the Open. My job is to help you prepare.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said to 'trust my feelings'!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you felt like breaking all the clubs in your bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't break the seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He smoked that seven, brother --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From what I understand, the U.S. Open is the most difficult golf tournament in the world played under the most difficult circumstances with the greatest players -- winning it means controlling yourself, managing your emotions, staying cool, not getting in a pissing contest with your caddie who, incidentally, quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He always quits, he always comes back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonetheless, from the mental aspect -- which is my domain -- you have regressed and are fumbling somewhere between delusion and denial.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Regression, delusion, denial'? You gotta use all this psychological language?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a psychologist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>62.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tin Cup turns to the regulars for support.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everyone turns to see David Simms enter the conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Have a bad day, Roy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shot 65 -- parred the backside with a seven iron.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>That's the question -- why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause he broke all his other clubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snapped 'em in two -- even the putter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Roy, I'm on your side here. We go way back... I hope you get into the Open, but if you don't play under control, you'll get slaughtered. Good players shoot 82 in the Open. You can't always go for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear to God, Doc, this guy is not who you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a well-known fact that if a camera's not on him, he treats old people and children like dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, don't forget the dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should go, David.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup's worst characteristics flare up, he won't let go.</context>
      <utterance>I think so...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever shoot par with a seven iron?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It never occurred to me to try.  C'mon, let's go. The car's over here....</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet you a thousand dollars against my car that I can beat you in any game -- any game, you name it -- with a seven iron.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a coward? You gonna lay up the way you did at the Masters last year?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGULARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms is a little drawn in, not so much by the challenge as the desire to shut up Tin Cup.</context>
      <utterance>Chickie, chickie, chickie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any game, I name it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, David --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to teach him a lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup takes her literally and rises, starting to unbuckle his belt.</context>
      <utterance>Why do men insist on measuring their dicks?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, awright! Let's measure,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>64.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God sakes, I wasn't being literal!  David, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Molly, trust me on this one. Call it part of his mental preparation for the Open, where the rough is deep, the greens are slick, and the nerves are shattered.  I'll take the bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Regulars cheer -- this is what they live for. Simms hands a roll of cash to Molly. Tin Cup hands her his car keys.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, jeez...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright! What's the game?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One swing each. Who can hit the longest seven iron --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Regulars whoop it up. Their man's a cinch. Tin Cup pulls a ball from his pocket, drops it right on the ground in the middle of the patio.</context>
      <utterance>It's a lock! I hit the seven like John Daly hits a three!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From right here, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are really being childish --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Molly, leave this one to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup takes a couple of swings to limber up, aiming out</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Griswold, I know what I'm doing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a full back-swing, opens beautifully, and launches a seven iron like a rocket out toward some driving range markers... to "oohs" and "ahhs" from his faithful. The ball lands at a 170 yard marker and bounces further.</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them signs are at least thirty yards farther -- that ball musta gone 220...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ball's about 2-2-7... toed it a bit... but it'll do...</utterance>
   <speaker>REGULARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup hands Simms the seven iron.</context>
      <utterance>Nearly 230 with a seven! Pureed it, baby, he pureed it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a minute to limber up, fine with me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms is still in a sport jacket, slacks, no golf shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your jacket off?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms drops a ball about where Tin Cup's sat. He stands above the ball and addresses it.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna need to muscle up, big guy -- give it the old steroid jerk... Simms is cool as ice. He smiles, then moves around to the other side of the ball, suddenly facing away from the course. This baffles everyone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REGULARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And David Simms hits an effortless seven iron out toward the desert, onto the lonely highway... 59 ... and the ball bounces and bounces and bounces, for 59 About three miles, forever. It's probably still going...</context>
      <utterance>What the hell you doin'? Wha's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She shrugs and smiles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the man, Roy...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You definitely the man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>P.A. ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Guys pull out singles and larger bills around the runway, placing them on the railing for the gyrating stripper.</context>
      <utterance>Bring out those bills, boys, if ya wanta see a little more of Sammantha!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, honey...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you qualified for the Regionals -- why you so down?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I broke my clubs -- don't ask why, my caddie's pissed off at me, I lost my wheels in a sucker bet, and my shrink thinks I'm a fool -- 'cause I probably am...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're seeing a therapist?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what's wrong with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only way you'd ever go into therapy was if the shrink was a doll and you were trying to get her into the rack --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so shallow. The Good Doctor and I are dealing with my regression and denial --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUY from the next table leans over, interrupting.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Tin Cup, what a crock. You got a hard-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You `Tin Cup'? Won the Local with a seven iron?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McAvoy? The Tin Cup McAvoy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only one -- thank God...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You looking for a game?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doreen can't keep his attention. Neither can Sammantha, who writhes only a few feet away.</context>
      <utterance>No, but I'd sure like to show you my grip...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you been seeing this `Good Doctor'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guy slides over to Tin Cup, quickly joined by his buddies.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Dor', the man's having trouble with his grip --</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup glances at the guy's grip.</context>
      <utterance>See, I used to play a real weak grip. But you look at Couples, he's got a left hand way over here...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guy nudges the COWBOY next to him.</context>
      <utterance>No, grip it like this, so you're holding on with the last two fingers of your left hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that? Tin Cup McAvoy says you grip a golf club like this, with these two fingers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy?  Roy? Tin Cup? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The grip and address are about 90 percent of the golf swing, so pay attention here...</utterance>
   <speaker>COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sammantha can't keep their attention, either, even though she's down to a G-string, inches away. At the height of the MUSIC, she stops dancing and looks down at Doreen --</context>
      <utterance>When you're done with him, can I ask you about my club position at address?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAMMANTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I doing something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Doreen heads to the dressing room, disgusted, but not at all surprised. She knows Tin Cup -- she knows men.</context>
      <utterance>No, honey, you ain't -- but a healthy woman's only got two choices in this world of ours...  Either fall in love with another woman -- or take up golf.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... And naked women dance before them, unnoticed.</context>
      <utterance>... Now the stronger right-hand grip can help ya draw the ball, which I plan to do at the Regionals next week in Tulsa... just shift the hand over a little bit... blah, blah, blah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get through the next 36 holes and we in the Open!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the yips and I ain't even teeing it up...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing to worry about, boys --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you ain't got Romeo?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need him till the Open -- he'll be back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't got the doctor lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a tape cassette.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, I got her. Right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't travel to Arizona for the Regionals -- she's got a busy practice, y'know... so she made me this tape to play while I'm out there... keep me calm, cool, and collected...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little James Taylor, little George Jones, little Kahlil Gibran, little this, little that... and a lotta the voice of the smartest chick I ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The good doctor herself...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we hear it or is it personal?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He punches into his deck and the Winnebago is filled with the sounds of MOLLY'S TAPE, beginning with George Jones... ... and the voice of GEORGE JONES takes us into...</context>
      <utterance>Since when is therapy personal, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... `Private victories precede public victories. You cannot harvest a crop before you plant it...' Kaboom! He launches a tee shot down the middle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... `How you view the problem, is the problem...' 66 TIN CUP chips into the cup. 66 67 TIN CUP drains putt after putt with confidence. 67</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>72 SCOREBOARD tells us we're down to the 36th, final hole. 72</context>
      <utterance>...`You can't have the fruits without the roots...' And Tin Cup just smiles and taps in.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You need birdie. I could shit.</context>
      <utterance>I think three under will qualify.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little more confidence there, Earl...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm a --</context>
      <utterance>I wish Romeo was here. I ain't cut out to do this. I'm a spectator by nature. An observer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up and hand me the Big Dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup takes the driver and uncoils a beauty.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Force is with me, pods...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need this one big time, Earl, whattya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks straight to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straight?! Thing's a roller coaster breaks four ways and dies at the hole -- you're blind!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I am blind... 20-60 in one eye -- and that's the good eye...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup studies the hell out of this putt. If it goes in, he's in the Open. He misses, back to Salome.</context>
      <utterance>I got a blind caddie... just hold the stick, Earl -- and be sure to pull it out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tin Cup shakes the Walkman and pounds his ears.</context>
      <utterance>... when the going gets tough, the, the, the, whirrrrrrrrrrr, the, the...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's abandoning me!</context>
      <utterance>Doc? Doc?  Earl, Earl -- the tape's jammed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah... I'm flying solo now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta make this putt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup stares endlessly at the long putt.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps up to the putt, still talking to himself.</context>
      <utterance>... just pick the line, feel the speed -- bad timing, doc, Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>76 He strokes the putt -- It starts right, curls back 76 left, straightens out, over the ridge, back again, endlessly...</context>
      <utterance>Like a million others you made in your life, Roy. Just see it going in. Just feel it... right in the back of the jar... just pull the goddamn trigger, you pussy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl's having trouble with the flagstick, shaking it, panicking, and finally -- he snaps it free, but... The ball stops dead on the lip of the cup. Tin Cup contorts in anguished body-English, then falls to his back like a shot animal.</context>
      <utterance>Pull the stick, Earl, pull it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the BALL falls into the cup with a CLICK -- and a</context>
      <utterance>Choking dogs die!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo gives him the silent treatment.</context>
      <utterance>Romes! You've come back!  You shoulda been there, Romes, I drained a 30-foot snake to qualify!  Earl gave me a straight read -- the thing broke half a dozen times -- missed ya, pods!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still nothing from Romeo.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, don't talk to me -- but you're still my guy...  It's a little late to be pissed off! We're in the Open! You and me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, be that way --  -- say... has Molly been around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you had the hots for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo stares back at that curious logic.</context>
      <utterance>What's this? Garbo speaks? Of course I have the hots for her and I'm doing a damn good job of keeping things platonic and professional till I kick Simms' ass and show her I ain't who she thinks I am because, in fact, I am who she thinks I am but if I win the Open I won't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't think her nor me nor the God of Golf his self can keep you from blowing up in the Open...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made it this far! I just got to hold it together for 72 more</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>76.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>holes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lotta triple bogeys out there waiting to grab your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Some chagrin.</context>
      <utterance>You're complaining again! Romeo's back! Whining, bitching, pissed off -- you're my man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't fall in love with Earl to be your caddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a wheezing heart attack waiting to happen -- cost me three strokes a side...  I carried my bag the last four holes. I love ol' Earl but I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, too, God damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As much as Earl?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Yes, yes, as much as Earl --  More than Earl!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I special?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo ponders it all.</context>
      <utterance>If you can remove the sexual connotations and overlay a golf theme, Romeo -- I am your Juliet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muy bien, Julietta. In that case -- I am your caddy once again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Podnuh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo sits back in the shade, still washing the thousands of golf balls in the rack, watching as -- 79 Tin Cup drops a bucket of balls on the hardscrabble 79 ground, pulls out a club and limbers up.</context>
      <utterance>Awright... now that we got that bullshit outta the way, I'm gonna hit me some balls and start oilin' that sweet swing o' mine for the big boys...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody heard from Molly, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it bad, don't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup addresses the ball and takes a swing. Everything looks normal in his swing, but... Thwock! -- the BALL squirls off to the side and RATTLES against a fence. Ugly.</context>
      <utterance>Somethin' about that chick...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm... little chili dipper there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unfazed, Tin Cup steps up to hit again, but... once more -- Thwock! -- Another horrible-looking squib to the right. Romeo stops washing balls and notices, watching Tin Cup. Thwock, thwock! -- Something's terribly wrong.</context>
      <utterance>Be sure to do that in the Open.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Concern crosses his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romeo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't no chili dipper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, boss, you got the 'S' word.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I doing wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thwock, thwock, thwock! -- Three more chili dippers. Our man definitely has the shanks. And he's panicking.</context>
      <utterance>Shanks are like a virus -- they just show up. Nobody can figure 'em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romes! Something's terribly wrong. What's your guess?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said it was a virus?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A woman can have the same effect.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep swinging...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never thought it would happen...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shanks is for us mortals, not</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>79.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>for the great ones...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup angrily throws his club out into the night and turns to the regulars.</context>
      <utterance>Esta muy feo... muy, muy feo...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CAR HORN HONKS -- All heads turn to see:</context>
      <utterance>Y'know why they named this game 'golf'? 'Cause the words 'fuck' and 'shit' were already taken!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, fellas!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doreen approaches the regulars, and we notice for the first time that there are a number of bags and packages with the boys.</context>
      <utterance>What is this? Everybody like to watch a train wreck?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in one of his pleasant moods, I see --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the shanks. We got the makings of a Greek tragedy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup drags his sorry ass to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Quit whining and get over here. We've got something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless it's a 'swing thought,' I'm not interested...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here to sponsor you in the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>80.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open. Me an' the boys have pooled our resources and come up with some cash so you can look and feel as spiffy as all them big-name pros.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I got the shanks --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and you obviously still have a hard-on for the doctor chick -- your face is all screwed up and tight like you haven't been laid in awhile --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it really that obvious?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup shrugs. She always has him outflanked.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a good look for you. Roy, your heart is not the only organ you wear on your sleeve. There's a certain, vulgar appeal to your transparency.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Tin Cup, we're trying to make you a presentation --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unwraps a tour golf bag -- Big gold and red lettering advertises "The Golden Tassel." Pastie tassels hang from all over the bag. Doreen sets it down proudly.</context>
      <utterance>Awright, awright...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the Golden Tassel to sponsor you at the Open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect me to pack that around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm carrying the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl steps forward with a golf shirt bedecked with sewn on patches and logos.</context>
      <utterance>It's worth four hundred dollars endorsement money to you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, Dewey got you First State Banking of Salome, and Clint got you Short-Haul Trucking and I got you Brink and Brown sanitation --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm being sponsored by a sewage disposal system?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jose steps forward with a golf cap, also emblazoned.</context>
      <utterance>We call it human resources management, Roy, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got Wally's Smokehouse for ya -- kind of a nice sign...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doreen and the regulars look at Tin Cup proudly.</context>
      <utterance>And since I couldn't get the post office to come aboard, me and my girl friend Muriel's gonna buy a fan club patch you can put anywhere you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to wear this shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This shit is us, man. You can't win without us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the pride of Salome!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I won't even make the cut!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your confidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's shanking his love life so he's shanking the golf ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be true love.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup surveys all the bizarre sponsorship loot, and starts loosening up. These are his people, after all,</context>
      <utterance>He's a goner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>82.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>and they're behind him all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, everybody, this is great. I'm sorry I'm acting so pathetic but my swing's never abandoned me before. I just need a little time to work it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything you want --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him some room, boys --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's my grip... maybe I'm opening up too soon... too late... coming over the top... no, dropping underneath...  Oh, sweet Jesus, why have you abandoned me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to stay, boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Romeo herds the rest of them out to their cars in the lot. And as they drive away, Tin Cup sits down, his head in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aarghh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Griswold... A moment of pathetic silence, then: Molly starts laughing -- He is destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The therapist laughs at her patient? Is that how it works? A man is laid bare before God and he's the butt of the cosmic joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of this shit might actually</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>84.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>work, y'know... I mean I think there's something to this hat with the pendulum golf ball thing... may be on to something here...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup lets down. The wind goes out of his sails and he loses his defensiveness.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Roy, Jesus... Quoting yourself, 'It is the paraphernalia for lost and desperate souls.'</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, God damn... a lost and desperate soul stands before you.  I assume I have the confidentiality of doctor-client privilege in regards to this outfit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the shanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you taking penicillin?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be treated! It's much worse than whatever you thought it was.  There's a glitch in my swing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's in Romeo's department?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks it's your department -- says it's a head thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well. I just came over to congratulate you on the regionals and return your car -- David says he doesn't want it, just wanted to make a point with you --  But I suppose we could have a therapy session right here and now</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want therapy. I want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy... I gotta get some air --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me --  Well, not right at the moment -- but listen to me. You're with the wrong guy. I'm the right guy. Everyone tells me my face is all screwed up tight as a drum 'cause I've been crazy about you from the day you showed up wearing this stupid stuff and the whole damn thing has both inspired me to get here on the verge of greatness yet it's also caused me to get the shanks which could humiliate me in front of a zillion people.  Such is life. So dump that phony bastard and come to the Open in my corner -- you can delay your romantic urges, which I know are lurking in there among the excess of brain cells you possess -- until the appropriate time...  Tell me you're not at least moderately attracted to me. Tin Cup stands there with the ball still dangling from his hat, the leather straps, the bucket, the arrows -- for the moment he's forgotten how stupid he looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have moments.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me which ones are my moments and I'll try to duplicate them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a moment. You look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Utterly exposed, completely vulnerable, the inner child trying to get out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My inner child needs spanking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always liked that part about saddling up, the smell of leather</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's thinking about it.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, let's have a drink. Call it therapy. Charge me 75 an hour. Little Cuervo, little Freud...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw... I gotta go.  Oh, I don't have a car, I need a ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a spot along the river's great to watch the sunset?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Not tonight' means maybe some other night?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean it like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consciously you didn't mean it like that -- but how about unconsciously, you're the expert, did you mean it unconsciously?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unconsciously, Roy, I don't have a clue what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel we're making progress.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck in the Open, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drives away, and we stay:</context>
      <utterance>Put your money on me, Doc, the odds are fabulous and God knows I'm overdue...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching Tin Cup careen away in his Caddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got to relax, boss --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' to the U.S. Open with the shanks. Gonna be chili dipping my way around the course on worldwide television... sure, relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get rid of them shanks for ya. No hay problema.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Molly and I are circling each other... I can feel it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She the enemy, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well she wakin' up with the enemy -- same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo keeps driving, pretends not to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Romes -- the absolute truth -- you think I can go 72 holes without falling apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me! I don't want no bullshit... do you think I can do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Tin Cup puts on his Walkman, and stares out the window endlessly at a thousand miles of passing scenery, to the MUSIC of GEORGE JONES...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, boss, I just don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Winnebago pulls up to a guard gate -- A SECURITY GUARD comes to the window. A banner hangs above the entrance a few paces past the security gate, proclaiming: "Old Pines -- U.S. Open Championship."</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... and the first Mexican...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Como esta, amigo. I have with me one of the legendary ball strikers in the history of golf -- The Security Guard strains to see in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup leans across Romeo to introduce himself.</context>
      <utterance>Who's that? Mr. Crenshaw? That you? Mr. Price, Mr. Norman? No?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard backs off quickly, turns to his SECOND.</context>
      <utterance>Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy. Representing the great American Southwest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have a... McCormack... on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McAvoy -- Roy McAvoy -- he's a legend!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo starts cursing in Spanish. The Guard is unphased.</context>
      <utterance>We got over 150 legends in this tournament. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police quickly appear to take over the situation. Tin Cup leaps out of the Winnebago to argue his point.</context>
      <utterance>Police?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a mistake here, fellas!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment David Simms pulls in, driving a con- vertible sponsor's car. He sees the scuffle, gets out.</context>
      <utterance>We'll throw your ass in jail right now, pal -- there's a lotta lunatics here and we don't take chances...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms spots Tin Cup -- a delicious moment for him. Tin Cup wants to hide but he just gamely covers his face.</context>
      <utterance>This clown says he's in the Open...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, David... nice sweater.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms takes the clipboard with the list.</context>
      <utterance>He's not on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Roy... welcome to the big leagues...  Here ya go, Charlie, his name's right here.  They spelled your name wrong -- easy mistake with a total unknown.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms smiles at Tin Cup, the easy smile of a man on top. Tin Cup doesn't respond, just asks the Guard:</context>
      <utterance>Let him in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Tin Cup tries to regain some dignity, and climbs back into the Winnebago --</context>
      <utterance>Which way to the practice range?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he was a 'legend'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all have a good laugh, and --</context>
      <utterance>Oh he is... he's a very big name at a driving range in Salome, Texas...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo notices that Tin Cup is staring at the pile of practice balls lying there on the tee.</context>
      <utterance>Look! Right there! Fred Couples... and Ray Floyd!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup limbers up, trying not to be in awe of the real legends who line the practice range, hitting beautiful shot after beautiful shot with graceful ease.</context>
      <utterance>Look at these balls. Brand new Titleists. Lookit 'em, every one a brand new Titleist.  Sneak a few in the bag when you get a chance. We swipe enough free shit we might even pay for this fiasco.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think it would be inappropriate to ask Ray Floyd for an autograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup nudges a ball from the pile into address position. Romeo hands him a different club.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's a dead giveaway, Romes... but if I still got the shanks we're gonna be found out real fast...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit the seven iron. You never miss the seven...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup waggles, shakes, limbers, addresses...</context>
      <utterance>Good thought, Pods...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWOCK! A hideous shank squirrels across line, almost hitting a group of U.S. Open officials. Heads turn.</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills... And he swings.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWOCK! A disaster. He crumbles.</context>
      <utterance>Who hit that shot? Anybody see? He addresses another one. And swings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little thin, Boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms has arrived and is watching Tin Cup with delight as he loosens up.</context>
      <utterance>A little fucking thin?! I still got the shanks! Everybody's watching! Christ, Simms is here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup pretends to limber a little more before daring to strike another ball.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should work on putting. Ya can't shank a putt.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're the Mexican Mac O'Grady, Romes, you gotta figure out why I'm still shanking the ball.  What's the problem? I'm catching it on the hosel, right? Moving my head? I'm laying off it, I'm pronating, I'm supinating, I'm clearing too early, I'm clearing too late, I'm off plane, I ain't dropping in -- oh, God, my swing feels like an unfolding lawn chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a virus in your brain. I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>93.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>got to kill the brain to kill the virus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything. Kill me now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup follows orders, not questioning the logic.</context>
      <utterance>Put all your change in your right pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, Tin Cup dutifully follows orders.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. Now tie your left shoelace in a double knot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esta bueno. Now, turn your hat around backwards and put a blue tee behind your right ear...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll look like a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you think you look like hitting those squirrelly chili peppers up Freddy Couples' ass, eh? Do what I say or I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup hits a perfect seven iron into the trees.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect... now hit a seven iron into that tree over there. You're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't thinking about shanking, you ain't thinking about the doctor lady, you ain't thinking period. You just lookin' like a fool and hittin' it pure -- your natural state.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cured.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. Your brain was getting in the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What now?</context>
      <utterance>That's rarely been a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I should recommend you go work on your short game but I think it's better if you go get drunk instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cups stares at the swami, and --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You always play better when you're wasted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's three in the morning, Romes, what time I tee off?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep drinking, keep dancing...</context>
      <utterance>Seven-o-five... first group off...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's four hours from now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're drinking till five... c'mon, c'mon, have another --  Get you in shape --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STARTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tin Cup and Romeo stagger to the tee, barely making it on time. Tin Cup is massively hung-over and unshaven.</context>
      <utterance>With the honor in the 7:08 pairing, from Salome, Texas, Mr. Roy McAvoy. A half-dozen people clap, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No time for a bucket, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup tries to get warm quickly, taking a few hurried practice swings. The early tee times are strictly for the longest of long shots, and almost nobody is around. Tin Cup's hand shakes as he closes the Velcro flap on his glove. He's wearing the hat and shirt with the sew-on patches, as he stares down the first fairway. Romeo hands him a driver.</context>
      <utterance>Almost missed the starting time trying to get you off the floor, boss. You don't handle the hooch like you used to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen this hole on TV. Hit the big dog down the chute --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I've learned my lesson. Gonna play it safe, smart, conservative. Fairways and greens. Hand me the two iron.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Tin Cup launches a two iron down the first fairway.</context>
      <utterance>Thought of the day is -- `be humble.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty-three. Well, you humble now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eleven bogeys and seven pars. I didn't make a three. I didn't make one goddam three all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't trying to make threes. You were trying to avoid making thirteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hungover!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that was a coaching error on my part.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, amigo...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>97.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David Simms is interviewed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the last person who expected me to come out of the blocks with a sixty-seven and lead the Open... It's been a long time since I played this game with the fire and determination you need to win...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Anti-Christ shoots 67, you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ol' Anti-Christ got a hot putter...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... you see, this game is all about integrity and tradition and honor...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? It's about cheating and racism and bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, boss...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tomorrow I'll just go out there and try to make some good swings and, Lord willing, maybe I can put up another good number. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms walks away, now off-camera. FANS call out --</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, David Simms, a brilliant opening round 67 to take the lead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David! David! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms cuts down behind the tent toward the clubhouse, away from the galleries. The marshals open a rope allowing him to avoid the crowds, but -- An ELDERLY COUPLE with a young child are there. The lady has a tiny dog in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Simms!  Can you sign an autograph for our grandson?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you see I'm busy?! I'm working! This is my office! Do I come to your office and ask you for an autograph?! Jesus... He practically stiff-arms them as he passes, heading up to the clubhouse. They stand there in shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS OVER TO the edge of the tent. Molly, trying to get to David, has seen the whole thing.</context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck these people think they are...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She speaks to herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old people, children, and dogs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got lucky out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms stops when he sees Tin Cup and Romeo drowning their sorrows.</context>
      <utterance>Great start, Simmsy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tin Cup -- heard you put a monster number up there...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small bar crowd is enjoying Simms' taunts.</context>
      <utterance>Coulda been worse...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I played in the Pro-Am with some asshole movie star shot 82 here once... how did a great ball- striker like you, a `legend,' manage to shoot an 83?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed a four foot putt on the eighteen for an 82, that's how...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't like playing some muni track in Brownsville, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does, `integrity, tradition, and honor' include kicking a man when he's down?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Tin Cup's about as low as one can go.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mol', this is just guy stuff, bar talk, part of the game -- no offense, right, Cup?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man still has a lot of good golf shots in his system --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Molly, it's okay, go away... I don't need any attention right</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>100.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOME GUY AT THE BAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the guy shot 83?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a double door, forty feet away across, the bar, about an 8 x 8 foot opening.</context>
      <utterance>David, I'll bet you a hundred dollars right now that Roy here can hit a ball --  -- from right here to... through that door to the patio...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Molly, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And give me a vodka tonic with a twist --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>dignified...</context>
      <utterance>Molly, really, this isn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanta go back to Texas...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone strains to look --</context>
      <utterance>What about the river, the piranha, the immortality? All that bullshit? You gonna drag your ass home with an 83?  In fact, two hundred says he can hit it through that door, over the patio, into the river, and make that pelican fly off that post.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Romeo's sizing it up.</context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly takes a swig of her drink and slaps some money on the bar.</context>
      <utterance>You got that shot, Pods, hood the seven, turn it over, start it low, right to left...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms puts a hundred dollar bill on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving till one of you men starts acting in a manly fashion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One ball, one swing, one gull.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just get this over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup still sits, head half buried at the bar. He's never passed up such an opportunity, but he's pretty low.</context>
      <utterance>Roy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns from his bar stool, glances at the situation.</context>
      <utterance>You the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One swing? Four to one odds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make it ten to one. Stick it up your ass. I'm leading the Open.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoas! From the barside gallery. Tin Cup rises and someone hands him a club. Suddenly there's a crowd, including Gary McCord who's been watching from the far end of the bar. He grabs a seltzer hose as if it's a mike and begins announcing. McCORD ... He's looking at thirty yards of bar and grill, an opening through the French doors, forty yards of patio umbrellas, a</context>
      <utterance>Now we're talking! Manly men!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>102.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup steps up to a ball lying on the carpet.</context>
      <utterance>hundred yards of water, and a lonely pelican sitting out there in a 15 mile an hour breeze, south by southwest...  He'll probably try to shut down a four iron -- no, he's selected his trusty seven iron...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of a thin lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats all that deep rough you were in today...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup suddenly backs off the swing and turns to Molly.</context>
      <utterance>Fore in the grill! Fore on the patio! You're the legend, boss...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up and hit the ball. McCORD  The Ledge still has to be thinking about that brutal, ego-sapping, manhood-robbing eighty-three he buried himself under yesterday. I mean, that's just an avalanche of golf swings, a landslide, a pyroclastic flow --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>98 And he swings -- the ball rockets through the hall and 98 clears the open door... The bettors pile from the bar and grill and race to the patio to watch the flight of the ball, as -- It's carrying, it's hooking, it's carrying, then: THWACK! -- It hits the piling! The SEAGULL lifts off, SCREECHING angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Dollar bills...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stiff, baby, stiff!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>103.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>99 A whoop goes up -- And Simms storms out. 99</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm outta here. You're all nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I musta been blind thinking you were worth a shit, Simmsy!  Drinks on me, boys! Helluva shot, Roy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the old Tin Cup -- and he's in the clubhouse with an eightyfuckingthree.</context>
      <utterance>Actually I thinned it a little or that pelican'd be flying around with a Titleist up his ass...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kinda shanked it, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no... you were great...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tempo is everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfection's unobtainable...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mighta rushed it on the downswing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come over the top a little...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well, as Walter Hagen once said -- 'Sex and golf are the only two things you can be bad at and still enjoy...'</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace with enthusiasm and start thrashing again.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a mulligan and tee it up again --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WRIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tin Cup gets his read, and steps up to putt.</context>
      <utterance>If anyone was ever to make a run at what is the most storied number in Open history, Miller's sixty- three, it would be today when the rain has softened the greens, enabling the players to take dead aim at the flags. Still, the unswerving courage of an unknown driving range pro from Salome has raised that humble journeyman from the ashes of an ignominious eighty-three to wave a mighty fist at the pantheon of golf's immortals. This man, this Roy McAvoy has laid siege to the record book by birdieing the first seven holes. A brave par from the water at eight, and a glorious birdie three at the daunting twelfth, another at thirteen...</utterance>
   <speaker>WRIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tin Cup putts -- When the ball is still two feet from the hole, Tin Cup raises his putter in triumph... and sure enough, the ball drops in the hole.</context>
      <utterance>... this putt to go ten under for the day...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said on the radio he was ten under --</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence, everyone watching the TV, everyone starting to contort in body-English, then: A joyous roar -- Tin Cup's putt went down. Earl twirls with glee.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhh!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's shooting the lowest round ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And eighteen's a par five. A birdie there, he shoots sixty!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta go, boys. We gotta get us on a Continental Trailways and find this damn place!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His adrenalin's gotten the better of him, Jim. If he lays up he takes bogey out of play.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if he knocks this ball in the water he could make seven or eight. And he still has to think about making the cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUMMERALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>111 Wearing that look, the look of eagles, Tin Cup addresses 111 his ball... And he swings -- The ball arches off his club, the gallery roars, and...</context>
      <utterance>Well, every golf fan in America is pulling for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Tin Cup drops the three wood on his bag, even as:</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carry, honey! Please! Carry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup hits a wedge to within five feet.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell. You ride 'er till she bucks you or you don't ride at all. I can save par from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up an' down...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you go from shooting an eighty-three one day to a record- breaking sixty-two the next?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter from the reporters. Reporter 1 follows up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't from clean living...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you had to do it again, would you still go for the green on eighteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And I'll go for it tomorrow and I'll go for it Sunday, cuz I didn't come here to play for no second.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo picks up some grass and flips it in the air. It blows away from the green.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme the three wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's wind up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NANTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he hasn't shown an ounce of fear all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't courage, Jim. This is inexperience, pure and simple.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>110.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tin Cup steps up to his shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings and holds the pose. He caught the ball perfectly -- it sails high and true into the luffing breeze, the GALLERY ROARS, and... ... the ball drops, SPLOOSH! into the WATER, a couple feet short of dry land. The GALLERY GROANS.`</context>
      <utterance>This is for Venturi, up there in the booth, thinking I should lay up...  Dollar bills...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a long fucking ways.  Gimme another ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup's eyes blink with thought as Romeo's words get through to him.</context>
      <utterance>It's a water hazard. You go up there and take a drop. Try to save par like you did yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he starts down to the water. A THUNDEROUS OVATION greets his approach, and he raises his hat to salute the fans saluting him.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. What the hell was I thinking?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saved par, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to understand your thinking. You were in the same spot on eighteen yesterday without a headwind and you --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I can knock it on from there?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seemed like a low-percentage shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So am I! Look at me. I'm playing for...  ... Rio Grande Short-Haul Trucking, Brink and Brown Sanitation, First State Bank of Salome, Wally's Smokehouse... You think a guy like me bothers to think about the percentages? --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got some money from the pelican bet -- why don't we go somewhere fancy and celebrate -- get ready for the final round.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing to celebrate yet. Plus these are my people. I'm a waffle house guy -- gotta stay in touch with that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus he needs his carbohydrates --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys from Salome walk in -- with Doreen, all looking like hell from the long bus trip. They're ecstatic to see Tin Cup and Romeo.</context>
      <utterance>If the boys from Salome was in town -- this is where they'd be...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The legend!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn, we been driving for two days to help you in the last round --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw the Winnebago outside -- we're starving...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty-two! Sixty-two!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're home now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys a sight for sore eyes. We so damn sick of guys in blazers and slacks that don't wrinkle. It ain't natural 'round here...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Roy -- we're with you all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doreen, meet Dr. Griswold... er, Molly... my shrink --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ex-shrink.  We're sleeping together now so I can't be his therapist.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knew what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, dear. Good luck.  Say, I have a little extra cash -- why don't we go somewhere fancy and celebrate -- y'know, kinda get</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>113.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the Regulars overwhelm her.</context>
      <utterance>ready for the final round?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Waffle House, Doreen --</utterance>
   <speaker>CURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I been dreaming of waffles for 1800 miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got a waffle house in Odessa just about like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Odessa? It's in Midland, ain't it?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all pull up chairs and settle in for a long evening at the Waffle House. Tin Cup leans back in his chair, turns to Molly.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's in Odessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just don't get much better than this...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT/EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo leans over to Doreen amidst the chaos and speaks with suave elegance.</context>
      <utterance>You the man, Cup, you the man...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking particularly lovely this evening... the coif is extraordinary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why thank you... Romeo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You nervous about tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Except for the random snore.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm nervous. So's everybody else. But I only gotta come and catch Simms. Sixty-seven guys gotta come and get me...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her finger over his mouth gently.</context>
      <utterance>It won't always be like this... y'know... with me... surrounded by all these guys... snoring... a stripper ex-girlfriend on the floor... my caddie sleeping next to her... all of us damn near broke... won't always be like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it will... yes it will... and it's okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one of you is the bookie?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all are, but Earl's the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the odds that Roy will win?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vegas has him at ten to one. They're sure he's gonna self-destruct.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Those sound good to me -- I want you to place a bet for me. Five thousand nine hundred dollars on Tin Cup to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your nestegg.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a bad idea, honey -- we love him, but he's gonna fuck- up --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said put it all on Roy. Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't let you --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Molly's in charge. She hands them a roll of cash.</context>
      <utterance>Boys --</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl reluctantly takes the money.</context>
      <utterance>Put it all on Tin Cup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACOBSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking a little tight, Ledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Musta got too much sleep last night. How you choking?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACOBSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got one thought in my head. Ten under. That's my number. Tin Cup looks up, amused by the gamesmanship.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's ever been ten under for the Open, not even Nicklaus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he moves off to putt. Tin Cup drops a couple balls on the green to putt, and: A ball rolls past them and into a hole. Tin Cup looks over and sees Simms.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Ledge. Not even Nicklaus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Roy, can't believe I didn't see you with all that high-priced endorsement crap you're flaunting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's always been your problem, Dave. You don't think about winning; you just want to look good.  Thing is, this ain't a beauty pageant.  And it ain't a rain-shortened Quad Cities or a Greater Greensboro you can back into. This is you'n me, pal. This is match-play, and this time you ain't getting no three shots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fairways and greens, Dave... and don't forget to wave as I blow by.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand shakes worse than it did the first day as he tees his ball. Stepping back to line up his shot, he peers down the fairway through a narrow corridor of faces. A daunting sight. He edges over to Romeo and tautly whispers:</context>
      <utterance>You mean blow up? Like you always do? And Tin Cup moves to the tee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor. Bet me a buck I don't put it in the fairway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you a hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, good.  Puts things back in perspective.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice double, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep making pars, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take eighteen of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I will own you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, Tin Cup ran it five feet past.  How did he get the name 'Tin Cup'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Molly puts down the periscope at that remark, and hands it to Doreen.</context>
      <utterance>He played catcher on the high school baseball team. The star pitcher had this big-league curve, and not all his pitches hit Roy in the mitt. Finally, you gotta respect a man's doggedness. You know?  The team decided Tin Cup sounded better than Clank.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Clank''s not a good name for a man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our boy's in trouble... ya think he's chokin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scorer changes the number beside Tin Cup's name to -- -4. Simms is -7, and --</context>
      <utterance>Our boy don't choke. He fucks up but he don't choke...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>120.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCORD This is definite jail. This is life without parole. His only chance to stage a jail-break is go at the ball left-handed and hope he can somehow snake it back into the fairway, and save par from there. Tin Cup glares balefully back at McCord. Then he walks over to a nearby tree, and surveys the line to the green from it. He walks back for his ball, turns to McCord... and we see that familiar fierceness aflame in Tin Cup's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he selects the seven iron, addresses the ball right- handed, and: He swings -- the ball rockets low off his club, and... ... it ricochets off the trunk of a nearby tree, and... ... it bounces up the fairway, skitters past a trap, and trickles onto the green, stopping ten feet from the pin. The gallery goes crazy as Tin Cup steps from the woods collecting his money from McCord while jabbing a taunting finger at Simms.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty bucks says I knock it on... with a seven iron.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That took balls...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he hits his iron to the fat part of the green, and --</context>
      <utterance>That's just Roy being Roy. Just wait him out, Dave. Just make pars. Let him make the mistakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beauty, Dave. Par written all over it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why'd you leave him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever dated a guy who actually believes in soul mates?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks he's a tough guy, but he's a hopeless romantic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They explode with cheers. Some twirl with glee. Others exchange high fives.</context>
      <utterance>Get in there! Come on! Go down!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's tied for the lead again! And they're running outta holes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NANTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's come down to the seventy- second hole of this great championship, and the skill and courage of three Texans who have dueled throughout the day for the chance to be crowned Open Champion... Peter Jacobsen is on the fairway at 8 under, McAvoy at the 18th tee is tied at minus 8, and David Simms trails by one...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the tee, and...</context>
      <utterance>Jacobsen's laying up.  You ain't gonna have that luxury, Dave. Not if you play to win.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NANTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McAvoy's hit a perfect drive, Ken.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure that's good news for McAvoy. With his inexperience, the last thing he needs is an excuse to fool with that water again today.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't catch it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms rips a drive down the middle, the ball landing a little short of Roy's.</context>
      <utterance>Then you got to lay up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Simms, ten yards across the fairway from him.</context>
      <utterance>So birdie wins it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simms points to himself. He has a wood in his hands, but he puts the club back and reaches for an iron. Tin Cup edges closer to Romeo.</context>
      <utterance>You or me, Dave?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's laying up. Birdie to tie, eagle to win, and that gutless wonder's laying up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Par to tie, birdie to win... you lay up too, Roy. You can make birdie laying up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know something, Romeo? Eagle puts me ten under. No one's ever finished an Open ten under, not even Nicklaus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup throws some grass in the air, looks back at the green, the gallery, the whole grand setting... and he seeks out Molly's face in the crowd. He moves over so she can hear him.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need an eagle. Birdie wins, par ties.  Hit the lay up. Hole a wedge for goddamn eagle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is everything, ain't it? This is the choice it comes down to. This is our immortality...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Molly stands with Doreen, hearing Tin Cup's words. Thrilled and terrified and spellbound, she finds herself nodding. Doreen, on the other is turning ash-white.</context>
      <utterance>No time to be thinkin' 'immortality,' Cup... time to be thinkin' 7 iron.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. This is what always happens. He's going for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go for it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! He just needs par to tie! Tell him to lay up! He listens to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go for it, Roy! Knock it on!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is why we split up -- he always went for it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My problem is I've never been with</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>126.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a man who went for it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, honey, he's your guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He selects the three wood. Romeo sighs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NANTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Lord, he's going for the green.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This could be tragic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings -- the ball explodes off his club. Tin Cup holds the pose...</context>
      <utterance>One swing, Roy. One good swing. Dollar bills...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a gust of wind blows, out of nowhere, and Tin Cup's cap blows off, provoking immediate concern.</context>
      <utterance>We're home...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... little gust there, Romes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can still make par from up there --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Tin Cup still has the look of eagles. He's staring at the shot he just made, still holding the three wood.</context>
      <utterance>She's right, Pods, a drop and a stroke, up and down par -- we'll win it in sudden death.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I nutted that thing. Little gust from the gods cost me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helluva move you put on that sucker, now let's get up there, take the drop, and make our par, tie Peter...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can make this shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup throws another ball on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm playing it from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup addresses the ball.</context>
      <utterance>Take your drop and make your par!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>128.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>drop from his original lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this. He just took himself out of the tournament with that drop. He could have walked up to the hazard line, saved par with a wedge and forced a playoff with Jacobsen. Now he needs a miracle shot. McCORD  Ken, I'm right behind McAvoy here. And all he said to his caddie was: I can make it across.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme another ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO DOREEN AND MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>watching behind the ropes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe he's doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can blow the whole tournament!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle he lasted this long...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He done blew a gasket, boys...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wheels is definitely falling off now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a miracle while it lasted...</utterance>
   <speaker>REGULARS' POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tin Cup swings a third time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROMEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your last ball, man. If this gets wet, you disqualified.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup snatches the ball from Romeo's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I can make it across.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VENTURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup unloads another three wood -- another splash.</context>
      <utterance>This is the most painful thing I've ever watched. McCORD  Jim, this is the last ball he has in his bag. If he doesn't finish the hole with it, he can't turn in a card. He'll be disqualified. Venturi and Nantz cover their eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romeo tosses down another ball -- Tin Cup launches his fifth attempt to clear the pond. Splash.</context>
      <utterance>She's just laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let 'er rip!</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Roy, what the hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two are made for each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta hand it to you, Roy. When you go down, you go down in flames.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he moves brusquely past Simms and out of the tent, congratulating Tubbs, the winner, as he passes.</context>
      <utterance>Someday you can tell your grandchildren you finished second in the U.S. Open...  -- just don't tell 'em how.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And out of the scorer's tent...</context>
      <utterance>Good job, Tubbsy... you won it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>132.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCORD Ledge, I know it's tough to talk right now, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not difficult to talk... it's difficult to explain... I coulda laid up and still won. I made a twelve on the last hole of the U.S. Open. You know how much money that cost me? McCORD Cost you a bundle...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tin Cup exits the scorers' tent and runs into the regulars -- They're beaming, undyingly loyal.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta get outta here. McCORD It was the greatest 12 I ever saw. Back to you, Jim...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLINT AND EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and there's Molly -- He stops short. They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Greatest 12 I ever saw... you crunched that dog, baby... gorgeous shot, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Molly, I'm an idiot. I gave away the Open. The one time in my life I know the play is to hit the lay up -- my whole life and future and career on the line, and I still can't make myself do it. I am a twisted human being and a cautionary tale. And I guess I'm a fool?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. A magnificent fool...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people don't like West Texas but I think it's the most beautiful place on earth...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has its charms...  Y'know, by finishing in the top 15 at the Open you qualified to be in it next year --</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, I didn't know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking with your game you should go back to the Qualifying School, try to get out on tour...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I wouldn't see you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I picked up a whole bunch of new clients at the Open. Lotta guys on the tour said if I could do that much for you, imagine what I could do for them...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lotta head cases out there, you could make a bundle...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And sleep in the Winnebago at night...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>134.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know... a man goes through what I've gone through, he's supposed to learn something.  I'm trying to figure out what I learned. Did I learn anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're learning some discipline and self-control...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that there's a time in life to play it safe...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great, Roy... and I'm learning how to listen to the tuning fork, throw caution to the wind, and take crazy risks I never thought were possible...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIN CUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Molly, when did you ever take a crazy risk?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fell for you...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
