<movie id="564" title="Tin Men">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a beauty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the beauty?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Salesman shrugs his shoulders. BB walks around the Cadillac.</context>
      <utterance>I thought maybe you saw some chick walking by. I lost my concentration. Why do they call cars 'she'? They never say 'he'... always 'she.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice... very nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do ya think I'm screaming at? How many of you are there up there? There's only you, and you're a sick human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nice one, you know.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my white on white shirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like yelling through a wall to you. I'm carrying on about what a disgusting human being you are, and all you want to know is where your white on white shirt is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the one with the permanent stays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do I make myself clear?</context>
      <utterance>Now don't try to hustle me here ... you know what I mean. I hate being hustled. Give me an honest price, not one of your 'special' deals... give me an honest price.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, how much are you willing to pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There ya go... there ya go... you're doing it... you're doing one of those hustle numbers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to get an idea how much you're willing to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four dollars... I want to pay four dollars a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not an honest answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya want to hear? That I'd love to pay three hundred and fifty a month... is that what you want to hear? Tell me how much you want me to pay and I'll tell you how much I'll pay, but don't do a hustle on me... I don't like that. How much do I want to pay? I'd like to pay nothing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're being unreasonable. You don't even want to listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley walks down the steps of the house and goes to his car -- a Cadillac. He gets inside, STARTS the ENGINE and pulls away. Nora remains on the porch watching the car ... one lonely figure in a neighborhood of hundreds of duplicate houses.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what I did... I got no idea. If it's my fault, I'm sorry... I'm sorry. I can do no better than that. A full unconditional apology.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you even have the smallest problem, call me personally and I'll just shoot you straight into the service department.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I get a loaner if the car's got to stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As we discussed, you get a car if the car has to be kept overnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Salesman nods.</context>
      <utterance>I get a loaner?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts moving his head -- stretching his neck from right to left.</context>
      <utterance>She's gonna drive me to my grave... I'm headed to my grave... the woman's driving me insane... it's not supposed to happen this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He juts his jaw out.</context>
      <utterance>It's not even eleven o'clock and my neck is stiffening up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My neck's tight... it's tight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a lunatic? Can't you see I'm trying to back out of this lot? There's a red light, you shoulda stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What kind of driving?</context>
      <utterance>Me? What are you, crazy? You just want to back into the middle of the street like that. A man's just driving along and you back into the middle of the street. What kind of driving is that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a red light, I'm making a space for myself... that's what I'm doing, in order to get into the street... that's something ya do!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came out of nowhere... you bolted out of no place... bolted out of nowhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves toward Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Bolted! At six miles an hour I'm bolting into the street! You schmuck! You schmuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back away from me.</context>
      <utterance>Back away from me, do ya hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to walk away from Tilley, walks and then turns back and kicks in the headlight of Tilley's car.</context>
      <utterance>Back away? You want me to back away? I'll back away.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes for BB, jumps him and they both fall on to the trunk of BB's car. People have started to gather and immediately jump in and pull BB and Tilley apart.</context>
      <utterance>You're a fucking lunatic!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People continue to pull them apart.</context>
      <utterance>You're a madman! Smashes into me, attacks me... the man is crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds BB's arms. Another MAN grabs for Tilley and tries to pull him off BB.</context>
      <utterance>Come on now, calm down, calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy... take it easy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley makes another jump for BB. Again, people try pulling them apart.</context>
      <utterance>Get this guy! Will ya get this guy? Backs in front of me, and then kicks my headlight in... and I'm crazy. You lunatic!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB looks at his brand new Cadillac with the smashed-in side.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to prison. Death! Death! They're going to give you death!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back and looks at Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Car only has one sixteenth of a mile, and I've been hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get even with you, you son of a bitch... I'm gonna get even with you. This is no ordinary traffic accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm gonna get even!</context>
      <utterance>You want to drive a Cadillac, learn how to drive. You want to get even with somebody? You picked the wrong person to get even with. Nobody backs into traffic, smashes my car and says they want to get even.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOUSE, who is picking his teeth with a matchbook, squints at Sam with an investigative look.</context>
      <utterance>Ben Cartwright had a colored guy stay overnight at the Ponderosa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he know this guy personally?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... he was just passing through, asked if he could stay over, and Ben Cartwright said 'sure thing.' It doesn't make any sense... he invites a strange colored guy in... invited him in to stay. Is that crazy or what? If a colored guy came to my door and said 'can I stay the night,' I'd tell him 'get the fuck out of here'! It's nothing personal, mind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a bigot, is that what you're telling us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? No, I'm not a bigot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not, how come you're making such a big thing out of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the fact the Ben Cartwright's on the Ponderosa... he's in the middle of nowhere. It's not like he's living on Reisterstown Road with houses all around... we're talking about the West here. It's the idea that a strange guy comes to the door in the middle of the West. It doesn't make sense, that's all I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on... you're a bigot, that's what you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLORENCE, who doesn't have too much energy, calls back to Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Florence, eggs and the toast, the way I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She trails the last word. Sam is still talking about his problem with "Bonanza."</context>
      <utterance>Not too gooey. Coffee right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley slips into the booth next to Sam. He indicates for Sam to give him more room.</context>
      <utterance>I just don't believe that 'Bonanza' is an accurate description of the West. I say no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, give me a couple of more inches.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll eat in the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to take my plate...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the loonies.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Sam, I'm having a terrible morning. You're not going to believe this, some guy just crashed into me... right in the middle of the street... then he attacks me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did ya live?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls a piece of paper from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got his name. The police came... God, I can't believe it... the guy's an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, here it is... some Polish name... Babowski... Bill Babowski ... fucking son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the guy... they call him</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the son of a bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he works with Bagel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sells aluminum siding? I don't believe it... of all the people that could run into me, it has to be a fucking tin man. How come I don't know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You musta seen him. He hangs out with Carly Benelli, Cheese ... you know, that group.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you remember, he was up at the Corral one night when we were there... he's a good dancer. You must have seen him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gil, he doesn't know the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he knew him, Sam... I can't believe he doesn't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seems to be indicating that he doesn't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good dancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do, date him? What do I give a shit if he's a good dancer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you saw him. I was amazed, he does a Marengay... I tell you if I was a girl I'd be impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Florence comes over and puts down some coffee in front of Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>You're not a girl and you're impressed!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it fresh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's fresh!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just asking, Florence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLORENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gil still talking about BB.</context>
      <utterance>You're always just asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, you just can't believe how well this guy does the Marengay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you one thing, when I get a hold of this guy, I'll break both his legs and then he won't dance the Marengay too good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GIRL #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES TO another corner of the room where we see 4 "tin men" salesmen sitting around one of the desks playing cards. MOE is beginning to tell a joke. He is a man in his 50's.</context>
      <utterance>... Superior Aluminum Siding Company. We will have a representative...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB enters the scene and goes over and gets himself a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>So the guy goes to the doctor for a physical... they do all those tests, all that stuff, blah, blah, blah...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the guy goes and picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>... Doctor says 'when we get all the information back, we'll give you a call.' Leaves the doctor. One day the telephone rings...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the doctor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, the guy picks it up. He gets a phone call... it's the doctor on the line. Doctor says 'I've got some bad news and some worse news.' BB join the tin men to listen to Moe's joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh. LOONEY, a thin guy who twitches and blinks a lot, stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Guy says 'Well, let me hear the bad news first.' 'The bad news is, you've got twenty-four hours to live.' The guy says 'What's the worse news?' Doctor says 'I forgot to call you yesterday.'</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good... I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never heard bad news and worse news... smart joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB, who is not laughing, stands behind Cheese who throws 50 cents into the card game.</context>
      <utterance>It's dumb, but good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up it fifty cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I call... I call. I'm in on this one... I call.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get it, you're calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carly, get out of the hand... I'm holding serious cards. Very serious cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bluffing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm lying, I'm dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe throws his hand in, too.</context>
      <utterance>Ballsy move.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get the new Cadillac?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's already been hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't have it five minutes, backing out of the place, and a guy comes out of nowhere and bangs into my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheese throws his hand down.</context>
      <utterance>So, what ya got?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pair of sixes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jacks. Win.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Pair of sixes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much damage?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet it's six hundred bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six hundred bucks? I'd get rid of the car. That much damage it won't be any good. You may have dented the frame.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't dent the frame.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you hit the frame, the car doesn't ride right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't hit the frame! I'll tell you this, I'm gonna get the son of a bitch. If he would have apologized or something, but this guy gets out, tries to push me around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip of his coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... the guy's totally off the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get him... just for the fun of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You want to get some coffee?</context>
      <utterance>Now, let me see... we gotta be at the Hickey house at four.  It's about three-twenty now... we've got some time on our hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates his throat.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm up to here with the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got any good pool halls around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  You know what would be fun to do..? Let's try the Life Magazine routine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>very good.</context>
      <utterance>I think this is a better position... the light is hitting it, which is accentuating the effect we're going for. It's very good...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This shows the flaws in the structure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's at the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going to be terrific in Life Magazine.  Terrific in Life Magazine!  Come on outside, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the Housewife coming out of her front door.</context>
      <utterance>This should be our single biggest issue of Life Magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Housewife approaches BB and Moe suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>Bingo!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I hope we're not disturbing you, ma'am. We're with Life Magazine... we'll be out of here in just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe moves the tripod.</context>
      <utterance>Move the tripod another foot... another foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, Life Magazine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two minutes, ma'am, and we'll be out of here. We just need the picture for Life Magazine, and we'll be out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life Magazine? I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very simple. Ya know, we're doing this layout about the benefits of aluminum siding -- a 'before' and 'after' kind of presentation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A 'before' picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they see your house, and another one done with aluminum siding... the other house looking so much more beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Life Magazine?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a special issue on home improvements and ways to beautify your home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A wonderful issue... it's one of the finest pictorial things we've done here at Life... the ways you can improve your house.  We're gonna be out of here in no time, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna look very good, BB.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't mine be like the 'after'?</context>
      <utterance>My house is going to be the 'before'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no... we've got a house that looked like yours and it's been done in aluminum... it's very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... really shows the contrast of what a house can look like.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it cost?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you have any idea, Moe?</context>
      <utterance>What? The aluminum siding? Oh... I don't know the figures offhand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's fairly reasonable.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could my house be the 'after' in Life Magazine and you get another house for the 'before.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean have your house as the 'after' and find another house that looks like your house for the 'before'?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it possible?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya think, Moe? Would that be ethical?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we didn't sign any agreement with the 'after' house. We'd have to move very quickly, ma'am... you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd have to work out an arrangement with an aluminum siding company and they'd have to do the job very quickly for us to make our deadline... we've got a deadline, that's the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How quickly?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BB, what do you think? Can we slide the deadline, or what? Six or seven days?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pressing it. Do you think we could manage it, Moe?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pushing it, BB.  What time would your husband be home, 'cos he'd have to go over the figures with the salesman... that's if there's a salesman available this evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be home at seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We might be able to work it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be wonderful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... we've got a total of thirty-seven hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-seven hundred dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, we're gonna be in Life Magazine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moe, did you call the office and make sure we can hold up the issue until this job is completed? This house really could be a showcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-seven hundred dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We got a deal?</context>
      <utterance>I tell you what... I've got an idea. Do you mind my guys working on a Saturday? 'Cos if my crew can work on Saturday next, that'll free my guys up on Monday. Yeah, that'll really help me out on another job. Anyway, if we can do that, I think I'll be able to knock off three hundred and fifty dollars from the job. You see, I've got an overlapping situation on Monday... I don't want to go into it. What do ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUSBAND #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sorry, Mr. Tilley, I just can't afford it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't even got to discussing terms. There are so many friendly financial arrangements that would hardly be a bite into your weekly salary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUSBAND #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... not this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Husband and wife stand to show Tilley to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well, as I said, you can always reach me... you've got my card, and when the time comes, let's talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, give my best to your little son... wonderful kid there. What's his name again, Ronnie?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Randy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Randy, right. Well, good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He demonstrates with his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I had 'em... I was this close.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The amount of time you spent there, I thought you were ready to send for me to close it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley STARTS the CAR and pulls out.</context>
      <utterance>Damn! I thought I had 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PIANIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last word of the verse -- "Ah" -- has great emphasis put on it and is lengthened considerably. The people sitting around the piano all join the pianist and say "Ah" in unison. CAMERA MOVES OVER TO a table where Mouse, Sam, Tilley, Gil and a few other tin men set. WING, the head of Gibraltar Aluminum, a tall, strong, imposing figure, holds court. The table is filled with papers, folders, etc., as if Wing's office desk had been trans- ported to the bar. He's reviewing a paper from a job that Mouse has done.</context>
      <utterance>'Tall and tan and young and lovely, the girl from Ipanema goes walking, and when she passes each one she passes goes... "Ah!"'</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his check book ledger and writes out a check.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-six hundred dollars. This looks like a sound deal. They own their own house... we won't have any problem getting the financing for them. Real good, Mouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finishes writing check and hands it to Mouse.</context>
      <utterance>So, that's one thousand, one hundred and thirty-eight dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mouse takes the check and pockets it. Wing turns to Tilley and Sam.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, boss. Pleasure doing business with ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, what's your guys' story?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing again... came up short. Let me get a little advance... three hundred, just to carry me for a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley, I'm already carrying you for, what is it -- twenty-three hundred? Something like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem... just in a little slump here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try to go walking on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, walking? You think I'm gonna work somewhere else... you've been very good to me... very honorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>he has.</context>
      <utterance>He's always said that about you, Wing. Always said that about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you hundred and fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I got expenses.</context>
      <utterance>Wing, I need a bit more than that...</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with your wife? She doesn't work?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wing writes out a check and gives it to Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but how much is she gonna make working at the Social Security office?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Wing, can't you do better than this... a man in my position in terms of this firm... I dunno...</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wing changes amount of check and hands it to Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll give you two hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, can you get me some Marlboros and a 7 and 7?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley pockets the check.</context>
      <utterance>And some scotch, straight up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen, guys, we got a problem here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she hear me say scotch straight up?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sources tell me this Home Improvement Commission is for real... it's no jackpot. These guys are going to be a real pain in the ass, so any of the scams that you guys are pulling, they get wind of it, they take your license and it's goodbye to this business.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They take away your license? They take away your livelihood? What kind of people are these?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have no respect for the working man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They got a list?</context>
      <utterance>Which scams are they talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any irregularities, you know, selling a house on the pretense that it's a model house and every job sold in the area they get a kickback... the Life Magazine hustle... you guys know all the bullshit numbers we can run.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! What a pain in the ass. Do you think this commission's gonna stick around or is it gone with the wind?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't mind seeing Africa some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. I don't want to go where they've got snakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got snakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits the brakes suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard they've got snakes that'll outrun a horse through the grass. They got a snake that bites you... you got eleven seconds to live. No thank you. I don't want to spend my good money to visit with that kind of jeopardy. I'd like to go to a place where... hold it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB backs his car halfway up the street. He stops in the driveway of the Pimlico Hotel parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the car into park and opens the car door.</context>
      <utterance>The guy who ran into me... that's his car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me eight points I take the Knicks over the Lakers for 20.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the sound of BREAKING GLASS. Tilley responds to the sound. He looks out of the glass doors and sees BB kicking in the headlight of his car. BB runs back towards his car.</context>
      <utterance>It's too big a spread.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races out of the door of the hotel towards BB's car which pulls away and speeds down the street. Several of the tin men run after Tilley. He stands in the street watching the car disappear.</context>
      <utterance>It's that fucking lunatic again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this guy? Is he sane or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he got, a gnat up his ass? What the hell's wrong with the guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you recognize him from the Corral?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never forget his Marengay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you something, if Mr. Marengay wants to play... we'll play.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you, quarter to three and home already. What happened? You and the fellas run out of things to talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes over to the refrigerator and gets himself some orange juice.</context>
      <utterance>Please! I'm out there working myself to the bone, trying to make a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a five letter word for a Portuguese overseas province?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try Macao.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>M-A-C-A-O... that fits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing up so late?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>We're off tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think this place may be a little too large for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about... this match box?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to the back door and looks out.</context>
      <utterance>It's got a lot of overhead to it. What do you do... spend your time in the bedroom and the kitchen, that's all. So why do you need a living room and a dining room.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do ya need a back yard?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not selling anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in a slump.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last year I'm number three top seller... year before, right up there. I can't get my momentum going this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you will. You always do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I like the idea of all this overhead breathing down my neck. When you have a place like this, that's a lot of overhead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? The monthly payments on your Cadillac are more than this whole house. Why don't you get yourself something cheaper, like a Chevy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't instill confidence in my clients. Cadillac means that you're dealing with someone of importance.  I thought I had a couple tonight... they just slipped away... slipped away.  I'm gonna take a bath -- my neck's been tight since this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora gets up and puts the cups in the sink -- gives a big sigh.</context>
      <utterance>I'll turn out the lights.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Tilley, we hardly ever do things together.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do things together that are enjoyable.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would we do together for it to be enjoyable?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we went on a picnic... it would be fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand a picnic... we just go some place... we put a thing on the ground, and we eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... it's nice to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? I don't get it. It's better sitting at home and watching TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think there's something nice about a picnic... it's fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's fun about it? Ants get into the food... there's bees. I don't get it. We have to drive, it takes maybe an hour to get there, then you sit in grass and eat. Why is that fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought it might be nice to do something together, that's all... thought it might be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't sound like fun to me... you take the stuff you've got here in the house, you take it someplace to eat it. It's just as much fun eating in front of the TV, and we do that together, don't we? No ants and no bees... much more comfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora picks up the back brush, puts soap on it and starts scrubbing Tilley's back.</context>
      <utterance>Scrub my back, will ya, Nora.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora drops the brush in the tub and walks out of the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Not too hard!  Don't get me wrong, I'm willing to do anything with you. I'm just a little stymied by a picnic. If you want to go, send me a postcard.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley turns the car.</context>
      <utterance>I think you make a left here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Tilley pulls up we see BB's car parked outside of the building.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... there it is... that's the place... Superior Aluminum... that's it over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into the backseat of the car and takes out a crowbar.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mr. Marengay... here I come.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tilley, don't go too wild...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out of the car, crosses to BB's Cadillac, and smashes in the windshield and all of the windows of the car.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show the son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll get a lot of air... won't be too stuffy in this car when I'm finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick, Tilley... let's get out of here. Tilley runs back to his car and drives away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you wanna get into the tin game?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money's good, I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot of crazy people you're gonna run into when you're knocking on those doors. Hermits that don't see the outside world, Jehovah's Witnesses that try and sell you the Bible at the same time you're trying to sell them tin. People that are just lonely and want to have conversations.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time you step in that door, you've got to be fast on your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the best way to qualify a mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe puts Stanley on the defensive.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know if you can get the upper hand? How do you know if you're dealing with a guy who's in an inferior position to you, or superior position? How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just have to talk and feel your way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick way... get a book of matches out of your pocket to light your cigarette... you drop the matches on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB walks over to the guys, having just poured himself some coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Guy bends down to pick up the matches for you, you got a mark... you got this guy in your pocket. If he looks to you to pick it up, you've got a long, hard, tough sell on your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley is quite taken by their information. BB puts his cup down and grabs his coat.</context>
      <utterance>You want to get in good with these people... you want to win their confidence? Good thing to try... get a five dollar bill, take it out when the guy's not looking, drop it on the ground. Guy looks back, pick it up, hand it to him and say, 'Mr. Blah blah, you musta dropped this five dollar bill on the ground.' Two things happen... he says, 'It's not mine,' you say, 'Musta been, 'cos it's certainly not mine,' or the guy takes it. Right away this guy is thinking you must be one hell of a nice guy... you're in. You start chipping away... you start getting inside those people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Moe, let's split.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we'd better go, too. Come on, Stanley.  Me and Stanley. It's like a first date.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB reaches into the car and picks up a handful of broken glass. He tosses it up and down in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>What? You got a special bargain when you bought this car? They come cheaper without windows?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB throws the glass down on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>This guy's looking to play tit for tat. That's not my game. I'm gonna play hardball.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looney just nods for them to go, and they start to walk over to Looney's Cadillac.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna find out everything about this son of a bitch, and then I'm gonna find the one thing that cuts him to the quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB nods and they start back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go inside... make some calls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, believe it. There's no sense not to believe it, because you did it... so believe it. That's twenty more... you owe me sixty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to rack to re-set. Mouse goes over and puts a nickel in the juke box. A RECORD slips into position, and Harry Belafonte's "Banana Boat Song" begins. Mouse, in unison with the record, sings, and is totally caught up in the song.</context>
      <utterance>You think I can't add?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sings very loudly, especially on the chorus.</context>
      <utterance>'Dayo!... da, da, da, da, day. Daylight come and he wanna go home...'</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is going to be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dayo!... da, da, da, da, da, da, da.'  'Daylight come and he wanna go home...'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods for Tilley to go over to him. They start to walk together through the darkened areas of the Pool Hall.</context>
      <utterance>Tilley.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the letter to Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Found this on your desk while I was going over some papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the IRS. I never even remember seeing it. I must have left it with my other bills. I wonder what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley opens the envelope and looks at the document.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's a refund check.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hum... says here that they haven't received my 1962 taxes. They seem to be saying that they didn't get my check for four thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? It must be a clerical error.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe they spend all that time and energy to write to me... to single me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? You didn't pay your taxes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I probably forgot... people forget their taxes all the time... just slipped my mind... I got so many things on my mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured they could wait a few years... it's not like they need my money to build a bomber. You think they're waiting for my money before they dig a new road? Are they all sitting there saying, 'Well, it's time we went to see that guy on Pimlico Road... can't run this government without his four thousand dollars.'  I figured they'd give me a little leeway. I'm going to pay them... I know I've got a debt... I just need a little leeway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't mess around with the government. Why don't you go to H &amp; R Block, they'll take care of your taxes for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm gonna let some schmuck know all my business... have some guy pull me over the coals for spending on this and that. I need some privacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taxes is serious stuff, Tilley.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>no way!</context>
      <utterance>I can just see that schmuck in that little tax shop telling people my business... how much I make... how much I spend...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I can say, is you better get a lawyer or somebody to look into this, 'cos the IRS, they don't fuck around.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws his arms up in the air in exasperation.</context>
      <utterance>Just what I need in my life right now... I'm in a slump and I've got the IRS on me. Like when something goes wrong, it's like...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These TV dinners?</context>
      <utterance>Are these any good do ya know?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues to choose her frozen foods. BB continues talking to her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think they're too good for you, not a lot of 'em anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife died.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm over it now, but it was a very trying time... very trying... I've only just started eating again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what would be a lot more healthy and satisfying is to get yourself a chicken... just pop it in the oven for a couple of hours with a little bit of seasoning on it. Makes a good meal, and you can make sandwiches with the leftovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then you have to sit and watch it cook. Something seems sad about a man sitting alone in a house and watching a chicken cook.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mr. Tilley. I can't believe it... this is the most generous thing anyone's ever done ... Swell! Like a gift from heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lord has certainly blessed us this evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what can I say... I'm a modest person... I just do what I can to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door for Tilley and Tilley walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's the scoop?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's very excited.</context>
      <utterance>We got 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley shows him the written contract. Written across the front of the contract in big, bold, black letters are the words: "THIS JOB IS FREE." Sam looks at Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look at this, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you fucking crazy? You just gave them forty-two hundred dollars in aluminum siding free?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the best scam I've ever thought of in my whole life. He kisses his hands with wild smacking sounds. He's ecstatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's in my blood... I'm brilliant ... I'm fucking brilliant... this is such a brilliant scam... I'm beside myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here it is... you go back in the house and this is what you say...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDEN to include Man and Wife from before.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Tilley is crazy... he had a nervous breakdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been under a lot of pressure recently... he snapped... he had a nervous breakdown... it's the saddest thing I've ever seen. Let's be honest about it, nobody gives away forty-two hundred dollars' worth of aluminum siding free.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was very generous, but sometimes the Lord moves in mysterious ways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anyway, it's not your problem.</context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you something, when I go and see his boss and show him this contract, he's out of this business... he'll lose his home ... his wife and kids will be thrown out onto the street. He'll probably spend some time in an institution, so God knows what will happen to his wife and kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do they have to be thrown out onto the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't expect his boss to pick up the forty-two hundred job, do ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's a bad state of affairs.  Let me ask you something, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think there's some way you could work with me to try and resolve this, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's look at it this way, what if I can sell you this job at a wholesale price... kind of lessens the burden. The big boss won't get so angry, and maybe won't throw the guy's wife and kids out... at least they'll have a roof over their heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of wholesale price are we talking about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a cup of coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you a coffee... won't be a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wife goes into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just sit down and kick this around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man turns to sit down, and as he does so, Sam throws a $5 bill on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>No hurry, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends to pick up the $5 note.</context>
      <utterance>What you doing throwing your money around?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found a five-dollar bill, here by the side of the chair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... he'd always put his hand over the break when he was measuring. Nobody looks at a yardstick to see how long it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The song ends.</context>
      <utterance>I never did that... I never did that... I was never very good in arts and crafts. I could never make the ruler come out right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else? Give me another story ... these stories are great!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute... I've got one. You know it's like the faster you can start spiking a job, the guy can't back out of the deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic, Sam! A twenty-seven hundred sale! 'This job is free'! What a beaut! I'm out of the slump! Tilley's riding high again ... Tilley's back! We ought to go and celebrate. Let's go to the Corral and have a drink... we can turn the paperwork in a little later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gil says that's where 'Marengay' hangs out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gil keeps saying it... I've never seen him.  I'm riding high... twenty-seven hundred dollars... 'this job is free'... the man went insane... lost control of himself... his wife and children are out on the street!  Sometimes I'm brilliant... I'm fucking brilliant... I can't believe it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that one, if you were married to that one two weeks you'd have to put your head out of the window for air... this one smothers.  That one is the kind that can't live without you...  ... 'Where were you? When will you be home?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should get out of here. I told my wife I'd be home early tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! It's not even one o'clock yet.  How long you been married now? What is it? Twelve... twelve years?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy God! Sixteen years? What do you think? Is it worth it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to answer.  Seems better than if she wasn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Quite a recommendation... can't wait to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scotch straight up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around the room at the women.</context>
      <utterance>Scotch straight up and a rum and Coke for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like there's good action here tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The place is hopping.</context>
      <utterance>What do you expect, it's half price night for divorced women.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm beginning to believe in God.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were never one of those atheists, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not saying that, but I'm beginning to give God more thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what did you do? Have some kind of religious experience?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell ya... I took my wife for lunch yesterday... we went and had some smorgasbord, and it kind of happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You found God at the smorgasbord?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam, people have religious experiences like on a lake or when they go up into the mountains, that kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe... but I had mine in a smorgasbord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam, you're too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to get myself a salad and I started to see all these vegetables, you know how they have all those salads laid out so that when it's time to get to the main course you won't eat too much... that scam to get you filled up so you don't eat too much chicken and beef and all that other stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah... I get the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I see celery, I see the lettuce, tomatoes, cauliflower... and I think, all these things come out of the ground... they just grow out of the ground. They had corn -- out of the ground... radish -- out of the ground. You say to yourself, how can all these things come out of the ground? You know what I'm talking about? All these things are out of the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, how can that be? It just happened that way? And I'm not even getting into the fruits... I'm just dealing with vegetables right now. With all those things coming out of the earth, there must be a God.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not getting the same religious effect that came over you. I don't know why, but I don't feel like running to a church to pray right this second.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta admit, it's amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks in the direction of BB.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah...  I don't believe it. See the guy over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam looks over to BB.</context>
      <utterance>That's the son of a bitch who crsahed into my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it! Mr. Banana Head is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That crazy guy that banged into my car and smashed my windows in. I don't fucking believe it! I'm gonna get him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a lot of nerve banging into my car, and you've got a lot of fucking nerve smashing my windows in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about? Why would I want to break your windows?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't smash my windows in?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got better things to do.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a hard-working guy... I don't go around breaking windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't break my windows?! You didn't break my windows?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB pushes him. Tilley starts to go for BB and they scuffle about. Moe and Sam try to pull the guys apart.</context>
      <utterance>Push me one more time and I'm gonna have to redefine your face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's go outside... let's settle this in the parking lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both head out the door. The other tin men follow, and others who have been paying attention to this alter- cation, also follow.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! You're not gonna get near my car... you're not gonna kick in my headlights again...  ... What am I talking about? I didn't even drive tonight. You wanna duke it? Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? What is this crowd here? We're charging admission?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB and Tilley both take up fighting stances and circle one another looking to take a shot. A police car pulls into the lot. The sound of the tires on the gravel catches Moe's attention and he sees it's the police.</context>
      <utterance>Back away... give me some elbow room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley and BB immediately drop their guards and lean against a car. One cop gets out of the police car and heads into the club, the other cop stays behind in the car. No one knows quite what to do since the policeman is so nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Police!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a lucky man... the police showed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his coat and leaves with Moe.</context>
      <utterance>We'll see who's the lucky one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SECRETARIES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lights go on again, and we see a group of GIRLS gathered around the cake placed on one of the desks. At the center of the group is ADA, in her late twenties, and very pregnant.</context>
      <utterance>Surprise!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never expected this. What a lovely cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ada blows out the candles, missing a couple, and getting help from one of the other Girls.</context>
      <utterance>Blow out the candles then.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Nine candles for nine months!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll miss you, Ada... you'd better bring that baby in to visit us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of girls hand around glasses of Coca-Cola. Nora stands in the midst of the girls, pleased for Ada. She yells out.</context>
      <utterance>Register him for his social security number.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cake is being passed out, and people are talking -- it has become somewhat of a party atmosphere. Nora turns to her friend, NELLIE.</context>
      <utterance>I love ya, Ada, and if you're smart you won't come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just decided... I'm going out with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sips her Coke.</context>
      <utterance>I have to. I just want to know what it's like to be with someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if what I've got with Tilley is as good as it gets, I just...  ... I gotta know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how are you going to manage it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley doesn't get home until at least two in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you know what you're doing ... you speak to some guy at the frozen food section for five minutes, you could jeopardize your whole marriage.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They touch their cups.</context>
      <utterance>Everything I've done in my life has been safe and practical, and where's that gotten me?  Well, here's to who knows what.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You want me to take you home?</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess that's to be expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance quietly for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>No, not right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Every time I listen to Sinatra, I always remember when I used to work in Atlantic City back in the late 40's... you know, a busboy job... Sinatra used to play at the 500 Club, and we used to take our dates and say, 'Hey, you wanna go and hear Sinatra?' Then we'd just lean on the door of the club in the alley and listen to the music. I think the girls were looking for something a bit more uptown.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance for a bit and look at one another. He leans toward her, holds her tight and kisses her. Then the RECORD STICKS on the words "that's the time"... "that's the time"... "that's the time"... BB slips off one of his loafers, while still embracing Nora, kicks it so that it hits the side of the record table. The RECORD SLIPS a little and continues to play correctly.</context>
      <utterance>I'd go with you and lean against the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a pretty good aim.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley gets up from the table and goes over to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tilley, somebody wants ya on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, this is Tilley...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to cry. She goes to hug BB.</context>
      <utterance>He must have gone crazy... I don't know what happened to him... he must have found out I was with you... I don't know... I don't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB puts his arms around Nora.</context>
      <utterance>Can I stay with you for a day or two?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, this is Gibraltar Aluminum Siding Company, we're taking a survey...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Would you be interested in our field representative giving you a home demonstration?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice calls out.</context>
      <utterance>... Home demonstration. We will have some factory representatives in your area today as it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Tilley walks over to the coffee machine.</context>
      <utterance>Tilley! Let me see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley passes Sam on the way to the coffee machine. Sam is looking through the sports page of the newspaper, along with Mouse and Gil.</context>
      <utterance>Wing, give me a minute to get a cup of coffee here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gil looking at the newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>What about 'Super Highway' in the seventh... it's paying 7 to 1. Ran well in its last race.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Super Highway'...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four in the fourth... twenty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... it just came to me -- number four in the fourth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number four in the fourth -- 'Rider's Revenge' -- 60 to 1, never been in the money. Nice pick, Tilley. Why don't you just throw the twenty dollars in the trash can right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley goes through the door into Wing's office.</context>
      <utterance>'Rider's Revenge'... I like that name. I've gotta go and see Wing.  Look, we can be scientific from now to doomsday, but we gotta be gutsy and go for the big one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps back, and puts his coffee down on a desk, and wipes his hand on the back of his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Ah! Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wing is sitting at his desk which is cluttered with papers.</context>
      <utterance>What's up, Wing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost a sale, Tilley. The Hudsons' loan didn't go through.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya mean? They wouldn't clear the loan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Mr. Hudson's some guy. He's got three outstanding shoplifting charges, failure to pay child support from a previous marriage ... guy's overdue on his mortgage, overdue on his car loan, and he was fired from his last job for misappropriation of funds.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with this world? There are sick people out there! Thievin' son of a bitch like that takes up my time... cuts into the amount of hours I have available to deal with other people interested in my wares! There's no fucking sympathy for the working man in this country.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't make our job easy, Tilley.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley goes to pick up his coffee off the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Wing, it was such a beautiful thing... you shoulda seen how I worked. Like a magician... 'this job is free'! It was my best... my best! There's no fucking justice in this world... there ain't no justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see the paper?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What section?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the newspaper to Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Home Improvement Commission... Hearings begin today..." Is this McCarthyism? What are they gonna see? If there are any communists?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free storm windows?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That you would provide a free set of storm windows with the sale of aluminum siding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I wouldn't be able to make any money if I was giving away storm windows. My cost of a storm window is somewhere like...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The storm windows, as I can recall, was not an issue. I mentioned that I thought the storm windows would cut down on their heating bill, and that they would obviously enhance the look of the house with the aluminum siding work we were going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you weren't dangling a free set of storm windows as a come-on to selling them the aluminum siding job? Because it says here, and I'm reading from a statement from Mr. Tabaleri...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya make of all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the future, Moe... it's the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'It was my understanding that the storm windows were included in the price of the sale.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno... looks like any tin man gets in that hot seat, then he's had it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk by a Volkswagen "beetle" car that's parked in front of BB's Cadillac. BB stops and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Then they can take your license forever... it don't seem fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I tell ya, I bet you could sell a ton of these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB looks at the car for a few more seconds, then goes to get into his car.</context>
      <utterance>That? Too silly-looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever see a dealership?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get in the car and drive off.</context>
      <utterance>Interesting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam sees a WAITER approaching and indicates to Tilley to get off the subject. Waiter arrives at their table.</context>
      <utterance>I keep racking my brain. I gotta find a way to really get even with this guy. It isn't enough to wreck his car... even breaking into his house and messing it up or something, that don't have enough impact. I mean, the man poked my wife! I gotta come up with something ingenious... something ingenious.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll take some meatloaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meatloaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the menu.</context>
      <utterance>No, I think I'll have some fish. No, no... fish doesn't fill you up. Meatloaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, it's meatloaf?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think, 'Sally's pride' in the second?  Get me a Bloody Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything other than the Bloody Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What number is Sally's Pride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Waiter walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Six.  No, I don't like to eat until the third race.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six... six... six... six.  I'm thinking one. Whose one?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Motor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then that's it, I'm going with one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley, this is insane. You're picking horses because you think you're clairvoyant or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look toward the track, the horses race to the finish line. Number nine streaks across the finish line.</context>
      <utterance>Sam, I'm not doing too well by checking the stats, so why not. I put my hand to my forehead, I see a one -- Mr. Motor in the second... twenty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallihan's Daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the racing form.</context>
      <utterance>I got it... I got it...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three to one... hundred and sixty smackers.  Hand to the forehead! Hand to the forehead!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley taps his forehead, with his eyes closed.</context>
      <utterance>You're not exactly talking about a long shot. Mr. Motor, for instance, is coming off at 50 to 1.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley stands up and is going through his money and race tickets.</context>
      <utterance>Third race, I see a six... I see a three. I don't think the verdict's in on that one yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wing paid a hundred on number five, he loses, I got hundred and forty... next race I'll lay down the bet.  What you taking in this race?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thrifty's Delight -- number four -- 20 bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take Thrifty's Delight -- 20 bucks, I got 20 on Mr. Motor, Wing's got a hundred on Night Fire. What's the odds on Night Fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see Night Fire winning. Fuck it, I'm not gonna even place the bet... I just made a hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, crazy? What happens if he wins?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not gonna win... I feel it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you something, she's getting on my nerves.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who, Nora?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah... who else is it gonna be... 'who, Nora"!... who else is there?  The whole idea of being with a girl on consecutive nights is new to me. It's one thing when they're with you for a night, but when they live with ya, it's stretching the point. They got a lot of things they bring with them... you go to the bathroom you see 'things' you never saw before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's the todo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they move your stuff around and it's not where it used to be... I'm not used to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean all this time you've never lived with a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Did we just meet? How long we been partners? No, I've never lived with a girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, oh boy! Did you wake up on the wrong side of the bed today?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB gives a big sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did. I came in last night, she was sleeping on my side of the bed. In my life I never got out of bed on the left side... in my life, never from the left.  I got close once up in the Catskills. I met this girl, Dorian. For a week we were together, but it wasn't the same because she always went to her room to change and do all that stuff. She didn't have things in my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All this 'cos I'm trying to get even with some guy.  You know what? I think I got to see her and put an end to this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that him?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB turns towards Nora. Nora waves to him, happily, with a twinkle in her eye. BB feels conspicuous -- people are looking at him. He gives a little wave.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Bill!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you stopped by. This is a real surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I got a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. How can I help?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... er...  Well, the problem is... like... is like... eh, you know... you're the problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's things that are bothering me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know... things.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, like things that come up... stuff... like... you know, annoyances.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annoyances?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to explain... very hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, try.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As an example... I came home last night, I get undressed, and I realize you're sleeping on my side of the bed. I've always slept on that side... it's something I've always done.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why didn't you just nudge me a bit and tell me to go and sleep on the other side?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to wake you up... I thought you might think it was kind of stupid or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's easily changed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there are other things... bigger things. But I realize just talking about it, they all sound petty and silly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB looks around, very uncomfortable, and he shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, if you think all of this is going too fast, maybe I should move out. Is that what you want, Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a long beat.</context>
      <utterance>I really care for you, but if you think it's best.  I don't want to make you unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think we've got to take drastic action.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I'd come by and get things off my chest... talk it out.  Listen, I'm going over to Pimlico... catch the seventh race... wanna come?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get away from work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to walk away, then turns back and gives her a quick kiss. He turns and walks away. Nora watches him as he walks by the rows and rows of secretaries and clerks.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe tears up his ticket.</context>
      <utterance>Way to go... Southern Belle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should have bet with me, Moe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was your horse, Wing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Southern Belle. You oughta know, you bet her for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wing goes to look at form.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna go with the favorite in this one -- Fordnee Lane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you what, I won sixteen plus on the other race, from those winnings you can bet me eight hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight hundred?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I wanna bet eight hundred on Fordnee Lane.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam is looking at Tilley knowing that he's really in a jam.</context>
      <utterance>Fordnee lane -- eight hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley looks over to Sam, with panic on his face. Wing turns back to Tilley and Sam.</context>
      <utterance>Waiter, can you get me a cup of coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys want anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I tell you, I got a problem.</context>
      <utterance>Er... hum... er... hey, Wing...</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the eight hundred on Fordnee Lane. I haven't got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the eight hundred.</context>
      <utterance>No, you got it wrong. You take it from the sixteen plus I won...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got the winnings.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya mean, you don't have my winnings?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wing, it was the craziest thing... I didn't want to mention it earlier because it was so nuts... it was the craziest thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to even tell you this without being embarrassed for myself. It was an accident... it's like one of those things out of the blue... it's crazy... you can't explain it... it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam, what is he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had an accident of some sort.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It happens... I don't know how... I don't know how to explain. It's too crazy, I swear to God, Wing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute... you're telling me that I didn't win the last race?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won, Wing... you won, it's just that you're not getting any money... it was a fluke. I swear, I don't know how it could have happened. A ten-year-old couldn't have made the mistake I made... I don't know, I swear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a beat while Wing just looks at Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>If there was some way I could make it up, believe me, I would, because you know where I stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where I stand, Wing. If there was any way, believe me, I'd make it up. I'd give you thirty percent of what you didn't get because it was a fluke... I'm willing to make some kind of retribution.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just pocketed the God damned money... you just took my money and slipped it into your God damned pocket, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'd split fifty-fifty with you, that's how badly I feel under the circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get this straight, you son of a bitch, you owe me sixteen plus... I want sixteen plus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>put it on my tab.</context>
      <utterance>Am I trying to shirk my responsibility? That's not the way I see it... it was a fluke, a crazy thing that happened, but I stand behind my honor on this...</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you tell me?</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is wrong with him? What the hell is wrong with him? He's stealing money from me... what the hell is wrong with him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the whole story.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wing is totally frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>You work with him, Sam... for Christ sake...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, wrong? It was a fluke... it was an accident. I don't know what the hell went wrong. It was a one-in-a-million thing that happened to me when I went to place that bet. I'm trying to do what I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley, what the hell happened to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you at least give him the six hundred that you pocketed from the six races he lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck him! It's on my tab. At least I've got six hundred in my pocket right now. It's like another loan. Sam, you got to think about today. Today, I got six hundred bucks in my pocket. You know what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Sam and Tilley walk towards Tilley's Cadillac, BB and Moe are walking to BB's Cadillac parked close to Tilley's car. They see each other.</context>
      <utterance>It's like some guy trying to sell me life insurance. You think I'm gonna take some money out of my pocket to give to some jerk so that somebody can take it when I'm dead? No, Sam, you gotta live for today. I'm gonna live as good as I can every day. You know what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mr. Marengay went to the track!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bother to bet, or did you just hand your money to the tellers?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sarcasm's killing me.  I thought you were looking to get even.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's your accountant, mister, 'cos I think you're down in the debit side.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Who's stuck with my wife. You or me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to believe that you were setting me up with your wife as some kind of decoy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a long beat as the two guys eye one another. Then, almost in a soft apologetic manner, BB speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Decoy is the word!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB gets into his car.</context>
      <utterance>Okay then, you win.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I win?  That guy would never let me win. He must be setting me up. The son of a bitch is setting me up, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For crying out loud, why don't you just leave it at that... you win.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB's car pulls away. Tilley and Sam watch him go.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't have won.  I smell a rat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BB, I think you're getting a little humility in your blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If getting Nora is part of losing, Thank God I didn't win.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley nods.</context>
      <utterance>This is good, Stan... nice work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a LOUD, SAWING noise and HAMMERING echoing through the warehouse throughout this scene.</context>
      <utterance>Fossey says it should go down very well with the city council. Could help us appropriate more funds. This goes a long way to establish our credibility in what we're trying to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot more where this came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I think you should do now. Why don't you pull some files... some files that were completed, others that went unsold, and I'll have somebody run it down, talk to the customers and get some statements.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That might not be easy.</context>
      <utterance>Pulling files is another thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To sneak a few here and there when you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that might be good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think if we made this one of our factory showcase houses?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good location... get a lot of traffic on this street.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHUBNER</speaker>
      <mode>MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean, Mr. Gable?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I do, Alan? I pick certain houses that are strategically located, we put up the aluminum siding, and for every referral, for every person who sees this quality job that we do... sees how beautiful it is... I give you two hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUBNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peels off four hundred dollars and hands the money to Shubner.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. God knows how many homes we could sell by people passing this house. It's perfectly placed for that.  Alan, this is how confident I feel that this house will drum up business for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four hundred dollars... I'm giving you commission on two house referrals before I put a panel on the side of your house... that's how confident I feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUBNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that many people are going to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm certain of it. I'm not giving away four hundred dollars for my health... I'm a businessman, and I'm a good businessman. This is good business for me. I'm giving it away 'cos I believe in this house, believe that it will refer me to other jobs which means money in my pocket, which means money in your pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUBNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB smiles. Suddenly Moe winces in pain.</context>
      <utterance>You got a deal, Mr. Gable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUBNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe collapses to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Something wrong, sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I finally got hold of May... she was over your sister's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be down here shortly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BB, I don't have any insurance. If I die, May's got nothing... nothing... nothing for Leonard. The only money I've got is in my pocket. That's all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just take it easy, Moe... rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they sign? Did they sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, BB! Did you sign them?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry... don't worry. I'll take care of it tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn, my chest hurts.  I always taught you, BB, never walk out of a place without a signed contract. Somebody's word ain't spit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They round the bend of the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>They'll sign, Moe. Don't worry, they'll sign.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Do you think you have some obligation?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno... I thought I'd better call, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm glad you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what's gonna happen to Moe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She gives BB a kiss on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope he's okay.  I'll see you when you get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone and walks to a room opposite. He opens the door and stands in the doorway looking at Moe who is lying beneath an oxygen tent.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the bill to Mouse.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see what the damage is.  Babum... babum... babum... babum...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mouse, figure it out, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just split it five ways?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>he eats like an animal.</context>
      <utterance>No way! I didn't eat anything, so why should I pay for Mouse...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sometimes you'll eat more than he does, and it'll even out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way! He's a pig! He always eats more than anyone else. Why should I pay for his food?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about? Today I happened to have eggs and flapjacks, some cantalope, some juice and then another juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like an animal! Like an animal!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But yesterday, what did I have?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he have?  Sam, what did he have?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get out my notebook. How the fuck do I know what he had?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't remember what he had. Gil, what did he have?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pancakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the diner window we see Nora's car pull up and park outside the diner.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what did you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, a quiz show? We don't know what you had. What did you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had very little.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very little!! You eat like an animal! It couldn't have been very little.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have that much... doesn't anybody remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't remember, I don't know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have sworn he had pancakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he didn't have pancakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a clue... maple syrup was used.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK at the window of the diner.</context>
      <utterance>French toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French toast? He had more than French toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear further RAPPING on the window.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but not a lot more.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a damn... it's split five ways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was not long ago you never would have seen a woman in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to tell me. How many nights did you drop me off and come up here all the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So, what's the scoop, Nora?</context>
      <utterance>I know. I was just trying to be congenial... you know, start a conversation off, on a nice kind of light level, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you know, I think we really should get divorced.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes sense. You want some more coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'll have some.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florence, some coffee here.  It's for the best.  You know, we were kind of fooling ourselves, weren't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it went wrong somewhere along the line -- I don't know where though.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Florence walks over and pours coffee for Tilley and Nora, then walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, something went wrong... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you like this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All in all I guess it'll all work out for the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you feel that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, can you figure it out? A guy bangs into my car, thinks I did him in, tries to get even with me by stealing my wife, you two people fall in love... can you figure that out?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You telling me you didn't know this was the guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I told you I ran into another tin man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't tell me he was a tin man... he told me he sold baby pictures.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your life. All I know is this guy has a bent weather vane.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God! Not another tin man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, this is Superior Aluminum Siding. We're going to have...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... a salesman in your area today... BB is sitting in a chair across from Looney.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beeb, why don't you let Stanley work with you. I'm off to Florida at the end of the week for some sun and fun. Let Stanley work with you, and when I get back, we'll see how Moe's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. To be honest with you, I think I'd rather work alone ... he's too green. Is he a pain in the ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He don't talk much; he's a good listener, so he can't really get on your nerves. He's a lousy pool player and he can't play cards for shit, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what good is he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Studious type... takes a lot of notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this is a sales pitch, I think you got to work a little harder 'cos I don't think you've got good product.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora drives the car forward and then backwards again almost running BB down. She rolls down the window (auto- matically) so that she can yell.</context>
      <utterance>What are you, crazy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she backs the car up. BB tries to go around the front of the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're a goddamn tin man!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora starts to move the car towards him. He moves away, and her car smashes into the side of his car. She presses the button to the window and rolls it down just a shade.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! Wait a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls up the window, floors the car, and drives away.</context>
      <utterance>You wanted to win me just to get even with my husband... screw you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora's CAR SCREECHES around the corner.</context>
      <utterance>I think you ought to get rid of this car... it's bad luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the guy again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some kind of sickness that runs in that family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mouse continue singing in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Why can't they get rid of that fucking record? It's not a hit anymore... nobody cares about this song anymore... it's history.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Day-O! da,da,da,da,day...'</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can always smash the juke box, or break in and steal the record.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's getting on my nerves. The guy eats like an animal, and sings like an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley hits the ball and sinks the shot.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's me, but I'm beginning to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir... yes, sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a look at this crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IRS? They're not gonna leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With those words there's a genuine moment of concern from all of the tin men -- even Mouse stops singing. Tilley picks up the envelope and pulls out the letter.</context>
      <utterance>Home Improvement Commission.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to appear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gil looks over Tilley's shoulder at the letter. Mouse comes over.</context>
      <utterance>I think that's the gist of what they're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we just ignore it? How do they know we got the letter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's certified.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Sam?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno... I don't know what they've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is this happening? Am I paranoid or something? I mean, why is this happening? The government is after me... the state is after me... Mr. Marengay ... somebody is always after me. What the hell's going on here? I'm just this guy. What's the big deal? They can't get along without me? The government can't operate unless they've got Tilley's money... the Commission's after my job! This shit's driving me insane! All the lying, thieving, stealing corporations in this world, and the IRS takes the time to come for me? There's billions of dollars out there but they've got to come and get Tilley's four thousand dollars!  Turn off the fucking Belafonte song now, or I'm gonna break the goddamn machine!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Beeb, let's dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight, Ruthie, my dancing shoes are on holiday.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruthie moves off. BB takes a shot of whiskey and downs it, and then drinks some beer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm more than sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was the best you ever saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his shot glass towards the bartender, and the bartender fills it up.</context>
      <utterance>Best I ever saw? Best tin man I ever saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry Apel... Dandy Flynn... those guys had good lines, but they burned themselves out too fast. Best? Moe's the best... the best there ever was. If he's in the door, he's got a sale. The best closer ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB downs another shot glass of whisky.</context>
      <utterance>What's some of the hustles he used to pull?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanely wants to get back to the topic of best tin man.</context>
      <utterance>God damn Nora... God damn Nora! I'm trying to adjust... I'm putting up with things I never put up with in my life. I mean, give me a break... give me a break, woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what are a couple of things you and Moe have done?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was getting to be real pleasant ... figure that.  More than pleasant. To hell with her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come Moe's so good? Why do you think, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB holds out his glass again to the bartender who refills it. BB downs the shot and drinks more beer.</context>
      <utterance>Great man, Moe. Great man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the $10 bill down on the bar and walks out of the club.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know why they're so irrational... chicks. I dunno. I think it's because air gets inside 'em.  She probably went back home, to her husband.  Eleven-thirty... he wouldn't be home yet.  This outght to cover it, Stanley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got nothing concrete against us, because if it's just hearsay stuff, it's neither here nor there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my car? What happened to my car?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's better I drop you off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB tries to focus on Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>You're a sick man! You smash my car, you steal my wife, and now you come to rob me! You're one demented human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley throws an egg at BB and hits him in the head. BB is groggy and confused and still drunk.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to call the police and send you to jail... but I'm going to humiliate you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya want to break into my house for? This ain't the fucking Rockefeller mansion! There ain't thirty-eight television sets here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tilley throws another egg at BB and hits him in the head again. Egg yolk drips down BB's face. He tries to get off the floor, but can't.</context>
      <utterance>They ain't saying 'Nelson, I think we've had a break-in... count the sets to see how many we've got left.' There ain't tons of jewelry hanging out of drawers... it ain't like I don't know which watch to put on, I got so many. I'm a working man, trying to make an honest living. What fucking morality you got, asshole?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley, getting ready with another egg.</context>
      <utterance>You're the craziest human being on the face of this earth!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else do you want from me? Huh? What else?! I've got enough problems with the I.R.S. busting my balls and the Home Improvement Commission bullshit to contend with. I don't need aggravation from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody!</context>
      <utterance>Nobody does this to me and lives!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws a tomato.</context>
      <utterance>How do ya like your eggs? Over easy?  Side of tomatoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley throws another egg.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to rue the day you ran into my car. This ain't the end... this is just the beginning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy breaks into my house and I'm being charged with assault? It makes no sense...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get it down right. The guy broke into your house, you hit him in the head with a gun, went to the refrigerator, took out eggs and tomatoes and threw them at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was defending myself... he was stealing from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't sound like defense to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to humiliate the guy. Here I am, out busting my ass all day making a decent living, I come home, and some schmuck is trying to steal from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you hit him with a gun, and pelted him with eggs and tomatoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had some soup I would have thrown soup at him... is there any law you can't throw eggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Babowski claims he didn't break into your house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I do? Invite him in so that I could throw eggs at him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe Mr. Babowski intended to break into your house, but these circumstances of the guy being pelted with eggs and tomatoes is something we need to look into.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's lucky that he didn't rob me last week, 'cos then my wife was living at home and we had all kinds of things in the fridge... I could have thrown barley soup, pumpkin pie, candied yams... yeah, he got off light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it, the man throws eggs at me and now I'm gonna have breakfast with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His partner says maybe the two of you can sit down and come to some kind of settlement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you what... I'll drop the charges against you, and we can wipe the slate clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See how quickly you can clear it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't understand how the slate gets wiped clean when he breaks into my house and I'm the one charged.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I wasn't breaking into your house. I was looking for your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WAITRESS approaches.</context>
      <utterance>All right... all right... I'm too tired... the slate's clean... the slate's clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress writes his order.</context>
      <utterance>Couple of eggs over, some hash browns, some toast -- toasted dark... butter on the side, large grapefruit juice and some coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see that BB is getting a little irritable.</context>
      <utterance>On second thought, instead of the eggs over, if I ordered soft boiled eggs do you take them out of the shell or leave them in the shells?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We leave them in the shell.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like them that way because they get hot in the hand and it's hard to scoop the stuff out... it's not good... and you get little bits of shell in there and it doesn't taste good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just order some scrambled eggs and be done with it... all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm going to order, at least I ought to be content with my food.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting a little hungry... I've got a headache as it is. Just order some eggs so some other people can have something to eat before the lunch trade comes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I need a guy telling me what I should or shouldn't eat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not a four-star restaurant ... we're not having a gourmet meal... we're ordering breakfast, for Christ sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It so happens I haven't been to this restaurant before. I don't know how they do their eggs... if they're over easy and they're gooey, I'm not happy with it... and I'm not happy if the soft boiled eggs are left in the shell...</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have some French toast and a cup of coffee?  Bagel, what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I'm ordering here. At least you can have the courtesy to let a man order his breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French toast and a cup of coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley stands up from the table and starts to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Sam, this guy gets on my nerves... from day one! I knew it then and I know it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley turns and is face-to-face with BB.</context>
      <utterance>I'm back to pressing charges against you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to play that way? This game ain't over, mister... it ain't over...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, you want to finish it now? You want to finish it right now? I'm ready... I'm ready now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ready?! You're ready, that's what you're saying?! You're ready now?! I have to be intimidated... I have to be brought here to be intimidated...</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB lunges for Tilley across the table, Sam and Bagel try to intervene -- the Waitress doesn't know what to do.</context>
      <utterance>I can't stand it any longer. You're driving me out of my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>take it easy.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, guys... take it easy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley and BB pull at one another.</context>
      <utterance>Get the people with the straitjackets... this man is out of control.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bagel and Sam pull them apart.</context>
      <utterance>We're gonna finish it... we're gonna finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam ushers Tilley to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not finished with him, Sam.  You heard me... I'm not finished with you, mister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moe, when you decided to marry May, how did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did ya know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean to make up my mind to marry her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe shrugs his shoulders as if he doesn't know.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How did ya know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moe smiles.</context>
      <utterance>This Nora is a pain in the ass, Moe... a pain in the ass. It's worse now than when she used to be around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna hear something? The other night at the Corral Club, I turned down a dance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turned down a dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the odds on that? You think you can come up with odds on that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hundred to one BB don't dance... a hundred to one against.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting out of the business, BB... I've got nothing for all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot of good times, Moe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of good times, but I can't live off the good times.  You know, my brother-in-law has offered me a job at Hess Shoes. I think maybe I should do it. You get there in the morning, you come home at night... you get health benefits... I get to be assistant manager.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, Moe? You're gonna spend the day measuring people's feet? 'You're an "E" fit... you're a "D" wide... you got a high arch... I'll show you something in an alligator... something with a wing tip...' How can you talk about that all day long?  Moe, you're the best tin man there ever was. Nobody's a better closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over, BB... it's over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, May's happy about this Hess Shoe thing, heh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To say the least.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you think, Tilley?</context>
      <utterance>You know, when I saw 'Bonanza' the other day, something occurred to me. There's those three guys living on the Ponderosa and you never hear them say anything about wanting to get laid. You never hear Hoss turn to Little Joe and say 'I had such a hard-on when I woke up this morning.' You know ... they never talk about broads ... nothing. Ya never hear Little Joe say 'Hey, Hoss, I went into Virginia City and saw a girl with the greatest ass I ever saw in my life.' Ya just see 'em walking around the Ponderosa saying, 'Yes, Pa,' and 'Where's Little Joe?' Nothing about broads. I don't think I'm being too picky... at least once if they talked about getting horny. I don't care if you're living on the Ponderosa or right here in Baltimore, guys talk about getting laid.  I'm beginning to think that show doesn't have too much realism.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam, I can't concentrate on 'Bonanza' shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got too much on my brain, what with that asshole and the Home Improvement Commission, I don't want to have to worry about whether Little Joe got laid last night.  Let's go and eat something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we'll go and have some lunch at the smorgasbord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, if you're responsible for all the stuff down here, maybe you got a moment's attention for me.  Between the I.R.S., this Home Improvement Commission and Mr. Marengay, I got it up to here with this bullshit. To be frank with you, I'm in the toilet here. If you can see your way... A WOMAN with a tray starts to approach Tilley. Tilley turns to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm praying here... go around.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to get some of the salad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals for her to walk around him. The Woman looks at him and moves down the line.</context>
      <utterance>It's out of order... go around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a WOMAN'S VOICE on the other end of the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Nora Tilley, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What department is she with?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's with Social Security.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which department is Social Security?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>she's got a desk towards the back.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno... she's there somewhere ... yeah, on the third floor...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a moment... checking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stanley, can I help you look for something?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm just making myself busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wouldn't do that. Bagel don't like nobody looking at the files.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Tilley.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE goes DEAD. BB reluctantly puts the receiver down.</context>
      <utterance>Nora, this is BB.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you approach Mr. Boloshevski August 18, 1961, while he was cutting his front lawn and tell him that his house had been selected, as one of only 16 homes in the state of Maryland, for a free aluminum siding job?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boloshevski.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't ring a bell.  Sam, does it ring a bell to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't ring a bell to me either, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you suggest that for a nominal labor charge, he would receive over five thousand dollars' worth of aluminum siding?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an awful lot for nothing. Doesn't sound like good business to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Boloshevski was ultimately charged twenty-four hundred dollars for labor, which according to our figures is about the average cost of an aluminum siding job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get the point of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-four hundred dollars that you charged for labor, is the same as if Mr. Boloshevski had purchased the aluminum siding and had the labor done.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'm missing the point here, but if he paid twenty-four hundred, which is the cost of the job, I can't see anything wrong with that. I don't know the guy, but I don't quite get the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we're getting at here... what we're trying to stress, is that the job was sold under false terms. The man didn't win any award... he was not getting aluminum siding at a special price. A clear case of deception was involved here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he talking about? The man got the job for twenty-four hundred dollars, and that's what it costs in aluminum siding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>if I make myself clear.</context>
      <utterance>Um... I don't know... we have no recollection of this particular job, but I don't know if this is deception. Look, if you work in a clothing store, some guy tries on a suit, it looks like shit, but you tell him it looks wonderful. The guy's standing there looking like a sack of shit, the salesman says what a great suit and the man buys it. That's deception as far as I can see, but I don't understand the deceptiveness that you say we're responsible for...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd go along with that as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we're trying to establish are the principles that have been laid down as part of the Home Improvement code of ethics... that you cannot mislead someone intentionally, and I think that's the principle that applies to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another commissioner, BUD DELANEY, takes the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Did somebody put a gun to this guy's head and make him spend twenty-four hundred dollars? I don't get the point here. I don't know the specifics of this case, not being privy to all the information, but all I can say is this guy got a fair price for a fair job.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know Mr. and Mrs. Rayburn of 156 Aberdeen Avenue, Essex?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you'd have to familiarize me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The couple purchased twenty-eight hundred dollars' worth of aluminum siding and the two of you were the salesmen on record. They say, and I quote here, 'that they would have received one hundred and fifty dollars per home for every person in the neighborhood who saw their house and decided to buy aluminum siding.'  Is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you aware that, according to the Home Improvement code, you are not allowed to exceed a twenty dollar limit in incentives?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We wanted to be a little more generous, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The couple said that they never did receive any money from any other jobs, as you had promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't get any leads from them. Their house was not the showplace that we thought it would be. It didn't generate the activity that we had hoped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But should a referral turn up in the community, we'd be more than happy to give them twenty dollars instead of the hundred and fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He then leans over to Delaney, and they start to confer. Tilley and Sam watch, wondering what's going on. Masters leans in the other direction, holding his hand over the microphone, and he talks to the other commissioners. They nod in approval, then Masters leans back into the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse us for one moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much, gentlemen. Should there be a reason in the future to call you back, we would like to reserve that right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We beat 'em, Sam... we beat 'em! What a piece of cake! No problem! They ain't got nothing on us... clean as a whistle... we're clean as a whistle!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a drink. I hate inquisitions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora still walking toward her car in the downpour.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a chance to explain. You owe me that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB lets her walk away. After a beat, he yells out.</context>
      <utterance>I don't owe you anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora stops and turns to look at BB.</context>
      <utterance>It was a lousy thing to do, okay? It was a lousy thing to use you to get back at your husband... but the fact is that I never would have met you otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>but a lot of good came out of it.</context>
      <utterance>It was lousy... it was a disgusting, terrible thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of a person would come up with such a devious thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand looking at one another in the rain.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not always a nice guy, I admit that. I got a lot of training in deceit... it's an occupational hazard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to know what it is about me that I have to fall for tin men. What kind of character flaw do I have?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to have to come here. I wish that I didn't have to ever see you again. I've gone this far in my life without having to have this kind of thing happen to me. I was going through life, sailing along, pretty good... doing okay, and I tried to get even with some crazy guy... and I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wet becomes you. Gets rid of some of the slickness.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora eyes him carefully. The rain falls on her umbrella and the rain beats on BB's head. After a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like the idea that I'm not in control of this, but if this stuff's got to happen, I guess I've got no choice. I wanna... ya know...  ... I wanna be with ya! Okay, I said that... I said it, okay?! I wanna be with ya! It pisses the hell out of me, and I'm gonna tell you that to your face, but I want to be with you because... I miss you and I'd like to live with you... I'd like to marry you... and that's that!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight smile comes to BB's face.</context>
      <utterance>I was hoping for something a little more romantic... but, okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, Tilley, we been working together for over a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, must be about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking that sometimes a different combination makes for better luck. Ya know what I mean? I mean, maybe the two of us ain't the right combination.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just getting used to ya, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's face it, we're not exactly setting the world on fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a slump... it's a slump, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's a slump, but like baseball, some time they have to change the lineup to get the team going again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not serious about this, are you, Sam?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're serious? You wanna get another partner? You don't think I'm gonna pull out of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're gonna... I know you're gonna.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>you know what I'm saying?</context>
      <utterance>Look, we beat the Commission today ... you know, we got a little bit of a victory. We split right now and maybe we can add to that...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know... I know. Change in the lineup. Okay, maybe it'll help... maybe it'll help.  You got any ideas for a new partner?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I had a conversation with Solly Shavitz, so... maybe I'll go with him.  Mouse is gonna need a new partner because Dennis is going into used cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Mouse! Mouse! He gets on my nerves... He eats too much.  Here's to some pretty good times, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it... the broad smashes into his car and he takes her dancing. Some kind of dating ritual that I'm not familiar with.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BB's a pretty good tin man, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna come back and stay the night?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both sit down. BB looks at Nora.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno... all my things are back at Nellie's -- the other side of town.  I know what I could do, I'll go back to the house... there's still a few things I left behind ... at least I can get a change of clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad this is working out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't really show a great deal of exuberance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, for me... I'm a parade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The I.R.S... they need my furniture. They got some living room somewhere in this country that needs to be furnished.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're taking the furniture?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The furniture, the whole house. They locked it up... they confiscated it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What do you expect? You expect to get some preferential treatment ... you're some special case? You've got to pay your taxes just like everybody else has to pay their taxes!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many arguments did we used to have about filing your taxes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora starts toward him. Tilley sits on the steps.</context>
      <utterance>We had a lot of arguments.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a responsibility that you've got to have. It's a long way from high school, Tilley.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I still got my Cadillac.</context>
      <utterance>I was doing pretty good there for a while... doing pretty good. Had my house, had a wife, a Cadillac...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you gonna sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll stay at Sam's for a couple of days until I get set up.  What're you doing here, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's just a couple of things you didn't throw out of the house ... a couple of things I didn't find in the drawer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I did a pretty good house cleaning number on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, about the divorce. Do you want to file, or should I file?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to be frank with you, this guy is nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me all about it... all about how you threw eggs at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told you it was about eggs? The guy tried to break into my house. He tried to steal things from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was trying to find me. We had an argument.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you'd be making a big mistake if you married him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not for you to make decisions for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe I should, because I think you're being misled... I think you're confused. I think...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what I'm doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora, listen to me. I know about guys...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your concern, but it's not for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this guy is as bad a choice as you could make. Bad choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good one to give advice... you're sitting on the steps, locked out of your house because you can't pay your taxes, and you're going to give me advice on life?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora looks at him, starts to say something, then stands up and walks down the steps of the house toward her car.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not giving you a divorce, and that's it. I'm looking out for your welfare. No divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora turns toward Tilley and suddenly snaps.</context>
      <utterance>It's for your own benefit, and you'll thank me for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My benefit! You don't give a damn about me! You don't give a damn who I marry. The reason you don't want me to marry is because he's the one taking your wife, and you've got your own problems with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't care about me... it's the same bullshit you're doing. That's what it always is with you, Tilley. It's always you! The I.R.S. took your house... your furniture! You don't say anything about my things in the house. I've got things in the house I worked damn hard for, and things that belonged to my family... the headboard that was given to me by Aunt Josephine, it's got to be at least a hundred years old... and the hand-embroidered footstool...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What footstool?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hand-embroidered footstool over by the TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember seeing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been there forever... it was my granny's.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been there forever? I've never seen it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've never seen it!? You've never seen it!? You put your feet on it to watch TV... the hand-embroidered footstool.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about. I never put my feet up to watch TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's the way it's always been.</context>
      <utterance>That's the way you are, Tilley, it doesn't mean anything to you. You don't care if they take it all away. It's all you, Tilley!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See ya around.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the lift back, BB.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Stanley closes the car door and BB drives off. Stanley watches BB's car turn the bend, and then he goes toward the office door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Stanley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to Stanley.</context>
      <utterance>You know something, Stanley, I can always smell a guy who's not made of tin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's against the law to steal files. I could call and have you arrested and sent to jail, right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll put everything back, nobody's the wiser.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan nods "yes."</context>
      <utterance>You work for the Commission, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't the Commission have enough information? They got to send out guys like you to spy?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB walks closer to Stanley, looks at him for a second, grabs him by his tie and pushes him backwards. Stanley crashes into the filing cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we just started out, and if we had some really good hard facts of some infractions, it would give us a lot of credibility in the community.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to the filing cabinet, flips through some files and pulls out three files. Stanley has gotten up from the floor. BB throws the files down on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>You know what your big problem is, Stanley? You're lazy. If you want to find out stuff, then you dig... you get on the phone... you canvas... 'We're from the Home Improvement Commission...' Go find your leads... that's what we do all the time. You're just lazy, Stanley. If we're doing something wrong, you should collect all your evidence. Instead, you snoop around... steal files. What is this? Undercover time? You think you're breaking up some big drug ring? Is this the Mafia you've infiltrated? All you've got here is a bunch of guys selling tin for Christ sake!  You want some files?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley gathers up the files from the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Here... here's some jobs I did. Leave Moe out of this... he quit the business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, get out of here. Stanley starts for the door, and turns back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley exits the office. BB picks up the files that Stanley had taken out of the filing cabinet, and starts to put them back. Then he slams the filing drawers closed very hard.</context>
      <utterance>If it's not gonna be you, it's gonna be somebody else... and if it's not tonight, it's gonna be another time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if I talked to him another day he'll change his mind. I mean, he's like that... one day, he's this way and another day he's that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, he's probably, you know, upset about the I.R.S. taking the house and all our stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever see a Volkswagen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, those little Volkswagens.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a car... a little car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that have to do with anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno... they're interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so interesting about a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. It's a little thing... you know, a little thing. Guy tells me they don't even have radiators... they're air-cooled.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>something new. I like it.</context>
      <utterance>It's interesting... different...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley and Mouse. It looks weird, doesn't it? Looks very weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's hope you have some better luck with Mouse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes over to the office door, opens it and yells to Tilley.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Marengay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley comes out of the office and stands looking at BB.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tilley... Mr. Marengay's out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley moves down the hall toward BB.</context>
      <utterance>Can I talk to you in private, or do I have to talk to you over fourteen pool tables?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got enough that's going down between the two of us, but the fact of the matter is that I love your wife, and I want to marry her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care who she marries, but I don't want her marrying you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just talk about this in a nice, rational manner.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rational? You're going to be rational?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got our problems, but let's try and isolate this particular situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isolate... isolate... I like this kind of talk. What the hell nonsense is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna gain from this thing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now let me see here... I've got to isolate that for a moment and think it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's going to benefit from making me mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ought to hear yourself. You know that? You ought to listen to the way you talk. You come in here, you want to take my wife ... you want to isolate this situation... you want to be rational. I've got no tolerance for you, mister. You know what I'm saying?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're saying is you don't want to discuss this, am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other tin men move closer to Tilley and BB, crowding in.</context>
      <utterance>You like pool?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I enjoy the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB stares at Tilley; Tilley eyes BB.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we play a little game of eight ball? If I lose, I consent to the divorce... if you lose, you give Nora up... walk away from her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rack 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tin men react. BB hits the ball and sinks it.</context>
      <utterance>Combination... side pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's four.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley keeps moving around the table, sinking one ball after the other. He's enthusiastic, excited and confi- dent. He sinks another ball, and another. He sinks every ball, then he eyes the eight ball for the coup de grace.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir! Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make this one here, and you win.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots. The eight ball heads for the pocket and doesn't make it. It hangs up on the felt about two feet from the pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Don't I know it... don't I know it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB quickly goes to work... sinks every one of his balls. He eyes the eight ball carefully. Tilley's nervous. A couple of the tin men make private side bets whether the ball goes or doesn't. BB lines up the shot; he shoots, and it misses, hanging up on the lip of the pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Bad break.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley quickly moves and sinks the eight ball.</context>
      <utterance>Tough break.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... that puts an end to one of our differences. Now, concerning you...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna beat the crap out of you. You want it here or do you want it outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB turns his back on Tilley to move toward the door. Tilley swings with all his might and hits BB in the back of the head. BB almost falls to the ground. Tilley goes to hit him again. BB hits him in the face, knocking him back. Tilley falls back... BB starts to move toward him. The tin men move in.</context>
      <utterance>Outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB gets to his feet... the two guys eye one another, moving. BB quickly moves with incredible cat-like speed with four hits into the stomach, really fast, and one hit to Tilley's head. Tilley falls into the rack of pool cues, they all fall to the ground. BB goes to jump on Tilley. He slips on one of the pool cues and falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Stay out of this... this is between the two of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Improves the insulation...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carly, Cheese and Looney are sitting around a desk drink- ing coffee.</context>
      <utterance>... We'll have a representative in your area...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB enters, says "hi" to the Girls, moves to get a coffee.</context>
      <utterance>... Danny's an example of that. Danny goes into a bar, chicks lined up and down the bar. Walks up to one and says, 'Honey, would you like to fuck?' She'd slap him in the face. He'd move down to the next girl, say the same thing... she'd slap him. Then he'd just keep moving down, going from one girl to the other. Fifteen, maybe sixteen girls would tell him to get lost... to get the hell out of there...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB moves over to the guys.</context>
      <utterance>... Call him names... but he doesn't take it personal, you see ... he keeps going, and then the next girl smiles. He says, 'Why don't you buy me a drink'... he scores. Every time. He goes through a lot of girls, takes a lot of slaps in the face, but he never takes it personally...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looney looks up and sees BB's face.</context>
      <utterance>... And he always gets what he wants.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Beeb. What happened to you? That broad beat the shit out of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bagel walks out of his office and across to NICK, a tin man sitting at a desk across from Looney. He hands Nick a file.</context>
      <utterance>I think you must enjoy these masochistic relationships. Smashes your car... punches you in the face...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bagel, you ought to get a load of this broad Beeb's messing with.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks back to his office.</context>
      <utterance>Looks a little too romantic for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who's no longer married to who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(NOTE: The following action and dialogue will run concurrently.)</context>
      <utterance>Well, we ought to know. There's like a million fucking people living in Baltimore. How many guesses do we get?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No, but they're friends here for William Babowski. of them.</context>
      <utterance>CHEESE I have a certified letter</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LOONEY  Friends of them... The guy over there. CARLY The Man approaches BB who Ed and Ethel? is standing back from the group a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>friendly with Ruby and Joe. William Babowski?</context>
      <utterance>Ed and Ethel aren't that MAN</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Essex.</context>
      <utterance>LOONEY Yeah... yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denise Essex. Did she have went down you seem a a sister named Wilma? little off your feed to me.</context>
      <utterance>CARLY Because ever since Moe</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. BB Thanks for the concern, CARLY Bagel, but I'll be all You're kidding me. right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get to that once we've discussed Wilma... they'll still be broken up... we'll get to that in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know Wilma?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points to car driving out of parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Wing, isn't that the putz from the Commission?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Masters? Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's he doing hanging around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants information.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I nailed his ass the other day, Wing. Can't lay a finger on me. I was amazing, you should have been there. I was amazing... I was respectful, courteous, but I was slipping and sliding... they couldn't touch me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna sell me out to the Commission? Wing, am I hearing this right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>what am I gonna do?</context>
      <utterance>I'm up front with you about this... I'm up front with ya, Tilley. I've got my balls in a vice...</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this about the money I owe you? Are you just pissed? You want to get even because of the horse race? I told ya it was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley, it's got nothing to do with the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're selling me out? You're gonna let them bury me? Jesus Christ, Wing... Jesus Christ! I'm not gonna be able to work in this business? Wing, this was my chosen field!</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Masters was gonna take this company apart. You're the low man on the totem pole, Tilley. There's a lot of guys earning a good living... no sense for it all to go up in smoke. You understand, don't you, Tilley? It's just business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out his wallet from his pocket, and peels off a few notes.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Tilley, you owe me sixteen plus from the race, and you're in for over two grand on the books, so I tell you what... I'll wipe the slate clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's a thou until you get yourself set up. I can do no better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd sell me out for a lousy three thousand dollars? Three thousand dollars and I got to go down the toilet? Jesus Christ, Wing, how long the two of us been busting our asses together ... Jesus Christ! We got some history to this relationship for Christ sake. Masters puts a little squeeze on you, you just sell out. Three thousand dollars?!</utterance>
   <speaker>WING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up to leave.</context>
      <utterance>The bottom line is, I'm running a business, Tilley.  Here's another deuce. I carried you a long time, Tilley. I've done a damn sight more than a lot of other guys would have done for you... and I don't see no gratitude from you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe that you're up so early. This is a rare occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands there watching Nora as she prepares the plates of food.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I just got some business downtown I gotta take care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues to stand watching her -- she's not aware that he's watching her. She waits for the toast to pop up out of the toaster.</context>
      <utterance>Toast will be ready in a second. Coffee's on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nora is still waiting for the toast, looking inside the toaster to see if it's getting brown.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Nora. I... um... I... er ... lied to you the other day.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>I went to see Tilley about the divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was not too agreeable, and one thing led to another, and we decided to shoot some pool to settle the matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We played pool. If I won he'd give you up, if I lost I'd give you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You played pool for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora, I had no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the most despicable thing I've ever heard in my life. I mean, it's disgusting... guys shooting pool to determine my future.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nora, I had no choice!  Hand me the toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB takes the toast out of the toaster.</context>
      <utterance>Get the toast yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a plate.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to be honest. It's been on my mind... on my conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This plate yours or mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB takes one of the plates and goes toward the table. Nora watches him a beat, amazed that he doesn't seem to recognize the seriousness of the situation.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take both... maybe you can choke to death on one of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB dips his toast into his eggs.</context>
      <utterance>How can you be so... how can you not understand how wrong that is? I can't understand that mentality! Shoot pool for me! It's insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tilley is not the most rational man in this world. I tried to talk to him... he wouldn't listen. So, what are my options? You know what I'm saying? What are my options?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you had to shoot pool! Don't you understand that ... don't you understand how crazy that is? You're sitting there... you're eating your eggs as if it's normal business in life here! Like feudal lords or something you used to read about in history books.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dips more toast into his eggs and eats.</context>
      <utterance>I lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I blew the eight ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="185" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means I'm supposed to give you up, and I'm never supposed to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you stop eating the eggs for a minute! How can you tell me things like this and casually eat your eggs?! What does this mean, Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, takes a quick sip of his coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm supposed to give you up as part of honoring that agreement, but I'm not that honorable a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you running off so fast here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a kiss. Starts to go, turns back, gives her another kiss, more passionate this time.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I got some business downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes down the hall to walk out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="186" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta testify, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. I already testified once. I beat 'em before, I'll beat 'em again.  You got a high-priced mouthpiece to speak for ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need one. I don't expect to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave them some pretty incriminating evidence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="187" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gave them evidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>The only way I could think to get out of this business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's activity in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's good... that's good, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Tilley stands.</context>
      <utterance>The hearing for the Home Improvement Commission is now in session.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... how's Nora?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN comes out of the hearing room.</context>
      <utterance>She's doin' all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ernest Tilley?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... here.  Take good care of her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="188" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB is watching the proceedings. CAMERA HOLDS ON him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not aware of the section numbers. Sometimes you get a little overzealous in the heat of the sales pitch, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it the heat of the sales pitch on February 23rd of this year that made you write across a contract 'This Job Is Free'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I remember, no sale was made concerning those customers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It fell out because a loan couldn't be arranged, but the people did agree in principle.  The point that we'd like to stress, is that you misled these people. Told them the job was free. Then you sent in your closer with some cover story about how you had suffered a nervous breakdown, and a sale was ultimately made for twenty-three hundred and seventy- seven dollars. That is misleading and deceptive sales practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was temporary insanity. I don't know... it just came over me ... it might have been something I ate. I don't know... it was crazy, I'm the first to admit it was a crazy thing to do. Believe me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="189" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have other specific examples of deceptive sales practices on your behalf concerning a job carried out on December 11, 1962. You violated sections 241 and 247. And concerning a job sold to Mr. and Mrs. DeFranco on October 9, 1962, violations of sections 251 and 257 took place.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are all these numbers here? I'm not familiar with all these section violations.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the feeling of this commission that these infractions are severe violations of the Home Improvement Laws, and therefore constitute misuse of the license to sell aluminum siding as approved by this state.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="190" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the decision of this commission to revoke your license to sell aluminum siding...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERA ON TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not very happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Which will prohibit you from practicing in the state of Maryland.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? Maybe the guys want to think this over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="191" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB walks over to the defense table and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Will Mr. William Babowski please come forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the right to have a lawyer present if you so wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="192" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Cadillac?</context>
      <utterance>Did you have a car parked here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. What about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man told me to say they took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who took it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilley walks over and stands in the empty space where his car had been.</context>
      <utterance>Man said, the tax man. Gave me a dollar to tell you so.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks around in the space as if somehow his car might reappear. He mumbles to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Tax man! Fucking I.R.S. How low can you get? How low can you get?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're lowlife. How can people come and take a man's car?... His Cadillac?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="193" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about your license.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. They got my license as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing standing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where my car used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stolen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB looks at Tilley for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I.R.S. Fucking bandits! Bandits! Thieving sons of bitches!</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a ride uptown?</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could use one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="194" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some bullshit commission, huh?  Tell me, where's it written it the Constitution that says you can't hustle for money? Where's it written? It ain't like I went into an alley and hit a guy over the head with a brick and stole his money... not like I broke into somebody's house and stole his stuff. All I'm doing is selling... where's the crime in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what the world's coming to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me. I don't know what the world's coming to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="195" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB stops the car at a stop sign. Something catches BB's eye. THROUGH the windshield we see a Volkswagen "beetle" going from right to left.</context>
      <utterance>Nickels and dimes. You got a good point there, BB. You're right on the money with that kind of thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta find a new business to get into.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BB puts his foot on the gas and starts to drive.</context>
      <utterance>New? Very hard to find something new to get into.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe... maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better put on my thinking cap... not easy to think of something new.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="196" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>It's just a matter of time.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, we'll find something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... matter of time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="197" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I hear the new Cadillac's gonna be out in a couple of months.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I hear it's a beaut.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... they're changing the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should put in my order now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about? You ain't got a pot to piss in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the pot... I'll fill it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
