<movie id="566" title="Tombstone">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dashing FIGURE in a Prince Albert coat appears, long locks tumbling down his shoulders, twin Navy Colts thrust into a red sash at his waist, a tin star on his chest. Next we see him in action, downing 3 barroom opponents at once, pistols FLASHING around the room like a strobe light:</context>
      <utterance>"The economic explosion following the Civil War created an unprecedented nation-wide market for beef. Previously worthless cattle running wild throughout Texas were gathered into herds And driven north to the railheads In Kansas. Fortunes were made as Cowtowns sprang up on the Prairies, wide-open centers of Commerce and vice, their streets Choked with heavily-armed young Men fresh from the cattle drives. In those days the correct term For a cowhand was 'drover'. 'Cowboy', like 'cowpoke', was originally an insult implying deviant sexuality and was rarely used. But these invading drovers were a wild breed for soon shootings and wholesale drunken riots became so frequent that ordinary citizens literally could not walk down the street. In fact at their height the cowtowns had higher murder rates than modern New York or Los Angeles and there Was no law but that of the gun."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Hickock sits facing us, playing poker as a shabby-looking FIGURE with a gun steals up behind him and FIRES.....</context>
      <utterance>"Straight-up at 75 yards or eye- to-eye at point-blank range, the greatest gunman of all time was an Illinois abolitionist farm boy named James Butler Hickok, better known as Wild Bill, the Prince of Pistoleers. But Wild Bill worked His trade on the side of justice And as marshal of cowtowns like Hays City and Abilene he became a Legend, the one man who stood Between law and chaos."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now a group of cowhands carouse a streetcorner, raising hell as 2 mustachiod young LAWMEN walk up, trying to quiet them down.</context>
      <utterance>"Wild Bill's fame spread nation- wide but his end came quietly in the spring of '76 when a strange cross-eyed little drifter put a bullet through the back of his head, apparently for no other reason than he wanted to kill a celebrity."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing it's hopeless, the lawmen whip out their pistols and start clubbing the drover's making them stagger and grimace, holding their heads....</context>
      <utterance>"In Dodge City meanwhile, Wyatt Earp and Bat Masterson were Becoming known as fast-guns. But Their fame had nothing to do with Shooting."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ARMED DROVER creeps up behind the lawmen, about to fire....</context>
      <utterance>"Earp and Masterson operated more like modern policemen, using teamwork and persuasion to keep order. Still, sometimes things got out of hand."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A REED-THIN FIGURE with a sawed-off shotgun steps from the shadows behind the drover and FIRES. The huge blast WHITES- OUT the screen for an instant, making the drover seem to disappear. The lawmen spin around. The thin man breaks the shotgun open then calmly holds out his wrists to be cuffed. Earp looks at him in shock, mouthing the word "thanks".</context>
      <utterance>"But Wyatt had a guardian angel."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene shifts to an elegant Victorian home: a stern Jewish patriarch orders his darkly beautiful DAUGHTER upstairs as her weeping mother looks on. The girl huffs up the stairs followed by her little white dog. Next, the girl and dog are seen escaping through a window to the street below and a waiting cab.</context>
      <utterance>"John Henry 'Doc' Holliday was the son of an aristocratic, highly cultured southern family. Trained in Philadelphia, he had Embarked on a career as a society Dentist when he contracted Tuberculosis. Advised to practice In the west where it was thought The climate and clean air would Prolong his life, Doc soon Realized it was all only a matter Of time and gave up dentistry to Become a professional gambler and Gunman..."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we see HORSEMEN silhouetted against the night sky, a hand knocking on a door, figures conferring in darkness, then more riders, moving west in restless haste toward the rising sun....</context>
      <utterance>"Others headed east. Bent on becoming an actress. Josephine Marcus defied her wealthy and Very proper San Francisco Jewish Family to run away with a Traveling theatrical company, Braving the perils of the Frontier on her own. Dangerous as This might seem, it was another Age and women were so rare, their Presence so cherished that they Could travel virtually anywhere In the west in perfect safety."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A jagged, moonlit landscape, a lone prospector and his burro moving along a ridge, a pick digging into a rocky ledge, an ore car emerging from a mine shaft, finally a hilltop cluster of tents becoming the skeletal wood-frame beginnings of a town....</context>
      <utterance>"At about this time the Texas Rangers, having eliminated the Commanche threat, turned their Attention to the outlaw gangs Marauding along the Rio Grande, Cleaning up the border strip in 4 Years of hard riding. Those they Could not indict or convict the Rangers put down in their Black Book, letting it be known that They could either leave Texas or Face summary execution. This Resulted in the mass migration of The absolute dregs of the Texas Underworld to the most dangerous, Uncivilized part of the entire Country, the southeast corner of The Arizona Territory."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An engraving of a stagecoach holdup, herds of cattle moving north, a newspaper story of a massacre in Mexico, congressmen railing at each other, shaking their fists....</context>
      <utterance>"Harsh and inhospitable, savaged in turn by the Apache and Mexican bandits, this had always been an accursed place, a virtual hell on earth where it was thought life itself could never prosper, much V.O. NARRATION  less civilization. Then in 1879, a prospector named Ed Schiefflin set off alone into the Dragoon Mountains. Friends told him he Was crazy, that the only thing He'd find in this Godforsaken Place would be his tombstone. Instead he found silver, lots of It, and overnight the town of Tombstone sprang up. Mining Taking out millions in ore. Land Value shot sky-high and Speculators and gamblers and Opportunists of all nations Scrambled in by the thousands to Make Tombstone queen of the Boomtowns, so rich that the Latest Paris fashions, hard to Find even in the biggest cities, Were sold there by the wagonload From the makeshift storefronts."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pounding hooves, flowing manes, a pack of night-riding HORSEMEN kicking hell-for-leather across the desert moonscape....</context>
      <utterance>"Meanwhile, the exile Texans had banded together to form the nucleaus of an organized gang. Seizing controp of the Surrounding countryside they Robbed stagecoaches at will while The big absentee business Interests employed them as tax Collectors and strongarm men. But The backbone of their trade Remained border rustling, Periodic raids into Mexico to Steal cattle while engaging in What was described as a virtual Orgy of murder and violence. The Raids became so frequent and so Bloody that the Mexican Government formally protested to U.S. President Chester A. Arthur, Prompting heated debate in Congress. General Sherman Declared that the only possible Way of bringing order was to send In the army but in the wake of Civil War Reconstruction federal Intervention in civilian affairs Was politically impossible."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>END MAIN TITLE as the screen fades to an ominous black and....</context>
      <utterance>"With only some 100 members, the gang was an elite body of gunmen, known by the red silk sashes they wore around their waists. Fiercely proud of their Terrifying reputation and Answerable to no one, they were a Law unto themselves, finally Emerging as one of the earliest Examples in American history of Full-scale organized crime."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"They called themselves the Cowboys."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's them, only an hour north.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG RURALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is the border.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain spurs his horse and they ride on at a gallop, plunging into the canyon....</context>
      <utterance>You saw what those animals did at That rancho. You think a border Is going to stop me? No, I'm Going to see them suffer for what They did! I swear it on my soul!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But suddenly GUNFIRE erupts from the shadows all around them, blasting them from the saddle, each powder flash lighting up the canyon for an instant, freezing each victim in the moment of his death. Then, just as abruptly the firing stops, leaving only the Captain, the young Rurale, and a 3rd Rurale alive. Dazed and bloody, they struggle to their feet as 6 armed FIGURES emerge from the shadows, walking into the moonlight toward them. With broad-brim hats swept up in front, silk scarves and red sashes, high boots and silver- studded gunleather, they look like 17th century pirates. These are the Cowboys: OLD MAN CLANTON, the ageless, white- bearded leader; CURLY BILL BROCIUS, 2nd-in-command, smiling, bull-necked; IKE and BILLY CLANTON, the old man's sons; FLORENTINO, a Mexican half-breed; and JOHNNY RINGO, dark, Byronic, with an air of something very strange. The Old Man nods to Florentino:</context>
      <utterance>Turn around! Fast! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN CLANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Florentino does so in Spanish. The others kneel but the Captain remains on his feet, steely-eyed, defiant.</context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em to get on their knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will not kneel. He is proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kinda hit the spot didn't it?</context>
      <utterance>So how'd you like our little Carry-on over at that rancho?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Animals! Butchers!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN CLANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curly Bill casually FIRES his shotgun into the Captain's legs, dropping him into a splayed lotus position. Curly Bill knods.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, somebody get that stick on His knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gracias.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN CLANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others rise and dash away but Curly Bill stops the Captain:</context>
      <utterance>They call me Old Man Clanton. I'm What you might call the founder Of the feast. Now maybe you ain't Heard, but we skylark through Your dingy little country just About any time we damn well Please and big-hat, crummy- Lookin' free-holes stumblin' Around in the dark ain't allowed. Messican po-lice, huh? Think You're bad medicine, don't you? Hell, I've let stronger stuff run Down my leg. So next time we come Better step aside. Get in our Hair again, we'll saw your prods Off with butter knives and stuff 'em in your gobs. Ain't kiddin' neither. You been told. Now git.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain speaks grimly in Spanish. Florentino smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hold up, jefe. Got a joke I wanna Tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He say he know you killing him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now how'd he figure that out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He say he is no' afraid, someone Will revenge for him. A sick Horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scattered chuckles from the others but we notice Ringo frown and draw his pistol as the Captain repeats the words.</context>
      <utterance>A sick horse? What the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is like, "a sick horse who sits---"</context>
      <utterance>Something, I don't know, he talk Fancy, you know, like a priest.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo takes aim. The Captain sneers, suddenly in English:</context>
      <utterance>That's not what he said, you Ignorant wretch. Your spanish is Worse than your English. Come on, Let's get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>RURALE CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you had a party!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man, Curly Bill, and Ringo rein up and look out at the sun rising magnificently from the desert floor. The Old man stretches his legs in the stirrups, taking out a whiskey flask.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, we had a big time!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN CLANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises the flask and drinks. Curly Bill turns to Ringo:</context>
      <utterance>Ain't that sweet? That's why I Stay out here. Thank you, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd the Messican mean, a sick Horse's gonna get us? Didn't make No sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was quoting the bible, Revelations: "Behold a pale horse And the one that sat on him was Death and Hell followed with him."</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now that's a little more Like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Dear Governor Gosper-in re yours directing action against Cowboys, stop. Beg to inform have Twice sent deputies to serve Warrants on Cowboy suspects, Stop. Nothing to show for it but 2 dead deputies, stop. Short of deputizing U.S. Army am at loss-</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tall man over there, Marshal. I'm not sure but I think that's Wyatt Earp.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back down the platform Wyatt strokes the stallion gently, looking up as Dake approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt Earp? Oh, right, Dodge City.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said forget it, answer's no, I Don't want the job and that's Final. I'm going to Tombstone and Nothin' short of dyin's gonn Stop me. Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wait, you don't understand-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Marshal, you don't understand. I'm through with lawing, I'm Through with the whole Proposition. Forever. I did my Duty, now I'd like to get on with My life. That is if you don't Mind. Jesus. Good day now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see, off to strike it rich, Huh. All right, fine, wish you Luck. Tell you this though, never Was a rich man yet didn't wind up With a guilty conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dake retreats. Wyatt turns back to his horse testily. Suddenly:</context>
      <utterance>Already got a guilty conscience, Might as well have the money too.</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S. VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt turns. His brothers stand behind him, smiling. Though VIRGIL is a little older and heavier. MORGAN a little younger and slimmer, they're otherwise identical to Wyatt, right down to their style of dress. Wyatt breaks into a grin, hugging them both, his cool replaced with an almost boyish enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, I'd know that sour face Anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well how do we look?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virgil's blonde wife ALLIE, small, fierce, and Irish, steps up with Morgan's fair, cameo-lovely young LOUISA in tow.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Virgil! My God! Morgan! Hey, Boy! You look great! Both of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, you remember Allie</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God, well he better.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allie-girl...And Louisa! You're So lovely. I'm at your feet, Darlin'. Just at your feet.  Guess it's only right. Ma always Said you were the prettiest.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt's handsome blonde wife MATTIE enters from the street:</context>
      <utterance>But she doted on the frowner</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, I couldn't find a single Store that had laudanum any-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mattie, they're here! Folks this Is Celia Ann but you can call her Mattie. Or even Mrs. Earp if you Prefer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns them toward the stationhouse window, arranging them in a group and pointing to their reflection.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, I sure been dreamin' about This. God! Since forever! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt smiles, shaking his head. Morgan's starts to speak, but:</context>
      <utterance>There, look at that! God Almighty</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand silently, studying themselves, together as a family. Wyatt still shaking his head happily, drinking it in. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Don't talk, just...yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, now let's go make our fortune.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>LOUISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Wyatt appears on his stallion, galloping across the moonlit plain toward them, sitting his horse like a centaur. It's clear he's a magnificent horseman. Virgil smiles:</context>
      <utterance>Don't you love their hair? They All have the same hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him go, will ya? I tell You, that's the real Wyatt, born In the saddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he can go all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can he then?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women cackle lasciviously. Virgil groans at Allie:</context>
      <utterance>Rather ride than eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt rides up and dismounts, unsaddling the horse.</context>
      <utterance>Try to be a lady, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What're you gonna do, race 'em?</context>
      <utterance>Give him some good exercise? Sure Some stud. Some string in fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louisa turns to Mattie, fishing in her bag:</context>
      <utterance>Hope so. Clean up with this boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mattie hon', did you say you Needed some laudanum? I have a Bottle right here. Just be Careful. It's full of hop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Wyatt leads the horse away the women get up, Allie and Louisa going to the river with dishes, Mattie crossing to the wagon. Virgil and Morgan watch her appreciatively:</context>
      <utterance>You're a lifesaver! Don't worry, I just get headaches sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the other end of camp Mattie climbs into the wagon and lies down. Wyatt appears and starts to stroke her head.</context>
      <utterance>Mighty fine. Wonder where he Found her. Same place we found Ours probably</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come up to the fire, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A coyote starts HOWLING from the far darkness. Mattie shudders:</context>
      <utterance>I think I'll just lie down awhile</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long as I live I'll never Get used to that sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're just lonely is all. Hell, I howl myself sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems genuinely surprised. Wyatt looks genuinely confused. Over at the fire, Morgan hugs and mashes Louisa playfully.</context>
      <utterance>You get lonely?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come up, Lou. Come up here, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fights loose. Wyatt walks up, sits, shaking his gold watch.</context>
      <utterance>Stop...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that. Busted. Brand new Money Ward, too. 33 years old And I don't even have a decent Watch. 'Bout time I started Lookin' out for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well here we are a family again. Been so long plain forgot how Good it feels. Want to thank you For that, Wyatt. All your doin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna do it, boys. Gonna Get ours. Feel it in my bones. All we have to do is keep our Eyes on that brass ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, look at all those stars. Bet You can see every star there is. Practical touch 'em. Kinda makes You think, you know? I mean you Look up and you think God made All that but he still remembered To make a little speck like me. Kinda flattering really. Hey, Wyatt, you believe in God? No, Come on, really, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, yeah. Hell, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what do you think happens When you die?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got me. Somethin'. Nothin'. I Don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read this book, book on Spiritualism...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, here he goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...said a lot of people, when they're dyin', they see this light, like in a tunnel. They say it's the light leading you to heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What about hell? They got A sign or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Wyatt, God damn it, I'm serious!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's your problem. Hey Virge, see anything of Doc while You were in Prescott?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit a streak when we left. Him And Kate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, that woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss Doc. I miss that ol' rip.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He makes me laugh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said that's 500 to you, Holliday. In or out?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KATE HORONY, Doc's voluptuous Hungarian consort enters, refilling his engraved silver stirrup cup. She has a faint accent:</context>
      <utterance>500? Sly boots, must be a peach of a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you, darling  Darling! Are you mad? You're not Wearing a bustle. How lewd!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, for Christ's sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc covers the bet and shows his hand. Bailey pounds the table.</context>
      <utterance>Ed Bailey, you look like you're Just ready to burst. Well call me A fool but I guess I'll just have To call. Cover your ears, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn son of a...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that a daisy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sick of listening to you simper.</context>
      <utterance>Just pick up your money and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc leans forward, revealing an ivory gun-butt under his coat.</context>
      <utterance>Now Ed, are we cross?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skinny lunger, your guns don't Impress me. Wasn't for those guns You'd be nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now a Cheshire cat smile we will soon come to know very well steals over Doc's face as he takes out his nickel-plated .38 Colt Lightning and .45 Peacemaker and lays them on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Why Ed, what an ugly thing to Say! Does this mean you're not my Friend anymore? You know, Ed, if I thought you weren't my friend I Don't think I could bear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc bats his eyelashes. Bailey jumps up, boiling. A long, sweaty moment, then Bailey LUNGES. Doc spring up, grabbing him by the hair and jabbing his fist into Bailey's armpit. Bailey screams and doubles over. Doc gives him two more blows, so light they hardly seem capable of the effect they're having. But as he turns to give him another we suddenly SEE that there's a KNIFE in Doc's hand. The bartender reaches for the shotgun under the bar. Kate pulls a Derringer from her muff and puts it to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>There, now we can be friends Again. But remember, Ed, Friendship is trust-so please Don't hurt me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He backs off. Kate covers the room. Bailey drops to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>Touch that gun, I burn you down!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes gleaming cruelly, Doc blows his cigarette smoke into Bailey's face. Bailey sinks to the floor in a fetal position. Kate gathers up the pot as Doc retrieves his guns, looking around the room. Then both back up to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Does it hurt? A lot? Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit. The others look down at the groaning Bailey lying in a pool of his own blood. A GAMBLER shakes his head:</context>
      <utterance>Well, good evening then.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST GAMBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judas...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I calculate that's the end of This town. And let's don't bother About the luggage, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate points to 2 horses saddled and packed outside the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>I been having the boy at the Hotel pack us up every night Since your streak started</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc gives Kate a peck on the cheek as they mount and ride off...</context>
      <utterance>My sweet clever Magyar, so that's Why you're not wearing a bustle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newcomers, eh? Names John Behan, I'm Cochise County Sheriff. Just Hit town?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just this minute. I'm Wyatt Earp, These're my brothers-</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt Earp...Dodge City, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gave all that up. Going into business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm the man to see. Besides Sheriff I'm also tax collector, Captain of the Fire Brigade, and Chairman of the Non-partisan Anti- Chinese league. A man of many Parts. Got a place to stay yet? I Also sit on the Townlot Commission. Got a couple of Lovely cottages coming up for Rent. Here, let me show you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt looks enquiringly at his brothers. They shrug. He's calling the shots. Wyatt shrugs back. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>The one next door and the one Across the street are vacant too. Same rent and I'll throw in a Good cleaning. Believe me, you Won't find a better deal within Town limits.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess we'll take all three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan and Virgil enter with FRED WHITE, the jovial old town marshal. Shaking hands, all 4 go up Allen, taking in the town.</context>
      <utterance>...and easy on the grain, I don't want 'em too fidgety.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, meet Fred White, he's town marshal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lotta law around here. Just met the Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who, Behan? He ain't no law, only Real law here's the Cowboys.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Cowboys, yeah. I heard of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White points to SHERMAN MCMASTERS and PONY DEAL, a half-breed, standing over by the hotel, joking in sign language.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody does nothin' without 'em. They're it. Hell, even the Apache're scared of 'em. There's A couple right there: Sherman McMasters and Pony Deal. Can Always spot a Cowboy, they all Wear those red sashes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look pretty rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gotta know how to handle 'em.</context>
      <utterance>Just like any other hard cases.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm no Wild Bill. Way I Handle 'em's just mainly live and Let live. That usually answers But even so, gets kinda spooky Sometimes. Still somebody's gotta Do it, I mean how the hell else You gonna walk down the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hell kinda town is this?</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't anybody raise a stink?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boomtown. Wide open. People Grabbin' with both hands ain't Got time for any law and order. In fact the less law the more Opportunities there are for Makin' money. Plain fact is the Cowboys're good for business.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about all these saloons?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods, suddenly very interested as they walk on and....</context>
      <utterance>Ah, now that's the real mother- Lode in Tombstone. Up and down Allen Street, full-blast 24 hours A day, liquor, hostesses, Gamblin', makin' money hand over Fist. All except the Oriental. On Account of the element. Have a Man for breakfast in there most Days. Regular slaughter house. High-rollers won't go near it. Too bad, nice place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me have one of those cigars.  Kinda nice in here. You run it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milt Joyce, owner-operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joyce points to the faro table in the corner where JOHNNY TYLER, an unshaven plug-ugly with a big D.A. Colt .45 carried ostentatiously in a shoulder holster, deals to a couple of scruffy-looking drifters.</context>
      <utterance>Well, excuse me for askin', Milt, But isn't it kinda dead in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see that bird at the faro Table? That's Johnny Tyler. He Barged in here one day, said he Was takin' over the game, started Slappin' customer, wavin' his Gun around, scarin' off all the High-class play. Only trade comes In here now's just bummers and Drovers, just the dregs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you get rid of him and Get yourself straight dealer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well sure, neighbor, easy to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You back that Queen again, you Son of a bitch, I'll blow you Right out of that chair!  Somethin' on your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to let you know You're sitting in my chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That a fact?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler looks Wyatt over, noting he is unarmed. He stands, sneering:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a man that don't go heeled You run your mouth kinda reckless.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need to go heeled to get The bulge on a dub like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That a fact?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm real scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt steps forward suddenly, eyes cold and hard like a shark. Suddenly realizing he's in way over his head. Tyler shrinks back reflexively, his hand moving toward his gun. The other players scatter. Wyatt nods, his voice calm and steady:</context>
      <utterance>Damn right you're scared. I can See it in your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Skin it. Skin that Smoke wagon and see what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt abruptly SLAPS his face, making his teeth clack together.</context>
      <utterance>Listen Mister, I'm getting' tired-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler goes pale, all pretense of courage gone. Wyatt slaps him again.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting tired of your gas. Jerk that pistol and go to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another slap. Tyler stays frozen, blood dripping down his chin.</context>
      <utterance>I said throw down, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler's done. Wyatt plucks his gun away, handing it to Joyce.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna do something or just Stand there and bleed?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt takes Tyler by the ear, dragging him across the room like an unruly child. At the door he gives the ear a twist.</context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't think so. Here, Milt. Keepsake, hang it over the Bar. All right, youngster. Out You go...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler winces. Wyatt shoves him out into the street then turns to Joyce casually:</context>
      <utterance>And don't come back. Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See how easy that was?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="46">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we're off and running. Just Acquired us a quarter-interest in The game at the Oriental.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acquired?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down the block, unseen by the Earps, a wild-eyed Tyler is advancing on them with a sawed-off shotgun. He is within 20 feet when suddenly:</context>
      <utterance>So to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S. VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler spins around to see Doc standing in a doorway, smiling. Tyler freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Why Johnny Tyler, you madcap, Where are you going with that Shotgun?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt spots Doc and walks up, brothers in tow. Though they don't so much as shake hands, we sense a strong bond between the 2 men.</context>
      <utterance>Doc. I didn't know you were in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc! How the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect, Wyatt. Simply perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt? Wyatt Earp?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going into business for Ourselves. Wyatt just got us a Faro game.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when is faro a business?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you always say gambling's An honest trade?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said poker's an honest trade. Only suckers buck the tiger. The Odds are all with the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends how you look at it. I Mean it's not like anybody's Holding a gun to their heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Frozen there. Tyler begins to tremble. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>That's what I love about Wyatt. He can talk himself into anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sorry, Johnny, I forgot all About you. You can go now. Just Leave the shotgun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyler scuttles off as Behan approaches affably. Doc sniffs.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff Behan, Doc Holliday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me if I don't shake hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's Tombstone treating you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, fine. But I was thinkin', You know what this town really Needs is a race track.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, you know, that's not a Bad idea, send a signal we're Growing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little ahead of yourselves, Aren't you? This is just a mining Camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See how everyone dresses? Awfully Toney for a mining camp. No, the Die's cast, we're growing, be as Big as San Francisco in a few Years. And just as sophisticated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if on cue, a bullet WHIZZES past Behan's head. Everyone ducks. More GUNFIRE as a man holding a bloody hand to his throat reels out the door of the nearby Crystal Palace, his gun firing wildly like a sputtering engine before he pitches face first onto the sidewalk, dead. Immediately 2 more men appear: a staggering DRUNK with a bullet hole in his shoulder; and TURKEY CREEK JACK JOHNSON, a leathery plainsman with his gun at the ready. A crowd forms as the drunk raises his pistol, bellowing.</context>
      <utterance>I can hardly wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, keep comin', keep comin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very cosmopolitan.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a 3rd man, TEXAS JACK VERMILLION, long-haired, hawk- nosed, appears, pistol at the ready, keeping bystanders at bay.</context>
      <utterance>I know him. That's Creek Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, gents. Private affair...  Wyatt! Doc! Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drunk now has raised his gun to where it's almost level and:</context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnson FIRES. The drunk drops in a heap. Johnson spots Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, good. Right about there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Wyatt! Hiya Doc!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drunks. Crawfished a bet, called Him a liar. I saw the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc points to his bloody ear. Johnson touches it, sees the blood, gives a silent start. Just then White arrives, looking weary, facing Johnson and Vermillion.</context>
      <utterance>Sheriff, may I present a pair of Fellow sophisticates, Turkey Creek Jack Johnson and Texas Jack Vermillion? Watch your ear, Creek.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fraid I'll have to have those guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair fight. We were legal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, boys. Gotta take you Before Judge Spicer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hand over their guns while Virgil looks at the 2 dead men lying in the street, shaking his head:</context>
      <utterance>Well law and order every time, That's us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda town is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look. A stagecoach stops in the street. JOSEPHINE MARCUS looks out the window, her little white dog under her chin. She and Wyatt spot each other instantly, both impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Nice scenery.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That must be the theatrical Troupe. There's a show tonight at Schieffelin Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Wyatt, you goin' to the Show? Maybe we'll see you there.  Won't we.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White leads them off to jail. Wyatt and Josephine hold each other's gaze as the coach drives on. Doc smiles:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, an enchanted moment</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting little scene. I Wonder who that tall man was.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typical frontier type. Long and Lean. And those gray eyes. Like a Wild hawk. You see quite a few of His type out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I want one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sister Boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curly Bill beckons. Happy as a lark, Breakenridge takes the seat next to him. Up above, the Earps sit in a box, the women thrilled:</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Zwing. Sit here, Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so much fun! We haven't Been to a show since years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope they're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc enters, Kate on his arm. The women exchange uneasy nods.</context>
      <utterance>Lady, they better be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit as White enters with Mayor JOHN CLUM and wife.</context>
      <utterance>Kate, you know the Earps.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, this is Mayor Clum and his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your reputation precedes you. I wonder -</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While the orchestra tunes up and the crowd's excitement rises, White sits next to Wyatt, pointing out the different Cowboys and giving a thumbnail sketch of each as we PAN over them:</context>
      <utterance>Not a prayer. Nice meetin' you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>spotlight hits easel at the end of the stage: "Professor Gillman and His Ballet of Gravity." Out in the audience, Barnes groans:</context>
      <utterance>Well everybody's here except the Old Man. Got the blade, Billy Grounds, Zwing Hunt, Billy Claiborne, Wes Fuller, Tom and Frank McLaury, Billy Clanton's The youngest. Wild one. Then the Breeds, Hank Swilling, Pony Deal. Florentino's Mex-breed. They all Hate Mex, but he hates 'em Special. Johnny Barnes, Frank Stillwell. That's Behan's little Deputy, Billy Breakenridge. Follows the Cowboys around like a Puppy. And the big boys: Curly Bill Brocius, he's the Old Man's Rimrod; the one looks like an Actor, that's Johnny Ringo. Best Gun alive they say. He's kinda Different. Curly Bill's the only One he talks to. I mean they're All rough boys, but Ringo... I Don't know. I really don't Music. The house lights dim. The audience hushes. A</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seen him in Bisbee. He catches stuff. The curtain goes up. PROFESSOR GILLMAN, a 3rd rate juggler in white tie, tailcoat, and black tights steps out and starts tossing Indian clubs in the air. The audience starts groaning but the Professor's rictus-like smile never changes. Having seen enough, Frank Stillwell stands up and shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Professor Gilllman? Oh hell, I</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stillwell raises his pistol and FIRES. An Indian club explodes in the Professor's hand. Screams and scattered laughter in the audience. The Professor is frozen in utter shock, staring at the bullet graze on his hand and saying out loud:</context>
      <utterance>Hey profesor! Catch this!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chord of music and the curtain drops like stone. Applause....</context>
      <utterance>They shot me! I don't believe it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1ST ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What'll we do?</context>
      <utterance>My God, they're shooting at us! They're actually shooting at us!</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only thing we can do, dear-be Good. In any event, at least we Won't have to wait for our Notices. Exciting, isn't it? Now This is theater!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabian throws open his cloak, revealing his lithe form in doublet and tights. The whores in the gallery hoot and cheer. Fabian bows.</context>
      <utterance>Prettiest man I ever saw</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come he ain't wearin' no pants?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how come.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another GUNSHOT and a bullet SPANGS into the column next to Fabian with a shower of plaster. Without missing a beat, Fabian casually flicks a chunk off his shoulder and continues:</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, the St Crispin's Day Speech from Henry V. To set the Scene, England is Now at war with France. Everything rests upon the battle About to begin. Henry, the young King of England, addresses his men Thusly: "My cousin Westmorland? No, my fair cousin-"</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the audience Barnes holsters his smoke pistol reflectively.</context>
      <utterance>"If we are marked to die, we are enow/ To do our country loss; and if to live./ The fewer me, the greater the share of honour..."</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Starry-eyed, Breakenridge answers without thinking:</context>
      <utterance>He's got nerve, I'll say that. What do you think, Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he wonderful!</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUNDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raw laughter from the others. Breakenridge sinks in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh, looks like somebody's in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On stage Fabian is in full cry, giving the local a slice of the ripest ham:</context>
      <utterance>Let him alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wild applause and cheering. Fabian bows with elaborate modesty.</context>
      <utterance>"We few, we happy few, we band of brothers;/ For he today that sheds his blood with me/ Shall be my brother; be he ne'er so vile./ This day shall gentle his Condition;/ And gentlemen in England now a-bed/ Shall think Themselves accurs'd they were no Here./ And hold their manhood Cheap whiles any speaks/ That Fought with us upon Saint Crispin's day!"</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The curtain falls. Another card: "Faust - or the Devil's Bargain" and the orchestra whirls into "Danse Macabre" by Saint-Saens, the rising curtain revealing a wild pained backdrop, all black and red, covered with weird, Beardsley- esque designs and images of death and damnation. A light comes up, revealing an ancient white-bearded scholar sitting alone with his books. Then a hooded Satan dances across the stage, slender and lissome in paned black doublet and breeches and black hose, tempting the old man with images of wealth and youth in the form of a shimmering blonde ballerina. The old man succumbs, signing Satan's contract. The audience watches in rapt attention, especially the Cowboys:</context>
      <utterance>That's great! That's our kinda stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>STILLWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna some up short on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what I'd do? I'd take the Deal then crawfish and drill that Ol' Devil in the ass. How 'bout You, Johnny? What would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satan makes a flourish. A flash-pad EXPLOSION transforms the old scholar into a young student. The ballerina flits by. The student offers her gold. They dance, swirling about the stage in a mad waltz with Satan hovering behind them, mirroring their every move like a puppet master. Finally, having gotten all his gold, the Ballerina drifts away leaving the young student alone, lost in bitterness as he changes back into the old scholar sitting with his books. Satan appears over him, exultant and triumphant, ready to collect the debt as the curtain falls with a final crashing chord. Thunderous cheering and applause. The curtain rises again and the performers come out for bows, all except Satan.</context>
      <utterance>I already did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very instructive</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Satan bounds out, removing the hood. It's Josephine.</context>
      <utterance>But who was the Devil?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that woman from the coach!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josephine spots Wyatt's box and smiles. Doc raises an eyebrow:</context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may indeed. If you get lucky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comin' to the Oriental, Virge?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs, shoving Virgil down the street. He looks at Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>Not tonight! Tonight me and my Old man're gonna have some fun. Get moving, old man!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her maiden name was Sullivan.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better go with 'em, honey. Here's Where I leave you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, stay. Please stay with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, I gotta start makin' money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right now. I guess I could stay a little while.</context>
      <utterance>Well I guess I don't have to go</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I don't want to keep you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No really, I can stay a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go. It's all right. Wyatt, Really. Work well.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another kiss and he heads for the Oriental with Morgan. Mattie walks on after the others, fishing through her bag for her bottle of laudanum....</context>
      <utterance>All right, well, good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's go!</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'm on fire! Black Seven, seven stickin' spades.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You are on fire.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your man...  You win again. Well played, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told you. I'm red hot, I'm Blazin'! Now, red seven. Seven Stinkin' diamonds. Look out! Five Thousand! Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awful lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't take the heat, get outta The kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the doctor.  sad news, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The high roller lays a set of deeds out on the table as....</context>
      <utterance>Damn! All right, wait a minute...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="58">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now we're in the mining Business. Turning into regular Tycoons. Gonna call this one the Mattie Blaylock. Mattie'll get a Kick out of that, it's her maiden Name.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what a maiden, pure as the Driven snow, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Doc! Come on now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just his style, Morg. Doesn't Mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tell me, Wyatt. I'm curious. Do you actually consider youself A married man? Forsaking all Others?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well yeah. Pretty much. I mean I Was no angel when we met but People change Doc. I mean sooner Or later you gotta grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. And what would you do if "she" walked in her right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"She"?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That dusky-hued lady Satan.</context>
      <utterance>You know damn well who I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Probably ignore her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignore her?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd ignore her. People can Change, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc point. Josephine has just walked in with the other actors.</context>
      <utterance>I'll remember you said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spots Wyatt and starts toward him but he looks away, as if ignoring her. She stops. Behan steps up to her, tipping his hat, very gallant. They move toward the bar. Wyatt turns to Doc.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josephine and Behan chat at the bar. White nudges Joyce:</context>
      <utterance>I stand corrected. Wyatt. You're An oak.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when'd you start servin' Ladies in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Fabian enters, dramatically gotten-up like Lord Byron. The whole bar bursts into applause. He bows. Breakenridge jumps up from his table, excited:</context>
      <utterance>Actresses. It's different.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seats Fabian near the faro game, gets him some champagne.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Mr Fabian, have this table.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you. You're very kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Fabian, I've got to tell you, That's the most wonderful thing I Ever saw. What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry's all right but he's no Match for the Melancholy Dane.  Hamlet, dear friend, the supreme Role of any actor worth his salt.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's a man you should meet, Mr. Fabian. Excellent character study For you, the real-life actual Melancholy Dane.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed, sir? How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he hems, he haws, he talks Out of both sides of his Mouth-but all on a very high Plane, just like Hamlet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc chuckles. Suddenly Curly Bill looms over the faro table with Ringo and a drunken Ike Clanton.</context>
      <utterance>Getting drunk, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt Earp, huh? I heard of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Mr. Kansas Law-dog. Law Don't go around her. Savvy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm retired.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. That's real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's good, Mr. Law-dog, 'cause law don't go around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you the first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Ike.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you must be Doc Holliday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the rumor.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You retired, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. I'm in my prime.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you look it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you must be Ringo. Look, Darling, Johnny Ringo. The Deadliest pistoleer since Wild Bill, they say. What do you Think, darling? Should I hate him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but there's just something About him. Something around The eyes, I don't know, reminds me Of... me. No. I'm sure of it, I Hate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In vino veritas.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Age quod agis.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Credat Judaeus Apella.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ecentus stultorum magister.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In pace requiescat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on now. We don't want any Trouble in here. Not in any language.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo looks at Doc, holding his gaze while suddenly whipping out his .45. Everyone but Doc flinches. Ringo does a dazzling series of twirls and tricks, his nickel-plated pistol flashing like a blaze of silver fire, finally slapping it back into his holster with a flourish. Cheers and hoots. Doc rolls his eyes, hooks a finger through the handle of his silver cup, then launches into an exact duplication of Ringo's routine using a cup instead of a gun. The room bursts into laughter. Doc shrugs. Ringo lets a strange little hint of a smile cross his face then exits with the others. White exhales, turns to Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>Evidently Mr. Ringo's an educated Man. Now I really hate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what I mean about it getting Spooky?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curly Bill, huh? Who was that Other idiot?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike Clanton, Old Man's eldest Son. Know he ain't got the stuff, Makes him miserable.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sitting up on the bar to see the show, Josephine turns to Behan:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man dealing faro. Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Wyatt Earp. Made quite a Name for himself as a peace Officer in Kansas.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A peace officer... Impressive man</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, very. And very married.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so that's it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my lovin' man. Just can't Get enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the High-Roller comes reeling up, loud and gratingly drunk.</context>
      <utterance>Enough? Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sounds like "Old Dog Tray".</context>
      <utterance>Hey, is that "Old Dog Tray"?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Stephen Foster. "Oh, Susanna". "Camptown Races", Stephen-stinkin'-Foster!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see, well this happens to be a Nocturne.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH ROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A which?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc plays on. Josephine leaves with Behan. Morgan sighs:</context>
      <utterance>You know, Frederic-fucking-Chopin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt grunts and nods, perturbed. Outside the others mount up but Curly Bill stands drugged-up in the middle of the street, arms out, head back, eyes closed, luxuriating in the moonlight.</context>
      <utterance>Now that wounds me. Little tin Swain walkin' off with that black Beauty. I mean I'm a married man And all but still, it ain't right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others shrug and ride off. Curly Bill pulls his pistol, spinning it. Back inside the Oriental it's late, few patrons remain. A few beats then suddenly everyone jumps as GUNSHOTS echo from outside. White goes to the window, looks outside:</context>
      <utterance>Boy, I feel great! Full of that Hop I got from Chinky. I feel Just capitol! You boys go ahead. I'm gonna stick around awhile, Howl at the moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curly Bill. He's over across the Street shootin' out the lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Behan dashes in, white as a sheet, Josephine in tow:</context>
      <utterance>This is great, this is just great.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somebody's got to do something.</context>
      <utterance>Have you been out in the street?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside Curly Bill starts taking potshots at a passerby's feet, making him dance down the street and scurry for cover. Curly Bill cackles. Inside White turns uneasily to Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>It's not County business, it's a Town matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just leave it alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I gotta do something. I don't Suppose you'd card-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt keeps dealing, Doc keeps playing. White draws himself up and exits. Outside, Curly Bill reloads and keeps shooting. White steps out into the street. We feel a sense of inverted terror as he draws his gun and we SEE that his hand is trembling. He crosses the street, coming up behind Curly Bill:</context>
      <utterance>None of my business, Fred.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curly Bill spins around. White's gun stares him in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Curly? Come on now, boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back in the bar, Wyatt puts his cards down, looks over at Doc.</context>
      <utterance>Well, howdy, Fred!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I ought to go out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc lays his head down on the keys, passes out. Wyatt frowns for a moment. Finally he stands, turning to Morgan:</context>
      <utterance>You will or you won't. Don't look To me. I'm going to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hey Milt, lend me a sidearm, will you? Joyce hands him a Colt from under the bar. Outside White covers Curly Bill, trembling harder now. An adrenaline rush in a man White's age is hard to look at, he seems so frail, so vulnerable. Even his voice has a quavering edge to it:</context>
      <utterance>Go wake up Virgil.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hand that over. Come on now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a reassuring smile, Curly Bill holds his pistol out butt- first. White reaches for it, visibly relieved. But quick as a snake's tongue Curly Bill spins it around and FIRES POINT BLANK into White's chest, blowing him over backward, the blast so close it sets his clothes on fire. Curly Bill turns just as Wyatt flashes into frame and SLAMS him over the head with his pistol barrel, laying him out in a groaning heap. Wyatt glances at White lying semi-conscious in the street, chest heaving, eyelids fluttering, making weak little bird-like sounds, smoke rising from his smoldering shirt and vest. Clum runs up:</context>
      <utterance>Why sure, dad. I'm only in fun. Here she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clum pats the embers out in White's clothes but as Wyatt starts to haul Curly Bill up he suddenly finds himself surrounded by Ike, Billy Clanton, and six other Cowboys.</context>
      <utterance>Put his clothes out.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn loose of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just killed a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said to turn loose of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm not so go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cowboys tense up, ready for action. Wyatt holds his ground, his hard, steady gaze zeroing in on Ike:</context>
      <utterance>Swear to God, Mister, step aside Or we'll tear you apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike steps up, full of brass. Without warning Wyatt jabs the muzzle of his pistol into his forehead, snapping his head back. Wyatt cocks the pistol. The other Cowboys hush. Ike freezes. Wyatt's eyes bore into him.</context>
      <utterance>You. Come here a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike stands stock still. Billy steps forward, undaunted:</context>
      <utterance>You die first, get it? The others Might get me in a rush but before That I'm gonna make your head Into a canoe. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is it. The Cowboys poise themselves, ready to start, but:</context>
      <utterance>He's bluffin'! Let's rush him!</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S. VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again a hush. Doc stands behind Wyatt, still drunk, but with his .38 trained on Billy. Billy sneers:</context>
      <utterance>And you, you simpleton, you're next.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc pulls out his .45, training it, too, on Billy:</context>
      <utterance>Hell, he can't hit nothin'. He's So drunk he's probably seein' Double.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy pauses, chastened. Suddenly there's another commotion as Virgil and Morgan bull their way through the crowd from behind with shotguns.</context>
      <utterance>I have two guns. One for each of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This breads the group's will and things suddenly calm down dramatically as the Cowboys disperse. Wyatt lowers his pistol, heaving a sigh of relief as he pulls the still-groggy Curly Bill to his feet and hauls him reeling toward the jail.</context>
      <utterance>All right, look out! Break it up. Go home, all of you, go home now...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crack me back of the head like Some stinkin' bull. Hell, you Ain't no fightin' man, you're Just a cop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The street is quiet as they start back toward the Oriental. Virgil and Morgan following at a discreet distance, smirking:</context>
      <utterance>There. He'll keep till morning</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't let anything side-track you.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your eye on that brass ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile across the street at the hotel Josephine turns to Behan.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I need a keeper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I guess you can see, never a Dull moment. Maybe you should Stay around to see what happens Next. Who know? You might find a Future here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe even my destiny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clum enters, frowning and anxious, just as Morgan sinks a shot.</context>
      <utterance>...but he says did I actually see it happen and I said, no, when I arrived Fred'd already been shot. So the judge said, can't have a Murder without a witness-case Dismissed. Can you beat it? After All that. Oh hell, who cares, None of my business anyways.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I love this game. When we're Finally set we gotta each have a Billiard room in our houses.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Wyatt, just a moment, Please, I wanted to try and Reason with you. We still haven't Found a Marshal and-</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Mayor, he already told You no.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you? You were a lawman.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy. We're all busy. Sorry, Mayor, but you're really barkin' Up the wrong tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clum exits shaking his head. They keep playing. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>You tell 'em, Virge.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I was thinkin', maybe We ought to open our own place. That's the real money. Build it Up, milk it for all it's worth, Then sell it off for a bundle and Breeze out of this burg with more Money than Croesus and ready to Live like kings. Let's you and me Take a walk around town, Virge, See if we can scout us out a Couple of nice lots.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hardly believe it. It's Working out just like you said, Wyatt. We're lootin' this burg Six ways through Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty fun too, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda, actually, yeah. I gotta admit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy stands stock still, staring at the men in silence.</context>
      <utterance>What're you up to today, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks back to the street without another word.</context>
      <utterance>Cat got your tongue?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virgil keeps going. Wyatt starts after him, leaving mother and child in confusion as....</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, Virgil! Where you goin'?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help it, Wyatt. I Looked at that woman and it was Just like somebody slapping me in The face. I mean these people're Afraid to even walk down the Street and I'm trying to make Money off it like some kind of God damn vulture. That's not me, That's somebody I don't even know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgil, please. Don't do this to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got nothin' to do with you, Wyatt. It's-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan looks down in sheepish silence. Then he pulls back his coat, revealing the Deputy's badge on this vest. Wyatt groans.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing to do with me? I'm your Brother for Christ's sake. God, I Don't believe this.  Talk to him, will you? Or hit him.  Oh no, don't tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you said, Wyatt. We're Brothers. Gotta back your Brother's play. Just did like I Figured you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, both of you. This Is no good. This is trouble we Don't need. For the first time in Our lives we got a chance to stop Wandering and finally be a Family. Do this and you throw it All away. You saw what happened To Fred White.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, we're not about pickin' Fights. Just gonna keep a little Order, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you said, just gotta know How to handle 'em. Old Fred Wasn't up to it. We know that We're doin', Wyatt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, say you're right, say You don't get yourself killed. There's something else.  It's too late for Virge, he Already rolled his bone. But it's Not too late for you, Morg.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt exhales wearily then crouches down in front of his baby brother, looking deep in his eyes, his voice soft, plaintive:</context>
      <utterance>What're you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the years I worked the Cowtowns, I was only ever mixed Up in one shooting. Just one. A Man got killed. Wasn't my fault, Just doin' my job. I don't even Know if it was my bullet that Dropped him, but... I don't kno, It's sort of hard to explain. At First I just felt funny, you Know, kind of clammy inside. But When it finally sunk in what I'd Done... Believe me, boy, you Don't ever want to feel that way. Not ever.  Didn't even make a dent, did I?  You're both makin' a big mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Hooker's ranch?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And I'm Hooker.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker suddenly falls silent, looking at the ground nervously.</context>
      <utterance>You seen anything of a man on Horseback leading a black Stallion?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you must've seen somethin', The trail runs right by your Waterhole.  Oh, I see. So it must've been a Cowboy, right? Really got you People treed, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods his thanks. Hooker looks down, ashamed. Wyatt stares at him a moment. There's something genuinely troubling about so strong a man living in fear. Wyatt rides on, shaking his head....</context>
      <utterance>Look, Mister, it's fine for you Boomers to court trouble, you're Just passin' through. Us Cattlemen gotta live here. Best I Can do's point you up to the cut. That's their roost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run for your lives, boys! It's That great two-gun dog-catcher From Kansas!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McMasters, isn't it? Listen, you Seen a black stallion with-</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I got a rule. I don't talk To lawmen. Dog-catchers neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a lawman, I'm just a Private citizen getting' my Property back</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well in that case, I saw your Horse. Billy Clanton was takin' Him up to the Cut to show him Off. The boys're all up there Right now, branding. And in a Mood. Still want your property Back, Mr. Private Citizen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what about you Cowboys anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had to explain it you Wouldn't understand. Just say We're brothers to the bone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but some of the things they Say your brothers've done...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's all kinds of horses, Ain't there? Same with Cowboys. What they do's their affair. I Don't preach and I don't judge. I Ain't no dog-catcher.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt rides on, making for Billy. Ike steps up with INDIAN HAWK SWILLING, the giant half-breed. They walk alongside Wyatt.</context>
      <utterance>You seem like a nice fella. Like To've know you better. Had you lived.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, law-dog. The hell you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWILLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt ignores them, riding up to within 20 feet of Billy and dismounting. Billy looks up, supremely confident and unconcerned.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout I just drag you off That horse and eat you blood raw?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get that horse?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beauty, ain't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked where you got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs. More cowboys gather, jeering. Wyatt steps closer.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think? I stole him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't want any trouble With you but that's my horse and I mean to have him back. One way Or another.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come and get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look kid, I know what it's like, I was a kid, too. Even stole a Horse once. But you can't--</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't sweet-talk him, make a move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWILLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy steps back, poised. Ike and Swilling do the same. 3 more Cowboys move up behind him. The scene seems on the brink of explosion when Curly Bill suddenly STREAKS into frame on his buckskin mare, majestic and 10 times life size as he pulls back and SKIDS to a stop in front of Wyatt, raising a giant roostertail of dust, making everyone but Wyatt recoil.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, go ahead, Mister. Make a move.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him his horse, Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Curly! Don't let him-</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Give him his horse, Billy. Billy reluctantly hands over the leadline. Wyatt mounts and rides off with Dick Nailor in tow, Curly Bill riding alongside.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel bad about ol' Fred. Just Can't hold back when I'm feelin' Woolly. Still, feel kinda bad. But now we're square. Anyway no Use for holdin' a grudge. I Deserved a rap in the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make you a deal. My brother took Over the Marshal's office in Tombstone. Got it in his head He's gonna make the place safe For widows and orphans. You and Your boys stay out of his way, I'll make sure he stays out of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough. You know I got to Admit, you got a lot of bark on You comin' up here like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were all gonna jump me back There. What ever happened to one Against one?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't our way. We go all on one, One on all. Fight one of us, you Fight us all. That's the Cowboy way.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how come you call yourselves Cowboys? Cowhands ride for the brand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we ride for a brand all right.  This brand. How 'bout you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This brand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna get along just fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't thank you enough. Since You took over there hasn't been a Single problem. We're finally Becoming a civilized town.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I jumped the gun. Maybe Those Cowboys aren't near as bad As they're painted. You know I Was thinkin', there's a lot of Money in the cattle business...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, you thinkin' of Getting in bed with the Cowboys?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business is business. Don't have To love 'em to work with 'em. Not If there's money in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the one, Wyatt. You sure are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG RURALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old one you kill. This was my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN CLANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hissing gleefully, he jams a derringer under the Young Rurale's chin and FIRES, blowing off his sombrero as he falls. The other Rurales fire, emptying their guns into the Old Man as if he were some monstrous rattlesnake that might bite them....</context>
      <utterance>What, and I'm supposed to Tremble? Kiss my ass, Messican.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STILLWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In tight on Curly Bill as the news sinks in. He clenches his fist in rage, then bites a knuckle, getting his control back.</context>
      <utterance>Old Man Clanton's dead! Ambushed In Guadaloupe Canyon. Messican's Got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, first thing's first: It's my outfit now, I'm runnin' The show. Ringo's number two man.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your outfit? I'm next in line.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seething with humiliation, Ike mounts up and rides off.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't got enough in your Britches. Think you can prove Otherwise, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody else? No takers. Curly Bill turns back to business:</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They mount in a bunch and take off south like the wind....</context>
      <utterance>All right. Billy, go after Ike And cool him off then go find the McLaurys, tell 'em what happened And keep an eye on things. Wes Fuller and Bill Claiborne, too. Rest of you come with me. We're Goin' to Mexico.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking for an escape, Wyatt turns up a narrow trail on the side of the cut. He follows it as it winds around the hill then abruptly drops back down and comes out on the other side of the cut right in front of Josephine. She waves. He groans:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've never actually met. My Name's-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt Earp, I know. I was Beginning to think we'd never Meet. This is fortuitous. That Means lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Wyatt's stallion groans nervously, throwing its head, aroused by the presence of the mare.</context>
      <utterance>I know what it means.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy now... That mare's in season.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...  Now she's starting. How do they know?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know. It's the scent. We Better split 'em up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Wyatt can stop her she's off at a full gallop. Wyatt pauses, debating with himself. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>I have a better idea, let's run It out of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off at a dead run. Catching up, the horses find their rhythm, breaking into a smooth gallop, flying over a jet black plain of volcanic ash into a rolling meadow carpeted with yellow desert poppies, so bright it almost hurts your eyes to look at them. Coming off a rise the desert floor shears off into a wide crevice. Josephine heads right at it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm an oak all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not that crazy, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSPEHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A crack of her crop and she streaks toward it. Wyatt grits his teeth and follows suit. The sound of their hoofbeats stops for a long instant as they take the jump together, sailing through the air side-by-side, Josephine giggling like a little girl. They light on the other side and gallop on....</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes I am!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was lovely!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you almost got us both Killed back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fun though, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd die for fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't you? You're laughing! I Was sure you never laughed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I laugh sometimes</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but how often? Tell me, are You happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I happy? I don't know. Happy As the next man, I guess. I don't Laugh all day long like an idiot, If that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a little touchy about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not touchy, I just, it's a Silly question, that's all. Am I Happy? Are you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, I'm always happy. Unless I'm bored. That blonde Woman, is that your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing... Tell me, what do you Want out of life?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you get these questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, make some money, Have some kids, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't suit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just doesn't, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I ought to know my own mind And I'm tellin' you what suits me Is a family and kids. That suits Me right down to the ground. In Fact, that's my idea of heaven.  All right, what's your idea of heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt laughs, almost in spite of himself. Josephine beams.</context>
      <utterance>Room service.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? You're laughing again. But That's what I want. Go places and Move and never look back and just Have fun. Forever. That's my idea Of heaven. Need someone to share It with, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Behan?  Then why are you with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's handsome and he's Charming. He's all right. For Now. Don't say it, I know, I'm Rotten. I can't help it. I've Tried to be good but it's too Boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way you talk. Never heard a Woman talk like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh look, I haven't got time to be Proper, I want to live. I'm a woman, I like men. If that's Unladylike then I guess I'm not a Lady. At least I'm honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, enchanted, but suddenly his face clouds.</context>
      <utterance>Well you're different, no arguing That. But you're a lady all right. I'll take my oath on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, doesn't make any Sense. I almost can't look at You. Like it hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her in his arms and kisses her. She sinks in his arms. He kisses her again then falls to her knees, throwing his arms around her legs and pressing his face into the folds of her skirts.</context>
      <utterance>I know, me too. What should we do About it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs a hand through his hair. He stands, lifting her with him until they are face-to-face and she can feel him pressing into her. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>God...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this is adultery. You Burn in hell for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's make sure we get our Money's worth</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say this certainly has Been an unexpected little Windfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fortuitous even.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't even know your full name.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy to fix. Wyatt Berry Stapp Earp.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My friends call me Josie.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm Josephine Sarah Marcus.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Josie... No, I'm gonna call you Sadie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate Sadie.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you'll always be Sadie to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks away and stands, helping her up. They go to their horses. He lifts her up into her saddle and stands awhile, arranging the folds of her skirt. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>Getting late. We better get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I assume we're regarding this As just a kind of interlude.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's too much of a tangle. I already cast my lot. I can't go Back and I can't sneak, feel back Enough as it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel bad about this? About me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you don't have to sneak. You could stay with me. I know Things, Wyatt. Sweet things. I Could make you so happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mounts and rides off with a wave. She watches him awhile....</context>
      <utterance>I can't, I'm sorry. Forgive me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What mood would you like for this Picture, Miss Marcus? Any Particular occasion you're Commemorating?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE O.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps out wearing a diaphonous veil shrouding her from head to toe. Though it partially obscures her form, we can see that she's completely nude underneath. Fly gasps.</context>
      <utterance>I want to remember exactly how I Looked on this day so I want you To take a picture of me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fly fumbles with his camera, his composure gone. She turns to a nearby mirror, studying herself-black tresses, rounded lips, maddening curves, and smokey eyes-a dark angel. She smiles:</context>
      <utterance>...all of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm wonderful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Better go easy on that stuff.</context>
      <utterance>That the bottle Lou gave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what I'm doing. Where have You been?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out ridin'. So... how you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt sits down on the bed, suddenly intent, his face alight:</context>
      <utterance>Sure I'm sure. What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was thinking, we've Already made a pile of money. Maybe we should just pull up Stakes and move on. And we could Stay on the move, you know? Just Keep going, see the world. Live On room service the rest of our Lives. How'd that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, what're you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just thinkin' out loud. Forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods weakly. Josephine gives him a half-smile. Wyatt blushes. Morgan approaches.</context>
      <utterance>New singer. Ain't she somehin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc won't quit, been up 36 hours. Clanton came in an hour ago, they Switched over to poker. Tried to Get him to bed but he just won't Let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go over to Doc's table and sit down. Doc beams drunkenly:</context>
      <utterance>I know. And nobody can make him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt! Just in time. Pull up a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been hittin' it awful hard, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense, I have not yet begun to Defile myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Doc-</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't be pawed at, thank you Very much</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Doc. Behan nudges Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Doc can go all day And all night and then some. Doc's my man. Doc's my lovin' Man. Have another one, lovin' man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you think of the singer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behan gives him a wink. Wyatt shifts uneasily in his seat. This hand is down to Doc and Ike and the pot is huge. Doc shows his hand. Ike throws his cards down in a drunken rage:</context>
      <utterance>That's not what I meant.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Earps stiffen as the Cheshire cat smile comes over Doc:</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch! That's twelve Straight hands! Nobody's that lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Ike, whatever do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, boys, take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe poker's not your game, Ike. I know, let's have a spelling Contest!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll wring your scrawny neck for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough, Clanton.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You takin' his part? I'm the one Was cheated. God damn pimps, You're all in it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's in anything, Clanton, You're drunk. Go home and sleep It off.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Understand, pimp?</context>
      <utterance>Get your God damn hands off me! Don't you ever put your hands on One of us! Don't you ever try to Man-handle a Cowboy! We'll out Your God damn pimp's heart out!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Violence seems imminent. Wyatt jumps in, separating them. Behan notices as Josephine gasps, a look of alarm crossing her face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you threaten me, you Little-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgil, don't! Take it easy! Ike, Just go home and forget it, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike lurches to the bar. Behan takes Josephine aside, whispering:</context>
      <utterance>I ain't forgettin' nothin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's between you and Wyatt?</context>
      <utterance>I saw that look on your face just now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc stands up, taking Kate's arm to leave. But he falls back down dizzily, suddenly breaking out in a sweat and coughing.</context>
      <utterance>Well that certainly was a bust. I Want my money back. Come, Darling, let's seek our Entertainment elsewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again he tries to stand. This time he keels over onto the floor and starts coughing up blood. Wyatt rushes to him.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Not a thing. I'm right As the mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lift the unconscious Doc off the floor. Ike turns to Joyce.</context>
      <utterance>Get a doctor! Virgil, give me a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lunger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DR. GOODFELLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your condition is quite advanced. I'd say you've lost some 60 percent Of your lung tissue. Maybe more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GOODFELLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two years, two days, hard to say. If you have any chance, it's to Stop now-smoking, drinking, Gambling, night-life. You must Have a healthy diet and most Importantly, you must have Complete rest-meaning you must Attempt to deny your marital impulse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that sounds inviting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GOODFELLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his bag and exits, leaving Doc alone with the abyss. Kate enters, going to his bedside, and starts rolling him a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry but I'm afraid you've no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feeling, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. I knew it wasn't nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must talk, darling. It appears We have to... redefine the nature Of our association.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that mean, Doc? You know I Don't understand when you talk up High like that. You mean you Don't want to be my lovin' man no more?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a good woman to you, Doc. Don't I always take care of you? Nobody cares for you like me. I'm A good woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate smiles, licking the cigarette. She puts it in his mouth and leans over to light it so her ample bosom bulges over her bodice. As Doc stares at her chest something behind his eyes seems to shut down. He takes a long drag from the cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know. You are a good woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then again, you may be the Antichrist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastards think they can cheat me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike reaches across the bar and slaps him. Joyce scowls, more irritated than hurt and too tired to make anything of it. The few other patrons left look up drowsily. Ike nods in drunken satisfaction, picking up his rifle:</context>
      <utterance>Nobody cheated you, Ike. Go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike and the McLaurys storm off as Virgil and Morgan step out onto the street. Wyatt turns to them in disbelief:</context>
      <utterance>And I don't take no mouth from Any bartenders neither. There, See? Give somebody a rap on the beezer, get some God damn respect Around here. Now you tell the Earps and Doc Holliday if I see 'em on the street, I'm gonna send 'em all to hell on a shutter. You tell 'em that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy Clanton, Wes Fuller, and Billy Claiborne. Now there's six Of 'em. This is like a bad dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stay calm, use your head. It'll be all right. Just the Same, though...  Guess you better swear me in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you swore you'd never Carry that thing again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, I swore a lot of things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here they are again. Look at 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Doc appears from around a corner, a little the worse for wear in a long, dark Inverness cloak and carrying a big gold-headed walking stick.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, Virge, they're just tryin' To egg us on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doin' out of bed, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on? I've Had five people walk up to me Saying the Clantons and McLaurys Are gunning for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like to teach those bastards a lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably already scared them to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call it, Ike. What're we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those Cowboys're tellin' Everybody in town they're gonna Clean you out. They're down in That lot right now behind the OK Corral.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc turns on Wyatt, genuinely shocked and hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Doc, it's not your problem. You don't have to mix up in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a hell of a thing for you To say to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell're we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait till the liquor wears off. Once they start getting headaches They'll lose interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, they're threatening our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never make that stick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're carrying guns in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virge, that's a misdemeanor. You Go down there to arrest 'em, Something goes wrong, maybe this Time somebody gets his head Broke, suddenly it's a mess and It won't end there, you'll have Cowboys comin' around lookin' for Trouble from here to Christmas. You gonna risk all that over a Misdemeanor?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, damn it, it's wrong, they're Breakin' the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Virge, your call. But Give Doc the shotgun. They'll be Less apt to get nervy if they see Him on the street howitzer. Virgil trades the shotgun for Doc's cane. Doc folds the shotgun under his cloak. They get set, waiting for Wyatt's cue. Finally:</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start down Allen, footsteps pounding the board sidewalk, Virgil and Wyatt in front, Morgan and Doc in the rear. Bystanders step aside, trading whispers as they pass, turning onto 4th St...</context>
      <utterance>Well... Come on, boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There they go. Look kinda like preachers.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vacant lot starts to come into view and the Earps are fighting nerves now. Fists clenched, gritting their teeth, eyes darting all over the street, they look all too human and nothing like their legend. It's only Doc, bringing up the rear, who couldn't care less. Wyatt narrows his eyes:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Or undertakers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right over the head.</context>
      <utterance>Virge, you're makin' the arrest. You make contact, I'll back you Up. Morgan'll back me up, Doc'll Keep an eye out for trouble. And Keep your hands on your guns. They even look like they're gonna Start something, buffalo 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, I know what I'm doin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Behan walks up holding up his hands, reassuring:</context>
      <utterance>Look at 'em all. They love it. How in the hell'd we get Ourselves into this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to worry about a Thing. I just went down there and Disarmed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Earps quicken their step as Behan enters Fly's gallery. Seeing the approaching Earp party, the Cowboys glance around at each other, setting themselves. Now at the end of the sidealk, the Earps can see that the Cowboys are still armed and their relief evaporates. Wyatt mutters under his breath:</context>
      <utterance>You did? Great, thanks. Come on, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Earps slow their step, gathering themselves. This is it, no turning back now. The Cowboys spread out. As the Earps get closer and closer, it seems as if the very air is electric with tension. But as they step into the street and fan out for their final approach, they suddenly do look like their legend, 4 tall figures in long black coats advancing in a line, grim and unstoppable, a fleeting moment in time frozen forever in our minds. Finally they stop. The 2 groups are facing each other, perhaps 20 feet apart. Doc raises the shotgun, the Cheshire cat smile spreading over his face. Virgil steps forward, his face set, holding up Doc's cane:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, great. Disarmed my ass...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A weird moment of confusion where nobody seems to know what to do. Then Billy Clanton and Frank McLaury SLAP their hands to their guns. The Earps instantly tense up, hands on their pistols. Virgil waves his hands frantically, afraid they've misunderstood:</context>
      <utterance>We've come to arrest you. Throw Up your arms!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly realizing what's happening, Fuller and Claiborne bolt and dash into Fly's gallery. Everyone else stands frozen, breath short, pulses pounding, each staring into the other's wide-open eyes. Then something in Billy Clanton's eyes seems to go dead and Wyatt groans under his breath as the awful realization hits him:</context>
      <utterance>Hold! I don't want that!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy and Frank jerk their pistols and the scene EXPLODES, everything happening in SPLIT SECONDS as Wyatt draws and FIRES, knocking Frank down with a gutshot. Morgan FIRES, blowing Billy back against the wall of the Harwood house. Tom darts for the cover behind his horse as Ike dives onto Wyatt shrieking like a woman:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, please! I don't have a gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt hurls him aside. Ike sprints for the gallery. Tom FIRES over his saddle at Doc who tries for a shot but is blocked by the horse. Billly bounces back up, howling, and FIRES, the bullet piercing Virgil's calf. He drops to one knee. Tom FIRES again. Doc FIRES one barrel into the air, the BLAST making the horse rear up, exposing Tom for a split second. Doc FIRES again. Tom's side EXPLODES into red mist, the full charge of red mist, the full charge of buckshot SLAMMING him into the Harwood house. Tom drops his gun and teeters into the street, talking eerie little mincing steps, already dead but still moving, like a chicken with its head cut off. Billy FIRES again, dropping Morgan with a hole in his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>This fight's commenced. Get to Fightin' or get away!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc pull his Lightning and FIRES DOUBLE ACTION 1-2-3 times, hitting Billy in the abdomen while Frank bounds back into the fight, FIRING wildly. Virgil gets up, FIRING BACK. The whole scene now bathed in thick smoke, the fight starts swirling into the street, each man jockeying for position. Inside the gallery, Behan and Fuller watch at the window as Ike dives in. He snatches Fuller's pistol and FIRES through the window. Ike's bullets WHIZ past Wyatt's ear. He spins around, calling to Doc:</context>
      <utterance>I'm hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flashing move taking less than a heartbeat, Doc pivots, replacing the .38 in this right hand with his big .45, then with one pass of his left hand RAPID FIRES quick as a machine gun burst 1-2-3-4-5 times, the bullets RIPPING through the gallery, showering Ike and the rest with splinters and broken glass.</context>
      <utterance>Behind us!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behan hauls Ike up and they dash out the back door, Fuller and Claiborne right behind, all frantically running for their lives. Outside Billy gets to his knees, seemingly indestructible, and FIRES at Wyatt, Wyatt RETURNS FIRE. Eyes wild and bulging, a bloody hand clutching his wounds, Frank staggers across the lot, bearing down on Doc through the smoke:</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got you now, you son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc opens his arms, giving Frank a clear shot at his chest. Frank FIRES. The bullet grazes Doc's holster. Frank trudges closer, about to fire again but Doc DRILLS him through the heart while in the next millisecond Morgan FIRES from his prone position on the ground, the big .45 BLAST carrying away the top of Frank's head. As the last shot echoes through the hills, Frank flops limply to the ground like a rag doll while out in the street his brother Tom finally runs out of steam and pitches face first in the dirt, leaving only Billy, leaning against the Harwood house, legs splayed out in front of him, absolutely shot to pieces, clicking his empty gun and wailing piteously as the smoke clears:</context>
      <utterance>You're a daisy if you do!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps repeating it with sinking volume as townspeople step timidly into the street. Fly bends down and takes Bill's gun from his hand and the fight is officially over, having lasted only some 20 seconds. Wyatt helps Morgan to his feet as Behan strides briskly onto the scene, addressing Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>More cartridges! Somebody load my gun...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt looks at him in utter disbelief. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>All right. You're all under Arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More bystanders arrive, a crowd scene rapidly developing. The Earp women run up from the west end of Fremont. Josephine fights her way through the crowd from the east. She and Wyatt catch sight of each other. She grins, tears in her eyes. He nods, smiling. Seeing the whole thing, Behan fumes. And so does MATTIE who turns and walks away while Allie and Lou run to their men, hugging them. Meanwhile Doc stands over Frank's body, fingering the graze over his thigh, jeering under his breath:</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'll let you arrest Us today, Behan. Maybe tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call that shooting?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods, pocketing his gun, sadly surveying the bloody scene.</context>
      <utterance>The McLaurys are both dead. Billy Clanton's just about gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess we did our good deed for today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. If there was any other-</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods, tips his hat, walks off. Looking after him, Curly Bill whispers:</context>
      <utterance>I know. Just did what you had to. That banner and stuff, that's Just Ike. Don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about a thing</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doin', boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan looks out the window, staring at nothing. He looks tired, older, all the fun and youthful zest gone from his face.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right. It's nothin' like I thought. I almost wish...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt touches his arm, a look of unutterable sadness in his eyes. This is the one thing he didn't want for his little brother....</context>
      <utterance>I know, kid. I know. Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all drink, long and deep, Ringo wiping away tears. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Here's to the memory of Billy Clanton and Tom and Frank McLaury. They went out real Cowboys, dead game right up to Their last kick. They won their Places at the big table with Davy Crockett and Wild Bill and Old Man Clanton. They're up there Right now tradin' shots with 'em. And they'll never be forgot. Not Ever. Hundred years from now There'll be men settin' around a Campfire, passin' a bottle, Tellin' stories about those boys. They're what you call immortal. And I say God bless 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, first we hang back, Just bide away till everybody Thinks this's blown over. Then...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mattie. What about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Least you admit it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Admit what, I'm an opium fiend? No, Wyatt, I just said I need it. I need something to keep me warm At night.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mattie, I know you're-</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This catches Wyatt off-guard. He looks at her. She sneers. Then:</context>
      <utterance>You know nothing. What you don't Know would fill a book. Jesus, I Feel like it's when you're around I need it most. You're never Yourself, you never relax. Never. Everything's so stiff and dead. You always have to keep a rein on Everything, ever yourself. Oh, You smile sometimes, I've even Seen you laugh. But there's no Light in your smile for me, Wyatt, nothing to keep me warm. And I get cold, Wyatt. I get so cold.  What's between you and that Jew woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, look. I can make it Right, I can make this up to you, Mattie. I can, I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt falls silent. Mattie stands, staring at him a moment, then:</context>
      <utterance>Will you go to her and tell her Right in front of me she's Nothing to you? Right out loud so I can hear? Tell her she's Nothing, tell her she's nobody, Just dirt? Will you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She keeps ironing. Wyatt looks as if a building fell on him....</context>
      <utterance>Until you can do that we've got Nothing to talk about, Wyatt. Nothing. Now leave me alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I want to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now. I don't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're my woman and I'm your man.</context>
      <utterance>I saw that look pass between you And Wyatt at the fight. Listen to Me! You're mine! Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My man? You told Wyatt you'd Disarmed those men. Do you Actually believe after that I Could see you as my man? You're Just a dirty little fixer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HAND reaches into frame, spinning Behan around. Morgan stands there, arm in a sling, red in his eye:</context>
      <utterance>You whore! You filthy whore!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't talk that way to a Female human being! Not ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his good arm Morgan SLUGS Behan in the mouth. Behan drops like a leaf, as much to avoid a further injury as from the blow. Morgan turns to Josephine, leading her away. Across the street Curly Bill and Ringo share a flask, watching, Ringo looking even odder than usual. Curly Bill chuckles:</context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't want to take Advantage of an injured man but You better-</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she's Wyatt's slice now. Looks Like we got another name for the Tally book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dropped him, that was it. Sorry If I made a worse mess for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt looks down, miserable. Virgil looks up at the sky:</context>
      <utterance>I'm the one made a mess. Made a Right fair mess of the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Morgan sees Breakenridge passing by in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Getting warmer. Guess spring's comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Billy. I say hello, Deputy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk to you. Those Men you killed were my friends. I'm just a nothing, but if I Wasn't I'd fight you, I'd fight You right now. So I don't wanna Talk to you. He hurries away, eyes tearing up. The Earps look on in amazement.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All they ever did was make fun of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S. VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn. A liquored-up RINGO stands behind them on the sidewalk like an apparition, murder in his eyes, hands thrust into the pockets of a long black buffalo coat, ivory gunbutts peeking out.</context>
      <utterance>Sister Boy should've stuck around.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you want, Ringo?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want your blood and I want you Souls and I want them both right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't want any more trouble, Ringo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you got trouble and it Starts with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt turns into the Oriental. His brothers follow. Ringo howls:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna fight you, there's No money in it. Sober up. Come On, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wretched slugs, don't any of you Have the guts to play for blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S. VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo turns. Doc stands there, smiling that Cheshire cat smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your huckleberry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just my game.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They face each other, eyes blazing, about to reach critical mass.</context>
      <utterance>All right, lunger. Have at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On three? You call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the last possible instant, Curly Bill flashes into frame along with Stillwell and Spence, grabbing Ringo from behind while the Earps step in front of Doc.</context>
      <utterance>Here it come: one-two-</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They haul Ringo up the street, out of earshot. Ringo is boiling:</context>
      <utterance>Johnny, don't, Jesus! Come on, Son...  Never mind. He's drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want them spitting blood!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Ringo into a doorway, away from the others. Tears in his eyes, clawing the air, Ringo is beside himself.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, Johnny. Now ain't the time.  I tell you, boys, even I'm Worried what'll happen once Ringo Runs this outfit! God have mercy!</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no God, there's no devil, I hate the God damn world! I want To die!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, son. You just need to get Your feet back under you, that's All. Come on, boy, let's kick South. Down to the old playground.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy. I just wanted to tell you Things're about to start changing Around here. Lots of so-called Hard cases and tough-nuts swagger Around this town but none of 'em's got a clue about the real play. None of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will after tonight. Bet on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there's a KNOCK at the door. Louisa looks out the window. Outside is the tall silhouette of a WOMAN in a dark cloak.</context>
      <utterance>God, it's a cold night. Come up To the fire, Mattie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Allie opens the door. Josephine enter, breathless, comes into the parlor. Mattie sits up in shock. The others gather round.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another KNOCK. Allie goes to the window. There's a weird sense of dj vu as outside we again see a cloaked woman's</context>
      <utterance>Please, I know it's awful me Coming here, but listen, I can't Say why, but I think something is-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Allie starts to open the door but Josephine suddenly leaps up and:</context>
      <utterance>Now who in... It's another woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With her dancer's quickness she dashes across the parlor, grabbing Allie and pulling her to the floor just as a tremendous SHOTGUN BLAST rips through the open doorway. The chandelier overhead explodes, showering the screaming women with broken glass and a harsh MALE VOICE cuts through the air as the shrouded figure dashes into the darkness:</context>
      <utterance>No! Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody dies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting late. Guess I'll turn in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virgil nods, exiting with a wave. Wyatt and Morgan keep playing, hardly noticing as moments later, Florentino walks out....</context>
      <utterance>Bundle up, Virge. Cold out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thunder's sure somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moments later Virgil walks back in, pale, hatless, a blank look on his face. He moves with odd, shuffling steps, holding himself sideways. Wyatt and Morgan exchange puzzled glances, then:</context>
      <utterance>That didn't sound like thunder.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgil?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virgil does an unsteady stutter-step, his face taking on a pleading, almost childlike look of panic. But as he turns his body toward Wyatt we suddenly see that his whole left side is in bloody shreds, his left arm dangling unnaturally by a few gory ribbons of flesh. His voice is a frightened sob:</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to swoon. Wyatt rushes over and grabs him as....</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. GOODFELLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid your husband's been Very badly hurt. I had to remove The entire left elbow joint. What That means is, well I'm afraid-</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts wailing. Suddenly alert, Virgil sits up, taking her in his big right arm, pulling her close, his voice calm, reassuring:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, no, no, NO!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still got one arm left to hug you with. She buries her face in his chest and sobs. He holds her, rocking her back and forth. Wyatt turns away, shutting his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, don't worry, honey. I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all my fault. If I hadn't been So damn smart, if I'd just... Oh God, Virge, I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Wyatt, I don't want to talk Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virgil, what am I going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virgil grimaces in hopeless agony. Allie touches Wyatt's arm.</context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, just leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt stands, backing away. He turns pleadingly to Mattie standing in the doorway. She looks away. He walks out....</context>
      <utterance>He doesn't want to talk now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, wait. Please. I know nothin' I say'll fix things but I want You to know it wasn't me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Brothers to the bone, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt looks into McMasters' eyes and we can see he means it....</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore, not after this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get down, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morgan, are you crazy? They're Out gunning for us! What the Hell're you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it look like? They want a Piece of me they can come and get It, I'm not crawlin' into my hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morg, use your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am usin' it, Wyatt. Been Wonderin' how the hell we got in This tangle. You know they hit Clum's house, too? Shot up his wife. His wife. Who ever heard of That? Men sneakin' around in the Dark, back-shootin', scarin' Women? They're bugs, Wyatt. You Know all your smart talk about Live and let live? Ain't no live And let live with bugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I was wrong. But Morg, Look, we got to get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan pulls back his vest, revealing Virgil's badge. Wyatt drops into a corner chair, defeated. Morgan makes a shot, leaving only the 8 ball. A few beats. Seeing Wyatt's misery, Morgan softens, poking him with the cue. Wyatt looks up. Morgan taps the middle pocket. Wyatt shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to yourself, Wyatt. Lie Down and crawl or you might get Hurt? What kinda talk is that? That's Virgil lyin' over there, Wyatt. Our own brother. Ruined For life. No sir, I ain't going No place. You want to go, fine. I'm stayin' right here and have It out with those bastards.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt holds up his watch. Morgan frowns. Wyatt raises his brows:</context>
      <utterance>How much you wanna bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got it fixed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan has to lean over the table but he sinks the 8 ball, looking over at Wyatt in triumph. Wyatt applauds, rolling his eyes just as a BULLET SPANGS into the wall by his head. Wyatt dives for the floor as ANOTHER SHOT pierces the window. Wyatt jumps up, bounding to the door to see several FIGURES cash into the darkness. Wyatt turns back and freezed. Morgan lies across the table with one leg dangling over the edge, jerking and shuddering involuntarily. Wyatt rushes to him. The dog whines as Doc rushes in with Kate and McMasters. Wyatt is trembling.</context>
      <utterance>You're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no! Get the doctor! Jesus Christ!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DR. GOODFELLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt takes Morgan in his arms. The doctor probes. Morgan jerks violently. Suddenly we hear a blood-curdling SCREAM. Louisa is in the doorway, tearing her hair, lost in utter hysterics.</context>
      <utterance>Hold him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now the whole scene sinks into hellish confusion with the dog whimpering, Louisa shrieking as others restrain her, and Morgan gives a violet jerk, breaking Wyatt's grip. The doctor snarls, about at the end of his rope.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, get her out of her! Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GOODFELLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said hold him, God damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan takes Wyatt's arm, his voice like a child's.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody shut that dog up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right, Wyatt. They got Me good. Don't let 'em get you Too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will somebody get the damn dog out-</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember about the light you're Supposed to see when you're dyin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy Morg, don't think about that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears well up in Wyatt's eyes. He touches his brother's face. Morgan's eyelids start fluttering. Wyatt squeezes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't true. I can't see a damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog starts howling, long and loud and pitiful-and in the next moment the air is FILLED with howls as every dog and coyote for miles joins in the mourning. Wyatt backs away from his dead brother and trudges out onto the sidewalk, staring at the blood on his hands. Standing in the crowd across the street, Josephine sees Wyatt and starts for him. Behan grabs her. She wrenches free and with the whole town watching, starts running toward Wyatt. Seeing her, Wyatt backs away in horror, shaking his head:</context>
      <utterance>Morgan? Morgan!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, get away, get away from me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She keeps coming. Wyatt panics. Finally, in desperation:</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses, unable to believe her ears, then runs away crying. Fuming with rage, Kate starts after Wyatt. Doc pulls her back:</context>
      <utterance>Whore! Filthy whore! Get away From me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The howls continue as Wyatt trudges down the street alone. Suddenly he doubles over, clutching his abdomen in agony, staring at his bloody hands....</context>
      <utterance>Can't you see why he did it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Passing Wyatt, she doesn't even glance at him. Doc sighs:</context>
      <utterance>Naw, she's nobody. Wyatt junked her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without a word Wyatt climbs onto the wagon and shakes the reins, driving off. He pulls up in front of the Cowboys. They make a show of pretending to hide their guns. Wyatt looks straight ahead:</context>
      <utterance>And so she walked out of our Lives forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to know it's over. We're leaving and we're not Coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... 'bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you smell that? Smells like Something died.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Allie's eyes flare, Louisa stifles a sob. The Cowboys snicker. Wyatt clenches his teeth, still staring straight ahead, and drives on. A few beats then Curly Bill turns to Ike:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus, Johnny...</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take Frank and finish it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STILLWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Virgil with the women. But Where the hell's Wyatt?</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S. VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They spin around. Wyatt stands behind them, looking down the barrels of Virgil's big 10 gauge. Stillwell raises his shotgun, Wyatt FIRES. Stillwell hits the floor in a crumpled heap, his torso a smoking bundle of bloody rags. Screams</context>
      <utterance>Right behind you, Stillwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>??????????</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 87 cut off right side Page 88 missing</utterance>
   <speaker>WAGONMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rest of us're 3 months out of Independece but we're from Carthage, Illinois originally.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carthage, really? I'm from Monmouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAGONMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have a feed.</context>
      <utterance>Another Illinois man! Practical Neighbors! Step down, Marshal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAGONMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't got law, ain't got nothin'. Only thing between us and the Animals. Always the way it goes, Though. Only way to down an Illinois man's from behind, the Dogs don't dare face 'em. Mr. Lincoln, Wild Bill, now your Brothers: Illinois men all and All downed from behind by dirty Dogs and Democrats. Guess an Ordinary man'd be out for Vengeance but I don't figure That'll answer here. It's a Reckoning you're after.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the Lord is my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAGONMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt pauses, nodding, suddenly understanding the truth of it. Looking up, his eyes meet those of Lucinda. She smiles, wiping flour from her hands. Wyatt smiles thoughtfully, moved by this unexpected encounter....</context>
      <utterance>Let not your heart be faint, let Your arm be steel-that's all you Need of the Lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know why you're here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way ahead of you, Wyatt. You want Us to help you get Ike Clanton And Johnny Behan. Everybody knows They're the ones to blame for Your brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're nothing. They're nobody. I want the Cowboys. All of 'em. I Mean to break 'em up, drive 'em Out of the territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind? What on Earth'd make us-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to his 5 magnificent blacks tied nearby. They look them over as Wyatt takes out a stack of warrants.</context>
      <utterance>I'll pay you 500 each in advance And I'll mount you on those.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a sheaf of federal warrants. Being in the Territories it's up To our discretion how they're Served. That means we got the Cowboys without quarter. The Black flag, brother. No Prisoners, no mercy, amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>500... Year's wages. And I never even saw a horse like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crazy? It can't be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake. Vermillion and Johnson confer in whispers, then:</context>
      <utterance>It might be done. If we hit the Waterholes through the southern Dragoons, the Whetstones and Huachucas, we could take 'em on In pieces, run off their herds.  Keep your money, I'll show you Where those waterholes are. Just Promise me you'll finish it. No Matter what happens you'll see it Through to the end. I'll have Your hand on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods. Vermillion nods to Johnson who crouches down with a pair of dice. He makes one pass, two passes... Finally:</context>
      <utterance>We come through this in one Piece, can we keep the horses?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crapped out. Okay, we're in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange glances, each man feeling a little shiver at the magnitude of what they're about to attempt. Wyatt faces them:</context>
      <utterance>The minute we start we'll be Going against local and county Law. If we fail the U.S. Government won't be able to lift A finger to help us. Nevertheless I want you to understand we carry The full force and authority of The law of this land.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All chorus, "I do", except for Doc who rolls his eyes. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Raise your right hands. Do you Solemnly swear to uphold the laws And constitution of the United States of America and to protect her citizens to the best of your Ability, even at the cost of your Own life?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt hands each a Federal Deputy's badges. Doc waves his away:</context>
      <utterance>Oh... All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt shrugs. They mount up, about to begin, but suddenly:</context>
      <utterance>You know why I'm here. My Hypocrisy only goes so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucinda runs up to Wyatt, reaching up and tying a blue and gold silk scarf around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods his surprised thanks as the wagonmaster steps up:</context>
      <utterance>Your colors.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAGONMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands then Wyatt motions to his men. They take off at a graceful lope, riding through camp toward the deadfall and the desert beyond. Unable to contain himself any longer, Lucinda's son bounds up onto a wagon, waving and shouting, spurring them on with a spontaneous frontier toast:</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, boys. And give 'em hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCINDA'S SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>cavalier's flourish as he and his men take the deadfall in a single bound and pass into the desert. An immigrant FATHER grabs his infant son, lifting him up.</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt Earp, the two-gun man, Whistling death and bloody Murder! Wyatt the widow-maker, Avenging and bright, purple Poison on horseback with Lightning in his eye and thunder In his heart! Wyatt and his he- Devils, holy terrors and true, Five black centaurs blowin' fire And quicksilver! Ride out and Charge and shoot and strike and Cleave and hack and thrust home! Don't let up and give no rest and Never call retreat till the last One's smashed and smote and Runnin' for cover. Best 'em all And break 'em up and bang their Heads together in a bunch and Give no quarter though they be Ten times ten thousand! Wyatt turns in the saddle, sweeping off his hat with a</utterance>
   <speaker>ILLINOIS MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ILLINOIS FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Music up, avenging and bright, as Wyatt and his men ride through the desert, 5 abreast on their giant chargers, glossy black coats shimmering in the sunlight, hoofbeats pounding in unison.</context>
      <utterance>Someday he'll be able to say he Was there when Wyatt Earp rode Out to bring the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They break into a dead run, streaking across the frame. As they crest a rise the ground seems to drop from under them and for a single perfect moment it appears as if they're airborne, flying across the skyline like the winged horsemen of myth. Johnson turns to Vermillion, laughing at the sheer joy of being alive:</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's wring 'em out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like flyin', son. Just like flyin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PONY DEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they smell a wolf.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cowboy mount a pinto pony and lopes up and over the far side of the ridge. Spence and the others continue cooking. Moments later a CRASHING SOUND comes echoing over the ridge like thunder. The Cowboys look up, startled. Pony Deal points:</context>
      <utterance>Go up there and take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONY DEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pinto gallops riderless back over the ridge. The Cowboys exchange confused glances, all attention focused on the far end of the ridge. Then the five black horsemen ride out of the sun, gliding like apparitions up and over the near end of the ridge and bearing down on the unsuspecting camp with the speed of a flame. They are within a few yards of the fire when Johnny Barnes suddenly spots them and:</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spence and the others turn and just have time to gasp before Wyatt and his horsemen SLAM into them with terrifying impact, the bodies disappearing under their horses' hooves. The Cowboys recoil in total shock, jumping up from bedrolls, stumbling in confusion, scrambling to get out of the way as the possemen plow through the fire and roar into camp, pistols BLAZING in air, horses rearing and snorting.</context>
      <utterance>Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone freezes. A worried-looking Florentino shrinks back behind the others, trying not to be spotted. Meanwhile Doc leans down and pokes his pistol into a nearby Cowboy's forehead.</context>
      <utterance>United States Marshals! Reach!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They herd the Cowboys over to one side of camp, shouting, "Get over there!", "Move it!", etc. But Barnes brazens up to Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>Say something witty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A loud crack as Wyatt's quirt lays his face open to the bone.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you can't come-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get over there!</context>
      <utterance>One more word and I'll blind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONY DEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey brother, what're you doin'-</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't your brother, I ain't None of your damn brothers. Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc and Wyatt cover the Cowboys while the others scatter their herd with pistol shots. Indignant, Swilling sneers at Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>All right, run 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWILLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A queer look in his eye, Wyatt dismounts and faces Swilling.</context>
      <utterance>Bastard! Stinkin' bastard! Like To eat you blood raw!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then Wyatt DRILLS him in the jaw with a straight right hand. Swilling drops like a stone. Wyatt hauls him up by the hair and hammers him left-right-left, steps around, digs down, and pile-drives a left hook to his gut. Swilling topples back into a seated position then rolls over with a moan and passes out. Meanwhile, seeing his chance, Florentino ducks down and makes for the remuda as Doc looks down at Swilling.</context>
      <utterance>All right, breed. Dig in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It appears he missed an excellent Chance to keep his mouth shut.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florentino! He's getting away!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McMasters draws a bead on the retreating form with his '76 Winchester and FIRES. 100 yards away, the bullet hits Florentino's horse in the shoulder with a "thunk". It drops, tumbling end over end and plunging Florentino face-first into the ground. He jumps up, spitting out a mouthful, and starts running. Wyatt leaps on this black and it streaks forward, closing the distance in seconds. Florentino gasps and runs faster, pulling a bellygun from his sash, Wyatt almost on top of him. He turns and FIRES on the run. A branch next to Wyatt's head EXPLODES. Wyatt keeps coming, drawing his Buntline, impervious, unstoppable. Florentino turns for another shot just as the black PILES into him, sending him flying and tumbling him down an embankment. He scrambles to his feet as Wyatt dismounts, starting toward him with deliberate step, eyes blazing, long-barreled pistol held in front of him. Florentino backs up in terror, gun at his side, shaking his head:</context>
      <utterance>Drop his horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't kill your brother! I Don't even know him. I was only Lookout. It was money, they give Me twelve dollars! It was money!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods, still coming, cold-blooded murder in his eye. Florentino screams, raising his gun:</context>
      <utterance>A human life. Twelve dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLORENTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt FIRES, blasting Florentino to the ground. He advances, FIRING over and over, emptying his gun into him....</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As his men prepare to fire the camp, several Cowboys move to pick up Floretino's body, but:</context>
      <utterance>Look at him. That's how you'll All end up if you don't get it Through your head: it's over, The Cowboys're finished. Forever. So tell the others and get out of The Territory 'cause next time I Leave no one alive. Understand? No one. You been warned.  All right, burn it! Everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave that trash where it lays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, we might just pull this off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile Wyatt and McMasters confer over a map. Wyatt points to a specific point on the map, very interested:</context>
      <utterance>Not so sure. Somethin' tells me It gets harder from here in.  Should've held out for more money.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that cut. You mean there's A waterhole near there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this time they'll be ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PONY DEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your eyes open for Earp's Bunch. Swear to God, ain't gonna Get the drop on us this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look. Wyatt and his horsemen stand waiting at the mouth of the cut. They tense, the 1st Cowboy squinting against the sun. At the cut, Wyatt and his men poise themselves, Doc nodding:</context>
      <utterance>Riders up ahead! ...four, five. It's them all right!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cowboys charge forward, outnumbering them better than 2 to 1 and only 100 yards away. The possemen choke up on their reins, alerting their horses for action as:</context>
      <utterance>They saw us. Here they come.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>75 yards and the first shots RING out, richochetting off the walls of the cut. The others blanch but Wyatt stays cool, waiting, 50 yards... 40 yards... till we can see their eyes and:</context>
      <utterance>Wait... wait... steady...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They whirl around and disappear into the cut. The Cowboys keep coming. Wyatt's group reaches the little trail leading up the wall of the cut he used to avoid Josephine. They clamber up the side of the cut at a bounding gallop, unseen, as moments later the Cowboys gallop by and continue through into the desert on the other side. Wyatt's group careens up and around the high mountain wall as if on a roller-coaster, following the tiny, narrow path at a breathtaking clip, the trail finally plunging them back into the draw behind the Cowboys. They speed up to the opposite mouth of the cut, drawing their pistols as the Cowboys gallop into the desert before them, unaware.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They CHARGE forward. Seeing the empty desert ahead, the Cowboys pull up, looking around in confusion. Suddenly a VOLLEY of GUNFIRE hits them from behind, knocking several from the saddle. They spin around just as Wyatt's group SLAMS into them HEAD-ON, guns BLAZING, Cowboys tumbling from the saddle left and right, horses rearing and toppling over backwards.</context>
      <utterance>Lay on!</utterance>
   <speaker>PONY DEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The remaining Cowboys turn and dash into the desert. Wyatt shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt's group CHARGES, the thoroughbreds closing the distance in seconds. Vermillion stands in his stirrups, roaring like an animal as he PLUNGES into them, swinging his quirt like a saber and LASHING a Cowboy across the face, making him tumble to the earth and bounce over the rocks like a rag doll. McMasters closes with another, throwing an arm around him and JERKING him from the saddle, SNAPPING his neck. Doc overtakes a 3rd, jams his pistol into his face and FIRES point-blank, blackening his face with soot and BLOWING out the back of his head as he falls. Reins in his teeth, shotgun at his shoulder, Johnson comes up behind a 4th and FIRES. The Cowboy's head DISAPPEARS in a cloud of pink vapor, the body dropping like a stone.... Wyatt bears down on Pony Deal at a dead run. Pony Deal turns in the saddle and FIRES at him. We feel a surge of breathless exhilaration as Wyatt swings out of the saddle like a Commanche and ducks his body down against the side of his horse, hiding in its lee. Pony Deal turns for another shot only to see an apparently riderless horse overtake him. But in the next instant Wyatt darts around under his horse's neck and FIRES, blowing Pony Deal head-over-heels off the back of his horse. Wyatt bounds back into the saddle as McMasters rides by, drawing a bead with his rifle on the lone survivor, the 1st Cowboy. Only a few yards in front of them, he whips his horse frantically, trying to get away. McMasters is about to fire when Wyatt rides up, deflecting the shot. The Cowboy makes it over a rise and disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you do that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he can tell the story.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1ST COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just everybody!</context>
      <utterance>Didn't make any sense. One minute We're chasin' 'em, next they're Right on top of us. We couldn't Stop 'em, they got everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curly Bill grins, his coarse face radiant in the firelight...</context>
      <utterance>Easy now, it's only five men. Been havin' it their way 'cause They been surprising you. Hittin' The waterholes and that Judas McMasters is showin' 'em right Where they are. Pretty damn cute. But nobody's cute as me.  Next up's Black Draw. But that Smart Wyatt'll say no, that's Where they'll expect us to hit, We'll hit the one after. Iron Springs. That's where they show Next. Only I'm gonna be there First. And throw a little party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls back. Doc wraps himself in the blanket. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really look awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not half as bad as I feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why in hell're you doin' This? You ought to be in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt Earp is my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I got lot's of friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile at the other side of the camp, Wyatt and McMasters huddle over the map, Johnson walks up:</context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you ought to have a talk With Doc, Wyatt. I don't know if He's gonna make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no reasoning with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next waterhole's Black Draw. We Could be there by mid-morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're wise by now. Which is Next, Iron Springs? Yeah, let's Try there, Iron Springs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There they are. No herd though.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pull shotguns from their saddles and start down over the rocks on foot, creeping up on the camp, seemingly undetected. But suddenly the Cowboys by the fire dive behind a log and:</context>
      <utterance>We'll go around that way, come up on foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And suddenly the deadfall on the opposite side EXPLODES IN GUNFIRE. Vermillion takes a graze and drops with the others, hugging the rocks. A bullet RICHOCHETS into a rock at Johnson's head, biting his face with fragments, making him wince:</context>
      <utterance>Ambush! Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunched behind the logs on the opposite side with 15 more Cowboys, Curly Bill raises his head, grinning and shouting:</context>
      <utterance>Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt and his men react to his voice. The fire continues. Suddenly there's MOVEMENT in the rocks above them. Doc points:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Wyatt! How the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing the spot they're in, McMasters turns to the silent Wyatt:</context>
      <utterance>Got some boys workin' around Those rocks behind you. Another Minute or two, gonna have you in A crossfire! How do you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now for the first time we see fear in these men, actual naked fear. But Curly Bill laughs, having the time of his life.</context>
      <utterance>He's right. They get set up in Them rocks it's the end for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crouched by Curly Bill, Barnes chuckles. A confident ripple of laughter goes through the Cowboy line-they know they've got them. On the other side, Vermillion shakes his head grimly.</context>
      <utterance>'Course you could give yourselves up and we could have a party! Then what larks!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McMasters looks at the still silent Wyatt, shrugging helplessly:</context>
      <utterance>Ain't takin' me alive, damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They really are at the end of their rope, all looking to Wyatt for a solution. He remains silent. Then suddenly, in this supreme moment, a strange, almost supernatural calm seems to come over him and he says simply:</context>
      <utterance>Think of somethin' fast or we're cooked.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now we can almost hear the ether RINGING in our ears as Wyatt takes his shotgun and, while the others look on in horror, rises to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bullets WHIZ around him. Doc jumps up to grab him but a RICOCHET drives him back down. Wyatt advances quickly across the clearing, walking right into the teeth of their guns, repeating:</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt's clothes jerk and ripple as bullets pass through, but he just keeps coming. Seeing this, Curly Bill also stands, a weird, manic elation coming over him. He hoots and howls:</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that! Yeah! Come and get Some, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curly Bill waves away his men's fire and walks toward Wyatt, 12 gauge shotgun in one hand, .45 in the other, BLASTING away.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me, let me, yeah! Die, you Bastard...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curly Bill FIRES again. Wyatt's hat flies off. He FIRES again, digging a gash in Wyatt's boot-heel. Now Curly Bill takes dead aim with his .45 and-CLICK-it's empty. He tosses it aside. Suddenly a sharp wind gusts up, making the tails of Wyatt's duster swirl around him like a halo as he advances. Eyes wild with battle rage, Curly Bill quickly raises his shotgun.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He FIRES. Wyatt's coattails EVAPORATE into swirling shreds as he takes deliberate aim with his mighty 10 gauge, hissing through clenched teeth:</context>
      <utterance>Die! Son of a bitch! Die!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Wyatt lets go with BOTH BARRELS. Curly Bill's mid-section VAPORIZES, the huge double-charge of buckshot RIPPING HIM COMPLETELY IN HALF. The other Cowboys flinch as they're sprayed with flecks of blood and gore. Barnes screams:</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes burning like two twin hells, Wyatt pulls his Buntline and FIRES. Barnes doubles over. Wyatt FIRES again. Barnes drops. The others recoil, their faces looking as if they are living in a waking nightmare as Wyatt advances on them, STILL FIRING. Another goes down. Doc leaps from the rocks, gun in hand, and:</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now they all rise and OPEN FIRE, advancing 4 abreast, a WALL OF GUNFIRE driving the remaining Cowboys off, running for their horses. Wyatt keeps snapping his empty gun as the others run up.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beside himself, Doc helps Wyatt to a nearby rock, sitting him down and examining him, running his hands all over his body. The others FIRE at the Cowboys retreating on horseback.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, my God! You're shot to pieces!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, better run, you bastards!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it. He's clean!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? But I saw 'em-</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look. Meanwhile Wyatt starts to tremble....</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, there isn't a Mark on him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a man without fear, Wyatt. I Literally don't care if I live or Die. But even I can't fight human Instinct. Somebody suddenly Starts shooting at me, I duck. But you... what on earth were You thinking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the other end of camp, Vermillion and Johnson sit together. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It all happened so Fast. If I'd had a chance to Think about it I guess I probably Would've been scared but... Swear To God, Doc, I just don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Creek, you ever see anything Like that before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vermillion nods. Both look shaken to the very core of their beings. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Never even heard of anything like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought of somethin' I Never thought about before.  I don't want to go to hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talked it over. We decided we Don't need the money. Took out 13 Dollars each, though. Federal Posseman's fee. That all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods, picks up the money and quietly moves off toward the stream by himself. Moments later, McMasters approaches:</context>
      <utterance>One thing. We come through this Alive, can we keep the badges?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Wyatt?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down at the creek. Walking on water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>1ST COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hit him half a dozen times but He just kept comin', walked right Up to Curly Bill with that 10 Gauge and blew him up!</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo starts making strange little inarticulate sounds, inhaling and exhaling like an animal, eyes swimming in panic....</context>
      <utterance>Curly Bill? He killed Curly Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't just kill him, he Burned him down! Blew him in Half! I mean all the way in half, Like a melon! Then he turned Around with that big Colt and Killed Johnny Barnes, shot up a Couple more 'fore we got out of there. But it was his face, you should've seen his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo looks up at them, suddenly dead calm, his face a blank.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't see his face</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of nowhere, Ringo draws and FIRES 2 shots so quickly they sound like one. The 2 survivors drop with bullets through their brains. The others jump, transfixed by the insane brutality of what he's just done. Ringo draws himself up, in full possession of the situation, the new leader, fearsome, matchless:</context>
      <utterance>You see my face, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is where I get woolly.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody get this through their Heads. Wyatt Earp dies. I'm Running the show now and I'm Telling you, Earp dies. His men Too. They all die. Understand? We're gonna kill 'em. For what They did to Curly Bill we're Gonna ride 'em into the ground And slaughter 'em like rabbits. 'Cause this is my time, children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GROUNDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you think? I didn't think Curly Bill could be killed. I'm Tellin' you, this whole thing's Gone sour. We got hands droppin' Like flies and Ringo's flat out Of his mind. I mean, hell Brother, you feel like ridin' Against Wyatt Earp?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell no, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUNDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then brother let's you and me cut out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They steal away toward the horses as....</context>
      <utterance>Right with you, brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? It's front page News all over the country. It's Getting out of hand, Ringo. If Things don't settle down soon-</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me, Behan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo glares at Behan, his eyes burning, implacable:</context>
      <utterance>Ringo, you don't understand-</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>3RD COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy Grounds and Zwing Hunt ran Out. Four, five others, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behan looks worried as Ike and the other Cowboys gather around. Just then Breakenridge rides up.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares? Separate the wheat From the chaff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here, Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curly Bill was my friend. I'd Like to come with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo slaps the little deputy on the back and turns to his men. His unaccustomed good humor is very troubling.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you it was time to get Woolly. Now gather 'round, Children, gather 'round. And Raise your right hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all exchange looks of disbelief, then:</context>
      <utterance>That's Ringo out front. And There's Behan. Must be 30 of 'em. What the hell... they're wearin' Badges.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly looking very sick, Doc sways dizzily in the saddle. Wyatt dismounts, reaching for him. The others do the same:</context>
      <utterance>Mounts're getting jaded. We're Gonna have to find a place to Rest 'em up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc turns his horse, as if to ride on, then faints dead away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me, God damn it! Just Don't touch me! Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all catch him, easing him to the ground as....</context>
      <utterance>Grab him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Horse're pretty well fagged and We got a sick man with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt nods. Hooker motions down the hill toward his house....</context>
      <utterance>You can put up at my ranch if you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it gonna be, brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUNDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a STAGECOACH comes into view, making its winding way through the crossroads below. Hunt points, grinning:</context>
      <utterance>I don't care. Colorado, New Mexico, 'long as we're out of the Territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They spur their horses down the hill, drawing their guns....</context>
      <utterance>Just what we need. Travelin' money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behan opens the door. Mr. Fabian lies inside cradled in Josephine's arms, surrounded by the other actors in the troupe. Reclined at full length, head back, he looks like the dying Hamlet, even more beautiful than in life. Breakenridge gasps:</context>
      <utterance>Robbery. 2 men stuck 'em up and Killed a passenger. One of 'em Rode a Mexican saddle, the other Had a Mother Hubbard. Billy Grounds and Zwing Hunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo shrugs. His soft face suddenly turning resolute. Breakenridge goes to his horse and mounts.</context>
      <utterance>We're headed for a booking in Denver. They tried to take my Watch. He cursed them for cowards And they shot him. He may've been Vain and an actor but he was Better than all of you. And Gentler and braver. I don't Understand any of this, I only Know it's ugly. You're all ugly And he was beautiful, he tried to Put something fine into your ugly World and you killed him for it. Anyway the ones who did it are headed north. Not that you care.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little deputy straightens his spectacles, turning to Behan:</context>
      <utterance>Where're you going? Get back here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he rides off alone into the Whetstones. Behan sputters, but:</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, but we got to Have some law.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him go. Who cares?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing each other, Wyatt and Josephine freeze. Wyatt approaches:</context>
      <utterance>Had a holdup. Came her to water Their horses before pushin' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about your friend.  And I'm sorry about...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgave you the moment you said it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver jumps back onto the stage, motioning to the others.</context>
      <utterance>You did. Well... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops. Wyatt falters. There's so much he wants to say, but... Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt opens the coach door for her. She gets in. It pulls out with a crack of the driver's whip. She and Wyatt hold each other's gaze as the stage recedes into the distance. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creek Johnson steps up next to him. Wyatt looks at him:</context>
      <utterance>Damn... Damn!</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See how she breezed out of here. Like she had wings. Funny thing But I can't really remember how She looked. I can remember parts Of her clear as crystal, her Mouth, her walk, how she shut her Eyes when she laughed, little Bits and pieces, but not the Whole package. Can't put it Together for some reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God, you're really-</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cards in spades. I'm in love with Every second of her life. Hell, I'll probably love her when I'm dust.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grounds grunts. Suddenly there's an O.S. SOUND. Both jump up.</context>
      <utterance>No fire tonight, son. Too many Riders out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breakenridge steps from the shadows, Winchester at his shoulder, squinting through the dark with his spectacles.</context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They relax and lower their pistols, heaving sighs of relief.</context>
      <utterance>It's Deputy Breakenridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sister Boy! Thank God, we was afraid-</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't've killed Mr. Fabian. You shouldn't've done That. It was wrong. I'm takin' You both in for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You gotta be kiddin'. Look, Just go home 'fore you get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't want to kill you but I will If I have to. I'm warning you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUNDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grounds steps forward menancingly. Breakenridge tenses:</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm warning you, Sister Boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUNDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grounds raises his pistol. Breakenridge recoils in fright, stumbling backward in the dark, and his rifle accidentally FIRES. Grounds drops like a stone, a look of utter disbelief on his dying face. Hunt looks at him in shock then turns on Breakenridge, raising his gun and snarling. Breakenridge FIRES again. Hunt grabs his midsection, dropping his gun and falling to his knees. He looks up at Breakenridge who shrugs timidly:</context>
      <utterance>Sister Boy, just go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREAKENRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunt falls over, dead. Breakenridge stares at the bodies, hardly believing it himself....</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behan suddenly steps up, beside himself, holding up his message:</context>
      <utterance>Hooker's got around 15 or 16 Hands. We could take 'em right Enough but it might be a mess. Keep the place bottled up for Now, see if we can figure a way To flush 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too much! It's completely Out of hand! Governor Gosper's Talking about asking the President to send in the Army! Listen Ringo, you've got to get This over with and you've got to Do it now. One way or another.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should get moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc's just in no kinda shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have to bother about that. Took a vote. Cowboys or not, you Can stay here as long as you want. Anyway maybe you done enough. I Mean you whittled 'em down Considerable, now there's talk of Sendin' the Army in here. Ask me, You done enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANCH HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up as the 3rd Cowboy rides up with a white kerchief.</context>
      <utterance>Rider comin' in under a white flag</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a message. Ringo wants McMaster to come over to our Camp for a parley.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't figure on all the stink This is causin'. Might be he's lookin' to strike a bargain. If So, he probably figures he needs Somebody like me who talks his Language. Could be we got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Wyatt can answer, McMasters rides off with the Cowboy....</context>
      <utterance>Might as well hear him out. Anyways, what choice we got?  But no matter what happens, see It through to the end. If you don't I'll curse the day I ever laid eyes on you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well hello, Sherm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, kinda, wanted to see if you'd join back up with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That what you got me up here for?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a Cowboy, you're a Brother. Come back, no hard Feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Ringo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't there anything I can say That'll change your mind? You're Gonna stay with your new friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCMASTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Least they don't scare women.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo moves closer, looking him in the eye and smiling:</context>
      <utterance>You're the boss. One thing, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you gonna get back to 'em?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't they've jus killed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ringo wanted to be sure he got Your attention, Marshal. He wants A straight-up fight, just you and Him, settle this thing once and For all. You win, we quit the Territory; Ringo wins, your Deputies get safe conduct to the Colorado line. Sundown today in The oak grove at the mouth of Sulphur Springs Canyon. Ride out With your escort, we'll meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell Ringo... just tell him I'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, are you crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made a promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'Cept maybe for Wild Bill.</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, listen, you can't beat Him. You're good and God knows You got the courage, but you Ain't in Ringo's class. Hell, He's the best that's ever been.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right, Wyatt. Ringo could Put five into you before you Could even get one into him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'd do it, I'd get that one Into him. So help me God, I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In tight on Wyatt as these words sink in and....</context>
      <utterance>All right Wyatt, maybe you can. But you gotta die to do it. Understand? You gotta die!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What makes him do the things he does?</context>
      <utterance>What makes a man like Ringo, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sick mad. Cold and dirty.</context>
      <utterance>A man like Ringo's got a great Empty hole right through the Middle of him and no matter what He does he can't ever fill it. He Can't kill enough or steal enough Or inflict enough pain to ever Fill it. And it drives him mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what does he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want? He wants revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc looks at him, a look of purest sadness in his sunken eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Revenge? For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt looks down again and it's a long time before he speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Being born.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc shakes his head. Wyatt nods then stands, ready to exit, but:</context>
      <utterance>Remember how I said it all Happened so fast with Curly Bill I didn't have time to think about it? Well I've had plenty of time To think about this. I spent most Of my life since I was born not Knowing what I want out of life, Just chasin' my tail. But now, For the first time I know exactly What I want. And who. And that's The damnable misery of it.  I can't beat him, can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc struggles to sit up, sweating and trembling, finally falling back down, almost passing out. Wyatt puts a hand on his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>No, wait, I'll go with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Wyatt. God, I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right, Doc. Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc points to Wyatt's badge. He takes it off, pressing it into Doc's hand. Doc smiles then does pass out. Wyatt exits....</context>
      <utterance>Never got to wear one of those.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo squints through the front door of the house to the open bedroom where Doc lies unconscious, chest heaving, sweating.</context>
      <utterance>It's Holliday. He's sick. Imagine He's dyin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drag him out here, let's have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker and his men look resolute. Ringo smiles, nodding:</context>
      <utterance>I looked the other way when you Did a lot of foul things but I Ain't lettin' you torment a dyin' Man. Not as long as he's under my Roof. I draw the line there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Hooker. I'll be back In about an hour. We'll see how Brave you are then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo and his men ride off. At the crossroads they stop, Ike peeling off.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they gallop off in opposite directions as....</context>
      <utterance>Soon as I'm through with Wyatt, Swarm down with the whole bunch And finish off Creek Johnson and Texas Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get ready. Soon as Ringo's done We're gonna take care of the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't we giving them safe conduct?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure we are. All the way to hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt shakes hands with Vermillion who turns away with emotion, hiding his face. Wyatt turns to Johnson.</context>
      <utterance>They're not givin' you any safe Conduct. Soon as the shooting Starts kick east for the New Mexico line. Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, I... I ain't got the words.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt pats his shoulder and walks off alone into the thicket, the only sound the musical clinking and chiming of his spurs....</context>
      <utterance>I know. Me neither.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, didn't think you had it in you.  Shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARK SILHOUETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo stiffens as the silhouette steps into the waning light. It's DOC, pale and drawn, looking like death itself, but awake and ready just the same:</context>
      <utterance>I'm your huckleberry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why Johnny Ringo, you look like Somebody just walked over your grave.  Oh, I wasn't quite as sick as I Made out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My fight's not with you, Holliday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Play for blood, remember?</context>
      <utterance>I beg to differ. We started a Fight we never got to finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the last time, that Cheshire cat smile comes over Doc's face:</context>
      <utterance>I was kidding about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ringo nods, his hock replaced by a growing malice. As they set themselves, once again their eyes begin to blaze, boring into each other, their concentrated rage focusing on each other, about to reach critical mass....</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't.  And this time it's legal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, lunger. Let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long tense moment then both grunt in unison. Blurred movement, the FLASH of a GUNSHOT. Doc slaps his gun back in it's holster as Ringo stumbles, a bullet hole in the side of his head....</context>
      <utterance>Say when.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But finally Ringo falls over into the crook of the oak tree, his pistol firing into the air harmlessly. Doc looks down at him, shaking his head:</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Wyatt appears, looking at Doc in total shock.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Johnny. You're no daisy, no Daisy at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc looks at him like he's a fool then points to Ringo:</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly we hear HORSES crashing through the brush toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Poor soul, he was so high-strung. Afraid the strain was more than He could bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dash off into the thicket. Moments later Ringo's seconds ride out into the grove. Seeing Ringo's body, their jaws drop....</context>
      <utterance>Let's go! My horse is over here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praise Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be dipped in shit. I will, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, what's it to be? New Mexico's that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colorado's closer</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So're the Cowboys. They're up That road right now, waiting to Jump us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERMILLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're the law, ain't we? Well the Law don't ride around vermin-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt looks at Doc, who shrugs. Wyatt swings his horse alongside, suddenly noticing his badge on Doc's chest. Doc smiles wanly:</context>
      <utterance>It rides right at 'em. Like McMasters said, see it through to The end.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts unpinning it but Wyatt stops him, pressing his palm onto the badge over Doc's heart. A last look around each other then Wyatt signals and they start up the north road at the lope, four abreast, the last charge of Wyatt Earp and his immortals....</context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to see what it felt Like. Here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>4TH COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behan heaves a sigh of relief, glancing around at the others.</context>
      <utterance>Riders comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But suddenly Ringo's seconds gallop up from the flank:</context>
      <utterance>Well I guess Ringo did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ringo's dead</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Straining to see in the falling light, the cowboy on the rock shouts excitedly:</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The word starts to spread, the crowd of horsemen BUZZING. Suddenly, off in the distance, the 4 horsemen come into view, coming straight at them at a lope.</context>
      <utterance>That's Wyatt Earp's bunch!</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down the road, Wyatt asnd his men pull their shotguns, holding them at the ready as they break into a gallop. The Cowboy on the rock jumps down, mounting his horse.</context>
      <utterance>They're comin' right at us!</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cowboys line-up on a rise, blocking the road. They draw their guns. Wyatt and his men keep coming, now 200 yards away. Behan groans, panic sinking sour and heavy, churning his bowels:</context>
      <utterance>Here they come! Get ready...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Wyatt's men break into a dead run, hurtling toward them at top speed, their thoroughbreds eating up the distance, now only 100 yards away. The Cowboys tense up more and more, biting lips, grinding teeth. The 4th Cowboy turns to the nearby 3rd Cowboy:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's time to start Workin' for a livin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They break and run. So does another. Suddenly the whole mass of them EXPLODES in panic with horsemen riding in all directions, scurrying away like cockroaches from a light. Ike looks around, screaming at them, beside himself as the 4th Cowboy rides by:</context>
      <utterance>Me too!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill 'em! Kill 'em! It's only Four men! Why don't you kill 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others keep going, leaving him behind. But seeing Wyatt bearing down on him, Ike finally bolts himself, pounding off hell-for-leather into the hills. Wyatt and his men keep coming at a full gallop and as they crest the rise, suddenly, as before, the ground seems to fall out from under them and for another burning moment they once again appear airborne, grim-faced avenging angels on winged horses, now even more majestic in the twilight, like a myth made flesh, awesome, superb, and unutterably beautiful. As they approach, only Breakenridge remains, giving them a tentative wave. Wyatt points a finger at him as they ride by in a flash, cresting another rise and passing into legend....</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well hell, Wyatt. Wyatt, I want You to meet Father Feeney. Father Feeney's just been initiating me Into the mysteries of the great And ancient Church of Rome. You See, it appears my hypocrisy Knows no bounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feelin', Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rather an obvious question under The circumstances, don't you Agree? A better one might be how Do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurts. Hurts pretty bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imagine it would, yes. So now We can add self-pity to your list Of frailties.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Doc...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm kidding. You're the Most fallible, wrong-headed, self- Deluding, just generally Benighted jackass I've ever Known. Yet, withal, even at your Worst, you're the only human Being in my entire life who ever Gave me hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I ever wanted was to live a Normal life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will you wake up? You Wouldn't know a normal life if it Bit you in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great coming from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest is relative.</context>
      <utterance>I played the cards I was dealt, Wyatt. Your problem is you're Always trying to play someone Else's. Allow me to tell you the Truth and thus set you free: There is no happiness, Wyatt There is no normal life. There's Only life, that's all. Just life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First you can grab that black- Haired woman and make her your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt stares into his eyes, letting this sink in. Just then, Doc looks up, as if something were pressing on him. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Run. Take that girl and start Running. Run and don't look back. All your life you been running And looking back and just barely Existing and calling it getting By. This time run and don't look Back and call it living. Live Every second, live it right up to The hilt. Live, Wyatt...  Live for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other and something passes between them, something so personal and powerful it transcends emotion. Wyatt starts to speak, but:</context>
      <utterance>Wyatt, please, if you were ever My friend, if you ever had even The smallest feeling for me, Leave. Leave now. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc turns away. Wyatt exits. Doc looks over at Father Feeney:</context>
      <utterance>Never mind, Wyatt. I know. Just go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now let's see, Father. What was That monkey show you were talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER FEENEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Extreme Unction?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father Feeney nods, picking up his Missal. As he starts to intone the Last Rites, Doc looks down at the end of the bed and sees his feet poking through the sheets. They are bare. Doc smiles:</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Better start that ball rolling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned...  This is funny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>1ST ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get used to this thin air Here in Denver. I thought I was Going to faint on that last buck- And-wing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the door bursts open. Screams and stunned reaction. Wyatt rushes in and goes to Josephine who sits in stunned silence. He falls to his knees and grabs the hem of her robe.</context>
      <utterance>I know, it's-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wyatt! My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt stands, pulling her close, clasping her hands in his:</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see the sun come up Over the Rockies? It hits all of A sudden and below there's California and you swear you're Looking at heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have nothing left. I have Nothing to give you. I have no Pride, no dignity, no money. I Don't even know how we'll make a Living. But I promise I'll love You every second of your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Wyatt. My family's rich.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>1ST REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wyatt and Josephine hunch down and duck through a knot of porters into the next car. Only the 1st Reporter gives chase. Moving into the passenger car furthest forward, Wyatt leads her through the door to the platform over the coupling between cars. Chugging up a steep grade toward a high crest, the train is immersed in shadows. Wyatt points ahead to the approaching crest:</context>
      <utterance>Mr Earp! One minute, please! You And your four men have just Accomplished in one week what it Took the Texas Rangers four years To do. Please, do you have any comment?</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside meanwhile, the 1st Reporter comes through the car and spots them up. A business-type PASSENGER tugs on his sleeve:</context>
      <utterance>There. It'll come up over that ridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the commotion? Who are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside, still bathed in shadows, Wyatt and Josephine hang onto the railing and lean out, watching in as the train nears the top.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you know? That's Wyatt Earp, the Lion of Tombstone, and His lady fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>WYATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, as if on cue, they crest the mountain and are suddenly bathed in golden sunlight, their heads leaning from the train, Wyatt's blonde hair and Josephine's black tresses flowing in the breeze, their faces luminous, looking straight ahead toward their future. Hold on this image as the sun gets brighter and brighter, finally making the frame white-out as we....</context>
      <utterance>Get ready, here it comes! Here it comes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figures of the old man and woman fade away, leaving only the desert and the mountains which are eternal....</context>
      <utterance>"Wyatt and Josephine embarked on a series of adventures throughout the west, making and losing several fortunes, always living the high life, spending every winter, just the two of them, prospecting for gold in the desert foothills of southeastern California. Up or down, thin or Flush, in 47 years they never Left each other's side."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flickering images from early Hollywood silent films split the frame: on one side the grim but impassioned figure of William S. Hart, the original western good-badman crouched menacingly behind a pair of sixguns, his costume dusty and severe; and on the other side Tom Mix, the original western fantasy hero, so light-hearted and optimistic with his sunny grin and fancy white outfit....</context>
      <utterance>"Wyatt Earp died in Los Angeles in 1929. Among the pallbearers at his funeral were early western movie stars William S. Hart and Tom Mix."</utterance>
   <speaker>V.O. NARRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on these two images as the music swells and we....</context>
      <utterance>"Tom Mix wept."</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
