<movie id="568" title="Total Recall">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't budge. Shortly, the clock CHIMES again.</context>
      <utterance>Tick, tock, seven o'clock. Time to rise and open your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail's wife stirs. Maddeningly, the clock CHIMES a third time.</context>
      <utterance>Tick, tock, seven-oh-one. Time to get up, the day had begun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail reaches out and shuts the clock off. Then he sits up in bed. He swings his legs out from under the covers and sits on the edge of the bed. He puts on his glasses and sits, lost in thought. He is a good-looking but conventional man in his early thirties. He seems rather in awe of his wife, who is attractive and rather off-hand towards him. Kirsten pulls on her robe, lights a cigarette, sits fishing for her slippers.</context>
      <utterance>Tick, tock --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dreamed about Mars again... it was bizarre, yet is was so real...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks at her quizzically.</context>
      <utterance>It's your time of the month again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least once a month. Douglas Quail's obsession. For twelve years you've been talking about Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People do go to Mars, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks crestfallen.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Douglas. But not you. Not us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As it is, we can barely scrape by on your lousy ten thousand a week. She leaves the room. He meditates on what she said, depressed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is absorbed in his own paper and doesn't hear her.</context>
      <utterance>What do they expect ... the way men dress these days ... then they scream rape.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know -- let's really do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rape men in the park?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Go to Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can pool our savings and I've got some sick leave coming, besides my regular vacation...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures toward the TV screen where Martian police are keeping protesters behind a barrier. Some have signs reading "A FREE MARS", "DOWN WITH COHAAGEN", "EARTH - OUT" etc.</context>
      <utterance>...more of a half-wit. For a start a war could break out there any day ...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just media talk. They're...  ...just a minority. They're powerless.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kitchen clock chimes and talks.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a lot of things we need around here before we waste our money on a trip to Mars. We're broke. I'm just a slave around this dump. Now if you were capable of finding a better job....</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's now eight. You'll be late!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps up quickly from the table, picks up his coat and briefcase, kisses KIRSTEN's perfunctorily offered cheek and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be late!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No weapon again, Mr. Quail?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep forgetting, Herb. They frighten me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GUARD gestures to his associate. They've obviously been through this with Quail before.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well, it's the law, Mr. Quail. Has been since 1990 they tell me. Tomorrow - ya carry ya gun or ya get reported.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail walks on to the track area. The train arrives. Signs above each approaching car say "CAR FULL", "ROOM FOR 10 PERSONS", etc. Quail goes to a carriage marked</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Herb, okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Everyone ignores the broadcast -- except Quail, who perks instantly at the word "Mars." The NEWSCASTER is a young black man.</context>
      <utterance>-- more violence today from Mars's strike-torn ore colonies --</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but Earth Intelligence Operations Director Vilos Cohaagen, clearly worried about the damage to Mars's all important tourist industry was today dismissive of the dissident groups.... TV scene switches to a press conference. COHAAGEN, sur- rounded by AIDES, steps in front of a podium packed with news network microphones and cameras. Cohaagen is a striking, intense man with an obvious air of power.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The train stops at another station and more people pile on. Quail tries to watch the broadcast through the bodies passing in front of him and intermittently blocking the image.</context>
      <utterance>We're dealing with a bunch of extremists and unrepresentative lunatics. Mars is a happy and prosperous protectorate of Earth... and will remain so.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There have been some criticisms, sir....</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The news conference ends and a bright looking young man comes on the screen. Quail continues to watch, though not as interested, initially, as he was by the Mars story. Few of the other passengers bother looking at the screen.</context>
      <utterance>I have no further comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail watches the commercial through to the end, but doesn't seem to take it very seriously. He glances away as a card comes on the screen with REKALL's numbers.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, commuters. This portion of your trip is brought to you by Rekall, Inc. Do you have a dream that never came true? Do you aspire - but only perspire? Has the great adventure passed you by? Then come to... REKALL, where what might have been will have been. For the memories of a lifetime... REKALL.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... is the process really that effective? A false memory!? McCLANE  We prefer the term "extra- factual implant". Your memory will be complete in every way. You will have gone to Mars. We guarantee that.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses the button again and the normal office returns. Quail looks around, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Is it in any way dangerous? I mean, the medical techniques? McCLANE Not when you deal with qualified operators - like us.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just - incredible. McCLANE And look at our follow-up program! He puts items on the desk as he talks. McCLANE  Space-flight ticket stub... passport... vaccination certificates... matchbooks from Martian Nouvelle Cuisine Restaurants, souvenirs, post cards... even names of people you met - now back there - who you can call and discuss your trip with... by the way, we plant these things where you'll come across them at random in the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... I'll know I hired you. That'll destroy the whole illusion. McCLANE  But you won't remember me, or having been here.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the press of a button, a list appears on the wall...</context>
      <utterance>I won't? McCLANE Your money back if you do! We've never paid out yet. Quail slumps backs in his chair, overwhelmed. McCLANE  And we have a special this month, for only two-hundred thousand dollars more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>A17  INTELLIGENCE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail's eyes linger on "Intelligence Agent."</context>
      <utterance>McCLANE  You can have a new identity for the duration of the trip. Pick one.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Intelligence Agent"... wouldn't that be dangerous? I might attack.... McCLANE  No. No. You're a retired agent. Mars was your last mission and you're never to break your cover. But you'll have got the girl, killed the baddies, and saved the Universe. Not bad, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is thoughtful, willing to be totally convinced.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... about the whole thing... it's all such a fake. I won't really have gone. I won't really.... McCLANE  Let's face it, Douglas, you, and millions of people like you have no chance of ever getting to Mars and you'd never qualify as a secret agent for EIO. This - REKALL - is the only way to achieve your dream. He gets up and walks around to Quail's chair. McCLANE  Think about it, Douglas. Think, too, what a terrible boor a real holiday is. Lost tickets, endless arguments, lousy hotels, missed connections, rotten weather... Rekall will supply you with perfect, happy memories.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that's illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Who's going to report me? You?... wimp.... She watches a torrid love scene on the video.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks at her with distaste. His expression changes to one of resolve.</context>
      <utterance>Screwing around's illegal, too. But just give me half a chance...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She dons a white medical smock that covers her jogging suit, then slings on heavy, lead-lined protective vest.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Doctor Sophie Lull. Sorry I'm late.  I'll be right with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This really going to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lull's assistant, the TECHNICIAN in b.g., who had been steadily working on the instrumentation, now looks over at Lull.</context>
      <utterance>It the Pope Martian?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode>TECHNICIAN</mode>
      <context>Now, Lull extends a long rubber tube, a hypodermic needle attached to it. Quail eyes it warily. She swabs the back of his hand in preparation, notices his apprehension.</context>
      <utterance>Okay -- that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She injects the needle into his hand as she speaks, tapes it down.</context>
      <utterance>Now, just relax, kid. This ain't gonna hurt. Just a controlled drip of Narkadine. When you're under, I'll just ask ya a few questions, nothin' real personal, just full details of yer private life so's we can tailor the wish-fulfillment program to your needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail, embarrassed, starting to go under, nods.</context>
      <utterance>See? Painless. I didn't feel a thing. Hey, you're a nice kid... you like a little somethin' extra?</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good! Kid -- have I got a girl for you! She's gonna like you. You're good-lookin'.  Gettin' sleepy?  Good. Now, what's the first thing you think of when you're thinkin' about Mars?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'd like to see the Martian Sphinx...</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- you will, Dougle! I want ya to start counting backwards from a hundred for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One hundred... ninety-nine... ninety-eight... ninety-seven... ninety-six... ninety-five.... His voice drops off; his eyes close. Lull studies him, adjusts some instruments, then turns to Ernie, glancing briefly at a typed sheet in front of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Ernie, the trip to Mars; number sixty-two... and throw in that blonde... We'll give him a real good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes two discs and inserts the first one into a machine.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty-two... and... the blonde...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie inserts the second disk.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, is this one wild. He won't want to come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can ya hear me?</context>
      <utterance>Dougie? This Sophie Lull.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Sophie....</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good! ... I'm gonna ask ya a few more questions now. Ya think you'll be able to answer 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yes....</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McClane has several file drawers open and is removing diverse objects and placing them on his desk. These items apparently are objects Rekall, Inc. intends to "plant" for some client of theirs to find (perhaps even Quail) -- as part of his fantasy. While he is putting these things on his desk, the PHONE BUZZES. He answers it. McCLANE Yes?</context>
      <utterance>Attaboy! To begin with, I wanna ask ya; -- You sex life. How many orgasms a week? 11 INT. McCLANE'S OFFICE - DAY</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howie? Listen, you'd better get in here. McCLANE  Not another schizoid embolism.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better get in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quail? Dougie, can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McClane glances sharply at Lull, then turns to Quail. Quail's eyes open and scan the room. They settle on McClane. These eyes have changed: they have become cold and steely. In fact, Quail's entire personality seems to have changed -- his face has acquired a flint- edged hardness. He is chillingly menacing.</context>
      <utterance>Tell McClane what you told us.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of you in this room are dead. McCLANE  What's he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McClane's eyes flash angrily at Lull.</context>
      <utterance>You've broken my cover. McCLANE What is this?...</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a chilly silence in the room as McClane digests this. McCLANE Forced suppression?</context>
      <utterance>The Narkadine cracked a memory cap. Mars --  He's really been there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at Quail as if he's a ticking bomb.</context>
      <utterance>With spontaneous breakthrough. McCLANE Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've compromised the Sphinx Project. You'll have to be silenced. Now they're all panicked. McCLANE Wait a minute. Quail --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Believe me.</context>
      <utterance>My name isn't Quail. McCLANE Listen... whoever you are... sir....  ...This is all an accident. We'll destroy all the records. No one will know. I swear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Rekall people stare at each other in quiet horror.</context>
      <utterance>I believe you, but that won't stop E.T.O. from killing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice trails off, his eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>Killing you... killing you... killing you....</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants a false memory implanted -- of a trip he really took.  Someone at Earth Intelligence Operations erased his memory. All he know was going to Mars meant something special to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do? Graft a false memory pattern over the real memory of the same thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh... That could promote a partial breakthrough of the real trip. McCLANE  Revive him without any false memory implantation and get him out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. The others stare after him, looking very grim.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just wipe out the memory of his visit here? McCLANE  Yes. Good. I'll destroy his file and cancel his fee. I have a feeling that the longer he doesn't know who he is, where he's been, where he's going and who we are, the better off we'll all be. I'm taking a holiday. A real one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Although the driver's voice is a little mechanical (flat in tone) he is filmed from Quail's POV, and it isn't obvious he is anything other than an ordinary cab driver.</context>
      <utterance>Travelling south along Third Avenue, passing Fourty-third street.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-three thirteen "G" Street, Sector "L", Twin Towers, Apartment six-thirty- five.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera now cuts to a shot in front of the driver. He is a fairly human-like robot.</context>
      <utterance>How did I get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don not understand the question, sir or madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I get into this cab?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stepped into it in the normal manner, sir or madam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a modern, lethal gun from his pocket. Quail turns, but the other man is behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the man from Mars?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks toward the doorman, who is paying little attention to the events. As the two men edge Quail towards the door, he call out...</context>
      <utterance>Don't give us a reason to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the doorman turns calmly away.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Zimmer...Mr. Zimmer... help me... they're...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you taking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told everyone at Rekall about you trip to Mars. Where you went, who you worked for, what you did --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I didn't... Are you telling me... I did go to Mars? I don't remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've remembered too much. The Sphinx Project, for a start....</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sphinx?... No, no, I don't, I... What about the people at Rekall? I don't recall Rekall but you said if they know what I did? Why don't you ask them? They'll tell you I didn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've been taken care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither man bothers answering. They arrive at their car and open the door for Quail. He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps Quail hard across the face. Quail is terrified. He is tearful with fear.</context>
      <utterance>Get in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cringes. His hands across his face.</context>
      <utterance>My God! No! You're going to kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's going to kill you if [you do what you're told.] We're visiting E.I.O. for some new tests. Now get in, or do we start playing rough?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to force him into the car physically. Suddenly, Quail stops cringing. the FEAR DISAPPEARS FROM HIS FACE, and is replaced by an odd, thoughtful expression.</context>
      <utterance>No! It's not my fault! You can't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, I remember --</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Quail? What do you remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Mars... they tried to kill me... And....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirsten gets up and turns off the movie.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know I've been to Mars?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What! This stupid obsess...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've been. I vaguely recall...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doug, you've got to forget...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget? Remembering is the problem I must've been to one of those artificial memory places...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But something went wrong... something about a real memory... and then those men... tried to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to mix a drink from a well-stocked cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>What men? Doug, you're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're here now. They didn't kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirsten stops pouring her drink and look at him sharply.</context>
      <utterance>No. That's what's so amazing. I killed them. I think...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail points down with his finger.</context>
      <utterance>Where? Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sips her drink.</context>
      <utterance>Doug! It's something they put into your mind at the memory place. Fantasies. That's their business.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a computer operator. You're a bore. You're a wimp. You're not a killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks around the apartment drawing curtains and putting out the lights.</context>
      <utterance>I'm involved somehow with E.I.O. It's true. It's no fantasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doug, I want you to see a doctor. Now Alec and Shirley Turnbull have a good man. He helped Alec through his breakdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirsten is taken aback at his use of language. He strides into the bathroom and slams the door. She turns on one lamp, goes to a telephone and dials.</context>
      <utterance>For fuck's sake, this is no breakdown!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God! Did you say I need a psychiatrist?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen you move that fast since I've known you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you do it? After eight years!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your wife, Quail.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not my wife! You are out of your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is totally disoriented.</context>
      <utterance>It's a false memory implant. I never saw you before six weeks ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you lying like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks, she walks to a picture on the wall and from behind it pulls out a small wallet. She flips it open to show him her E.I.O. badge. He looks down uncomprehendingly at the holographic lettering "Earth Intelligence Organisation".</context>
      <utterance>No, Quail. It's true. You work for E.I.O. So do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why all of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had to watchdog you...make sure the erasure took. A wife seemed like a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I remember it! All of it!... Us!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All implanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>eight years.</context>
      <utterance>Our friends... my work...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down, holds his hand to his head.</context>
      <utterance>The job's real -- you've had is six weeks -- since you got back from Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything you know.</context>
      <utterance>It's all a fabrication, Quail.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy! If all my memories are false, who am I? What am I? Jesus... it's like I don't exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause as Quail mentally gropes frantically, for what to do next.</context>
      <utterance>You exist, all right.  That's the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why does E.I.O. want me dead?</context>
      <utterance>Why did you try to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't particularly. That was my idea. This assignment was boring me to death. The personality they gave you wasn't too thrilling.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what did I do on Mars that they have to keep me from telling?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no idea. I just work here.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't try and follow me --</context>
      <utterance>All right... I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks at her as if seeing her for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to follow you. You can't get away from E.I.O. Nobody does.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Kirsten smiles secretively. She goes to a drawer, opens it and removes a tiny instrument that looks like a TV channel-changer. There is a very small light on the instrument, which begins flashing on and off, as the instrument begins to make BEEPING SOUNDS.</context>
      <utterance>No wonder you got the role as my bitchy wife -- type casting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FIRST GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second gunman adjusts a small plug - a radio receiver - in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode>EARPLUG WEARER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't be able to track him again until he comes up above ground!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBOT DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bullets rip into the robot driver's neck, severing the head from the body. The head hits the window then bounces back onto the front seat. It continues talking.</context>
      <utterance>[Please....]</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...leave the cab as bullets are hitting the vehicle in considerable quantities.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help you, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A room for the night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DESK CLERK looks up at him, with interest. His hand hovers over the money.</context>
      <utterance>Here's ten thousand. Forget the ID.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a liaison with a lady... and I'm married...</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks at him with distaste but is only anxious to be given the key to his room. He says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>I understand, sir. Nothing like a bit on the side, eh? Bit of fugitive flesh. The greatest aphrodisiac is a new body, wouldn't you say, sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't want to be disturbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is stunned. He says nothing, but doesn't hang up.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to live, don't hand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got you bugged... They're gonna find you. Faster than you can say "Back Rodgers".  And don't bother shaking down your clothes -- the monitor is embedded in your skull.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? What the hell is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail puts the phone down and rushes to the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>There's a real old saying - "Beggars can't be choosers". Go and soak your head!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARPHONE WEARER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut the language, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARPHONE WEARER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unscientifically, he prod the screen.</context>
      <utterance>It's gone! Some...malfunction...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toldya the Martian assembled [stuff don't work.]</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head over to Skid Row -- to the Lucky Stub Pawnshop -- corner of Park Avenue and Fifty-eighth. Tell the man you're Mr. Hotchkiss; you came for your Grecian candlesticks.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I want with Grecian candlesticks!</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just do it! This is no time for small talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know where to find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been tailing you since you get back from Mars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're E.I.O. You're on the other team.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm E.I.O. But I was your best friend. Scott Stevens - we arranged this...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't remember - only bits...</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was your fail-safe -- if and when the shooting started. Good luck. Look me up if you remember me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1ST MAN</speaker>
      <mode>RED-HEADED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look at that. He's really got his hands full.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still urinating, the frustrated Scott Stevens can only look back over his shoulder. Laughing, both men open fire, riddling him with bullets. He collapses in an undignified heap, his head in the water at the base of the trough.</context>
      <utterance>Not so full, so I've heard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EARPHONE WEARER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick. The guy who checked in fifteen minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Most of the armed men instantly head off up the stairs, their weapons at the ready. Clerk watches, astonished.</context>
      <utterance>Room...thirty-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was only meeting a lady... Aren't you guys overdoing it a bit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAWNBROKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>you want...</context>
      <utterance>You wanta camera? I got some good, top-quality ones. You want silk rugs? Handmade last century in Iran...all perfect. You want videos? Old movies... classics...all those Vietnam war ones...real quaint stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look around as someone enters.</context>
      <utterance>I wonder if you could tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAWNBROKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust these will look well in you... mosque.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail smiles, presses the red button again. There is a HUMMING SOUND -- and the man FADES INTO THIN AIR -- like a television set being turned off. Quail looks bemused. Now he unrolls the leather pouch and looks inside. There he finds what look like SURGICAL INSTRUMENTS; a sponge, a long piece of wire doubled over, with some attachments and a tiny METAL HEAD on one end, and some tubes of salve. He turns on the cassette recorder. The VOICE he hears on the cassette TAPE is HIS OWN!</context>
      <utterance>What the hell...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSETTE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Hauser, this is Hauser -- or whatever you think your name is now. If you're listening to this, I'm talking to myself. Your memory's been erased and you've got a wet towel around your head.  "The first thing you've got to do is get rid of that bug in your head."</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSETTE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Quail makes a face.</context>
      <utterance>The monitoring device is located in your left maxillary sinus cavity. Make a small incision in your neck just below the left ear, and insert the wire up into the sinus. The head is self-guiding. Just shove.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSETTE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Holding the wet towel against his neck, Quail slowly withdraws the wire. On the end of it is a tiny, metal bead, the Transmitter.</context>
      <utterance>You won't feel a thing. The spray cartridge contains a local anesthetic and a blood coagulant. Careful, it's my neck, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARPLUG WEARER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's come on again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The 1st man quickly check the map-grid in the dashboard. A small bright 'x' is flashing.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARPLUG WEARER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in that old flophouse. Plaza Hotel. Central Park South.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're running every one of his memory tapes for the past fifteen years. Nothing yet, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red-haired E.I.O. man joins them.</context>
      <utterance>There must be something -- some place he would go, some friend he would run to.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED-HEADED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They lost him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red-headed man nods.</context>
      <utterance>Again?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure the original suppression took?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely, sir. He thinks he's Quail, a computer...</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how do you explain what he's doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just his instincts. He was well trained by E.I.O.... Maybe the memory cap's fractured. Portions of his prior identity could be leaking through.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll remember Mars? The Sphinx Project?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fragments. Nothing more. Nothing he could piece together. I did advise terminating him, rather than implanting an identify alternative.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the video screen again. An image has flashed onto it of an attractive Eurasian girl.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think I am? A barbarian? We're not living in the twentieth century!</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies the picture, which changes to show the same girl from different angles.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PLAINCLOTHES MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he had to travel to Mars with that bunch, I'd be sorry for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAINCLOTHES MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We couldn't have missed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAINCLOTHES MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. Let's get a coffee before the next shuttle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The liner drops toward the surface of Mars. Below: a NETWORK OF INTERSECTING LINES crisscross the planet.</context>
      <utterance>Those long gorges you see, clearly are the legendary canals of Mars....</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, they are not manmade canals, but vast natural chasms ...many deeper and larger than the Grand Canyon. Though utterly without moisture now, scientists have determined that they were formed by massive flooding millions of years ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no Garden of Eden.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR ORGANISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The canyons, the old Sphinx...</context>
      <utterance>No. Quite a bit to see, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR ORANISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much, really. Millions of years old. Bit like the one that used to be in Egypt, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Got destroyed in the Arab wars... What about this independence movement?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR ORGANISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not worth worrying about. Mostly descendants of the original colonists from Earth. Now they want self-rule so they can sell us all the minerals... I don't think we've met. You with our group? Takes me a while to know everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Douglas Quail.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR ORGANISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Richard Toltz.  Well, Doug, I hope we'll see a lot more of each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how it is, sir. Some of these red-asses are a bit prejudiced.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prejudiced? Against what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The street song has swelled, adult MINERS and CITIZENS joining the belligerent chorus.</context>
      <utterance>Earthmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they singing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail tips the doorman, enter the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>The Martian National Anthem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CANNED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...the Martian Sphinx... only evidence of non-human civilization ever discovered ...age estimated at over eighteen million years...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - SHOESHINE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He stares at Quail.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quail approaches the Registration Desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is startled to be recognized -- particularly by this name. He tries to stay casual.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to have you back with us, Mr. Hauser.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to be back.  I'm flattered you remember me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Part of my job, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember my first name, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles. Charles Hauser, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you arrange it for me?</context>
      <utterance>I'm impressed.  Listen. I need transportation to the... uh... the Sphinx.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clerk taps a few keys on a computer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. But Earth government has sealed off the excavation site completely. No one but survey teams and archaeologists are allowed closer than twenty miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...  Do you want the item you left with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clerk turns to the safe, retrieves an envelope. He hands it -- and an ELECTRONIC ROOM KEY -- to Quail.</context>
      <utterance>What item? Oh... yes, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CALYPSO GUY</speaker>
      <mode>BENNIE</mode>
      <context>Quail hesitates, unsure of the protocol.</context>
      <utterance>Need a cab, boss mon?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine's right around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one's closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I out-hustle him, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO CABBIES exchange curses as Quail, wary, follows the Calypso Guy around a corner, climbs into the small solar car.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>MINER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...if that intergalactic little Napoleon thinks I'm sellin' and clearin' outta here, he can think again!</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...watcha gonna do when he cuts off the air, Luke?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie and Quail pass another group.</context>
      <utterance>...you'll be breathin' red dust and shittin' bricks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>she hates flyin'...</context>
      <utterance>...my wife ain't goin' on one of those space shuttles...</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...aw, come on... flyin's safer'n crossin' the road...</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #6</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yeah, there ain't been a real disaster since that collision off Phobos, nigh on twenty years ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...well, that killed twelve thousand...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tombstone?</context>
      <utterance>What is this, Bennie...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail attracts the attention of the BARTENDER.</context>
      <utterance>Sorta. Bunch of miners out here got their own claims, from way back. Cohaagen's buyin' em all up, says he's gonna cut off the air an' water if they won't sell...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Melina Noel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His nod indicates an area behind Quail. He turns to see an attractive waitress placing drinks on tables. She doesn't notice Quail. He walks toward her through the crowd. Bennie watches, then tactfully slips away. MELINA turns to return to the bar and runs straight into Quail. She stops, obviously astonished to see him.</context>
      <utterance>You've found her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost in tears, she pushes her way through the crowd to a billiard room, which is separated from the main bar by swinging doors. There are no occupants and it is almost in darkness. Quail, bewildered, follows her. Inside the billiard room he turns on the lights which illuminates the area of the table. (NOTE: As Quail and Melina speak, the activity in the outside bar can be seen above the swinging doors.) Melina is still fighting back tears. Quail stops in front of her, unsure about what to do. He has no recollection of how well he might have known this woman. Suddenly, she slaps him hard across the face.</context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rubs his painful cheek.</context>
      <utterance>You bastard...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is speechless.</context>
      <utterance>That's new -- the innocent look.  You didn't have that one before.  Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks relieved (but tries to cover).</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll say it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You discharged your obligation.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I got the note.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What note?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the wife needs me..."</context>
      <utterance>Oh, the usual one. "Must return immediately to Earth...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a wife. Well, I do - but not a real wife.  Hell... look... someone else sent that note. Someone who --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you here for?!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melina bursts into tears. Quail rather tentatively puts his arms around her. She welcomes this at first, but then pushes him away.</context>
      <utterance>For you! I don't even know why --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever I was, I must have been a helluva guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Whoever you were"???</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. I've for to tell you something. I beg you to believe me... help me -- All Melina's suspicions come rushing back.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something happened to my mind. Memory suppression, false implant, I don't know what -- Melina backs off. Quail grows more desperate.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm saying is... I don't remember you. I don't remember us. I don't remember me -- Melina's expression grows dead hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>[And I thought...]</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Memory erasure is what they use on agents. Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a step toward her, nearly frantic.</context>
      <utterance>Wait... I was an agent -- I'm not now -- just tell me who I am! How did we know each other? Why are they trying to kill me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not trusting you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You loved me once, you must have --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you was a liar. Who you are now I don't even know.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Melina --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need your help --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail gives up; goes through the doors and leaves. Melina slumps her shoulder against the table and cries.</context>
      <utterance>Get out! Get the hell away from me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a tough planet, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie bright tone isn't improving Quail's mood.</context>
      <utterance>Some guy really screwed her - screwed her up real good. Some Earthman. Just hopped on a space shuttle.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Bennie. You're pretty well informed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that means I know it all, you're right, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about the Sphinx?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothin'. Not about the Sphinx. That's out of the ball park.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to get there. Can't you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the Sphinx... that's</context>
      <utterance>No can do, mon. You want women, cigarettes, red-market money, booze, even air or water... Bennie's your man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... look at that one, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big cheese in town. Big smelly cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cohaagen? But isn't he often here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail keeps his face in shadow and watches Cohaagen with curiosity as he passes. Cohaagen is lit up briefly by a street lamp. His face makes an impression on Quail, who perhaps faintly remembers him in the past.</context>
      <utterance>No way. That cat just cheat the Martian workers without ever leavin' his place in Beverly Hills. Somethin' must be cookin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hauser...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quail ditches the recorder and the "emergency case" into the drawer -- everything except the PISTOL. Quail approaches the door very cautiously (from the side -- out of the line of fire).</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hauser, I want to talk to you... about Douglas Quail.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>I work for Rekall, Incorporated.</context>
      <utterance>My name is George Edgemar.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rekall??</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quail opens it carefully, his gun at the ready, but out of view of the person at the door. A dignified-looking GENTLEMAN stands there, calm and pleasant, wearing an Earth-style business suit.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's difficult to explain... Could you open the door, please? I'm not armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't see the gun, but somehow knows.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Quail. May I come in? I won't be offended if you prefer to keep the gun you're holding trained on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail does keep his gun trained on the man. The man enters, holding in his outstretched hand -- a business card.</context>
      <utterance>All right... come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail frisks him, then takes the card, glances at it.</context>
      <utterance>My card, Mr. Quail.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- so you're Doctor George Edgemar of 'Rekall, Inc.' So?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I said... this is going to be very difficult -- for both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Quail... I'm afraid you're not really standing here at this moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sat that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause.</context>
      <utterance>I said, you're not really here. Neither am I. We're both in the Memory Studio -- in the offices of Rekall, Inc. On Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That I never really left Earth?</context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to tell me that this is all part of some... artificially injected fantasy?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not quite. We didn't give you this. You're creating it yourself --  Remember the option we offered you? Intelligence agent? Something inside you liked that idea, fastened on it. What you're experiencing now is a free-form delusion that you yourself are fabricating.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this shit you're giving me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not -- shit, Mr. Quail. It's the truth.  I know it's very hard for you to accept, but you're having a schizophrenic reaction... we can't snap you out of the Narkadine. You're in a world of your own fantasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how the hell can you be in my dream -- if you know it's just a dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been artificially implanted -- like the first part of your fantasy. I'm actually monitoring your dream at a psychoprobe console. This is a last resort. When somebody gets stuck in their own fantasy, we send in someone after them. A specialist, like myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe a word you're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door starts to open. Quail pivots and points his gun at the opening door. MELINA walks in, carrying a CLIPBOARD. She looks at Quail with professional detachment.</context>
      <utterance>I was afraid you'd think that. I'm sorry to have to do this, but you really are stuck.  Doctor Noel, would you come in now please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail is staggered.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Quail, I'm afraid it's all true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to break through to you earlier, but you just molded me into your fantasy. Sometimes it takes Dr. Edgemar to get through to a client as tough as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's supposed to happen now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just do exactly as we tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow that doesn't appeal to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Mr. Quail... try to cooperate. You're having a schizophrenic embolism.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your wife calls every day --</context>
      <utterance>If we can't get you out now... you may never come out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even more suspicious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this is a fantasy, there'll be no real consequences when I pull this trigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there will by consequences inside your mind. Consequences that won't hurt me... but could be fatal to you.  If you shoot me, you'll wipe me out of your fantasy -- I can't come back again. Because to you, I'll be dead. I can't help you get back to reality. You'll be stuck in permanent psychosis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE - EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showing no fear of tension whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGEMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to lower the gun, Mr. Quail. You're going to hand it to me --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail spins toward the door just as it BURSTS OPEN. A man enters, firing, but Quail has fallen to the floor and returns the fire. He staggers back out into the corridor and slams against the wall, dead.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out, Charles! There's more of them in the hall!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Melina is still crouched by Edgemar's body, holding his HAND for some reason. Her CLIPBOARD dangles by her side.</context>
      <utterance>You've had it, Hauser! Throw out your weapon if you want a past!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Squeezing Edgemar's hand shut with one of hers, she holds up her other wrist -- to show that the CLIPBOARD IS BOUND</context>
      <utterance>There's an explosive in the clipboard! He has a dead-man switch in his hand!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quail (Hauser) SHOOTS OFF the chain.</context>
      <utterance>What do you say, Hauser? We haven't got all night! Hauser?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail takes the CLIPBOARD from Melina and eases himself to the side of the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>What happens it I come out?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll put in a word with the big boys. Maybe you'll just get exile to Venus.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail reaches around the corner and SAILS THE CLIPBOARD into the hallway. Melina lets go of Edgemar's hand -- There is a TREMENDOUS EXPLOSION in the hallway,</context>
      <utterance>All right. Here comes the weapon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back in, quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't you prefer your order in your room, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail bundles the waiter unceremoniously back inside the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>In!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Answers! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They kidnapped me. Said they'd kill you if I didn't cooperate. I told them I didn't care, but then when I realized they meant it...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why they're after me, but what's your connection with all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were together before.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator has reached the basement. They rush out.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, I'm really sorry I can't recall the details of that encounter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad news, boss lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black cruiser just pull out behind us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the shooter, boss. I lose 'em for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lose them? In this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie reaches down, grasps a KNOB. He yanks it, like someone starting an outboard motor -- and an ear-splitting LOUD ENGINE roars to life. Bennie opens the throttle and the solar car HURTLES DOWN THE STREET. Quail and Melina are thrown back in the seat.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>shouts over</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNFIRE)</speaker>
      <mode> GUNFIRE)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get a ticket for that engine, Bennie --</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yutani 650 -- you like it, boss? Nothing like the old gas when you want a bit of speed. BULLETS from the cruiser rip through the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better have two aces, Bennie.  There's a second cruiser -- and it's gaining --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cohaagen turns to an associate, EMILE, a youngish, well-dressed executive type.</context>
      <utterance>I take it, then, you've failed to get him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proceed with Operation Sphinx.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With him...  ...on the lose, I'm not taking any more chances. Operation Sphinx will flush him out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have now climbed out of the car. Quail looks searchingly at Melina and Bennie.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin', boss. Just old smokies. Only place they can come for a puff. It's all banned topside.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you two are into something a bit more serious than the taxi and truck-stop business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unzips his jacket to reveal a T-shirt with "MARTIAN LIBERATION FRONT" (and an appropriate symbol) emblazoned on it.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God!... T-shirts. They died out on Earth years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe we ain't fashion leaders, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk as they talk - into a room off the main tunnel. It is adorned with "FREE MARS" and "MARTIAN LIBERATION FRONT" posters. A group of people are printing T-shirts and leaflets. They exchange greetings with Melina and Bennie.</context>
      <utterance>No. But we still believe in a free Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where did I fit into all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You - when you were Charles Hauser with E.I.O - infiltrated our group. I guess Cohaagen didn't trust you any more when you and</utterance>
   <speaker>I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her gesture suggests their liaison.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And I can't even remember it. We'll have to arrange a return bout.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so he had your memory wiped and fixed you up with a new identity.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But - the Sphinx. Why is that stuck in my mind? Why's it so important?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just an ole heap o' stone, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slumps into a chair with frustration.</context>
      <utterance>It's more than that, Bennie, I know it's more. Somehow it's connected.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe there's a way you can get your memory back.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? What? Where? When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bit of Martian Wisdom. We're not all stupid colonists.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VOICE FROM LOUDSPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...all residents are to report to their nearest space-travel agent within twelve hours, all residents will be departing on shuttles within twenty-four hours. Air and water supplies will be cut off at that time. I repeat...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's doing it!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The searchlight approaches Bennie, Quail and Melina. Bennie ducks into a doorway, while Quail grabs Melina and kisses her passionately. The light sees only the back of his head. She responds warmly to his kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Clearing everyone out! It's been rumored for months...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. I can see why I was willing to betray E.I.O.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I though you believed in our cause?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Of course. That, too. They move into the crowd. The message on the loudspeaker is repeated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Kuato speaks, Quail, unimpressed, talks, sotto voce, to Melina.</context>
      <utterance>Your servant, Fahreem Kuato. I greet you by the twenty-seven names that still remain, praying that you cast jewels into the darkness and given them to glow with the colors of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What use is this weirdo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssssh...there are skills on mars that Earth has forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the street the sound of loudspeakers giving information about Quail and Co. can be heard. Searchlight beams occasionally sweep past the windows.</context>
      <utterance>No need to introduce yourself, Mr. Quail.  Tolerate my presumption, but it does not tax my powers to know that you are the most sought-after man on two worlds.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This way, my dear man. We have much to accomplish --  -- and very little time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kuato takes a seat on the pillows, invites the others to join him. Quail hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>The turbulence you hear outside is but a reflection of the turmoil within you. You have brought it to Mars in your search for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're going to help me by reading my mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indubitably. There is only small matter of a fee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fee!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is for our cause!</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Income before ideals. Shall we say five-hundred-thousand dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five-hundred-thousand Martian dollars, that's...</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail - Earth dollars.</context>
      <utterance>Not Martian dollars, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's interplanetary robbery!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With today's exchange rate... that's over two million Martian dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What price do you put, Mr. Quail, on the future of the solar system?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, come off it, man. Just for a bit of mumbo-jumbo with a crystal ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jerks his thumb toward Quail.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, buster, we're talking heavy stuff here. You try and work out what's with this guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kuato smiles. He extinguishes all the lights save one small blue one, which illuminates the room eerily, like a seance.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! Okay! I'll pay it, but the Interstellar Trade Practices Commission might be interested in this. Everyone calms down.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his eyes and concentrates.</context>
      <utterance>Retrieving the past is like walking backwards along a perilous road. The half-recalled, the half-forgotten, the repressed, the fantasies, the triumphs, joys, failures, betrayals...</utterance>
   <speaker>KUATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kauto turns around and sits down with back toward Quail. He reaches up and lowers his cowl, REVEALING:</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I can feel it... a wall. Erasure techniques are so brutal.  Blocks. Side channels. Future and past all jumbled. I shall have to enter deep trance to break through.  I will be scanning you through the Oracle Head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORACLE HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CONTINUE ZOOM UNTIL ENTIRE FRAME is filled by QUAIL'S EYE.</context>
      <utterance>Open you thoughts to my presence...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail stares at her, as if an entire bank of lost memories were suddenly clicking back into place --</context>
      <utterance>Charles! Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He kept dragging you deeper and deeper into the trance! We couldn't wake either of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail gives Bennie that same eerie look, then turns to Kuato, who is sprawled motionless across the pillows, a curl of smoke rising from two entry wounds in his spine.</context>
      <utterance>You stopped breathing!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you kill him? It was the next bit I really...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail lunges across the pillows to Kuato's unbreathing form. Quail shakes the ancient mystic, trying to find a last flicker of life. Kuato's body is dead white. Quail releases his grip; he about to give up when -- A MUFFLED CHOCKED SOUND comes from behind Kuato's neck. It's the Oracle Head! Quail instantly rolls Kuato's body over. The Head is still alive! Quail bends closer, kneeling.</context>
      <utterance>No choice, boss. It was him or you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- the vengence you seek... and the salvation of Mars... are waiting for you in the crown of the Sphinx.  The Oracle Head lets out a LONG SIGH and goes limp, a small trickle of blood oozing from the corner of its mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail ignores him, still kneeling -- deep in thought -- over the Oracle Head.</context>
      <utterance>Phobos and Demos! What was that all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail reaches out and closes the Oracle Head's tiny eyelids. Melina and Bennie exchange a glance. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?... Charles? Doug? Whoever?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Bennie</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine... only I'm not Doug -- I'm Charles Hauser... and I know everything Hauser knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bennie, where's your depot?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>water bureau you...</context>
      <utterance>Well... you go outta here... take a left, then down past the first... no second...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get us there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides off. The others follow, still full of questions.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to the Sphinx.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible, man. Guards everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Oracle... what did you learn?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are now heading down the stairs toward the street.</context>
      <utterance>Only everything. I've got total recall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail ignores him as he continues to mumble to himself. He rapidly but carefully inspects each vehicle as they pass. Camera tracks rapidly with them.</context>
      <utterance>We'll never get near the Sphinx! They'll blow us apart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For God's sake, tell us.</context>
      <utterance>What are we doing, Charles?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in front of a large, odd-shaped vehicle with a large scoop or propeller on the front.</context>
      <utterance>The Sphinx... it's not some useless artifact, it's a machine built by some alien race eighteen millions years ago. The same race that built the on one Earth... for the same purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to climb in; the others follow.</context>
      <utterance>This is what we need.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a hunk of old stone, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie starts the engine.</context>
      <utterance>Purpose? What purpose?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melina shakes her head. The vehicle moves off.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Bennie, move it.  Have you heard the word, "terriform"?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once through the second door of the air lock (i.e. to the area outside the city), Quail and Melina emerge and sit up on the rear seats.</context>
      <utterance>Just deliverin' some old junk to the mine out at Apidalia Planitia. Got them people you're lookin' for in the back as well. The Guards laugh and signal him on.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The machine in the Sphinx is tapped straight down to the molten core of this planet. There are tunnels and ducts everywhere, all powered by fusion generators...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure the little man didn't fry your brain, Quail?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what? To do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To combine elements in the Martian core and release them as oxygen, hydrogen and nitrogen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's air!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Air and water. Terriforming will create a permanent livable environment for Mars. No more pressurized cities, no more containers in the desert. There'll be rivers, vegetation - life - the same as Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why is Cohaagen shipping everyone out?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you see?! From being a pile of red dirt with minerals, Mars is going to change into a chunk of priceless real estate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Cohaagen's going to own it all!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right! He can start selling it off to well-heeled investors from Earth. Beach condos, ski resorts, you name it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>penetrate... out group.</context>
      <utterance>No wonder he wanted you to...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once word of this gets out, the whole planet will support you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what can we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melina is amazed.</context>
      <utterance>Ruin his little scheme by terriforming ahead of schedule - while the inhabitants are still here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you know how?</context>
      <utterance>But who'll work the machine?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the only one who does. Why do you think Cohaagen's left me alone all this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the first one inside when they cracked the riddle of the Sphinx. It must've been programmed. Some kind of...force...shot into me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Cohaagen wiped your memory!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a way of putting me on ice. He'd of reversed it once the planet was evacuated.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Go over it again, real slow.</context>
      <utterance>Man! This is real complicated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to see Bennie is covering him and Melina with a pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Bennie, don't stop now, take it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said. It's a tough planet. I'm a baddie, not a goodie.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have known, you were just too helpful.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>EIO Rule One, man. Trust Nobody. Now you can do your terriforming stuff right when those space shuttles are gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the Martian people? Out cause? I thought you believed in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that instant, Melina lunges, PUNCHES A RED EMERGENCY BUTTON. The VENT beside Bennie's hand BLOWS OPEN, [causing] a powerful suction caused by Mars's vacuum atmosphere. Bennie's gun hand is PLANTED AGAINST THE VENT [OPENING.] Simultaneously, the air in the vehicle starts rushing out! All three parties begin choking. As Bennie's mechanical hand claws for the lever that seals the vent, Quail has a moment to jump him. He pounds Bennie's gun hand, the</context>
      <utterance>Your cause? That bunch of dead beat radicals! When I hand in this little number...  ...I'll get real estate rights on the whole of Chryse Planitia...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The air supply is off under the domes?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. In a couple of hours it'll be all gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any trouble with the rabble?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On some of the video screens a number of space shuttles can be seen, ready for departure to Earth.</context>
      <utterance>Not much, sir. A lot of complaining. But they're all heading towards the shuttle areas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got in with this thing, but we'll never get back out.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a lighted area at the end of the tunnel. Quail and Melina hurry toward it, moving silently, close to the wall.</context>
      <utterance>A shame. Such a pleasant trip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the main tap -- straight down to the core of Mars. When we trigger the mechanism, fusion reactors will detonate down there -- four hundred miles deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remind me not to slip.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's right at home -- and full of confidence. Quail climbs onto the ladder, which links various top levels. He starts to climb. Melina follows him. They are tiny figures. The space around them plummets down to infinity.</context>
      <utterance>The new elements will come booming up through this shaft -- and six thousand others all around the planet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GUARD LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seven of the Guards move off, two remain in position. We HEAR the FOOTSTEPS of the seven guards recede. The two remaining guards realize their isolation; they glance tensely to one another.</context>
      <utterance>Stay in contact. I want to hear from this checkpoint every four minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear something?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The First Guard points to the edge of the main shaft -- right where Quail and Melina are hiding. The Guards cock their weapons, start cautiously forward. Just as they're about to peer over the brink, guns at the ready:</context>
      <utterance>Over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The guards spin around, weapons poised. Standing in the shadows, near the corridor, is Quail! (Still with no gun) Both guards walk quickly toward Quail, covering him with their weapons.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not there, boys. I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're all full of tricks.</context>
      <utterance>Watch him. He was EIO trained.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail has his arms raised high. Just as the Guards reach him, he fizzes electronically, emitting a humming sound, then disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Like...who was that guy? -- Fred Bond??  Keep 'em up, Fred, keep 'em up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before either Guard can react, the real Quail appears -- one foot behind them. With two LIGHTNING BLOWS, he dispatches the Guards. (Apparently Quail has climbed out of the shaft while the Guards were distracted.) Quail snatches both Guards' weapons, grenades and ammo belts. Melina climbs out of the shaft. Quail tosses her one of the Guard's guns.</context>
      <utterance>A hologram!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get that little trick?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mail-order company. It's a great one for fooling the wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell did they get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the fusion core.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exhibits begrudging admiration for Quail.</context>
      <utterance>Up the fusion core??</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wall sign behind Cohaagen reads: "LEVEL THIRTEEN".</context>
      <utterance>They're on Level One.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A button is pressed and huge doors slide across in front of the formidable doors already closing the Control Room off from the outside corridors.</context>
      <utterance>Seal all upper levels.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls something toward the armed men in the elevator. Instinctively one of them reaches for the thrown object. It is an explosive device of some sort. Quail and Melina press themselves against the wall just around a corner from the elevator. There is a tremendous explosion. Quail, followed by Melina, rounds a corner. The elevator is in ruins; bodies are scattered everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Catch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points toward the upper levels.</context>
      <utterance>Great stuff, but how do we get up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EMILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Quail's the only one who can operate all this...  ...then he can call all the shots.</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll tell him the computer's worked out the operational details so we don't really need him. We're just doing him a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if that doesn't work?</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We offer him rewards.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if that doesn't work?</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll torture him. You don't think I got this far by being a nice guy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An aide dives for an EMERGENCY SWITCH. But now -- Quail and Melina, wearing breather masks, bursts in onto an overhead catwalk. They OPEN FIRE on the Guards, who are choking, struggling with their masks. An EMERGENCY PRESSURE SEAL powers into place, sealing the breach in the eye. REPRESSURIZATION comes up, the internal atmosphere stabilizes -- None of the men inside the control room still moves. The victors tug off their masks, spring down to the main level. Melina hurries to the main control panel. Melina looks towards the video monitors showing half a dozen huge space shuttles lined up for departure.</context>
      <utterance>Seal the breach! Repressurize!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail tentatively approaches the imposingly complex machinery.</context>
      <utterance>Those shuttles are starting up any minute. If you know how to work this thing, you better do it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Transfixed, mesmerized, Quail moves closer to the control panel.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you know how?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches even closer. He begins to raise his arm towards a blank area a little above his head.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... there's a vital connection missing...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...me...</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you activate the mechanism you'll die...there were glimpses of it in your memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong, Cohaagen, there's a long tunnel, a brilliant white light, hands reaching for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail looks around him, half-convinced.</context>
      <utterance>That's your death. That's what it looks like. That's what is always looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quail hesitates. He looks from Melina to Cohaagen.</context>
      <utterance>Charles - for Mars's sake....</utterance>
   <speaker>COHAAGEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not too late. Join us again. U've a lot to offer. A whole world. Quail continues to look at him, thoughtfully.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to the machine and slowly raises his arm again. His fingers reach towards the blank section on the panel. Slowly, through the panel, a luminous hand reaches toward Quail's fingers. Gently, the fingers of the two hands touch. The entire control room begins to rumble and shudder. As Quail reaches for Melina, Cohaagen suddenly dives on him. They grapple amid the shuddering Sphinx and can be seen only intermittently as debris crashes around them. The fight ends as Cohaagen is hurled backwards and disappears when a section of floor collapses underneath him.</context>
      <utterance>You don't deserve a new world, you and people like you made too big a mess of the old one. Time someone else had a chance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BACK TO QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In terror, lost, disoriented totally.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASKED MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't lie to you, pal. You are. MINER  I'd say in about forty years...  ...come on, we've gotta get to the Space Port. That Intergalactic Napoleon's switched off the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MINER'S WIFE watches them. She is crying. Quail looks up at the sky. Melina follows his glance. So do the others. Slowly, but perceptibly, the color is changing from yellow to blue.</context>
      <utterance>Shippin' us all out. Mars is finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the miners are puzzled, apprehensive. Quail reaches toward the one who spoke to him before and pulls off his breathing apparatus. At first the man is shocked, then realizes he can breathe without it. Quail takes off his own, then Melina's All the miners watch in amazement. They all remove their breathing masks.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melina embraces him.</context>
      <utterance>That's just the start. Next there'll be rain and growth and ... life.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
