<movie id="571" title="Traffic">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. RODMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One particular justice, ROBERT WAKEFIELD, younger than the others, is clearly bemused by this performance.</context>
      <utterance>This informant, paid by the police, using taxpayers dollars to continue his felony drug habit, was the link which allowed police to raid a private farm. A working farm. A farm where honest Americans make their living.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. RODMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The government, in its haste, has employed an army of criminals whose allegiance to the truth is, at best, questionable -- Judge Wakefield interrupts --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A polite chuckle from the justices --</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Rodman...it's too bad your client didn't show as much sense in choosing what he planted as he did in choosing his attorney...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lately the only variation I'm hearing in your argument is the name of the client. And you can sit there all day arguing the ins and outs of Illinois v. Gates, but you aren't going to convince me that this country has not sanctioned the use of anonymous informants.  Furthermore, there is no sacred protection of property rights in the United Sates. When you make the decision to have marijuana on your farm, whether it's one joint or an acre of plants, your property can be seized and your property can be sold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. RODMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry the court finds my argument repetitious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Rodman, may I offer a piece of advice? The next time you argue this point before this court, regardless of my whereabouts, I recommend you have something up your sleeve other than your arm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends who it's from.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friends at Warren, Putnam and Hudson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can learn a lot about somebody from this stuff. Three categories: you like me, you hate me, you want something from me.  Definitely third category.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would a law firm want from the new drug Czar?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on the state.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arizona.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh. Robert reaches up and pulls a bottle of Scotch from a shelf. He pours a couple of fingers in two glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Medicinal marijuana initiative.  Or am I being cynical?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk takes one of the glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe there's a book in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They toast and drink.</context>
      <utterance>Not by me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>I had that dream again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue to wait until there is the sound of a JET ENGINE. It grows LOUDER as it approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Where my mother's suffocating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver hesitates a confused beat then reaches for his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>No. There's no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver pulls a wad of bills. Javi shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I see. How much do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi shakes his head. The driver exchanges a look with his partner.</context>
      <utterance>You want more than this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi smiles. The driver gets out and walks to the back of the truck. He opens the rear door. There are neatly-stacked crates marked with a SCORPION logo and "911." He reaches into one of them and pulls out a tightly-sealed package also with the scorpion stamped on it. He turns to see Javi with his gun drawn. Manolo, at the passenger side, has also drawn his gun and is motioning the partner to move to the back of the truck.</context>
      <utterance>You want something else?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver hesitates. He starts to comply then looks at Javi and Manolo.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the package. Put your hands behind your head. You're under arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. I think there must be some mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi motions to Manolo who cuffs both teenagers. The driver begins spewing OBSCENITIES under his breath. Javi puts the driver in the front of the Shadow. Manolo follows in the moving van.</context>
      <utterance>No, there's no mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Javier Rodriguez.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier stares into the implacable reflection of his sunglasses. In the distance, the DC-3 takes off and ROARS over their heads.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Javier Rodriguez, you've done a very good job, but we'll take care of it from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men follow Salazar's orders.</context>
      <utterance>We've been following these Narco- trafficantes for some time but had not been able to bring them to justice.  Put the prisoners in the car. Impound the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One question. How did you find about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An informant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the name of your informant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salazar looks at Javi a beat.</context>
      <utterance>It was an anonymous tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a State Police officer, you're very well informed. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMENTS LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Javi and Manolo watch the convoy of vehicles drive away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't that General Salazar?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start for their car.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No telltales. Nothing to read. Not touching my face. Not even blinking. No giveaways.  How're you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more pissant basin league bullshit for us, hunh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Castro stretches his arms, swings them around.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the door to the office. Gordon looks at Castro, then turns the handle.</context>
      <utterance>Limbering up, gonna stay loose, keep it all together. Take this motherfucker down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showtime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another "businessman" enters from another door and whispers in Ruiz's ear, then leaves again.</context>
      <utterance>You ever buy a quarter ton? Not many people have.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, it's worth the wait, right? What can I do? Rent a Huey? Have an airlift? It's not like you can put it in a condom up some mule's asshole, right? How many peasants would that take? A line stretching from here to Mexico City --</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of Ruiz's hands dips under the desk where we see a handgun is holstered on the underside.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody said shit, Eduardo --</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax. We're waiting, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you want to hear a joke? I got a joke. Why do women wear makeup and perfume?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill out --</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a funny fuckin' joke and it's quick. Why do women wear makeup and perfume?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Castro laughs uproariously.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause they're ugly and they stink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you never been close enough to a woman to know how she smells.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEA AGENT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his hand doing? Watch his hand. Anybody? I don't like the hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEA AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous this fucking thing.  Look at this shit -- the first television transmission. I had better shit when I was the AV guy at junior high, swear-to-God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER DEA AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watch his damn hands.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Castro, pay attention.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FBI AGENT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The unmarked cars split up and one turns into the parking lot of a fast-food restaurant. The other circles around the back of a building.</context>
      <utterance>Three unmarked vehicles.  Three unmarked vehicles accompanying.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI AGENT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's local. Local or Customs. Oh, man, I don't know. Looks like the cavalry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is our show. Ah, man. I don't want to share this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth leans over and snorts a line of coke from a mirror. He hands it to Caroline who effortlessly does one.</context>
      <utterance>Father of Greek tragedy? Anyone? Okay, Aeschylus it is.  His trilogy? The Oresteia. I mean this is beautiful, can anyone stop the Seth Machine?  Score. Thank you. Madmax from Omaha we own you. And Tragedy is closed out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth looks at her. He has a crush.</context>
      <utterance>Entertainment. The Susan Lucci section or Banal Love Songs of the Nineties?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. They both take a swig of beer. He takes her hand pulling her past the stoned people on the couch --</context>
      <utterance>Banal Love Songs it is.  Hey, you wanna try something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches the substance in the spoon as it swirls and bubbles, then separates... He pours the most viscous part onto the aluminum foil, making four separate little puddles. He quickly dismantles a ballpoint pen, making a straw. He hands it to Caroline.</context>
      <utterance>Just watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inhale the smoke and hold it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, like freebase?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lights the flame under the aluminum foil. The puddle crackles and pops, then starts to smoke --</context>
      <utterance>Not like. It is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a rush of thick grey smoke. Caroline catches most of it.</context>
      <utterance>Go... Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls it in deeper and holds... Suddenly her expression changes... Her eyes lose their focus, her face slackens, an almost sexual response. Seth is watching her intensely.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline slumps back against the counter. Seth moves against her, kissing her, running his hands over her breasts and body. She stares over his shoulder, holding it as long as she can. Finally she exhales --</context>
      <utterance>See... Now, you see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cloud of grey smoke from her lungs fills the room.</context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHIEF OF STAFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until you officially take over the office of National Drug Control Policy, under no circumstances should you speak to the press unprotected, without going through this office or having someone in the room. There are a lot of interests in this town and, right now, they're all scared of you. The reason they're scared of you...technically, you have veto power over their budgets. So think about that: FBI, CIA, DEA, CUSTOMS, TREASURY, ATF, DEFENSE, IRS, Radio Shack and the DMV, they're all gonna want to speak to you. And that's the good news... You'll also be meeting Senators and Congressman, each with a specially prepared question. Their question is designed for one thing: to make them look smart. If you lecture them, they won't think you respect them. If you respond with utter humility, they will. Remember, this is about your respect for them, and the President's respect for them. Speaking of which, as soon as he gets back from Russia and China, we'll get you in there for some face- time, let the two of you catch up.  It'd probably be a good idea for you to meet your predecessor. I'll have Jeff Sheridan take you over. Also, four weeks from today you will give your first official press conference. In it you will outline the President's strategy for winning the war on drugs.  Okay, anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be sure to let you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to be clear about one thing. I used to work for him, but now I work for you. I'm not a partisan person, I'm an issue person. In the next few weeks, if you allow me, we'll get you well-versed on an incredible array of issues. The most important of which, in my opinion, being Mexico. I know everybody that you're gonna meet. It's important that they like you. It's not important that they like me. That's why I can help protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you protected Landry?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see where you're going with that, but if I could just say something, which is basically that a guy like Landry is so autocratic he doesn't know how to let himself be helped; it's a point of pride to take every bullet, no matter who fired it, or whether it was even aimed at him, which personally I think it very self-defeating. Now, don't get me wrong, he's a man of enormous integrity, but there's a political component to this job that the General just didn't have any patience for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GENERAL LANDRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheridan nods and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Jeff, you want to excuse us for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LANDRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert and Landry shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Functionaries. Nice people, the Schedule C's. About twelve graduate degrees apiece, but it seems sometimes all they do is start rumors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Landry tries to determine whether Robert believes this. He looks around the office as if the policy is hiding somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>You've done a fine job here, Sir. The Office of National Drug Control Policy is in better shape than when you found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LANDRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I made the slightest difference.  I tried... I really did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of encouraging statistics. The work's just started, but I intend to see it through. You've got my word on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LANDRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're here for two years, three maximum. What'd they promise you? Court appointment? What? District? Appeals?  Not Supreme... Supreme?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General Landry SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>I've come in to do a tough job and that's what I'm going to focus on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LANDRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at each other a beat. Then Landry smiles.</context>
      <utterance>When Kruschev was forced out, he sat down and wrote two letters and handed them to his successor. He said "When you get into a situation you can't get out of, open the first letter and you'll be saved. And when you get into another situation you can't get out of, open the second." Soon enough this guy found himself in a tight place. So he opened the first letter. It said, "Blame everything on me." So he blamed the old guy and it worked like a charm.  He got into another situation he couldn't get out of, so he opened the second letter, which read, "Sit down and write two letters."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax. If they were going to kill us they would have done it in the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manolo tenses, and throws open the window.</context>
      <utterance>They wouldn't do it in front of all these people. They'd send someone later, when we're alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MANOLO'S POV out the window as KIDS play in the car, sitting behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Away from the car. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if that were true, they're not going to come to your house where you're waiting for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. They'll do it when you're walking somewhere, make it look like street crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna sets a cup of coffee in front of Javi and stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Shut your fucking mouth. Nobody's talking to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You should learn how to keep a secret.</context>
      <utterance>If you want her to stay out of it, then stop telling her everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's nosy. She hears me on the telephone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I don't think we'll ever see them again. Everything's back to normal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TOURIST WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a police officer. Aren't you going to take a report or something? Don't you want to know what kind of car it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Brown Ford Explorer --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was right here. It's been stolen. I want to file a report.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Filing a report will not help you find your car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The police won't find your car.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier pulls out a note pad and scribbles a number.</context>
      <utterance>But you're the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call this man, he'll find your car for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will this guy know who has our car?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a beat of confusion.</context>
      <utterance>The police will tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why will they tell him but they won't tell us?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then our car appears.</context>
      <utterance>Because we pay him, stupid.  Right? And he pays the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man reaches in his wallet and offers Javier a twenty. Javi waves him off. Javier and Manolo walk back to their squad car when two SUV's come to a stop in front of them. Javier and Manolo exchange a look. The doors SLAM and FOOTSTEPS approach.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Better than filling out forms, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Javier Rodriguez.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duck salad?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nan can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena, you never order duck salad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's true. I don't.  I think someone else is asking for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's got good taste. Isn't it the most wonderful thing you ever tasted? I mean ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's delicious --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're the most marvelous little creatures. Canard. They fly, swim, walk. And so cute with their babies marching along behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs. Helena is by far the youngest in her crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Looking for a nice sauce ala orange.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a very fatty bird. All that winter insulation. Just like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean all breast, just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're bad --</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jealous, that's all --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard... I can't remember where... That it's full of that good kind of fat, the kind you're supposed to eat --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unsaturated fat --</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO WOMEN IN UNISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Polyunsaturated.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now there's a good cholesterol and bad cholesterol. Everything they tell you completely changes every other week. I don't know why they think we should listen at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nan reaches for a taste and the other women lean forward also, a sea of inanity swirling around Helena's salad.</context>
      <utterance>What I know is ducks, as cute as they are, were designed by God to be eaten.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll put this in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the professionals keep them in the trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Tiger Woods.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the putter away from the reluctant boy and sets it on the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Especially Tiger Woods.  ...Actually, he keeps his on the back seat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to the bed and the sexy equipment --</context>
      <utterance>Gates, Myrhvold, Bezos. I sell to all those guys. Why? Because the technology to intrude has reached the masses. Your competitor, your ex-spouse, adversaries, stalkers, they're at the local electronics store right now, and they're gonna be intruding on you not only through your telephone, but your fax, cell phone, pager, cable TV, Musak, windows, walls, air conditioning ventilation, modem, and internet connection.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederico picks up a piece of equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody has these babies, no way, not the shiznit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnie lovingly picks up a laptop computer with a sleek device attached to it --</context>
      <utterance>I want to intercept cell phone calls, digital and analog. And locate the source of the call. I need databasing capability, to cross-reference calls and numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco looks at Lonnie coldly.</context>
      <utterance>Your Cellular Secretary, friend across all the digital wireless spread spectrum.  So, Francisco, what do you do? You a PI? Private security?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assassin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assassin, okay. Let's get you started in surveillance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHARMACEUTICAL LOBBYIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We in the legal drug business, and I mean Merck, Pfizer, the rest of my very powerful clients, realize this isn't a war with a traditional winner and loser, but an organism at war with itself, whose weapons of mass destruction happen to be intoxicants. And if you want a body count look no further than alcohol which racks up 80,000 kills a year. Cocaine manages a measly 2,000. Same for Heroin. But, the big daddy is Big Tobacco which kills 380,000 each year, which, by the way, is more people than have been killed by all the illegal drugs in the last century.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lobbyist smiles. Robert sips his drink.</context>
      <utterance>That's very interesting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert turns away --</context>
      <utterance>What's the difference between Prozac and Ecstacy, you ask? One's a mattress and the other's a trampoline. Molecules don't have morality. Really, think about it: some molecule changes the way a serotonin re-uptake inhibitor works, it's not suddenly a bad molecule; it's just a molecule. My theory: America has a real fear of short, intense experiences.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robert at the bar getting another scotch. A secretive man, TIM, 40's, nerdy, sidles up beside him and whispers furtively in his ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chemicals? Some say problems, others say solution. Imagine a cloud that when it rains prohibits the growth of poppies or takes the THC out of marijuana. Imagine a pill that eliminates any psychological craving, from Dilaudid to Dove Bars. Law enforcement hasn't let science sit on the sidelines. Addiction is no more relevant than polio or the Black Plague. Tim slips away into the crowd. Robert moves away from the bar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ECONOMIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not battling traffickers or dealers, but a market, and the market contains a paradox: if you arrest traffickers, you raise prices, and you also raise profits, which brings more traffickers into the business.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back in the real world, we're talking about Mexico and not John Maynard Keynes. We will spend 18 billion dollars this year on this "war," and the question on the table every year is do we certify Mexico as an ally or not? Another man, RUSH PHILLIPS, a middle-aged powerbroker, overhears, then joins and Robert is encircled.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSH PHILLIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to make a difference, hit the users. You don't jeopardize our financial markets by some hypocritical stance on drug consumption. We're snorting it, why penalize Mexico for supplying it?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mexico, don't talk to me about Mexico --</utterance>
   <speaker>ECONOMIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the stick of law enforcement that creates the carrot of huge profits... That's economic truth --</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSH PHILLIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Addicts don't vote; they don't have PACs; they don't spend soft money, that's political truth --</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're locking them up and consumption is falling --</utterance>
   <speaker>ECONOMIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The price of coke and heroin has dropped and purity has increased. All this law enforcement has achieved is kids can get better stuff, cheaper. In economic terms, you can forget it; this is not a winnable war.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSH PHILLIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We don't need them for anything.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, you want to decertify somebody, take Pakistan or Columbia.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECONOMIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you manage to seize an inconceivable 50 percent of all drugs coming into this country, you'll still raise the price of coke and heroin less than 3 percent which won't affect drug use at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSH PHILLIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MICHAEL ADLER, about Robert's age, and as successful, but in a different way, approaches, catching Robert's eye through the arguing demagogues.</context>
      <utterance>Why are we calling this a war at all? You don't declare war on your own people. Addiction is a little worm that gnaws a house apart from the inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERSECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need Mexico for these reasons: number one -- Defense; two -- Trade; three -- Tourism; then, way on down the line, comes Drugs. The President knows this. Why's he holding everybody's feet to the fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Wakefield, there's a situation that needs your attention right away. Robert looks at Michael, squints, looks closer, then follows.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSH PHILLIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One in sixteen Americans is of Mexican descent. Mexico our third largest trading partner...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking pretty good for an old guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My work keeps me young.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which part, getting terrorists loose on bail or freeing convicted murderers on technicalities?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The worst serial killer in history - who? Gacy - right? Killed forty two people. Our government killed fifty thousand in Vietnam and lied about it every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael, you represent drug dealers, not civil libertarians.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Because it isn't in mine.</context>
      <utterance>We kidnapped Noriega out of Panama. Is that covered in your Constitution?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noriega is a criminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noriega was head of a sovereign nation who made the mistake of doing business with the U.S. Government. So, no, I don't have a problem waking up every day and fighting our government, fighting people like you, trying to keep this system a little bit honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last I read your clients were chopping people up with chainsaws and delivering illegal narcotics into this country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope when you were on the bench, Judge Wakefield, you didn't handle the presumption of innocence in the same fashion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I ever return to the bench, Counselor Adler, I hope I have the pleasure of hearing your arguments.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You planning on going somewhere, Eduardo? You don't like it here? This is the best situation you're going to have for a long, long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a legitimate business. Fishing boats. Tuna. Check it out. Tax records, everything --</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen you motherfucker, you tried to kill me with a fucking cannon.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't visit me here. I want my lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The amount of coke we got on you means capital punishment in some states.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move 'em to Texas, fry 'em up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A NURSE appears in the doorway. Gordon goes to the door and shuts it in her face.</context>
      <utterance>We got you on tape making the deal. We got you bragging about the quality. We got you bragging about your business. We got you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One chance here, Eduardo. Make us believe you got a boss. No boss, it's all on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a death sentence. I'll never make it to the trial.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz looks at them in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>We can protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you work for?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is coercion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a big word for a fisherman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon and Ruiz stare at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Who do you work for?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know another word... Immunity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The window lowers and we see CARL AYALA, 40's, handsome, charismatic, second generation American, in expensive, conservative clothes, covering his cell phone as he greets his kids.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back to his phone call, pulling around to the garage. David goes back to his game.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. Hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl clicks off the phone, turns to Helena.</context>
      <utterance>This is America, a different country. I am Carl, a different man. So you see, everything about our situation is different and I believe the pricing will be different, too.  You're a reasonable man... So take the weekend to think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl winds down and finally becomes present in the room with his wife. He looks at her. She looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Every day with this guy is like starting all over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just watching you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes the topiary away from her. Suddenly, she seems tired. Carl comes over and puts his hand on her pregnant belly.</context>
      <utterance>I got that. How was your day?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her husband watches her, then wraps his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>I keep feeling like I'm forgetting something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, POLICE and DEA enter the front yard. Gordon and Castro enter the yard and move quickly up the drive to Carl.</context>
      <utterance>David, come inside --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? What is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ayala?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon and Castro spin him, cuff him, and without emotion begin pulling him from his yard. David is trying to get to his father. In a kind of shock. Helena trails after him. Castro drags Carl into the street toward the open door of the cruiser. He pushes him down into the backseat.</context>
      <utterance>You're under arrest for violation of Federal Narcotics laws.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon hits the side of the cruiser and it pulls away. Carl looks at his wife through the window. Gordon and Castro head up the driveway toward her house. Helena is left standing in the street. NEIGHBORS, who have appeared in front yards and at the ends of driveways, stare at her with suspicion. David approaches and holds onto her leg.</context>
      <utterance>We have a warrant to search your home, Mrs. Ayala.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salazar crumples the piece of paper and tosses it in the trash.</context>
      <utterance>Javier Rodriguez. Twenty-nine years- old. Graduated from Montessori school. Five years as a beat cop in TJ. Three years with the State Police. Parents died four years ago in their apartment from carbon monoxide poisoning because they could not afford to fix their gas heater. Your sister works in a Maquiladora in Juarez, making designer blue-jeans. On the police force three years, you currently make 316 dollars a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your past. I want to talk about your future. Would you be willing to do something for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to bust the Tijuana Cartel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier thinks about this.</context>
      <utterance>A small thing. Nothing really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does this offer include my partner?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if he can be trusted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salazar slides a folder across the desk. Javier opens it and sees a black and white surveillance photo of the informant.</context>
      <utterance>He'll do what I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Francisco Flores. He is a killer and gun smuggler for the Tijuana cartel. I need to speak with him. I need you to find him and bring him to me so that I can speak with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is fucking crazy. Instead of killing us, he sends us on a suicide mission. Do you know who Frankie Flowers is? He's a psycho-cokehead- hitman. A faggot. He's killed fucking who knows how many people. You'd need half the force to get close to him. And you can't get their help because he lives in fucking San Diego.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I guess I'm going by myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it like?  Imagine you're being accosted by a swarm of beggars in the heart of Calcutta, except the beggars are wearing $1500 suits and they don't say "please" or "thank you."</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Has anybody talked about that?</context>
      <utterance>What about legalizing everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine -- legalization. Okay, forgetting all of our international trade agreements, legalize everything today. The Government inserts itself into all drug transactions. The U.S. becomes a giant pharmacy. Our borders are mobbed, lines of people from here to Europe wanting to smoke, snort and shoot themselves into oblivion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a Grateful Dead Concert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drugs begin pouring out of America into every other country in the world. Canada is completely overwhelmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if every country legalized at the same time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow, I don't see that happening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you know we put the case before the arbitration panel, none of whom had any expertise. Superfund is just one of those words. People stop paying attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's frustrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is wine on the table and Caroline is allowed a glass. Her parents watch her take a responsible sip.</context>
      <utterance>It's so frustrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you meet the President?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, your father knows the President.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As it happens, the President of the United States, my new boss, the leader of the free world, has me penciled in for some "face time".</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will we get invited to the White House?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long's the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a presidential appointment so... until I quit or get fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Czar for life, just like a real czar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline thinks about this.</context>
      <utterance>That makes mom the Czarina. I'm a Czarette. Like Anastasia.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of my friends can fucking believe my dad is the actual Drug Czar.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caroline --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert doesn't know if she's putting him down.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, but I mean, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at each other. Caroline sips her wine.</context>
      <utterance>It's great, daddy. It's just amazing, that's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena, I'm so sorry --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Metzger sits, giving her a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Arnie, thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie looks at her as if to say, "do you really not know?" Then, he speaks quietly with his hand in front of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Can you please tell me what on earth is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. You're upset. You want to know what's going on. That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you talking like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks to see if this is registering.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me carefully. First of all, Carl isn't here. DEA's got him and they'll hang on to him until arraignment, which will probably be tomorrow. So here you're wasting your time. Are you with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Got it?</context>
      <utterance>Good. From now on I want you to expect that every word you utter will be tape-recorded, that the movement of your lips is being read.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes eye contact with her.</context>
      <utterance>Arnie, this is crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it?  Good. Do not discuss anything over the telephone. Do not talk to the neighbors. Stay out of your yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he being charged with?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That is very important.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but under no circumstances would I talk about it here. I want you to go home and relax the best you can. Continue your life as if nothing has happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arnie, I feel like Alice stepping through the looking glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a very apt analogy, Helena. Now, go home and be with your children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm curious how you did this with such economy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody has a weakness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at Fucked-up Bowman who grinds his jaw appreciatively --</context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying, what I'm saying, is it never seems like anybody ever says anything that matters to them, like we all look at each other and nod with responses we've been trained to make, not real responses, just social conventions, phony, fake smiles, surface bullshit... I mean, we're all smart and do we have any idea what each other are like, really like? Do I know what Seth's afraid of, or Vanessa, or fucked-up Bowman?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Probably, but do I ever say this stuff, just say, "hey, I'm uncomfortable in this crowd, I don't know what the fuck I'm doing, either? I know you're afraid and it's okay--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fucked-up Bowman takes another slug of vodka and almost pukes.</context>
      <utterance>We act like we have all the answers and we're totally invincible like our parents seem and their parents before them and it's fucking bullshit --</utterance>
   <speaker>FUCKED-UP BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For instance --</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For instance I know you jack-off thinking about Caroline even though you're supposedly "in love" with Vanessa. Whatever the fuck that means?  I mean, what is that convention, anyway? We're all these random collections of self-interest, and then we just decide that now we're two people walking along -- Caroline expels a hit of rock cocaine --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at each other with love. This is an adventure and they're having a connection --</context>
      <utterance>And Vanessa doesn't think she's pretty so she does all these weird fucking diets which is totally about self- esteem. And she's beautiful.  And that's not even fair. Because listen to me. I'm fucking lying right now. This is exactly what I'm talking about... I'm supposedly talking about you, making some big point about you, and it's really about me. So I should talk about me, not you, not even the universal "you..."  Okay. Okay, I'm worried I'm not really smart or that I'm not nearly as smart as people think I am, or that my parents' expectations have been way too high since I was five, I mean who knows they're going to Harvard when they're five, not that I'm blaming them for anything because everything's great, and I may not even get in, but we all feel this shit and we never acknowledge it and if we can't acknowledge it to the people we care the most about then who will we ever say it too and what kind of life will that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>FUCKED-UP BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bowman does another huge hit of freebase.</context>
      <utterance>I jack-off thinking about Seth. Everybody I know does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ach, that's what I'm talking about. Sarcasm. Always fucking sarcasm. You're afraid and you think if you admit it people will think you're weak or won't like you --</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at each other, vibrating with the moment --</context>
      <utterance>We live our lives by these unspoken rules that are handed to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's be different --</utterance>
   <speaker>FUCKED-UP BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bowman looks around, squinting, confused. He's chalk white.</context>
      <utterance>I can't feel my hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUCKED-UP BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, he clutches his chest and begins to twitch. Puke and foam come from his mouth. He seizes and falls from the chair. Vanessa SCREAMS. Seth and Caroline push the table aside to get a better look. Other people in the kitchen slowly take notice.</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious --</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's blue. He isn't breathing --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bowman's eyes have rolled back in his head.</context>
      <utterance>Is he breathing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do? Okay. Fucked-up Bowman's turning blue. Doctor. We need a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your dad's a doctor. Call him --</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a research doctor. You're dad's a doctor, too --</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of research?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mapping the fucking pig genome. We'll call your dad, he's a neurosurgeon --</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's three a.m. I'm not supposed to be here. I snuck out --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding... I'm staying with you --</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna fucking die right here on the kitchen floor --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't. My parents are in Barbados --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TORTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches Francisco and begins shaking up the soda water. He rips the tape off his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>We know Tijuana Cartel gunmen killed our chief of intelligence, Francisco. We know you killed police commanders in Tijuana and Mexico City. Why do you resist?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father is rich. He'll pay you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TORTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The torturer puts another strip of duct tape across Francisco's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Not the correct answer, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>TORTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco starts to squirm and whimper. The torturer closes one of Francisco's nostrils and sprays the pepper-laced water into the other nostril. It's like a bomb went off in Francisco's brain. He SCREAMS and passes out. Blood and mucous oozes out of his nose.</context>
      <utterance>We know that you went after the neighbor of General Salazar, a simple alfalfa farmer. His grand-daughter was shot. This is stupid behavior, Francisco.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is fabulous, Helena. What a turnout.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena circles away. As Helena leaves, the women speak their minds --</context>
      <utterance>Thank you so much, but I had a lot of help.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a turnout because it's a spectacle. Can you imagine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've met her husband, as nice as they come.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It teaches me a valuable lesson...  Apparently crime pays.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silly, you knew that already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Live with your parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parents still together?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you work?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I volunteer. I read to blind people. One day a week for two hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In school?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Social worker looks up from her questionnaire and sees Caroline for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Cincinnati Country Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Private?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are your grades?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm third in my class.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get A's. All A's.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do? What else you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The social worker pushes the forms she's filling out away and looks again at Caroline --</context>
      <utterance>I'm a National Merit Finalist. I'm on the Hi-Q team and the Math team. I'm in the Spanish Club. I'm a Thespian. I'm Vice-President of my class. I'm on the volleyball team.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna tell me what you're doing here, Caroline?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you tell Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this bad for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The streets are deserted. Their Saab wagon sits forlornly under grey skies in an uncovered public parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am on the board of my son's school. I had a fundraiser for A.L.V. in my front yard. I have a right to know if my husband is a legitimate businessman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena is relieved, but she's not looking at Arnie and when she does she sees him shaking his head in a very definitive, "No." Arnie stands and continues talking as he walks to the windows and shuts the blinds one by one.</context>
      <utterance>Of course he is. I've known him for twenty years and he doesn't jaywalk...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blinds are closed. Arnie crosses to Helena and talks very softly in her ear. She's a beautiful woman and Arnie manages to make this act seem both practical and inappropriate.</context>
      <utterance>...Carl is a very important member of this community and when we're through suing the police and the district attorney and the DEA, they'll have to rename the public parks for your husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena leans back and looks at Arnie. He whispers more --</context>
      <utterance>Your husband is very good at his job...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is smuggling illegal drugs into this country.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're whispering. I can't hear them, but I know it. I smell conspiracy. I feel the lie vibrating out of the home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't in on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have dreams about this, actual dreams about busting the top people, the rich people, the white people.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, she doesn't know shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knows Arnie Metzger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So does half of San Diego.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to make a wager on this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If all our assets are frozen and our "sales force" has scattered... How am I supposed to survive? I'm giving birth in three months. How do I get through this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get through it, but the first thing we do is get Michael Adler to represent Carl. We get Adler and we beat this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do I pay him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect he'll accept his payment in publicity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up beseechingly.</context>
      <utterance>Caroline? How well did you know this boy who overdosed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't hang around us. He's like one of those hippie kids. I'm not part of that group. It was a party in all these rooms. His girlfriend who I barely know was completely hysterical... He's blue, he's puking... We didn't want to get in trouble, but what were we supposed to do?  I mean, what would you have done if you had been us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How well do you know this boy, Seth, who was driving? You know the police have charged him with a DUI and possession of marijuana.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She searches her parents' faces. It has been a convincing performance and she expects victory.</context>
      <utterance>He's a friend. He's also like the only one who was dealing with the situation. He'd definitely had a few beers, but it's not like he wanted to drive. We didn't know what else to do.  It wasn't my pot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline is confused by this reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, honey. We understand. You're mother and I have to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline stands abruptly --</context>
      <utterance>Honey, we'd like to talk alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline leaves the study and shuts the door harder than necessary. Robert and Barbara look at each other, raising their eyebrows and breathing deeply --</context>
      <utterance>Like always.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll ground her, clip her wings a bit. School and scheduled activities and that's it until further notice. This has to be handled delicately. Dan Kelly, in the District Attorney's office, will probably help us out, quietly. Christ, this could be embarrassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, this is difficult, but we've all had our moments. I tried --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't want to hear about that.</context>
      <utterance>Stop. You experimented in college.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we take the quotes off experiment and call it what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is different.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To begin with, she's only sixteen years-old.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she has to find out for herself, on her own. We have to allow her space --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Space for what? To O.D. like that other kid? I will not send the message that this type of behavior is okay with her parents. Because it isn't. Correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert looks at his wife, then it dawns on him.</context>
      <utterance>We don't want to push her away. These are growing experiences.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>How long have you known about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you known?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six months. I found some marijuana, that's all. And a little pipe about two inches long. I talked with her. She said her friends smoked pot and drank --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explain to me how you could think that I shouldn't know about this. Explain to me how this wouldn't be relevant to me. As a parent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>She asked me not to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watch and learn. I earn his trust. Then more pain. Then I appear with kindness. Within a week he will follow me around like a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But will he be house-trained?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the barracks.</context>
      <utterance>When he loves me like a father, he will never tell anyone he was here. He will freely give the names of his superiors. Then we get them and they too will give us names. And eventually somebody will get us to Juan Obregon and the cartel will fall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is shameful. A disgrace. Francisco Flores -- Francisco cowers in the corners --</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUARD appears in the doorway. Francisco is spooked.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, son. It's all right. Salazar is here. You're among gentlemen, now. This shameful treatment will stop immediately.  Guard!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know who is responsible for this treatment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We aren't barbarians.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring this man a change of good clothes. Has he eaten?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prosecutor sits. Carl's defense lawyer, MICHAEL ADLER, from the Georgetown party, stands and speaks.</context>
      <utterance>This is a man who heads a large criminal organization with international contacts we can only begin to understand. Our case against him is very strong. He is not a flight risk. His flight is assured. The people ask that your honor denies bail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My client is no more a flight risk than your Honor or the able prosecutor. He is a pillar of his community, a family man with a wife and child in La Jolla, the community where he has made his home for over twenty years. As our defense will quickly show, my client is guilty of nothing more than being a handy target for an admitted criminal. Therefore we ask that you release Carl Ayala on his own recognizance. Adler sits. The JUDGE makes a quick decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The judge SLAMS his gavel. The crowd is on its feet. Carl tries to get a glimpse of Helena. They make eye contact. Reporters from the press gallery are yelling for Helena. Arnie ushers her away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna deny bail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ayala, were you aware your husband is the largest cocaine smuggler in America?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena gets into her car and slams the door. Adler faces the reporters.</context>
      <utterance>Alleged, people, alleged.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adler is in a role he relishes. Helena drives away. We move up to Gordon, who is watching from the hotel window across the street. He speaks into a walkie-talkie, and a car down below pulls out to follow Helena.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ayala is it true your husband has ordered a hit on Eduardo Ruiz?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl Ayala sits on the board of the Children's Hospital. He is heavily involved with Adult Literacy. He has a small boy and another child on the way. If you spread this kind of innuendo, you can expect legal recourse. Are we clear on this point?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate you coming in so early.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.A. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judge Wakefield, it's an honor to handle it for you. Consider it gone away. She's a minor; it probably would've expunged on her 18th birthday anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, this was a sensitive issue for me and I wanted to thank you personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.A. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A.D.A. Kelly thinks a moment, then tries for tact.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, open container, P.I., Misdemeanor possession. Easy to make it disappear. For you, poof, it's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.A. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing bothers me... That kid they dropped off had coke and heroin in him. Serious amounts. He's lucky he lived. So I gotta ask: what's your daughter on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.A. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert is silent for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, did you ask her? What kind of drugs has she tried?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't really know.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.A. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she in any kind of therapy... professional help?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, of course not. She's one of the top students at her school.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.A. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope it stays that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little Montel is the next Maradona.</context>
      <utterance>You should see little Montel play.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maradona is a cokehead. Hand of God, my ass. We're wasting our time here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won. He was a winner. That bothers you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon looks at the monitor --</context>
      <utterance>Winners don't do coke. Or haven't you been reading the bumper stickers?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we have here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she closes distance the man stops juggling the ball and abruptly picks up David and begins swinging him around by his arms. David is having fun as Helena approaches.</context>
      <utterance>David, come back here this minute. David!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David --</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strange man swings David up so that he's under his arm.</context>
      <utterance>We're playing!</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, this is fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man holds David.</context>
      <utterance>Please put down my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't let your kid wander off with strangers.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strange man holds David tighter so that he's no longer having fun. He begins to wriggle --</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. That's a valuable lesson. David, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ayala -- This gets her attention --</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David begins to cry. Helena looks around wildly for help.</context>
      <utterance>Your husband owes a lot of money. Enough that snapping this kid's neck wouldn't nearly cover it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops David who runs to his mother.</context>
      <utterance>You better come up with it in a hurry or your kid is going to disappear, and he won't turn up until the evening news.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strange man moves away across the field.</context>
      <utterance>You get exactly one warning.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues walking away.</context>
      <utterance>The first payment is three million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you getting this on tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love my job. I love it. The next time I'm having a bad day you gotta remind me of right now and I'll get over it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A group of us are going out tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guzman, Tomas, Esteban --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your new friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It should be fun. You wanna come?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my home I have B&amp;W speakers. I recently purchased a compact disc burner. I can make my own cd's, with whatever music I like, as if I bought them at the store, only I don't have to pay these crazy prices.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have much in common. We both attended school in the United States, and both of our fathers are engineers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got into stereo equipment when I was a kid. Some people don't notice the difference but it is very important to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A soldier pours another glass of red for Francisco.</context>
      <utterance>Of course it is. Have some more wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salazar slides a pad of paper toward Francisco who slowly begins writing.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Francisco, my friend... I must know where these men are who killed my captains. Not where they were last week, but where they are today, and better still, tomorrow. You are clever. You can predict where they will be, can't you? Francisco begins to weep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks beseechingly at them.</context>
      <utterance>I can't go home. I don't want to go. Please don't make me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not our decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They push him out of the SUV.</context>
      <utterance>Stop complaining. Nobody knows what you've been up to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carlos, I mean Carl, started out in the family connection business: real estate in Tijuana, fishing boats out of Ensenada, hydroponic raspberries. He met up with the Obregon brothers of the Tijuana Cartel who were interested in two things: entering society and using his fishing boats.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you pay off our customs officials?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Mexico law enforcement is an entrepreneurial activity, this is not so true for the USA.  Using regression analysis we made a study of the customs lanes at the border and calculated the odds of a search. The odds are not high, and we found variables that reduce the odds. We hire drivers with nothing to lose. Then we throw a lot of product at the problem. Some get stopped. Enough get through. It's not difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd think he wasn't sitting here facing life in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has worked for years and it will continue to work for years. NAFTA makes everything more difficult for you. The border is disappearing.  You people are like those Japanese soldiers left behind on deserted islands who think that World War II is still going on.  Let me be the first to tell you, your government surrendered this war a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This attitude's not gonna help him any, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got greedy. I decided to bring a little in on my own and somebody tipped you off. That was my mistake. Carl would never be so stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hired you. That was a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl and I were friends from childhood. He was loyal, that's not a mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The busiest land border crossing in the world. Over forty-one thousand vehicles per day, twenty-two thousand pedestrians on foot. I think we do a pretty good job but we know a lot of drugs are still getting through.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any idea how much?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've read official estimates but I wouldn't bet my house on them. I've heard the entire cocaine supply for the United States can fit into four tractor-trailers.  At least a half-dozen of those cars right out there are carrying a load of dope, with drivers employed by people who don't give a damn if they're caught or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you look for?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ask questions and measure the answers. When something doesn't ring true, a fact that doesn't make sense, a slight hesitation, then it's off to secondary for a closer look. Before NAFTA we had about 1.9 million trucks a year. Now it's almost double. Pretty soon there'll be Mexican truck companies that will have as much freedom in crossing the border as American truck companies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any way we can do it better?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. More money in intelligence on their side of the border. So we have a better idea who we're looking for. More dogs. More people. Supposed to be getting some giant x- ray machines to run the trucks through. Outside of martial law that's about the best you're gonna do.  But, I should tell you, there are two things that really have us on edge right now.  In the last six months seizures have tripled, even though we're pulling over the same number of cars. What does that tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That triple the amount of stuff is going through.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert looks out at the border activity. It's anarchy.</context>
      <utterance>Right. But, that's not the biggest problem. One of our Intel officers picked up information from DEA that traffickers have come up with a process, a chemical process, to turn coke into something else. It doesn't smell like coke. It doesn't look like coke. And what's worse, it doesn't react to field test. It could be anything. Maybe it's already happening. I mean, how would we know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Castro and Gordon looks at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. She's coming out. She's leaving her property. Okay, she seems to be heading for the van! She is approaching the van!</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCKING at the door of the van.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think she wants?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon opens the door. Helena is standing there with the lemonade.</context>
      <utterance>She's your girlfriend. Open it, talk about your kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I so hope I didn't startle you. I thought you might like some cold lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the cups to him. Helena gathers herself.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this is a difficult situation and you're only doing your jobs. I don't bear you any ill-will, but I do have a small favor to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to ask us a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man threatened my children. These charges have attracted a lot of attention and it seems to be bringing all the nut-jobs out of the nut jar.  Would you keep an eye out for anything out of the ordinary. I don't know what else to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, we will.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shut the door to the van and sit for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon takes a big sip of his.</context>
      <utterance>It's probably poisoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good. Not too sweet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anna. What's wrong? What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find Manolo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never came home last night. Was he with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets her into the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out a plastic packet with the scorpion insignia and 911 stamped on it. Javier thinks a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm worried. Last time he was out late, I went through his clothes while he was asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manolo is sweaty and crazy-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing? You're supposed to be at work. Look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no problem. I was just with everybody we work with.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really. General Salazar was there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but a lot of other people. You should come. You should come out with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home. Get cleaned up. Get to work. Salazar is heading down to Mexico City next week and I'm not getting left behind. Don't fuck this up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know my dad takes eight red cold pills every day? He and my mom have cocktail hour every night, from six to seven, set your clock, two bourbons --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we could show up and smoke a little rock with them to unwind --</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, then some dope to take the edge off at the end of a long day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you done your homework, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, mom --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn down a street with a lot of activity on it.</context>
      <utterance>Then here's a little bump.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO YOUNG STREET DEALERS fall in step with them. One talks without moving his lips --</context>
      <utterance>Drugs weren't even a problem until a hundred years ago when the white men in power declared them a problem. Opiates. But, who was using 'em? Chinese immigrants. Slave labor. And the darkies up in the inner cities dancing to them evil rhythms of ju- ju music. People on the fringe. Artists. Decadent rich people. And who got scared? White men in power. Who's scared today? White men in power. If J.P. Morgan and John D. Rockefeller ever admitted using, it'd be a whole different story.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One dealer hurries ahead toward the doorway of a falling- down building.</context>
      <utterance>911, and the come down.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dealer looks them over. He looks behind them down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Two hundred of C, hundred of the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on... We've been here before.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth and Caroline are suspicious. They carefully show money they both have in their front right pockets. The dealer feints like he might grab it.</context>
      <utterance>Then, let's see your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hurry up the steps into the dingy brownstone.</context>
      <utterance>Up the steps. You the experts. You know what to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUNKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you two, about twelve?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wait. Finally, the first dealer appears in the inner door and lets them through.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands over her money to Seth who pays and gets the drugs: gram baggies of rock stamped with a scorpion and "911," and wax-paper bindles of heroin, also labeled, "911." Caroline has been watching the transaction. Sketch makes slow eye contact with Caroline. After a beat --</context>
      <utterance>Caroline, give me your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth and Caroline make their way out of the building.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye... Caroline.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd like room 205.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you hand me twenty-eight dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth dumps the drugs on the bedside table. From other pockets he extracts aluminum foil, lighter, tube. She trails away watching him fix the first hit.</context>
      <utterance>I love this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Courtney Love play Nancy in Syd and Nancy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. If she didn't she should have.  I've only got maybe an hour. Then volleyball practice is over and I have to be home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He prepares the first hit. She does it and lies back. He does one.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Nobody's there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans over to snort a tiny line of heroin.</context>
      <utterance>I wish we could stay here. Just be here forever and ever. Make it a little home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline's distracted by the line she's snorting. After a while...</context>
      <utterance>I want to have sex and do a hit right as we're coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth begins undoing her jeans.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are these guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL-AGENT-IN-CHARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agents who died in the field.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SPECIAL-AGENT-IN-CHARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That house, that you see from the DEA headquarters, belonged to Porfirio Madrigal -- the Lord of the Skies, largest trafficker in Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He died in a liposuction surgery, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL-AGENT-IN-CHARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BINOCULAR POV: a child running in circles holding a clutch of colored balloons.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Now it's used by somebody from the Juarez Cartel, one of his lieutenants... Who knows?  Every damn day there's birthday party. At first I thought they must have three hundred children, then I realized they're taunting us. Three miles away and we can't touch them. Ha, ha, ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do we interface with on their side?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL-AGENT-IN-CHARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, who runs interdiction on the Mexico side?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL-AGENT-IN-CHARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I don't think there's any one person.  See the problem is the Juarez cartel owns everything and everybody, all the property on the Mexican side, sometimes all the property on both sides. Warehouses, transportation, even tunnels. It's very organized.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men on the plane just stare at him. Finally the REP FROM DEA leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>I want everyone thinking out the box for a second. What are we gonna do about Mexico?  Come on, guys. Out of the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>REP FROM DEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unlimited funds?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unlimited.</utterance>
   <speaker>REP FROM DEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert turns to the others.</context>
      <utterance>From a DEA standpoint we need a vetted task force and matching funds. And cut the red tape on getting them equipment and training.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still, no one else says anything. They watch Robert impassively.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. I want to hear from everyone: FBI. Customs. Treatment. Is there anyone from treatment on this plane?  Then I want an answer for why there isn't anyone from treatment.  Look, we know we have to bust one of these cartels, Juarez or Tijuana, not just as a symbol, but hell yes, also as a symbol - they are symbols - and there's nothing wrong with sending a message. That's why when Carlos Ayala hired Michael Adler lead defense, I flew Ben Williams to San Diego to prosecute. Because he's the best we have, he's our symbol that we're serious about putting the top people away.  So, as of right now, this flight only, consider the dam on new ideas thrown open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm not mistaken, we got DEA, Pentagon, U.S. Attorneys office, about a billion dollars of budget right here. So what are you people waiting for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie stands very close to Helena and looks at her profile.</context>
      <utterance>On a clear day you can see Mexico City.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is swept twice a day. I learned that in Miami in '85. Then the U.S. shut down the whole Caribbean, but it's a big game of wack-a-mole. Knock it down in Miami, it pops up here. And San Diego is so much more relaxing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arnie, I need money. Somebody threatened my children. They want a first payment of three million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena, if I had it I would give it to you, but I don't have that kind of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arnie, help me. Doesn't anyone owe us money?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I told you before, there are people who owe you money but they're not paying. There's too much heat on Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Tell me who Carl sells to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if I knew I wouldn't tell you. You do not want to come into contact with these people. Only Carl knows who they are. That's his real asset. Ruiz doesn't know them. They don't know Ruiz. Church and State.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about legitimate businesses? We own a construction concern, real estate --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laundromats for the washing of money. Unfortunately, Carl had only one successful business.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There isn't. Helena looks Arnie in the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you have some good news? Isn't there something positive you could say.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I wonder what I'll do if Carl doesn't get out. I'm not very adept at being on my own. I've always had a man in my life. Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember when I first met you: little Helen Watts from the wrong side of somewhere. I had a feeling even then that your survival instincts were pretty well honed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a great effort for Arnie not to answer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you think so, but I'm picturing a debt-ridden, thirty-two year-old mother whose ex-husband is being compared to Pablo Escobar.  And I'm wondering who would want to be with someone like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROSARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manolo laughs and looks her up and down. Javi watches her in the rearview mirror.</context>
      <utterance>You two don't like me, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have an opinion on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's because I'm getting an apartment nicer than anything you'll ever see in your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe the old man kept his promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The General is a man of his word.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi just looks at her in the rearview mirror.</context>
      <utterance>They will say anything to get what they want, but then you remind them, it's always tomorrow, tomorrow, tomorrow.  Occupational hazard, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier pulls the SUV to the curb in front of a beautiful colonial-style apartment complex in the verdant neighborhood.</context>
      <utterance>His friend is giving us the apartment so it's not like he paid. It's more like a favor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manolo knocks again. They wait a long beat.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have the keys. Oh that's perfect. Are you an idiot?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, the door swings open and a BODYGUARD is standing there. Rosario SQUEALS and sweeps past him into the vast space. The bodyguard motions for Manolo to put the bags inside the door. Manolo sets the bags down and sees another MAN standing a few feet away. The man wears sunglasses. His complexion is strange and his neck is bandaged. The body guard escorts Manolo back outside where he hears Rosario's happy LAUGHTER drifting down from an upstairs window.</context>
      <utterance>There's supposed to be someone here to let you in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madrigal's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat as Javier considers this.</context>
      <utterance>Porfirio Madrigal is not dead. I just saw him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier calmly drives away.</context>
      <utterance>This is why Salazar is so interested in cleaning up Tijuana. Madrigal, who's supposed to be dead, owns him. And Madrigal is making a move on Juan Obregon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi --</context>
      <utterance>Javi! Come on. Don't pull this you don't care bullshit. This is incredible information. It must be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We keep our mouths shut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we may have found our Mexican Drug Czar. It's this General, Salazar. At least I'll have somebody on the other side I can talk to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence.</context>
      <utterance>Does this mean you're going to be gone more?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another silence.</context>
      <utterance>Possibly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might want to pencil in a little face-time with your daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barbara --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm at the edge of my capabilities, Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first thing we have to do is present a unified front.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you start in on the war metaphors I'm going to drive this car into a fucking telephone pole.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm as worried as you are --</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think so. Leave me alone, give me money. That's what I get from our daughter. She has a way of shutting me out that seems very familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, stung.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, she has a way of self- medicating that probably seems familiar, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not the one who has to have three scotches just to walk in the door and say hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a drink before dinner to take the edge off my day. That's different.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, because the alternative is to be bored to death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the remaining crack, lighters, tubes, little smudgy druggy bits of paraphernalia and carefully places it all in a hiding place above the bathroom cabinet. She pauses a beat, then opens the door, and tries to brush by her father while avoiding his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>One minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert grabs her by the arms. He pushes her against the wall and looks at her pupils. He looks at her fingernails. The blister on her thumb from working the lighter is red and irritated.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert sniffs the air. He throws open cabinets, searching for drugs. He sees the smudge mark on the counter left by the charred aluminum foil.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going anywhere, young lady. She stands there; she's very high.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it? Where are the drugs?  Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert KICKS the cabinets.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you. I wasn't doing anything. You're like the Gestapo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert is losing it. He throws stuff around the bathroom and then, for the first time, looks up. He sees the long light in the box atop the medicine cabinet and it dawns on him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck me? Oh, okay. Fuck me. Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just stares.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to ask you one time to tell me the truth so that I can help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, young lady, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert reaches above the medicine cabinet and pulls out a charred spoon. It confuses him. He throws it into the sink. He pulls out another spoon. He pulls out crumpled bindles, rolled up, encrusted dollar bills, exhausted lighters, a pill bottle, an empty pint of vodka. The detritus of drug addiction keeps on coming, filling up the sink. Robert stares at it, the amount and complexity has him momentarily baffled.</context>
      <utterance>Like I give a fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with you? What?  You're going away. You're getting help somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't make me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes I can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hughes sticks out his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agent Hughes, Drug Enforcement Administration of the United States.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agents exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you taking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somewhere safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A place we have, that we know is protected.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Where would you like to go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's important that we work together. Mexico. America. One hand washing the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... maybe you tell me about your informants in our operations.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We thought maybe you'd have that kind of information for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnson and Hughes exchange a glance.</context>
      <utterance>This is a very different proposition.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fat kid in an inner-tube floats behind them.</context>
      <utterance>We pay for that kind of information.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi makes eye contact with one agent, then the other.</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you're talking about, Javier?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten years ago Tijuana had no drug problem. Now it is epidemic.  Ten years ago America takes a hammer to Pablo Escobar, a hammer to the Miami drug trade, and you allowed everything to move to my country. You dumped the problem at our feet. Now, drug use is epidemic. Now, the treatment centers are full and get no state money. They survive on donations and what they get for building doghouses to sell to the</utterance>
   <speaker>U.S.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi starts to get out of the pool.</context>
      <utterance>We need lights for the parks so kids can play at night. So they can play baseball. So it's safe. Everybody likes parks. Everybody likes baseball.  What I'm talking about is I would like to see somebody take an interest in Tijuana. That's what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Javi, You want to come see us again, you're going on the box. No more of this water-wing bullshit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna tell me what the hell that was all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got something. We just have to be patient.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's David?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's David? How's David? He's terrific, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't even look at him.</context>
      <utterance>We watched his father get dragged away by federal agents. I don't even know how to begin to tell him where you are or when you're coming back... Or if you're coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get through this, I promise. I'll make it up to you --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? Supportive letters from prison while I'm being kicked out of our home?  Do you have any idea what is happening out here? Our credit cards are maxed. The people at the bank, you should see their faces when I walk in there. I have a letter from the government telling me that anything I sell from our house will be taken against an income tax lien. Our friends are behaving like the crowd at a public hanging. Nobody will help us. Nobody will take us in. Nobody wants anything to do with us. So tell me, Carl, how you're gonna make it up to me.  Tell me again how we'll get through this, and maybe while you're at it you can put your hand up against the glass so we can have a tender moment of connection.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl looks at his wife as if he is trying to weigh her. He thinks, then leans forward --</context>
      <utterance>Tell me what to do, Carl. I need guidance, not a fucking platitude.  I'm not bringing a child into the kind of life I grew up with. I won't do it. I want our life back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That painting is very valuable.</context>
      <utterance>I built our house and I don't want to lose it. Every stone, every brick, every board.  My business... That would take a lot of private study...  That you don't have time for. I suggest you look into the Coronel...  Into selling it. If you can stomach it, you should look into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look into the Coronel; otherwise, there is nothing to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Marty looks to Caroline who didn't relate to one word he said.</context>
      <utterance>So it was my birthday an my ex-wife was getting remarried and I was in some church basement telling a bunch of strangers how it was a good day because I didn't have to eat out of a dumpster. That was enough to send me out on big one.  I've been thinking a lot about the first step: that I came to believe I was powerless over alcohol and that my life had become unmanageable.  See my disease tells me I don't have a disease. That I'm fine. That it's my birthday and I can have one little drink, then one little line, then one little Valium, then two more fat lines, then two more 10 mil Valium... Six months later I wake up in a sober living house in Philly. And I'm from Dallas, people.  It's a disease -- an allergy of the body and an obsession of the mind. I know that now. So my name's Marty and today I'm a grateful recovering alcoholic who didn't eat out of a dumpster. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People in the room nod encouragingly.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Caroline. I'm not sure I'm an alcoholic.  I mean I don't really like to drink. For someone my age it's so much easier to get drugs than beer. I don't know, this is really weird and I'm really nervous...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blushes, and stares out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm angry. I mean I think I'm really angry about a lot of stuff, but I don't know what exactly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ART APPRAISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tamayo. Carrington. A simply wonderful collection of Mexican Modern. Give me three months. I know several collectors in South America, very discreet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have three months.</utterance>
   <speaker>ART APPRAISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It takes time to find the proper collection.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The appraiser taps out some numbers on a calculator and shows the figure to Helena.</context>
      <utterance>How much will you give me in cash? Today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be joking. That's a fraction of their value.</utterance>
   <speaker>ART APPRAISER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena turns her back. She walks to a window and looks out, then surveys the contents of her beautiful home.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but that is the figure I can get today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right. We're have a disagreement, that's all. The art appraiser passes them on his way out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I recruited the best men in Mexico for my task force and put them through a rigorous screening process. Not only physical, but also psychological.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to bring you up to Washington, walk you around our side of things, and share some of the information we've been able to develop on your cartels.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be very helpful to me.  Also, I received the offer from DEA and the FBI to train some of my men at Quantico. I think this will be extremely useful, a good way for us to absorb some of your methods.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Salazar proffers a chair and they sit next to each other like Brezhnev and Nixon. PHOTOGRAPHERS begin SNAPPING pictures. After a few moments, Salazar waves them away, and they lower their cameras and leave.</context>
      <utterance>I've been too busy to completely settle in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been making very good progress against the Tijuana cartel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am confident that Juan Obregon will be taken into custody before the end of the year. But, you must understand that it is very difficult because of corruption in the police force. We get a tip that he is one place, then we get there and he is already gone, having been warned by someone on our side.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopefully the exchange of training methods and information between our countries will help with this problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I hope so as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you a related question. We've talked about the supply side, but what about demand? What is your policy for treating addiction?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALAZAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert cannot respond.</context>
      <utterance>Addicts treat themselves... they overdose and then there's one less to worry about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous. Why is there no elevator?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk down a hotel hallway. Two more AGENTS stand outside Room 407. Gordon opens the door and they enter.</context>
      <utterance>When the DEA gets into the narcotics business, then we'll stay at the Four Seasons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz looks around with disgust. He's accustomed to finer places. He goes to a window and looks out. RUIZ'S POV: of the Federal Court building not far away.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie, how you like your new home? I hope you hate it as much as I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon pours himself a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>This is not what my lawyers negotiated.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck your lawyers. You aren't getting any cappuccino or Biscotti either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the company secretary from 1991 to 1994. I supposedly worked for all six companies. But... they weren't... I mean, it was just one empty office with a desk and a telephone. We never sold anything the whole time I was there. Sometimes people came and got paid. I don't really know what we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Mr. Ayala say where the money came from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, and I didn't ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl's lawyer, Adler, is on his feet --</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think it came from?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAUFMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This speculation --</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheila is reluctant to answer.</context>
      <utterance>I'll rephrase. Did you feel like you were engaged in a legal enterprise?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena catches Carl's eye and they share a grim moment.</context>
      <utterance>No, not really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Helena gathers her courage, then...</context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long pause.</context>
      <utterance>A friend... of Carlos Ayala.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on a special phone, may I speak freely?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a job for you and I don't have much time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Behind her Francisco Flores takes a photo with an instant camera.</context>
      <utterance>I love this place. Don't turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were followed by the police, but they won't hear us over the children. I want to use a bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding. Can't you shoot him or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really like guns. You shoot someone in the head three times and some doctor will keep them alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Eduardo Ruiz is the only real witness against Carl. The security is very tight. There may not be a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francisco laughs.</context>
      <utterance>There's always a way. If people get to the Pope or the President, you can get to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful... You're sounding like your husband, Mrs. Ayala.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier just watches her.</context>
      <utterance>It's very hard for me to come and tell you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps watching.</context>
      <utterance>It's Manolo. He's going to do something stupid. I'm worried that he'll get himself killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says they pay a lot of money.</context>
      <utterance>He's saying he's going to talk to the Americans. Become an informer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does he need money?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has debts. He has gambling debts. He owes a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>Nine thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he planning on telling them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javier just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, he's going to say about Madrigal... and Salazar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. He stands and reaches for his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody saw her leave?  Yes... I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go. I have to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we bring the police into this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERT AND SETH ABRAHMS - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sit in a coffee shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not at that place you sent her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She snuck away. And we haven't seen her. She hasn't come home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hasn't called you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to talk to her when she was up there, but they wouldn't put me through.  I'm surprised she hasn't called.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HUSTLERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you want? Rock? Rock? Hey, what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT AND SETH - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in the coffee shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell me anything? Do you have any ideas?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm worried to death.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not the police. I don't care about experimentation. She's a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't say anything to my parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a fuck about your parents --</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sometimes went downtown to score.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The West End. We buy it off the streets.  I can stop, you know, and she can't. Two people, really similar, we can talk about anything, but for me it's like a weekend thing, then I get my shit together, and for her it's different --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what the hell you're talking about. You're a cocky seventeen year-old and you don't have a clue what the stakes are. You don't know the value of the life you've yet to throw away. And neither does she.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, what do I want?</utterance>
   <speaker>FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rock or dope, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, I'm sorry. I'm just trying to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to help? Stay the fuck away from her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOMEBODY outside says something. Sketch walks over to a duffle bag and extracts some product. Caroline's eyes are glued to it as Sketch hands it through the door. Sketch sees her staring at the drugs. He comes back to bed.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline nods.</context>
      <utterance>You want some of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you gonna do to get some of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please --</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns her back to him, pouting. He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>What you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches over beside the bed where there is a small tray. On the tray is a rig, spoon, several powders, and an eye dropper. He pulls the candle over and rapidly fixes a speedball. He pulls the fluid into the neck of the syringe and holds it up the light. It has Caroline transfixed.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe a taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He squirts the tiniest amount of fluid into the air. It arcs in the candlelight.</context>
      <utterance>Feed this to you like a little bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>You want this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her concentration is entirely, hypnotically focused on the syringe. Sketch moves the syringe toward her lips.</context>
      <utterance>This is the Express train. Baby turnin' pro and getting down in a big, big hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline moves her mouth toward the side of the syringe, her lips part. Sketch pulls the sheet back, exposing her legs. He grips one powerful hand around her ankle and squeezes... Veins stand out on her foot. He slides the needle into the largest vein and slowly depresses the plunger. Caroline watches, then her head tilts back, then forward, she GROANS, sexually and slumps against the pillows, her eyes half-open, her lips twitching. Sketch puts the rig back on the tray, then admires Caroline's beauty for a second before starting to fuck her again.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss it. Kiss your new mommy hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The judge is surprised to hear this.</context>
      <utterance>Your honor, it has come to our attention that your honor, while in private practice, previously represented the town of Seal Beach in their stop-work suit against the Police Department of Seal Beach. We believe this disqualifies you from hearing this case and we therefore move for a temporary suspension while this is investigated.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Adler, this is a most unusual motion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonetheless, your honor, we feel that our client deserves every fairness afforded under the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The judge considers.</context>
      <utterance>If this is in any way designed to delay the testimony of Eduardo Ruiz...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the gavel down again.</context>
      <utterance>We'll recess until 9:00 am Monday morning. And I'll see counsel in chambers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember when we sat on that mob guy, that chef, for like six months?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, I've never eaten so good in my life.  Why don't you develop a useful skill?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the car.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like turning into a beautiful woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind if today we walked? It's one block. I could use the fresh air.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANCISCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to walk right past me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Francisco watches the three men walk past his car. He makes a decision and opens his door.</context>
      <utterance>What are you? A mouse? Get out of the car and do it. This is your chance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw this guy at the courthouse.  The car -- Gordon takes off running, yelling for Castro.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take seats uncomfortably close to Manolo.</context>
      <utterance>Manolo, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're looking around like you're expecting someone.</context>
      <utterance>Manolo, have we interrupted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm looking for the waiter. I want to order.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna have?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you like steak, we know a much better place. We'll take you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They each take Manolo by an arm.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manolo, we should really be going now, before it gets too crowded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men say nothing. After a beat --</context>
      <utterance>I was going to feed them wrong information. Feed them lies to... it was for...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANOLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell Anna I died like this. Tell her it was something else. Tell her it was official business. Tell her that I died doing something honorable. Please, tell her that for me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi hesitates before turning. We're on Javi as we hear the GUNSHOT. Javi doesn't flinch. Manolo's body falls into the grave. Javi stands there, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi shakes his head. Finally, another GUNSHOT. After a beat, a hand reaches out of Javi's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You got anything you want to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk back to the SUV.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that... we had to be sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMEBODY ELSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi says nothing, doesn't even acknowledge them. We hear a</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you don't have anything to tell us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a stupid thing you did. Incredibly stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried, Arnie. And, I will continue to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you gone crazy? You are not Carl. You aren't as good as Carl.  They are moving the trial to a high security location. The press has gone berserk. The jury will be influenced. Stay out of things. Let us try to win the case.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena steps closer to Arnie, close enough that her breasts are almost touching his chest.</context>
      <utterance>That is going to be rather difficult when all the evidence is against us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena, please. This is out of your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena looks searchingly into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I know I made things worse. I know that and I'm sorry, but Arnie I need something from you. Something only you can help me with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helena --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need an introduction to the Obregon Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena leans closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured out what Carl was up to and I need your help. Will you help me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the other night, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I don't get it. Are we supposed to say to ourselves, be prepared to lose her, be prepared to lose our child?  Why does this happen to someone? How does it happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena nods to Tigrillo --</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Ayala. Thank you for coming. I am Juan Marquez, I work for Mr. Obregon. I believe you know my associate, "Tigrillo," the Little Tiger.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he threatened to kill my five year-old son.  I was under the impression I would be meeting Juan Obregon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is not possible. And I thank you for coming down here, though I suspect it's been a pointless journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that, Mr. Marquez?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear these stories. Your husband in jail. His business in chaos. Various people fighting over the scraps.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband is the victim of an informer in your organization, not ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is not true, Mrs. Ayala. Your route is compromised. Perhaps it is time for me to deal with other distributors in California.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you're going to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't? Listen to this woman in a man's world, a very violent world.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are plenty of other suppliers in Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena reaches into her bag and pulls out the Spastic Jack action figure. She puts it on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>But not in whose interest it is to help you out of debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband had been working on something he called, The Project for the Children. Are you aware of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Perhaps I remember something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have the ability to change the color, odor, and physical property of cocaine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to smuggle narcotics in Mr. Espastico Jacobo. That's nothing new.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juan Marquez is confused.</context>
      <utterance>Not in...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juan picks up Spastic Jack and looks at him. He bangs it on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>This doll is cocaine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every part, from his ears to his accessory belt, is high-impact, pressure-molded cocaine. Odorless. Undetectable by dogs. Undetectable by anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes out the "solvent" and puts it on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a bowl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juan takes out a razor blade and chops the dried substance into two white powder lines. He hands a silver straw to Helena.</context>
      <utterance>Try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm six months pregnant. I won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, then we don't have deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands. He watches her a beat, then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, then we don't have a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans down and quickly snorts a line. After a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good coke.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It should be... It's yours.  I want our debt forgiven. I want to be the exclusive distributor of Obregon Brothers Cocaine for the United States. And I want the principle witness against my husband, Eduardo Ruiz, killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena waits. Juan Marquez reaches in his desk and pulls out a quarter kilo of cocaine. He pushes it across the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps... Perhaps... I'm afraid I must first ask you to pass a test. I asked the same of your husband and he succeeded with flying colors.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this back with you. Deliver it safely to Tigrillo in San Diego and we have a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's crazy. My husband is on trial for smuggling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the quarter key in her bag and stands.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly, and this is how I know I'm not getting into business with the U.S. Government.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will help me with my other problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tigrillo escorts her out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Deliver that safely to Tigrillo in San Diego. And we have a deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi finishes talking and sits back. Agent Hughes shuts off the tape recorder and looks at the polygraph operator who nods approval. Hughes and Johnson exchange a look. They are dumbstruck.</context>
      <utterance>...And I have the electronic serial numbers for their cellular phones. They change them every twenty-four hours but I have a contact at MexTel who can get me the new ESNs within twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that you have what you want, let's talk about how I get what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't worry, Javier, you're not gonna have any problems there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to take a minute and talk about what type of precautions you're taking to protect yourself. When Salazar and Madrigal go down, they might send someone to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a beat. Javier seems discomfited. The two agents notice this and exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>You worry about getting me the things that I want. I'll worry about myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should feel good about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like a traitor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CUSTOMS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please step from the car, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in a hurry --</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena gets out of her car.</context>
      <utterance>Step from the car, Ma'am. This won't take long from your day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CUSTOMS MATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, we have reason to believe you may have illegal drugs hidden beneath your clothing. I need to conduct a pat down search. Supervisory Inspector Haig will witness the search.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to be kidding me. I'm pregnant. What if I refuse?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMS MATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This pamphlet explains the law and your rights under it. You're welcome to read it first. It says we have the authority to conduct this search. Would you like to read it first or shall we proceed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MRS. CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon hugs her.</context>
      <utterance>Montel... Oh, Montel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how much he cared about you. You do, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CASTRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another AGENT hustles toward him from the other direction, the direction of the cars.</context>
      <utterance>I know if he could have it back somehow, he wouldn't do it differently or have it any other way. He wouldn't. He loved his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon runs for his car.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Agent Gordon. Mrs. Castro.  Helena Ayala left Club Platinum in Tijuana. The Obregon Brothers' place. They stopped her at the border but she was clean. She's in San Diego now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking, calling me at home with a message like that? You've compromised me and our relationship -- Helena sits confidently on his couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie reaches into a desk drawer and pulls out a quarter- kilo baggy identical to the one Juan Obregon gave her in Tijuana.</context>
      <utterance>The place is swept twice a day. I learned that down in Miami in '85...  Arnie. I'm the housewife. I belong to the most exclusive country club in La Jolla that accepts Latinos. Until recently, I believed my husband imported hydroponic strawberries, which I donated at the school fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the same stuff? From the rainy day stash?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helena puts the bag in her purse.</context>
      <utterance>It's the same. What happened to what they gave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I flushed it in the bathroom of their godawful nightclub.</context>
      <utterance>I'm desperate, but I'm not stupid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Robert looks at Barbara and shakes his head. She gets up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... Did I wake you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a beat.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salazar's been taken down. He was working for Porfirio Madrigal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I thought Madrigal was dead. I thought it was verified.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently not. Look, it's a shit storm here right now. When are you coming back?  I don't know what to tell people any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get there as soon as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're moving the press conference, we need to do it now.  Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The tone in Barbara's voice causes him to look up. She holds an empty jewelry box.</context>
      <utterance>Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to call you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Leica's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So's the video camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert turns for the door.</context>
      <utterance>At least she's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten minutes after that she'll be at her dealer's. If I find him, maybe I find her.</context>
      <utterance>She'll be at a pawn shop in an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Robert yanks Seth out of his seat. The teacher is approaching.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seth has to be excused. He's going on a field trip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women's room, stall two.  Should we stop for ice-cream?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tigrillo disappears into the restaurant. As Helena pulls out of the Fun Zone parking lot, an unmarked DEA cruiser falls in behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, maybe we missed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you used to bring my daughter here, to this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hey man, back the fuck up. To this place. What's that shit? Right now, all over this country, a hundred thousand white people from the suburbs are driving around downtown asking every black person they see, You got any drugs? You know where I can get drugs? What kind of effect you think this has on the psyche of a black person, on their possibilities? If you sent a hundred thousand black people into your neighborhood, Indian Hills, and they asked every white person they saw, hey, you got any drugs?, within a day, your friends and their kids would be selling. It's market forces, man. The product's marked up three hundred percent. You can go out on the street and make five hundred bucks in two hours and then do whatever you want for the rest of the day. You think white people would still be going to law school?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert and Seth get our of the car and walk across the street.</context>
      <utterance>You're starting to piss me off. Get out of the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert shoves Seth toward the door. Seth knocks. The door opens a crack and Sketch's face appears.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get me killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert moves around Seth.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for my daughter, Caroline. She comes here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a business. Get the fuck outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sketch pulls a gun and shoves it against Robert's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I need to find my daughter. I'll pay you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck do you think you are? Where the fuck do you think you are? Why the fuck do you think I shouldn't just put you in a dumpster?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have money --</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay you a thousand dollars. I have it in my wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want your money, I'll take your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sketch pushes Robert back into the hall. Sketch sees Seth lurking there.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell me where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sketch slams the door in their face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that shit again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. What a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert looks at him, carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Man, I'm telling you. Don't do this vigilante thing. Either the cops find her or she'll call you. I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He KNOCKS again.</context>
      <utterance>Anna. Anna, please. Let me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, the door cracks open. Anna has clearly not been out of the house since the last time we saw her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. You can't stay locked in your house all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>I know this is a tragedy, but you have to realize that good has come out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Manolo hadn't gone and told them what he did then Salazar and Madrigal would never have been brought to justice. He did a great thing for Tijuana. He did a great thing for Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to believe you. I really do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will believe me, because it's true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN'S VOICE comes from the other side of the door.</context>
      <utterance>Open the door. Open the fucking door, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUFFLED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert closes the distance. Seth pounds harder.</context>
      <utterance>Go away!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know she's in there. Let me talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUFFLED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert reaches the door. Seth sees him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about. Go away!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert kicks the door in.</context>
      <utterance>I know she's in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline is passed out on the bed. Robert goes to her as the John scrambles for his clothes. She stirs and sees him --</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I haven't touched her --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Daddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline gets lost in her grandiose vision. Robert looks over at her as she drifts off into a nod. A moment later she's awake and rambling again.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be great... I mean, I'm okay and all, because, see, I met a guy, he's in this pretty famous band and...  They've invited me to write lyrics for them, I'm gonna be able to do that and maybe sing, too... not at first, but later.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert fights back tears. He reaches over and takes his daughter's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I've been doing research for the school paper, that's what I've been doing, like on assignment kind-of, I've seen some stuff you wouldn't believe, but I'm gonna write it all down into lyrics. They think I'm really good, everybody says so, what do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juan nods toward Pablo and Tigrillo.</context>
      <utterance>Salazar and Madrigal are no longer with us.  A feat none of these people could get accomplished.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARQUEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi just stares at him for a long moment, then looks off.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to be made the Special Assistant to the new drug Czar, which makes you a very valuable law enforcement officer.  I hope you like to travel because we have plans for Juarez and El Paso, Nogales, Sinaloa, Jalisco, Michoacan...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARBARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really not sure. She seemed to recognize it wasn't Serenity Oaks. It's a pretty hard-core facility, but at least we know where she is.  Maybe it's what she needs now.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT ROBERT IN HIS OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He holds the phone and doesn't say anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz walks over and sits across from Gordon, switching off the radio show he's listening to. Gordon looks up from his paper.</context>
      <utterance>Big day.  You're a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a KNOCK on the front door. An AGENT goes to answer --</context>
      <utterance>Go shower. You smell.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon watches the interchange --</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'll be testifying for at least ten days. What if we stop feeding you? Ruiz begins to eat hungrily.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the love gone, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect me to be grateful for spending the rest of my life looking over my shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz pushes eggs into a piece of toast.</context>
      <utterance>That thought makes me feel awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you for a second imagine none of this had happened? That my drugs had gone through. What would have been the harm? A few people get high who are getting high anyway. Your partner is still alive. We avoid having breakfast together. Don't you see this means nothing? That your whole life is pointless?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're breaking my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The worst thing about you, Monty, is you realize the futility of what you're doing and you do it anyway. I wish you could see how transparent you are.  This food tastes like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So go shower already.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz stands and heads for the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>You only got to me because you were tipped off by the Juarez Cartel, who's trying to break into Tijuana. You're helping them.  You work for a drug dealer too, Monty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agent laughs. There's another KNOCK on the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's like having another wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMEBODY ELSE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Gordon and the agent look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMEBODY ELSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon moves to the side of the door and pulls his gun. The other agent opens the door. A MAN with a breakfast tray enters. Gordon puts the gun to the side of his head.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up. It's getting cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH TRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon is momentarily confused, then goes for the bathroom door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on your side. God, you're jumpy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon tries the bathroom door. It's stuck. He gets it open a crack. There's a body against the other side. He shoves.</context>
      <utterance>Call an ambulance. Hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz's convulsions get worse, his claw-like fingers scratch across the tile.</context>
      <utterance>Call the ambulance.  Don't die on me. You will not die on me. Do you hear me? Don't you die on me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cocaine brand, 911, is an East Coast brand, a Juarez Cartel brand, and you must know it usually comes through into El Paso?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm aware of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi looks Robert Wakefield squarely in the eye. He shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>So what's it doing in Tijuana?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you a hypothetical question: if Salazar worked for Madrigal and the Juaraz cartel, and he went out of power, would it mean the Juarez Cartel is losing influence?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could mean that, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would probably mean the Tijuana Cartel is gaining power?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Javi thinks along time before answering.</context>
      <utterance>Is it possible to have a Drug Czar in Mexico who isn't connected in some war to one of the cartels?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's possible... if you're prepared to die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Saturday, Arnie. You work too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Arnie in the office there is a movement of SHADOW.</context>
      <utterance>Carl, I'm running late. I'm coming right now --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Arnie, when were you going to tell me about the 3 million dollars we got in from San Francisco two days after I got arrested?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just waiting for the right time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you didn't feel like you could trust my wife with this news?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just didn't want to take a chance. I didn't want to risk it. It could have been frozen along with everything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had it all figured out. You move into my house. You raise my kids. You sleep with my wife. It was a good plan, Arnie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl, that's insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So my wife is lying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>On the front lawn CHILDREN are lined up for the ice-cream sundae bar that is being tended by a WAITER.</context>
      <utterance>Carl, think about it, if I was trying to rip you off, I would have left town after Ruiz was killed. I wouldn't sit next to you in court listening to the dismissal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arnie, do think there's a difference between a reason and an excuse, because I don't think there is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye Arnie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl and Helena share an embrace and a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Arnie. He's not going to be able to make the barbecue.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl and Helena turn to leave the room and Montel Gordon is standing in the doorway with his glass of champagne.</context>
      <utterance>Come downstairs. Everyone is waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Helena. What a great party.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gordon takes a sip of his drink. Two SECURITY OFFICERS appear in the doorway behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody. I'm a nobody who arrested you, but your wife is a murderer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you can't be in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security officers grab Gordon. There is a scuffle. Gordon falls to the floor by the window. They are wrestling. As they wrestle, Gordon reaches out and, unnoticed, affixes TINY LISTENING DEVICE underneath the desk. He continues to struggle with the guards. Helena and Carlos start from the room.</context>
      <utterance>Throw him out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't win, Helena. You lost everything. Tell your children a nice bedtime story... How you killed my partner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRESS SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Applause from the assembled PRESS. The Press Secretary signals and Robert walks to the podium. He looks back to the Chief of Staff; he stares out at the expectant faces and television lights and camera flashes.</context>
      <utterance>...a sterling reputation and close friend of the President, recently confirmed into The Office of National Drug Control Policy... our new Drug Czar, Robert Hudson Wakefield.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert is becoming increasingly uneasy. He glances at the Chief of Staff who bores into him. He looks again at his speech. With great effort he continues.</context>
      <utterance>The War on Drugs is a war on our nation's most precious resource... our children. Sixty-eight million children have been targeted by those who perpetrate this war and protecting those children must be priority number one.  There has been progress and there have been failures, but where we have fallen short I see not a problem but an opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robert stops again as though the words are choking him.</context>
      <utterance>An opportunity to correct the mistakes of the past while laying a solid foundation for the future.  This takes not only new ideas, but perseverance. This takes not only resources, but courage. This takes not only government, but families.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't finish. Everyone stares at Robert. The crowd of reporters senses something is wrong.</context>
      <utterance>I've... I've outlined a ten-point plan, representing a new bilateral effort...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If there is a War on Drugs then our own families have become the enemy. How can you wage war on your own family? He walks out of the room. The crowd waits, expecting him to return. Robert walks down a corridor and out of the White House.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAROLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caroline is finished sharing.</context>
      <utterance>On the good days I feel like I get it, like it all makes sense. I can stay in the moment. I don't have to control everything in the future. And I believe everything is going to work out fine.  On the bad days, I just want to grab the phone and start dialing numbers. I want to pull my hair and run through the streets screaming.  But, thanks to the people I've met in these rooms, people like Margaret and Jim and Sarah, people who've taught me how to listen, I'm pretty sure I'll make it through today.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We pan over to reveal Robert and Barbara sitting next to Caroline.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to share?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Robert. This is my wife, Barbara. We're Caroline's parents. We're just hear to listen.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
