<movie id="572" title="Tremors">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OLD FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Old Fred climbs out with a bushel basket of carrots.</context>
      <utterance>She wants to lay down. I'm a little worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I brung her something I know she likes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, Fred, you can't give away all those.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. I got vegetables coming out my ears. Usually the varmints eat up half my crop, but lately I ain't so much as</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We playing cards tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna be sitting up with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd do the same. Well, catch you Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men nod, and Old Fred drives off. CLOSE-UP of the donkey's hooves thumping along as Edgar leads her to the barn. EDGAR (cont'd) Let's get you out of the sun for a spell. EDGAR (cont'd) I'll get you some fresh water. But, suddenly, we hear the donkey restlessly stomping its hooves and braying. Edgar turns, concerned. Now we hear an odd sound. Distant thunder? The wind? The donkey gets more and more frantic. The barn shudders violently. Frightened birds explode from the eaves. Dust puffs from every old seam. Roof shingles rain down. Edgar stares in amazement. EDGAR (cont'd) ...some kind of</context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl is a good-ol' boy who has lived his life just like Val, drifting from job to job. He knows why</context>
      <utterance>You dumb shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did it yesterday. Franks and beans.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...it was eggs. I did eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl raises his fist. This is The Challenge, and it instantly triggers the partners' conflict-resolution technique. They solve all disputes using the children's game of "scissors, rock, paper." Earl raises his fist in response. The game is played swiftly and silently -- one, two, three. On three, Val mimes "paper" (open hand. Earl mimes "scissors" (two extended fingers). Scissors cuts paper. Val has lost. He shrugs and starts pumping up the stove fuel tank. VAL (cont'd) Well, when I'm your age I'll probably forget what I eat, too.</context>
      <utterance>Hell you did. Your turn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many cows does it take to make a stampede? Is it like three or more? Is there a minimum speed?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there was one nearby I'd probably ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep thinking, if we were but half serious about money, we should quit being hired hands and...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Handymen, Earl. We're handymen.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val gestures to the vastness around them.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever the hell we are, we should quit and go get ourselves some real employment.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, and give up all this personal freedom?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn jeep trail gets worse every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl pulls a box of Hershey bars from under the seat. There's only one bar left. He sets the box down between them. Val glances at it -- and raises his fist: The Challenge. One, two, three. Val mimes "paper;" Earl mimes "rock." Earl loses. Val takes the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Has a lot of rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get us hung up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWONK! The truck lurches to a stop, its frame caught on a big rock. Val glares at Earl.</context>
      <utterance>Do not talk to the driver.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...Digging that waterhole for Nestor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt and Heather's place is closer. Let's do their kitchen today. Do Nestor tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Val is peering at the desert up ahead. Off the road a ways is a small Toyota pick-up truck and, beside it, a lone figure trying to flag them down.</context>
      <utterance>Nestor's out of town tomorrow. We don't dig today. We don't get paid today. Damn it, Valentine, you never plan ahead. You never take the long view. Hell, here it is Monday and I'm already working on Wednesday.  It is Monday, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell's that? That's not what's his name...the grad student?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, it's September. Must be the new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl braces himself, knowing what Val will do. Val swerves the truck wildly off the road, barreling across the desert. VAL (cont'd) (almost praying) You</context>
      <utterance>The new one! That's supposed to be a girl!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm up here for the semester...</context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Rhonda. Rhonda LeBeck.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, geography.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, geology. And you have to be Val and Earl. I've heard all about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda smiles.</context>
      <utterance>We deny everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, got a question for you. Do you know if anybody is doing any blasting or drilling or anything like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Around here? Why would they?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm supposed monitor these seismographs. You know, they measure vibrations...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, vibrations in the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, I'm getting what I refer to scientifically as "weird vibes." every sensor I've got is giving me strange readings. I mean, the school has had these machines up here three years and they've never recorded anything like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we'll ask around. Let you know if we hear of anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. God, I hope they're not screwed up. I might have to bag the whole semester. Anyway, sorry to bother you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda unhappily turns back to her equipment as Val and Earl drive off.</context>
      <utterance>No problem. Nice meeting you. Hope you get it sorted out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if you wanted, we could take a look at those seismographs for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell do we know about seismographs?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. But it sure might be a nice way of getting to know her.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, Valentine, you won't go for any gal unless she fits that damn list of yours A to Z...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val flips down the truck's sunvisor. Tapes to it are snap- shots of nearly identical blonde bimbos. Val points to one.</context>
      <utterance>...And is dumber than my hind end. Like that Bobby Lynn Dexter...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tammy Lynn Baxter.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't matter. They're all the same: dead weight. Can't make a decision, can't walk because of their shoes, can't work because of their fingernails. Make my skin crawl!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm a victim of circumstance.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val rolls his eyes -- "Give me a break."</context>
      <utterance>I thought you called it your pecker. Look, don't make the mistake I made. Twenty years of looking for a woman exactly like Miss October 1968, and where'd it get me? Here with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Val and Earl enter, Pham automatically pops the tops on two cold beers and has them in place before the cowboys reach the bar. Everyone exchanged nods.</context>
      <utterance>No, Pham, they're not hollow points. I ordered hollow points and that's what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys, what you been up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ran into the new college student, Rona.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rhonda. Rhonda LeBeck. She's getting some kind of strange readings on her things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eminent domain."</context>
      <utterance>Damn, you know, those kids turn up oil or uranium or something out there...next thing the Feds will be at our door. "Sorry, time to move.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down, honey, down.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Burt. The way you worry, you're gonna have a heart attack before you get to survive World War</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Val, listen. Bearing going out, you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts toward the compressor, but Earl heads him off.</context>
      <utterance>Could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch it later, Pham. Gotta get over to Nestor's.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they turn to go, Val does a take, amazed, as he spots a decorative bleached-out cattle skull displayed on the counter -- with a $29.95 price tag. VAL (cont'd) Hey, Pham Van, what the hell is this?</context>
      <utterance>Right. We plan ahead. That way we don't do anything right now. Earl explained it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A beauty, isn't it? We bought three of them for the rec room.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sell 'em to you for three bucks a piece!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't get it, Pham. The idea was: we were ripping you off. Suddenly a car alarm blares from outside. Burt's out the door in a flash. The others follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Melvin, you little pain-in-the-ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt angrily switches off the alarm. Val and Earl laugh as they climb into their truck.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't me, man! Your truck's just screwed up, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't his parents ever take him to Vegas with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta ask</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl and Val start fishing in their pockets for pen and paper. Earl comes up with various pieces of paper, Val with three or four pens. It's a moment before they realize each has the other needed implement. Earl writes out the bill during: NESTOR (cont'd) I'll have to send it to you the first of the month, boys. Val and Earl exchange pained looks. NESTOR (cont'd) Now, you know I'm good for it.</context>
      <utterance>It came out great, boys. Should fill up just fine come the next rain. Lemme have your bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They amble over to their truck. Earl takes the driver's side -- and starts fishing in his pockets for the key. VAL (cont'd) Are we too easy-going?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Nestor, we know. Don't worry about it. Catch us when you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val realizes he has the key and hands it over.</context>
      <utterance>No, we're not too easy-going. This area is economically depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what if we just did it...today. Pack up. Drive straight down to Bixby. Get serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could. We could. But we'd have to get</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Car wash?! That's got no future. If we're gonna take the plunge we oughta have a better plan than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. Go ahead and plan it...for a year or two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Stop it, you horrid animal!  I'm going to give her back to my son. I swear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Viola, you've got my permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God almighty, my mama sure didn't raise me for this. Val gets up and starts the pump's gas engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well,</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What keeps us doing jobs like this is you dragging your feet. I was up for going to Bixby. I was getting excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the past year I must've said a hundred times "We gotta get out of Perfection. We gotta better ourselves." You gonna stand there in broad daylight and tell me you think I'm the reason we're still here? You want to know how close I am to going to Bixby right</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh oh, it's Nancy. She wants another load of firewood.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy spots them and beckons excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it, man. It's not worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got us. Now, listen, the plan is: we have done our last job in Perfection.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop beside Nancy. While they talk, Nancy's daughter, MINDY (9), comes bouncing along on her pogo-stick, listening to her Walkman and slowly circling the truck.</context>
      <utterance>That's the plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mindy, honey, don't pogo in the street. Hey, guys, I've got a job for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Nancy. We ain't doing odd jobs anymore. We're headed for Bixby permanent.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure...  ...My God, you really are!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep, we're relocating to an area with a greater economic base.  Hey, Mindy, what's the count?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six hundred three, six hundred four, six hundred five...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go for it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl glance at each other -- five hundred dollars!</context>
      <utterance>Gee, guys. I made the big decision. I'm putting in that satellite dish. I was going to offer you five hundred dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did it! We faced temptation and we did not bend!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh, then are thrown half out of their seats as Earl accidentally hits a big pothole.</context>
      <utterance>Damn straight! Now there's nothing between us and Bixby but nothing! They zoom past the sign. VAL  Last time we'll see that sign!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time we hit that goddamn pothole!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So long, cactus!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adios, bridge!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's the plan. We bust our tails in the car wash six months... well, maybe nine...and we don't spend a</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One job I'd never take is working around electricity.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially when it's two hundred feet off the ground. But as the pass the tower: VAL  Hey, hold up...That's Edgar Deems!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're full of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's him, I'm telling you.</context>
      <utterance>He's only got one damn jacket.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real sorry to bother you, Megan, but we figured since Jim's a doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's fine. You did the right thing. When Jim is done we'll call the Coroner's office in Bixby. We'll take care of it.  Poor Edgar.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I see you got all the wallboard up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim climbs out of the pick-up.</context>
      <utterance>That was easy. You two did the hard part. Sure sorry you're leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was is a heart attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He died of dehydration. Thirst.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that doesn't make sense. That takes a couple of days, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three or four even.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean he sat up there three or four</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckon he hated Perfection more than us? You suppose he</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he just couldn't pull the trigger...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, he figured it was easier to die of thirst? Come on, sombody must've chased him up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val has no answer. It's too weird.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean somebody who ain't scared of a twelve gauge shotgun. And then what did they do? Camp out down below and just wait for him to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whatever the hell happened it's just one more goddamn good reason to haul ass out of this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are passing the shack. Earl suddenly realizes: EARL (cont'd) Hey, where the hell's that asshole dog?</context>
      <utterance>You got that right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably up a pole starving itself to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, the plan is: pedal to the metal the whole way. We don't stop till we hit the carwash, not even to pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go with that plan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl is staring wide-eyed. Val follows Earl's gaze and is aghast when he sees -- The sheep pen -- it's a ghastly, bloody mess. Scattered on the churned up ground a few dismembered sheep legs and heads are all that remain of the flock.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl leap out of the truck to investigate.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl dashes into Fred's house. Val checks around outside. Earl comes back out.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Old Fred! Fred! Where are you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they spot something lying in the middle of the garden -- Old Fred's hat. Still looking all around, Val squats distractedly to pick up the hat. He and Earl stumble backward in shock. OLD FRED IS STILL WEARING HIS HAT!! His mangled face stares up at them, eyes and mouth frozen open in a death grimace.</context>
      <utterance>Not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on? I mean WHAT THE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys better get the hell outta here! We got a killer on the loose!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmine stops jackhammering to listen.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he edges over to the truck and takes out a heavy steel pry-bar to keep within easy reach. Carmine goes back to work, pounding the asphalt with the jackhammer. Suddenly the blade strikes something beneath the road, something soft. We hear a strange, unearthly shriek from underground. A weird orange goo gushes up around the blade. Then the jackhammer takes off by itself like a harpoon stuck in a whale! Carmine gets tangled in the jack- hammer's air-hose and is dragged along, shouting for help. Howard chases him down the embankment and into the scrub- brush. He hears Carmine screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now there is only silence. Howard crashes through the brush. All he finds is the torn end of the air-hose -- which suddenly sucks down into the ground. He's momentarily staggered by an awful smell, but forces himself to keep looking. He lets the pry-bar drag on the ground. Then something -- it looks like a mouth or a horrid beak -- shoots out of the ground and grips the pry-bar with uncanny strength! Howard drops his weapon and scrambles madly away. He clambers back onto the road. But almost immediately cracks form in the pavement around him. More beak-things break through the asphalt between him and his truck. He dashes across the road, scrambling up the embankment. He clings precariously to a tree root, looking down -- where'd they go? Suddenly the dirt around him begins to "bubble." Several hungry beaks break through and grab him, yanking him head first into the embankment. Then the embankment gives way, crashing down onto the road, taking with it a nearby telephone pole and snapping the lines.</context>
      <utterance>Carmine! What the hell is it?! Where are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His head? You mean</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something happen to Fred?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious, man? They killed him just to take his</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val stares at the phone.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to Edgar?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this. The phone is out! Pham, your phone is out!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl rush out.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't do it! What's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl hands Val the key.</context>
      <utterance>We've gotta get the police up here. You guys gotta step on it to Bixby.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consider it stepped on.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brother, we decided to leave this place just one day too late, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl points ahead and screams:</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's sure as hell nothing to stop us now. Everybody we know between here and Bixby is already dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Val is in no mood for philosophy. He leaps out and peers into the highway maintenance truck which sits undisturbed, emergency lights still flashing. There's nobody in it. He starts looking around.</context>
      <utterance>Is some higher force at work, here? Are we asking too much of life?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those assholes are supposed to be</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! I don't</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both lean out. The rear tires are clear. Val restarts the truck and tries to pull forward, rocking the truck against some unseen pull. Smoke wells up from the clutch.</context>
      <utterance>I am not!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val slams the truck into low-range four-wheel-drive and revs it. The tires dig in, fighting for traction -- and suddenly the truck lurches free. We hear an eerie shriek mingled with gear and engine noise as Val angrily roars away. EARL (cont'd) Jesus, you can break an axle like that.</context>
      <utterance>You're hung up I tell you. You're gonna burn the clutch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I don't want spend the night out here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell you doing back already?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he stops because they're all staring wide-eyed at the rear of the truck.</context>
      <utterance>You're never going to believe this, but the canyon road...we were on it not two hours ago...well, it's completely...</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl jump out and look where everyone else is looking. Their jaws drop. REVEAL: hanging from the rear axle of their truck and trailing out behind like a nightmare wedding decoration -- a sex foot long, grotesque, fleshy, tentacle. The end gripping the axle looks like a vicious, razor-sharp beak or hook. The trailing end is mutilated, oozing orange goo -- as though the creature was torn in half.</context>
      <utterance>My God...!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unreal! Where'd you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...didn't know we had it...</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like...and eel.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw...eels live in water.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...it's some kind of snake?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or a big mother slug maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt, more daring than the others, pries the thing off the axle with a shovel.</context>
      <utterance>Some kind of mutation...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch, don't touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's dead all right. Tore the damn thing in half.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must've grabbed us. That's why the truck stalled-out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Next time I tell you I'm not hung up...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pham Van leaps over them.</context>
      <utterance>Stalled out your truck? Have to be one strong son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl square their shoulders. This time they're ready for him.</context>
      <utterance>I give you boys five dollars for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, ten dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt is deep in thought.</context>
      <utterance>Damn right fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cold chill spreads through the group. They stare out at the vast, forbidding desert. They suddenly feel alone -- very alone.</context>
      <utterance>Just one of these couldn't eat up off a whole flock of sheep. There's gotta be more out there, a lot more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slick as snot and I'm not lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen lousy bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominating the discussion are Burt and Heather now armed with scoped, magnum hunting rifles. Heather stands guard at a window, peering out into the night.</context>
      <utterance>A man who plans ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Look, we organize, we arm ourselves. We go out, we find those damn snake things, we make 'em extinct.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Burt, we don't even know what they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might be aliens. Who knows?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why go looking for trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If we're not ready...</context>
      <utterance>Miguel, the trouble's come to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phone's out. Road's out. We're on our own.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you two just love it, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt steps over to a faded topographic map on the wall and points out details during:</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Nancy, don't let's get personal. We need to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right. You folks gotta analyze the situation. With that road out we're completely cut off. Got the cliffs to the north, mountains east and west. That's why Heather and me settled here in the first place, geographic isolation.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...there must be dome way to get help.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's what I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How, for chrissake? You gonna walk thirty-eight miles to Bixby?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All heads turn toward Pham Van.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what about Pham Van's saddle horses?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All heads turn toward Val and Earl.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome to them. Does anybody know how to ride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dead. Let's finish in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go into Bixby in the morning.  The concrete blocks are in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The con...! Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep looking at that beautiful sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the sky that's going to be over our roof every night, when we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim digs out a powerful flashlight and heads over toward the generator. Megan lies back, taking a welcome breather. After a moment:</context>
      <utterance>We could always buy a new generator.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what's wrong with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's...gone...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure this is where it was?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(points with flashlight) It was right there. There's the cord. The severed electric cable stops at the edge of a cone-shaped depression in the dirt where the generator sat. He hands her the flashlight and kneels. We watch tensely as he probes the loose earth with his hands. JIM (cont'd) Maybe the ground caved in. There's a lot of old mines and stuff around here. Megan grabs his shirt, trying to pull him back.</context>
      <utterance>Am I sure?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, about ten feet away -- WHOOMP!! The generator shoots up out of the ground! Jim and Megan dive for cover as it sails through the air, and crashes to earth. They stare, transfixed. The generator is dented and bent almost beyond recognition -- and covered with oozing slime.</context>
      <utterance>Well don't then! You don't want to fall in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Megan is all action. She yanks him back.</context>
      <utterance>What the...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Get away from it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We again hear that mysterious rumbling sound. Jim stops, sweeping the flashlight around them. JIM (cont'd) Hear that?</context>
      <utterance>God, what a stink!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pham, we don't want to be stuck on a couple of canners. They better be fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax. A snake thing like that couldn't move too quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw you. For all you know they could</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So does Earl. He raises his hand. They swiftly do a round of scissors-rock-paper. Earl loses. He hands Val the rifle. Just then, Burt and Heather pull up in their Blazer, climbing out with their hunting rifles.</context>
      <utterance>The rifle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys all set?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready as we'll ever be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather and I are going to drive around a little, see if we can find that college girl and tell her to get her ass back into town.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl mount up.</context>
      <utterance>Good idea. And we'll swing by the doctor's place. They were going to go into Bixby but we don't know if they left before the road was out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl takes the awesome-looking gun with a smug glance at Val.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on. You guys oughta take something that packs more punch than that thirty-thirty. Take one of our Browning autos, or even my model seventy...  It's three-seventy-five H and H mag.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heather unhooks a box of cartridges from her belt and hands it to Earl. Suddenly there's a blood-curdling SCREAM! The door to Pham Van's flies open. Out staggers Melvin, wrapped in Pham Van's hook-tentacle, writhing in apparent agony.</context>
      <utterance>Gee...thanks, Heather. Hope we don't need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People scatter like sheep. Burt and Heather have guns trained on him in an instant. Then everyone realizes it's a sick joke. Melvin collapses with laughter. Burt is livid. He almost shot Melvin. He charges over and yanks the kid to his feet, screaming:</context>
      <utterance>IT'S GOT ME! IT's GOT ME! AAAAHGH!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stupid punk! You came</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...you fellas watch yourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back with the Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ride out to an adlib chorus: "Keep your heads down;" "Go careful, boys;" "Keep a sharp lookout;" etc.</context>
      <utterance>Sheriff, like hell. Come back with the National Guard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val doesn't want to hear it.</context>
      <utterance>You know, we can't possibly make Bixby by nightfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means we're gonna be out here, like, in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Faint Country and Western radio music drifts to them. They're nearing Jim and Megan's house.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. He opens the door and peers inside. Behind him Earl steps out of the half-finished house and shrugs. Nobody around. Wind rustles the plastic sheeting over the windows. Strangely they can still hear the muffled radio clearly.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, doctor, anybody here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Car's gone. We just missed them, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They focus on the sound and walk gingerly toward it, keeping constant watch in every direction. The ground here is all torn up like the sheep pen -- and the music is coming from</context>
      <utterance>Then where's the goddamn Conway Twitty coming from?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! They got wind of something they don't like!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws his rifle. They look wildly in all directions at once -- but there's nothing, only empty desert. VAL (cont'd) But I don't see anything! They keep staring. The horses keep pacing nervously. Then -- Earl's horse rears wildly and falls! Earl goes flying. Val wheels around wildly, dismounts and runs to Earl, who's bruised and winded but basically unhurt. They think Earl's horse just tripped. VAL (cont'd) Hey, you okay? You okay?</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes bulge. Several "snake things" have engulfed the horse's head, sucking, crushing, slurping. Val's horse goes berserk and gallops for the horizon. EARL (cont'd) What in the name...?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...yeah.  What about the hor...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how they get you! They're under the goddamn</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val raises his rifle and takes a well-aimed shot, hitting one of them. Orange goo spurts out. We hear a deafening shriek as all the "snake things" instantly zip back underground. Then -- A HUGE MOUND OF EARTH RISES UP UNDER VAL AND EARL!! The cowboys tumble down its side, Val losing his rifle. They roll over and stare dumbfounded at the mound. VAL (cont'd) (gasps) There must be a million of them!! The mound of earth turns toward them. The ground splits open and out rises -- a huge head!</context>
      <utterance>Sons of bitches!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as if that weren't enough, Earl points to more trouble ahead.</context>
      <utterance>It's gaining on us!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leap and -- they don't do it!! They smack into the opposite side of the ditch, clawing frantically at the lip, only to tumble to its sloping bottom. A split second later the charging creature slams like a wrecking ball into the foot-thick concrete wall! The wall CRACKS AND BULGES OUT! A hook-tentacle flops out through one of the cracks! Terrified Val and Earl scramble away. But the wall holds together. And the, strangely, all is quiet. The tentacle lays dead still. Eventually, the cowering cowboys dare to creep back a little closer, still panting, exhausted, jumpy.</context>
      <utterance>We can do it, we can do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now orange slime begins to ooze through the cracks in the concrete.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid son of a bitch...knocked itself cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly shakes his fist at the dead beast. VAL (cont'd) You FUCKER!! They allow themselves a small wheeze of nervous laughter, only to jump like rabbits as some pebbles rattle loudly down the concrete wall behind them. They whirl to see Rhonda, up on the opposite side of the ditch, staring down at them. She's lugging a bunch of her equipment, including a small folding shovel.</context>
      <utterance>Cold, my ass! It's dead! We killed the bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl look at each other, then burst out laughing. Rhonda spots the cracked wall. RHONDA (cont'd) What's that?</context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys, how're you doing? Look, can I ask you something? Did you just notice something weird? Vibrations? You know, some kind of earth tremor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...think it smells like that 'cause it's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see any eyes...must be totally subterranean...and those tentacles...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they shoot right outta its mouth, hook you, and pull you right in. Good thing we stopped it before it killed anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm lucky it didn't find</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is one big mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, stepping down to study the creature. The body is stream-lined, cigar-shaped, maybe eight feet in diameter at its thickest. It's covered with</context>
      <utterance>So this is the guy that had your seismos working overtime?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Rhonda interrupts -- now really scared.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, don't want to winch it. That'd tear it all up. Want to lift it. Some kind of crane with lifting straps.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val and Earl shut right up. Earl edges up a fencepost. Val sidles up onto a rock during:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, shut up! The way I figure it. There are five more of these things!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda paws through her unwieldy printouts, pointing out jagged ink lines on the graphs, comparing different ones.</context>
      <utterance>Five more?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men leap from their perches and hustle her in the direction she came from.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, darn it, look. I've got seismographs all over the valley. If you compare the different readings, there have to be five. Here's one at two o'clock yesterday, but here's another one three miles away at the same time. So that's two. Now, here...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take your word for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Where's your truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She indicates what to most of us would be a hill, dotted with huge boulders thrusting out of the sandy desert soil like big mushrooms. The trio jogs toward the hill.</context>
      <utterance>The other side of that dome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prairie dog burrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda tenses as she hears a sound she knows well -- the soft scratching of the seismograph needle across its paper cylinder. She whacks Val on the shoulder and points speechlessly at it.</context>
      <utterance>Little sons of bitches.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least the bastard can't climb. Pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably couldn't move too easily on the surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, the live ones smell worse tan the dead ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda points. They can see the roof of her truck, maybe a hundred yards away through the boulders. Val and Earl think about it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, now, how far's your truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. If this one's any faster than that other one...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we wait right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing like them in the fossil record, I'm sure...Okay, so they predate the fossil record...  That'd make them a couple of billion years old...and we've just never seen one till now. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd vote for outer space. No way those are local boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atomic testing. Or, no, bio- engineering! The government built them, a</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it is. Why don't you take a little stroll and see?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, too. Pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we've got to do</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a god</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all settle back, having no idea what to do next. Rhonda gazes out at the desert that surrounds them like an ocean. RHONDA (cont'd) I always wanted to be stuck on a desert island. But somehow I always imagined, you know, water.</context>
      <utterance>Of course! It can sense the slightest seismic vibration...hear every move we make. Especially on this rock. It's a perfect conductor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I hate to be crude, but I'm gonna have to take care of some business here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silhouettes shift, Val and Earl moving down one side of the rock, and Rhonda down the other. We can no longer see them. We just head zippers zipping down -- then soft sighs of relief from Val and Earl. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Same here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. But I'll tell you, if you ever wanted proof God is a man, this is it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Val glances at Earl, who looks away. Who, me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl gropes through his pockets, coming up with only cigarettes. Val fishes in his own pockets, finding only their lighter. They exchange items and light up during:</context>
      <utterance>No problem. Anytime.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, folks, what's the plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time he tosses a piece of wood out onto the sand. With soft rustling, a bulge forms in the earth, moves over to the wood, then subsides. Rhonda starts looking around during:</context>
      <utterance>First let's see if Stumpy's still out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't he have a home to go to?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's why Edgar never got down off that tower.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might have an idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna have to come up with some kind of plan or it's just gonna wait us to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was wondering if we could...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda gives up on them. She goes over and pulls a long cross rail from the fence during:</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's just run for it. We outran that one yesterday, at least on a sprint.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run for it? Running's not a plan. Running is what you do when the plan fails. You're not even trying to come up with a plan!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not like we've got a hell of a lot of options...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think it's still following us?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's assume that it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda and Val nod. Rhonda grips her car keys in her teeth.</context>
      <utterance>And once we hit that truck we gotta go fast. I say we all jump together.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all vault in unison, landing in the truck bed. Rhonda scrambles up, slides open the cab's rear window, and begins wriggling through headfirst.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. One, two, three...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val leaps out and jumps into his pick-up truck. He searches for the key.</context>
      <utterance>We better get everybody together.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go north, I'll go south.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val holds out his hand for the key. Earl tosses it to him. Val drives off. We FOLLOW Rhonda and Earl as they drive the other way, toward Viola's.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet you're sorry the college ever sent you up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm scared, but I'm not sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda sees straight through Earl's clumsy attempt at match- making. She can't help but smile. Earl grins sheepishly. EARL (cont'd) All right, I'm about as subtle as a donkey's ass. Pardon my French. I'm just saying the boy's got potential, that's all. MOVE IN on Rhonda -- her and Val?</context>
      <utterance>You know, Val went to that college, too. For a whole year. Couldn't quite sit still for it, though. Had too much vinegar in his system. But once he settles down, forgets this cowboy stuff, he'll be one in a million.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You serious, Val? You think we're not even safe here in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask me that after you meet one. I think we should all get the hell out while the getting's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not just take a Number Ten pick axe and give it one good whack...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nestor, damn it, these things are bigger than an Airstream trailer!</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy rushes out.</context>
      <utterance>God, I've got to find Mindy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pham, where's Burt and Heather?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't raise them. I guess they're still out there somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you've got a radio, why aren't you calling somebody in Bixby? The police or...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know, because of the mountains.</context>
      <utterance>Can't reach outside the valley.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rhonda, what's the name you call those things, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd they come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a scientist, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have a theory at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, these things are absolutely unprecedented!</utterance>
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but where'd they come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd they come from? Okay, worms, probably in the Jurassic period. Cosmic radiation was much higher then...so they mutated...and they got so big they just sank right into the ground and fell asleep... But now continental drift has brought them to the surface, ready to be harvested by the ancient alien meat growers who planted them here. Everybody stares at her, then they smile, realizing she's pulling their legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, don't matter where they come from.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. We need to be talking about what we're gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My goodness, Valentine, once they see the road is out and the phone lines are down, someone will be along to look in on us. Don't you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no no, they</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spots he indicates describe a line leading along the valley straight toward town. VAL (cont'd) This valley's just one long smorgasbord and if we don't haul ass outta here we're the next course. We hear an a eerie SHRIEK from outside. Something shoots in through the window, striking Earl in the chest!! Earl flails frantically at it -- but it's only Melvin's basketball. We glimpse Melvin outside, doubled over with laughter. Earl grabs the ball and hurls it viciously back, but Melvin easily dodges it.</context>
      <utterance>They caught up with Edgar here. They grabbed Old Fred here. They nailed the asshole dog here. And the doctor's place is here...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You little ass wipe! You knock that off or you're gonna be shitting that basketball! Pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Val, let's assume they're as dangerous as you say. Where are we going to go that's safer than right here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rhonda's got an idea about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, see, they move very easily through the Pleistocene Alluvials...  ...the dirt...the loose soil that makes up the valley floor. But they can't move through solid rock. I think we should travel west to the mountains.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, up the jeep trail.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mountains are solid granite. We'd be safe there, and we could hike along them...all the way to Bixby if we have to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Valentine, I'm not leaving my place.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's gonna take us days to get back with help.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Then, to Melvin's astonishment, the steady rhythm of his bouncing basketball suddenly stops. The ball just goes flup and doesn't bounce back up to him. He looks down. No ball! Just swirling dust at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Doggone it, Viola, it's just plain crazy to stay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna kick his ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! Man, you gut a gun?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big as a house! What are we gonna do...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miguel and Pham shut up. Then we hear something new -- the building itself creaking and groaning like a ship. The liquor bottles behind Pham Van's bar vibrate and clink. The creature is moving beneath the building. The people freeze like mannequins. Now we can hear its pig-like snorting. Pham Van and Miguel react as the awful smell percolates up through the floorboards. Val signals them to keep quiet. Finally, the creaking stops. Rhonda addresses the group in an intense whisper:</context>
      <utterance>Quiet! QUIET!!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone stands stock still -- and sweats. But, then, slowly we become aware of a faint, yet oddly familiar sound. Squeak, squeak, squeak -- Mindy on her pogo stick! They all scramble to the windows.</context>
      <utterance>Remember...no noise. No vibration.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val claps his hand over her mouth. She goes wide eyed as she sees: her pogo stick standing straight up in the cracked asphalt! Then it is sucked down like so much spaghetti! Nancy rushes into frame, hugging Mindy. Val signals her to be quiet. They sit uneasily. Where's the creature? Suddenly the pogo stick erupts out of the earth right in their midst! Val runs one way, Nancy and Mindy the other, heading up the street toward their house. Val scrambles up onto his pick-up truck! The creature rams the truck, rupturing a tire. As it shakes the truck violently, Val spots Rhonda and Earl, now standing uncertainly halfway between him and Pham Van's.</context>
      <utterance>Oww! Val, you hurt me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda and Earl hesitate.</context>
      <utterance>Go back, for chrissake!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Earl now hears something behind them! Down the street, a little wall of cinder blocks framing Viola's driveway suddenly topples over.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta get him off there. It'll suck that truck down!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. Rhonda, another one!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dive through the open door of Pham Van's. The rippling boards zoom on past it. Earl quickly eases the door shut.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Come on! Don't look back! Just run! Run like screaming fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon my French.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You paying attention? This oughta hurt like hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does. She smiles at him. RHONDA  So, is that one of your usual jobs, saving peoples' lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gazes at him. He looks away. Over at the bar, Pham holds up a new pair of pants for Rhonda.</context>
      <utterance>First time for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grateful for something to do, Val eases over to get the pants. Rhonda looks after him. Then she becomes aware of someone staring at</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got the patience of Job. They just sit and goddamn wait til they hear something that sounds like lunch. We need a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hike to Bixby. Get us some help.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a plan. You and Val take your truck, get to the mountains.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those scumsuckers are my radials, Pham!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we can take my truck then.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all shut up when they hear Viola's dog yapping in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>No good. You need major four- wheel-drive just to get up that jeep trail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut it up! Shut the little bastard up!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chuck him out the door! Like a little hors d'oeuvre.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VIOLA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The trailer is finally knocked right off its foundation! It tips over and tumbles all the way down the hill! As the dust clears, all is silent. A huge hole is torn in the trailer's floor. Viola's possessions are scattered everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Get away! Get away! Oh God in heaven, help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitchin' lowlife, putrid, scum...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta do something. Gotta get the bastards!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, what the hell can we</utterance>
   <speaker>PHAM VAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone turns away from the windows, gingerly sitting down, glumly pondering this possibility. There is a long silence. Then suddenly -- ROAR! The silence is shattered as Pham Van's big freezer compressor suddenly comes on.</context>
      <utterance>Now wait a minute, Earl. I got enough food here to last us for weeks. Those damn things can't wait around forever.  We can do it. I mean, if we have to, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pham runs to the freezer. Its on/off switch is buried behind stacks of soft-drink cases. He tears at them like a madman, toppling them this way and that. Earl and Val join him. But right behind Pham, the floor BUCKLES UP, a monster's snout BURSTING THROUGH and engulfing one of his legs! The creature starts to back down into the jagged hole, dragging screaming Pham with it. Val, Earl, Rhonda, and Miguel grab Pham's arms but are no match for the monster. It shakes and spins him like some gigantic dog, effortlessly throwing them off, relentlessly pulling Pham down. The hole in the floor is</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Shut it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl leaps from the bar to the rear shelves. Val and Miguel slide sideways till they're beneath the hatch, then use the shelves as a ladder, climbing up to the hatch. Val pounds on it frantically. In the middle of the store, Rhonda leaps from shelf to shelf, trying to get closer to where Val is. Soon she reaches the last one, balancing precariously. But a creature tips over the first one! The shelves topple like dominoes, crashing toward Rhonda. She is half catapulted, half jumps right through an open window, ripping through the screen. Val sees what's happened. With maniacal strength he smashes open the hatch and climbs out onto --</context>
      <utterance>Everybody! This way! The roof!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down where Rhonda fell. She's not there. He hears a whistle and is relieved to see:</context>
      <utterance>Rhonda! Keep moving. Don't stop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What's going on, man?! What the hell you doing up there...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's too late. Wham! A creature strikes. The little shed shudders, dust puffing from every old seam. In a split second Melvin has climbed to the shed roof.</context>
      <utterance>Melvin, shut the hell up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The store shakes and shimmies. We hear the monster's thunderous crashing from below.</context>
      <utterance>Get up on your roof! On your roof! They can come through the floor!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you shout a little quieter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it. No tracks, no sign, no spoor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, whatever they are, you'd think after they ate all those sheep they'd have to take a dump someplace...  What the hell's going on in town?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val stares at him, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, here's the plan: Nestor's Cadillac. His tires are nine hundred sixteens. We sprint for it, grab the spare, put it on our truck with our spare.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell long it take</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, down in the store, Pham Van's CB radio squawks loudly.</context>
      <utterance>We need another plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The building shudders as the creatures again smash through the floor inside, looking for the source of the noise. Val, Earl and Miguel scramble to the edge of the roof.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, P.V., Burt here. Come back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative copy on that, Pham, check your frequency. I'm on forty-nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt, can you hear me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few feet away Heather works at their ammunition reloading bench. She dumps a few hundred empty cartridge cases into a case cleaner and switches it on. It HUMS loudly as it vibrates.</context>
      <utterance>Just barely, Pham. What are you all doing up on your roofs. What the hell's going on? Come back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val talks a little louder into the mic. INTERCUT as needed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, they're going, man! I think they're going for Burt!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt! This is Val! Get out of your basement!! Take your radio! You and Heather get up on your roof! Then we'll talk, okay?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Val? What the hell you doing back already?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt, get out! Get up on your roof or someplace! We found out what's been killing people! They're under the ground!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's under the ground? We're not getting up on the roof. Earth shelter's the best. Known that since I was a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're coming right now!</context>
      <utterance>Listen! Listen! We know what they are! They're big things under the ground! Much bigger than we thought! They're coming after you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val is frantic. How do you explain these things?</context>
      <utterance>We don't see anything, Val. Now what the hell are you talking about? Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're coming</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The CB goes dead. The men stare numbly. Then, drifting across the desert, a soft popping sound. The men perk up; they know what it is -- distant gunfire.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Chri...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got one! They killed one of the sons of bitches!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to go, dudes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val grabs the CB mic.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess we don't get to make fun of Burt's lifestyle anymore, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt, any chance you can get the rest of them?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the elephant gun and takes two well-aimed shots -- two deafening BOOMS which echo off the distant mountains. But the bullets bury themselves harmlessly in the dirt. The bulge in the dirt moves calmly away and sinks from view. Heather shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>One second, Val.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not getting any penetration, even with the elephant gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn!  Val, we can't get them. Never figured on having to shoot through dirt! Best goddamn bullet stop there is. Come back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Burt, listen. Forget shooting them. Tell me this: can you get to your truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Rhonda interrupts, pointing urgently from the water tower.</context>
      <utterance>Good. You've got the only truck in the valley that can make it up that damn jeep trail. So, here's the plan: You and Heather go for help. Get to the mountains...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val, Earl and Miguel rush to the edge of the roof and look down where she's pointing -- A creature is running its tentacles along the building's foundation. It's a strange, more studied movement than we've seen before.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, guys! They're up to something.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all stare nervously down as the tentacles feel their way along the wall, moving toward a corner of the building. Suddenly Miguel spots something down the next wall.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you all keep asking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another set of tentacles is feeling along the adjacent wall. The two creatures meet at the corner, their tentacles touch- ing rather like ants' antennae. They they submerge; tenta- cles zipping into the earth. Nothing happens for a moment. Then the corner of the building suddenly heaves up a couple of feet. Clapboard siding splits. A warped window shatters. (We don't see the creatures, only the effect of their shoving from below). The men nearly lose their balance. Then the corner sinks back down.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, there's another one coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why they bothering them for?</context>
      <utterance>They weren't making no noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda chimes in from the water tower.</context>
      <utterance>They're studying the buildings... trying to figure them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they're confused. They can feel our vibrations, but they can't find us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're working together, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like they got a plan...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breaker there, Earl. What do you want us to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on, Burt. The bastards are up to something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt! Heather!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Val.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A hump of dirt raises near the base of the house. Burt jerks the rifle to his shoulder and squeezes off a shot. The hump moves away from the house.</context>
      <utterance>We're in deep shit over here. Let's change that plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off, Burt!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I scared it!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Still moving away, the hump of dirt passes under the side- walk, rippling the flagstones gently.</context>
      <utterance>Forget going for help. We'll all be dead long before you get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here, Val. Just tell us what you need. Come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The hump of dirt passes under Burt and Heather's truck, rocking the vehicle slightly.</context>
      <utterance>They're tearing down the houses here! We all gotta get outta here together! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truck's security alarm starts BOOPING! Burt and Heather stare down helplessly as the noisy truck is furiously attacked by the frenzied creatures. Dust flies as metal rips and tires shred.</context>
      <utterance>We're with you, Val. We'll come get everybody. Just hang on tight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Val, we're going to have to forget about the truck...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you better think of</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miguel nods in agreement. Val and Earl stare at him, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>You and Val, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!! Since when the hell's every goddamn thing up to us?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Rhonda tries her desperate best to be logical:</context>
      <utterance>We don't have a hell of a lot of time here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There must be</context>
      <utterance>Look, the situation hasn't changed. We still have to get to solid rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a helicopter is what we need, or a goddamn tank...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute...the Cat. Could we take the Cat?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. It's slower than hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it weighs better than thirty tons. No way they could stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Val is warming to the idea.</context>
      <utterance>We can't all fit on that bulldozer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...we could pull something! We could, I don't know, drag a car behind it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A car, huh? Like a big armored car? Need something bigger, tougher...our truck maybe...or, hell, that old semi trailer!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its tires are flat...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter. The cat can pull</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, good! Something to keep them busy. We need a decoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Melvin, you wanna make a buck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miguel grabs Earl and points down at little garden tractor in a jumble of Pham Van's equipment and tools near the side of the store.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how about the tractor? Start him up. Let him go by itself. Let those things chase it all over is they like that noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The store takes a heavy hit. The front porch collapses with a terrific crash.</context>
      <utterance>Not bad.  What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the ground's getting closer. I think we do it. We're gonna save our asses here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! How are you going to know they're all following it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good point.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val scrambles to the highest point of the sagging roof and shouts to Nancy. VAL (cont'd) Nancy, we gotta find all four of them. How many you got over there?</context>
      <utterance>We got two right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one. I think one.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come back.</context>
      <utterance>Burt, Heather, we got a little sort of a plan going here, maybe. Can you tell if you've still got any of those things out at your place?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, still got one poking around.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's four. Let us know if it starts moving, Burt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going...  There goes this one! It's going!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Earl is poised to leap. Val steps up and slaps him on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, this guy just took off like a shot. What'd you people do?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch your ass, shithead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val instantly elbows Earl hard in the stomach. As Earl doubles over, Val springs off the edge of the roof. EARL (cont'd) You goddamn suicidal son of a bitch! We see Val running for all he's worth -- and there's the bulldozer at the edge of town a</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about me, jerkoff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val sees, almost right above them, an exposed pipe which spans the ditch. He shoves Melvin toward it. They leap up and grab the pipe, pulling their legs up as high as they can. An instant later, the creature blasts through one wall of the ditch, roars past beneath them and burrows into the opposite wall! Earl brings the bulldozer to a thundering stop next to them.</context>
      <utterance>We got about three seconds!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go you two. We're headed for the mountains.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a coil of blackpowder cannon fuse. He cuts off a length and stuffs it in the end of one of the pipe bombs during:</context>
      <utterance>In a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt hefts the finished bomb.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Burt, we can't hold still long. They're damn smart and getting smarter by the minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine. We've got some new things to teach them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then the bulldozer starts to tilt sideways, creatures digging dirt away beneath it. Earl guns it forward out of the depression they're making.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it! They'll sink this rig just like a boat!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt and Heather are impressed. They rush around the rooftop, gathering food, ammo, guns, the finished bombs, handing them to impatient Val who hands them down to people in the semi trailer during:</context>
      <utterance>See that? They're doing it now! They try it every time we hold still.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, we're only going nine miles. Be there in two hours, tops!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up to rifles to Heather, the HK91 assault rifle and another elephant gun.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well those things are gonna be on our ass every foot of the way, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think? Max firepower or...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt nods. Everyone on the bulldozer and semi trailer shouts:</context>
      <utterance>I'd go for penetration. The 458 shooting solids -- less ammo to carry anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNSFOLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dust flies up. The bulldozer tilts. Earl guns it forward again. Heather and Burt grab a few more things and leap down into the semi trailer.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Who cares! Forget it! Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a gun! I'll take one!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't give</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they just gave up, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they top a gentle rise, Burt excitedly points ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the bulldozer's too much for them, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone cheers. But then Heather points up ahead to one side.</context>
      <utterance>There we go, solid rock!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else could it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they're taking a dump.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going over there, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We go straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it. What the hell are they doing? They're up to something.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl shoves the throttle all the way. The engine screams.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care what they're doing as long as they're doing it way over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The idling bulldozer engine coughs and dies. There is a moment's crushing silence. Then the dreaded digging begins. Dust boils up around the semi trailer -- creatures digging from below! The semi trailer shakes and shudders, slowly sinking. The people huddle together in sheer panic. Val and Earl grab the nearest of Burt and Heather's guns and fire wildly, hope- lessly, down at the dirt. Ricochets whine into the distance. Burt grimly digs an overloaded knapsack for one of his pipe bombs. He leaps up between Val and Earl and lights the fuse, looking for a target.</context>
      <utterance>They...they dug a trap! I can't believe this!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses the bomb at some churning earth and dives back into the semi trailer. BURT (cont'd) Keep your heads down! KABOOM! The explosion throws up a big plume of dust and rocks. We hear a</context>
      <utterance>Hungry?! Eat this!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Burt...did you get one...!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, there's still four of them. See...there's like four different dust trails.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure got their attention, though. Nice going, Burt.  Earl, what about the Cat? Earl's already staring down at the bulldozer.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val looks around.</context>
      <utterance>No way. It's down for the count.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heather unexpectedly fire two deafening blasts from her elephant gun at the approaching creatures, then shakes her head, frustrated. They're still coming.</context>
      <utterance>Here they come! They're coming back!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, everybody! We gotta run for those rocks over there!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Val, it's pretty far.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, man! They'll get us!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There sure as hell get us if we stay here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait, listen. Burt do you have any more of those things?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bombs? Damn right I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what is you throw one</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It</context>
      <utterance>I don't think it does scare them!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. We're gonna run. Get ready. Val squats in front of tear-streaked Mindy. VAL  Mindy, you understand what we're going to do?  And don't worry, they can't get us once we're on those rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Burt readies another bomb, he pauses to hand bug-eyed Melvin a huge Ruger Super Redhawk 44 magnum handgun.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, man. They're too fast! You can't outrun them, no way!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melvin's eyes bug out further. Burt lights his bomb. BURT (cont'd) Heads down!! He hurls the bomb. Wait. Wait. WHOOOM! Again we hear the creatures' unearthly shriek of pain. Rhonda's on her feet before the rocks stop falling. She spots the creatures.</context>
      <utterance>Here, kid. This'll make'em think twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It worked! There they go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asshole! There's no bullets in this gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt's line gets a laugh from people, but then tentacles burst up on all sides of the rock, probing, feeling. The effect is instantly sobering. Burt swiftly grabs out his remaining bombs -- six of them -- and holds one ready. But they're in no immediate danger.</context>
      <utterance>Got you moving, didn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could we make it to the mountains?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hopelessness of the situation suddenly hits Val, Earl, and Rhonda. After a moment:</context>
      <utterance>No way. We'd need fifty of those things.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...that's it. We're not getting off this rock...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's for sure.</context>
      <utterance>Not going to pole vault anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you? What are you talking about?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As this sinks in, Burt loses his cool, igniting an argument.</context>
      <utterance>They'll just wait out there till we're dead. That's what they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Well, for chrissake, we could have made a stand at our place! We had food, water...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't fight'em that way...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two jackasses hauled us way the hell out here...!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who put you two in charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burt! Those animals would have killed you! Everyone stares in surprise at normally quiet Nancy. NANCY   You haven't seen what they can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, Burt picks up a bomb and contemplates it:</context>
      <utterance>They'd have dug your place out from under you in half an hour! There's a long, grim silence. Everyone sits glumly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it comes to starvation, I know what</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others react. Is Earl nuts?</context>
      <utterance>You know, that's not a bad idea!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>going fishing like...</context>
      <utterance>No, I mean, it gives me an idea...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt has his coil of fuse.</context>
      <utterance>There! Right straight out in front of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burt nods, expertly eyeballing a fifteen second length and snipping it off. As he stuffs it into the bomb:</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... They're pretty quick...fifteen seconds?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cannon fuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you're not going to do your lasso thing...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val shakes his head and lights the fuse. Earl whirls the bomb on the end of its rope like a lasso, and lets it fly out as far as he can. Then he starts pulling it back in along the ground like a fishing lure. Rhonda stares at her watch as they all sink down behind the protective boulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, just 'cause you're no good with a rope...</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on...come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a snout subtly surfaces and gulps down the bomb. A tense two seconds later -- KABOOOM! Bullseye! It's a volcano of gory creature parts. They splatter all over! The remaining creatures shriek and race away again. The people cheer wildly.</context>
      <utterance>Take it...take the bait...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before she can fire, the creatures mysteriously sink from view. Val, Rhonda, and Earl remain frozen. What the hell is going on? Nothing happens -- then -- A HUGE HUMP OF EARTH suddenly wells up near Rhonda. It sinks back down as fast as it appeared. It's like the creature suddenly lifted its whole body almost to the surface then submerged again. Another hump rises and falls right near Val and Earl. There's a pause as the men whisper:</context>
      <utterance>I'll make'em pay attention goddamnit...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're...they're trying to make us move!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or just knock us over. Look, use the bomb!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creatures try another random "barrage" of humps, some coming perilously close. They know they'll eventually topple their prey. One comes so close to Val and Earl that pebbles roll down its sides into their boots!</context>
      <utterance>It's out last one. We can't kill them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use the fucking bomb!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we get back on that rock and in three days we're dead anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He veers off in a new direction. Startled Earl and Rhonda have no choice but to follow. As they desperately try to catch up to Val:</context>
      <utterance>No wait! This way!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they skid to a stop at the very brink, Val breaks off the bomb fuse, leaving only one inch of it. He whirls to check the progress of the advancing creatures.</context>
      <utterance>This better be one great plan!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the bomb out to Rhonda. She instantly tries to light it. He grabs her wrist so hard it hurts.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Light it, man! LIGHT IT!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The charging creatures are almost underfoot. Finally Val pulls Rhonda's hand over to light the fuse. Instantly he hurls the bomb as far as he can,</context>
      <utterance>Not yet, not yet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A highway maintenance truck is rolling into town followed by a police car. The townsfolk happily swarm around the MAINTENANCE MEN and POLICE OFFICER who gape at the destroyed town. Val and Earl eagerly start bolting on one of their new wheels.</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Road's in!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Road's in! Now, soon as we hit Bixby we start making phone calls. We could make some real money off this whole thing, get in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...but no ties.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rhonda pulls up in her truck, leans out and snaps their picture with a top-of-the-line Nikon.</context>
      <utterance>No ties.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys. Burt loaned me his camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Rhonda.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really leaving, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet. You gonna be staying up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RHONDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward pause. Finally she extends her hand to them. Val just gives it a quick shake. RHONDA (cont'd) Uh...well, maybe I'll see you two sometime... (to Val) And thanks for everything, you know, saving my life and stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah! There's going to be major research up here. First thing is to get some pictures of that one we dug up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gazes at him, just a hint of something in her eyes. Earl springs to attention. Is the boy</context>
      <utterance>Well...you're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, Val, maybe she's not your type, but you could, at least, be civil.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Civil? I'm civil.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not civil, you're glum. We got the world by the tail with a downhill pull and all of a sudden you go glum on me. Earl freezes as a bell goes off in his head. EARL  Oh my God. She got to you. You</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Val glares at Earl for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>She just practically asked you for a date. What the hell is wrong?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl is dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>Earl, get real. What does she need with a guy like me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that? All this time she's not good enough for you. Now, suddenly, you're not good enough for her? God, my work is never done.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, make the mistakes I did. I think I'll just be playing this hand myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Think about this: She ain't as narrow-minded as you. I'll lay odds she's looking for character in a man. For my part, I'd be proud to have her. I'd goddamn worship her. Earl hops into the truck. EARL  I'm going out there right now, help her take those pictures...set up her seismo-jiggers. Whatever she wants. Who the hell</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
