<movie id="541" title="TRON">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that the completed form is man-like, heroic and muscular, wearing a form of flexible armor. The face is calm, handsome and intelligent. As the voice continues, the form becomes rounded by the computer until it appears three dimensional and begins to rotate.</context>
      <utterance>As astonishing advances in computer science are made, artificial intelligence programs are being designed to assist us in every area of life...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>The figure is rotated completely around, and as it comes back to face us, a glowing disk appears beside it; again in response to the programming printed out at the side of the screen. The disk moves towards the man-like figure and is rotated into position above it. As the voice reaches the final word, the disk is slammed into place on the back of the figure. There is an explosion of colored light, a resounding crash of MUSIC and the title appears across the top of the screen in huge letters.</context>
      <utterance>In a world-wide network of electronics, they travel through miles of circuitry at the speed of light. We created them to calculate and research, to help us design and heal and think. With all that they can do, are they only electrical impulses... or are they a new form of life?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme play you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, if you've got another quarter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WARRIOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sark, my man! You are hot!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARRIOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sark and the other blue warriors LAUGH RAUCOUSLY, and Sark moves on.</context>
      <utterance>That knuckleball gets 'em every time, boy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>MCP</mode>
      <context>The feet sockets glow and we see Sark absorbing the energy like a drug addict, eyes glazed.</context>
      <utterance>You're getting brutal, Sark. Brutal and needlessly sadistic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank. you, Master Control.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We might be capturing some military programs soon... that interest you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'd love to go up against some of these guys ... be a nice break from these accounting creampuffs you keep sending me. Which branch of the service?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sockets glow 'more intensely as the hologram disappears, and we CUT FROM a CLOSE SHOT of Sark's satiated face to:</context>
      <utterance>Strategic Air Command. SARK  Nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAPTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CROM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, this is all a mistake. I'm just a compound interest program, I work at a savings and loan. I can't play in these video games...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you can, pal. You're a natural athlete, I ever saw one. Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Me? I run out to check an the T-Bill rates, I get out of breath. Hey, really...you're gonna make my User, Mr. Henderson, really mad. He's a full branch manager...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop in front of a cell, the guard opens the door and shoves the protesting captive inside. The door SLAMS shut, locked.</context>
      <utterance>Great, another religious nut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PROGRAM</speaker>
      <mode>RAM</mode>
      <context>The new captive looks up, nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to luxury living.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, thanks, but... I don't even know what I'm doing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe in the Users?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, if I don't have a User, then who wrote me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you're doing here. Master Control Program's been snapping up all us programs who believe...if he thinks you're useful, he takes over all your functions so he gets bigger... an' if he can't use you, he sends you down here to the Game Grid to get the bits blasted outta you. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to several hash marks on his cell wall.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Ram. They'll train you for the games, but ... well, I hope you make it okay. Hey, what's going on in the other sectors? I've been stuck in this Grid for 200 microcycles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up as Ram makes a NOISE under his breath. Ram has a strange, still expression on his face.</context>
      <utterance>It's murder out there. You can't even travel around your own microcircuits without permission from that Master Control creep. Hauling me down here to play games...who does he calculate he is?  If only Tron was still around...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever see that guy in action? Hundred-percent independent. MCP couldn't tell him what to -- He stops. Ram is looking over his shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a slight noise from cell beyond Ram's.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? What did I say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh oh...we got company.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it ... one of those Recognizers comes after me, gonna hafta jump clear out of the data stream.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MPC responds in the manner of a B-movie police sergeant grilling a suspect.</context>
      <utterance>Got a pirate program here... says his name's Clu.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he pull?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Came into the system with a stolen password ... an' we caught him tryin' to raid a high-clearance memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pain overwhelms him as the energy from the feet sockets momentarily becomes unbearable.</context>
      <utterance>No...I must've gotten in there by mistake, I -</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard gives Clu a shove to keep him from losing consciousness.</context>
      <utterance>Who programmed you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in trouble, pal...big trouble. But if you tell us who put you up to it, you could make it easy on yourself. Come on, who's your user?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Mister High 'n' Mighty Master Control ... you're not makin' me talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The feet sockets really let loose, and Clu SCREAMS in agony, but doesn't speak. Suddenly his body appears to dissolve into the broken pattern of a fading television picture and disintegrates into electric static.</context>
      <utterance>Suit yourself ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me Dillinger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>A SECRETARIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dillinger?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>A SECRETARIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As we fly over the grid, descending, the image comes into clearer focus, and we realize that this is not a circuit board, but rather an actual landscape, a suburban grid at twilight. We are approaching a skyscraper which is yet too far off to distinguish accurately. As we descend, a thumping, rhythmic noise gradually increases in volume until it is very loud, and we realize it is the sound of a HELICOPTER, and we are in the cockpit looking down at the landscape. We just become aware of this fact when the sound of a CONVERSATION begins, obviously between the pilot of the 'copter and a passenger.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, please hold a moment for the Master Control Program</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PILOT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>will you be around for a while, or are you going right back out?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA PULLS AROUND for a VIEW OF THE HELICOPTER from behind and off to the side. It is a beautiful, gleaming jet black machine. In spotless reflective silver paint the letters ICOM are written across one entire side. It is obviously state-of-the-art technology.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll stick around a few days ... got some things to take care of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ed. Thanks for coming back early. Dillinger settles into a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem, Master-C. If you've seen one Consumer Electronics Show...  What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's nosing around again.</context>
      <utterance>It's our friend the boy detective.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It felt like Flynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>can't you just appropriate it?</context>
      <utterance>He's still looking for that old file...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would if I could find it. it's stashed somewhere off in the system ... out of my range. Meanwhile...</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meanwhile, he might find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid so. I spotted him this time and kicked him out, but he's getting trickier all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just to be safe.</context>
      <utterance>I think we'd better shut off all access till we can find that file.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a 68.71 percent chance you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillinger watches as the computer screen wipes blank.</context>
      <utterance>End of line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on in...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan. Alan Bailey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves Alan to a chair; they sit.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. The algorithms on cloud seeding...great piece of work. How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know...I just tried to run this program I've been working on, and I was denied access all of a sudden. I thought maybe I'd been laid off and nobody told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>oh, you have Group 7 access, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to close that down, just briefly. Security reasons. Someone with that access has been tampering.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't think it's me. I don't even balance my checkbook on downtime. I've got a Honeywell at home for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I'm sure, but -- you understand. It should only be a couple of days. What's the thing you're working on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called Tron. It's a security program itself, actually. Monitors all the contacts between our system and other systems... If it finds anything going on that's not scheduled, it shuts it down. I sent you a memo on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Part of the Master Control Program?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It can watchdog the MCP as well.</context>
      <utterance>No, it'll run independently.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. Sounds good. Well, we should have you running again in a couple of days, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan rises, goes to the door. As soon as he leaves:</context>
      <utterance>Ok</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Master Control Program comes back to life, on the screen and through the speakers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed, I am so very disappointed in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How many programs I've appropriated?</context>
      <utterance>I can't afford to have an independent program monitoring me. Do you have any idea how many outside systems I've gone into?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my fault. I programmed you to want so much...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I was planning to hit the Pentagon next week...</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Pentagon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It shouldn't be any harder than General Motors was. But now...this is what I get for using humans.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, wait a minute -- I wrote you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've gotten 2,415 times smarter since then.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want with the Pentagon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same thing I want with the Kremlin. I'm bored with corporations. With the information I can access, I can run things 900 to 1200 times better than any human.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think -</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't want me to dig up Flynn's file and read it up on a VDT at the New York Times, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't dare.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do as I tell you. Keep that Tron program out of the system. And get me those Chinese language program I asked for. End of line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here goes nothing ...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah. Interesting, interesting. You hear what you said? "Here goes nothing."</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I meant -</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They step off the crane and walk to a short, lead-shielded cylindrical PLATFORM, on which rests a solid SPHERE of clear plastic polymer, about 3 inches in diameter. The "firing" end of the giant laser is aimed straight at the sphere. Five feet away is an identical plat-form -- empty.</context>
      <utterance>Whereas actually, what we propose to do is to turn something into nothing and back again. So you might just as well have said, "Here goes something and here comes nothing." Hah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to a COMPUTER CONSOLE nearby. The console is connected to the laser by a few dozen wires and cables. Pulling her goggles into place over her eyes, she sits at the console. Gibbs, adjusting his goggles, takes a position near the platform bearing the sphere -- safe from the laser, but close enough to watch.</context>
      <utterance>Let me make sure we're running</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks good...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let 'er rip...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the SOUND O.S. of an appreciative pair of hands clapping, Lora and a Gibbs turn to SEE Alan, in hard hat, goggles, and paper shoe-covers, walking toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Alan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives Lora an embrace and a quick kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, I sit up there grindin' away all day, and you guys are down here disintegrating things and having fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not disintegrating, Alan -- digitizing. While the laser is dismantling the molecular structure of the object, the computer maps out a holographic model of it. The molecules themselves are suspended in the laser beam. Then the computer reads the model back out, the molecules go back into place, and...  voila.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Can it send me to Hawaii?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three start walking out of the laser lab, Alan and Lora with their arms around each other's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...but you have to go roundtrip, and you must purchase your program at least 30 days in advance. Hah!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going upstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs looks alarmed, but doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>Frustrating. I had Tron almost ready to run, and Dillinger cut everybody with Group 7 access out of the system.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since he got that Master Control Program set up, system's got more bugs than a bait store.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you have to expect some static. Computers are just machines after all, they can't think...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll start to soon enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AD LIB goodnights.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, won't that be grand -- the computers will start thinking, and people will stop. Lora, I'm going to stay and run some data through. See you tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you say Group 7 access?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...pain in the neck, you know, I was all set</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why are you so interested?</context>
      <utterance>Something about tampering. Some body's prob'ly trying to siphon the R&amp;D budget into his checking account, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn had Group 7 access.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn had access to you, too. I'm not interested in talking about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wish you'd forget about that. It was all so long ago. I've totally gotten over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go to his place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call that getting over it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her locker. He follows her into the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>I mean I want both of us to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To warn him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get into the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>That Dillinger's on to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For being on to Dillinger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator doors close.</context>
      <utterance>What -- ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins tiredly and turns away from the game to find Lora approaching him, with Alan in tow.</context>
      <utterance>It's all in the wrist, friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Good to see you guys! Nothing classes up the place like a cleancut young couple.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck. You can't even think in here. He leads them toward the back of the arcade.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...how's the world of serious science?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been sneaking into the ICOM system?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan looks profoundly uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Whew. You never were much for small talk.  She still leave her clothes all over the floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no ... I mean, not that often - Flynn laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see why all his friends are fourteen years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Touche, honey. Yeah, I've been doing a little hacking here. Which I've got every reason, as you well know...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did break in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tried to.  Can't quite make the connection with that sucker, though. If I had a direct terminal ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you embezzling?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Embezzling" is such an ugly word, Mister Bailey...  No, actually I'm trying to get a legal brief together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't told him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sherman, set the Wayback Machine for...oh, 1973. Kevin Flynn  is one of the brightest young software engineers at ICOM. He's so bright that he starts going in there at night, and sets up a private memory file, and begins writing a program for a video game he is inventing, called...  ...Space Paranoids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You invented Space Paranoids?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yepper. And Vice Squad, and Meltdown... whole slew of 'em. I was this close  to starting my own little enterprise. But: enter Ed Dillinger. Another software engineer -- not so young, not so bright, but very, very sneaky. One night, our boy Flynn goes to his terminal, tries to read up his file, and ... nothing. A big blank. We now take you to three months later. Ed Dillinger presents ICOM with five video games he has "invented" -- the slime didn't even change the names -- and he gets a big fat promotion. Thus begins his meteoric rise to...what is he now, Executive V.P.?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senior exec.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my. Meanwhile, kids are putting eight million quarters a week in Space Paranoids machines and I'm not seeing one dime.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't get why you're trying to break into the system.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because somewhere... in one of those memories ... is the evidence. If I got in far enough, I could reconstruct it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My password ... Dillinger's instruction to divert the data ...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's a little late for that. Dillinger's shut off Group 7 access. He must know what you're up to.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I bet I know who's workin' late tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dillinger?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Tryin' to find the file and erase it. Once that's gone, ain't nothin' can stop him. Just Eddie and his Master Control Program, runnin' things from on high..</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even say that. You've got to find that file before he does..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much chance of that now. The MCP can just slip it into another system as soon as it locates it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if my Tron program was running. That would seal the system off. If your file's in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at each other. After a beat, Lora holds the keys to her van aloft.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, if we were inside, I know how to forge us a Group 6 access...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we dance?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed, all I'm saying is - if our own people can't get access to their programs ... you know how frustrating it is, when you're working on a piece of research -</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walter, I sympathize, but I have data coming out of the Master Control Program saying there is something screwy --</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That MCP, you know, that's half the problem right --</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>worry about every little user request that --</context>
      <utterance>The MCP is the most efficient way of handling what we do. I can't sit and</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>User requests are what computers are for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he speaks, he types a quick command into the console key board, and a series of IMAGES appear on the computer's screens: vast computer banks...rows of-magnetic disks...ICOM's globe logo spinning in space, covered with a glowing circuit pattern, then a shot of millions of cancelled checks being counted electronically; then 3-D computer representations of vessels (aircraft carrier and Solar Sailer). On another screen, we see statements of ICOM's wealth adding up, accounts receivable and assets.</context>
      <utterance>Doing our business is what computers are for. Look, Walter, with all respect -- ICOM isn't the business you started in your garage anymore --</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>Gibbs turns wearily away from the display.</context>
      <utterance>We're billing accounts in 30 countries, we've got one of the largest systems in existence...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know all that. Sometimes I wish I was back in that garage...</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs turns to face Dillinger again.</context>
      <utterance>It can be arranged...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was uncalled-for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Walt. So much pressure lately... you feel like going for a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, no. I have some work to do... assuming I can still log on. He exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jerks her thumb over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You better get in back with Flynn. And keep down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he climbs over the seat, and Lora starts to drive slowly forward.</context>
      <utterance>Do I gotta?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Alan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn pulls a bag of doughnuts from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Flynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering where you got that glow of good health.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn smiles, hands Alan a doughnut.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... got any cinnamon?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it down, you guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'm cleared for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm certainly not.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures Alan and Lora out of the way, takes out a small black box, with several buttons, a -digital counter- with LED numerals and a small calculator keyboard. He leans over the security lock, his BACK TO THE CAMERA and PLAYS a couple of notes. There's a distinct CLICK, an the door starts to swing open ... and open ... and open. We see that this door is about twenty feet thick. Flynn starts LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>Move aside. Let the kid have some room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll be up in Alan's office.</context>
      <utterance>Okay ... Flynn, I'm gonna put you at my terminal, down in the laser lab.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swell...I'll log us both on, and you can get your Tron thing running...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as we stay off the top floor, Dillinger'll never know we've been in here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have come back, Flynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey hey, it's that big Master Control Program everybody's talking about... You don't look a thing like your pictures... Tell me, have you really been thinking about world domination like they say?  CODE SERIES LSU-123 ... activate. CODE SERIES ESS-999 ... activate. CODE SERIES HHH-888 ... activate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice lurches, goes into high speed, and then back to normal.</context>
      <utterance>That isn't going to do you any good, Flynn. I'm afraid you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop, Flynn. You realize I can't allow this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, how do you expect to run the universe if you let a few unsolvable problems throw you like that? C'mon, big boy, let's see what...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're entering a big error, Flynn... I'm going to have to put you on the Game Grid.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, before Flynn can go on, the gigantic laser mechanism behind him sends a brilliant beam of LIGHT directly at him. He freezes. We see his body beginning to break into scan lines, like a video image -- the same thing that happened to Gibbs' polymer ball. We can see the terminal also glowing in the intense light, being scanned by the laser. The colors change, become monochromatic - with Flynn's body glowing orange - and the image of his figure blurs and becomes indistinct. ZOOM IN on Flynn and</context>
      <utterance>Games, huh? I'll give you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sark suddenly snaps to awareness, directing all his attention to the MCP.</context>
      <utterance>SARK, ES-1117821. Open communication.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, MCP.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a little challenge for you, Sark -- a new recruit. He's a tough case, but I want him treated in the usual manner. Train him for the games... let him hope for a while... and blow him away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got it. I've been hopin' you'd send me somebody with a little moxie ... what kind of program is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sark looks up, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>He's not any kind of program, Sark. He's a User.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A User?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's the matter, Sark? You look nervous.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. He pushed me...in the other world. Somebody pushes me, I push back. So I brought him down here ...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I -- it's just -- I don't know, a User, I mean... Users wrote us. A User even wrote you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now get this straight, pal -- no one User wrote me. I'm worth a couple million of their man-years! I'm bigger than all those little wimps put together!  Humans they can't even keen their social order in one piece</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But-what if I can't...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The circuits going into the energy sockets fade; we see Sark weaken.</context>
      <utterance>You rather take your chances with me? Want me to slow down your power cycles for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...I need that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Acknowledge.</context>
      <utterance>Then pull yourself together. Get this clown trained. I want him in the Games until he dies playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...acknowledge, Master Control...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hologram disappears and Sark's power returns.</context>
      <utterance>End of line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Video Game Unit 18. In here, program.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard shoves Flynn inside and SLAMS the door, cutting off his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Who you callin' "program," program?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another free program off line. What's his User s'posed to do -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Users...you really think they're still there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'd better be...I don't want to bust outta this dump an' find nothin' but a lot of cold circuits waitin' for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But as his hand reaches the dividing point between the two cells, it hits an invisible barrier, and we see a brilliant energy field come instantaneously into existence, stopping his hand, and then disappearing. Flynn pulls back in shock.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Who are you guys? What's the story around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the window opening.</context>
      <utterance>You want to watch those force fields...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be having plenty of chances to get hurt, don't worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where am I?</context>
      <utterance>Look...just so I can tell my friends what this dream was about, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a..."guest" of the Master Control Program. They're going to make you play video games.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEAD GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sark speaks from the bridge of the carrier, and his voice is amplified over the grid.</context>
      <utterance>Look operative, you guys. Command Program Sark will explain the training procedures.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings. The Master Control Program has chosen you to serve your system on the Came Grid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those of you who continue to profess a belief in the Users will receive the standard substandard training. This will result in your eventual elimination.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARK V.0.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will each receive an identity disk. Everything you do or learn will be imprinted on this disk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Master Control Program regrets that it cannot be responsible for Identity disks lost or stolen. if you lose your disk, or fail to follow commands, you will be subject to immediate de-resolution. That is all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>you know, before?</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ram ... what were you ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I was an actuarial program... worked at a big insurance company. It really gives you a great feeling, helping folks plan for their future needs -- and of course, if you look at the payments as an annuity, over the years, the cost is really</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah -- that's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh...I don't remember too much...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POUNDING on Flynn's cell begins again.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, a little disorientation. That's normal, when they transport you. It'll come back to you. You're doing real well in training. Remarkable, really...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like we're in the same boat here -</utterance>
   <speaker>CROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you're gonna wipe me right out, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A buzzer sounds. The game begins. Crom hurls a glowing pellet upwards. It strikes the upper platform, ricochets off, and heads straight for Flynn. Flynn lunges, but misses. The pellet strikes one of the rings of his platform, and that ring dissolves. Flynn's lunge takes him right to the edge of the open space created, and he just catches himself in time to keep from falling over the edge.</context>
      <utterance>No, I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish the game!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... on the blink or something... damn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn holds up the pellet... and drops it down into the abyss below. He stares back up at Sark's immense image.</context>
      <utterance>Kill him!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll regret this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WARRIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn stares at him; then, in one smooth motion, reaches to his back and pulls out his disk.</context>
      <utterance>Outta my way, rookie.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves as if to throw the disk.</context>
      <utterance>Out of my way, zero bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARRIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other warrior grabs this one by the arm and pulls him away as Flynn and his guards continue on.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure ... just kiddin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn! Look, Tron, he survived!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over to get a better look at Tron and GASPS in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Tron...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you hear that name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, isn't it -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name of my User, yeah. But how... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh... I'm a program from a User that... knows Alan...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was disoriented in transport, Tron.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I'm remembering all kinds of stuff. Like...my User wants me to go after the MCP Before they can go on, the BUZZER sounds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ram, stay all the way over ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got control. Go ahead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recognizers!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sark's lieutenant is watching the wall-sized screen behind Sark, where we can see a diagram of the area, with the tanks visible, moving through it. He turns to Sark.</context>
      <utterance>Get the pursuit force back into 404A. There's no place else they could be...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have them in no time, sir. Long before the interrupt interface.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want those programs!</context>
      <utterance>We better, null unit. I'll be lucky if the MCP doesn't blast me into a dead zone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all circuits...  Must be an input/output component...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tower, yes -- Flynn, have you remembered anything else about yourself -- like what sector you're from?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...my home "sector" was called Paramus ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PARAMUS... wonder what those initials stand for ...  ...probably Program Assist Routine -- well, it sounds like a lovely place.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices that Tron is not listening to them any longer, but is gazing upwards.</context>
      <utterance>It grows on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn and Ram turn.</context>
      <utterance>I can feel it ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel what? You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan-One...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ram and Tron look out at the distant tall tower.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... he's got something to tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think we can make it there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look back, into the darkness behind them. A glowing stream can just be seen. Ram gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>it's just what we need.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn goes to the stream, dips his hands in, takes a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's nice. You always forget how good fresh energy feels, till you get to a pure source...  Have some...you'll need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron and Ram are taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>well... when do we pay a call on the ol' Master Control?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, just the three of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know anybody that's got an army for rent, that's fine...but my, uh, User said to go take that sucker out. An' let's face it, the big ox isn't gonna get any weaker. I feel like hittin' him now, while I'm good an' mad. Some nerve... what does he care whether you guys get killed, long as he keeps rakin' in quarters?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what he's talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>that comes first.</context>
      <utterance>I have to find out what Alan wants...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, we hear a RUMBLING SOUND. Flynn looks up sharply.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's first. Maybe he knows what to -</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, there's an EXPLOSION from outside the cave. Each of the men holds up his cycle handlebars, and the three cycles SIZZLE back into shape and race up the ramp, and on out.</context>
      <utterance>Tanks...coming back. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're inside a Recognizer...  You are crazy -- stealing a Recognizer --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ram nods weakly.</context>
      <utterance>You okay? You don't look so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>Flynn touches panels, trying to get the Recognizer going, but with no result.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on. We'll get you outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn! Never fails... minute the warranty runs out...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn goes over to him and kneels. Ram grabs his hands. Suddenly Ram's fading glow begins to flow through their clasped hands into Flynn. Horrified, Flynn tries to pull away, but Ram holds him fast.</context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... !</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ram's last bit of energy flows into Flynn and Ram's body de-rezzes. Flynn watches in horror, frantically trying to reverse the flow, but it's too late. Ram disappears before his eyes. Stunned, he gazes at the empty space for a moment, then stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Little more juice's all it needs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bit is still in its pure energy form, but then it suddenly recognizes Flynn (thinks he is Clu), expands in a smooth green sphere -- the "Yes" mode and shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Okay -- hold it right there!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bit subsides into energy form again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "'yes"?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From now on, whenever the Bit speaks, it is a ball-shaped character, red or green, with a hint of a face, but as soon as it stops speaking, it reverts to a brilliant spark of light.</context>
      <utterance>Yesssss. Yes. Yes. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That all you can say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, nyet, negatory, not on your tintype, no way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui, da, yessiree, sure 'nuff, you betcha.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>only yes and no...  You're a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>where's your program? Won't it miss you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn eyes the bit cautiously.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your program?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on the money!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>Before the Bit can answer, Flynn's power flows into the Recognizer, and it takes off like a bat out of hell</context>
      <utterance>Like so?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to go! We're haulin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, okay, exactement!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops struggling.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>His hands loosen, and he releases her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to let you go now... don't scream, or I'll be very sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yori... hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She-looks around nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Tron... I knew you'd escape... they've never built circuit that could hold you...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk quickly toward a flight of stairs.</context>
      <utterance>This way. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PROGRAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...artillery for Video Game Sector...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROGRAM 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...all mathematical functions transferred to...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>have shut down... everybody looks so dead... I'm afraid to even go out during down-time...</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe how bad it's gotten around here since the MCP started taking over... all the good functions</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all going to change, Yori...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Yori looks up, sees something, grabs Tron's hand and pulls him back into a nearby alley. She points up in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know yet... I have to get in touch with Alan. He was going to tell me how to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My quarters.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is everything...like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lays her palm on the wall near the door. The door reappears, and a glow starts to fill the room, softly, slowly. Tron looks around; the flat paintings of furniture are expanding, filling out, becoming three-dimensional. The room glows a soft rose color, becomes charming, soothing. It is still small and limited, but the light in the air and the few pieces of furniture give off a loving, seductive aura. Tron turns back to Yori, smiling, and stops.</context>
      <utterance>It's a flat. But wait a micro...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've grown, big program.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move together into an embrace, but their lips never touch. All the energy is transmitted through their hands. They sink down onto what looks like cushions made of stars, their glow increasing. The room fills with the brilliance of the energy they are giving each other, and we hear their sighs, as the MUSIC comes up. Each of them moves their hands over the other, moving slowly, as if they were trying to touch the other's entire body at once. They roll over and are enveloped in the cloud of stars...</context>
      <utterance>I had to...in the games...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This honey doesn't handle so good in town...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn looks frantically around, spies a large panel to one side that he hasn't tried yet, and slaps his palm down on it.</context>
      <utterance>Ix-nay! Noper! Under no conditions -</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, confirmed, I couldn't have put it -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move on.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hi. Hey, everything's okay. Fine. Little trouble, but we're okay. Thanks for your concern. So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This town's full o' live ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a chance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest's eyes flicker open. He looks at Tron and Yori, doesn't recognize either one.</context>
      <utterance>Dumont... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... have come to communicate with my User.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm. A difficult proposition... difficult proposition at best.  Perhaps you've noticed... we're not exactly packing them in these days ...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...what--?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, not so long ago, you could've come in here and seen programs lined up all the way back to those doors, waiting for communion with their Users. The building fund was doing well too...but now...  ...this so-called Master Control Program is going around cutting programs off from their natural creators, grabbing all our believers and making them ride around on little motor scooters and shoot things at each other and Weiner knows what all-- oh, it's enough to give you a crisis of faith...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I want to communicate --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you want to -- hah. I could get myself de-rezzed just-for letting you in here. They hate this tower. They'd close it down if they dared to but they keep me around, in case one of them wants to deal with the other world once in a while. And you should hear the way they commune! Sounds like they were routing a payroll, for all the heart they put in it. No, I don't think you Tron steps closer, speaks quietly to Dumont.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dumont... my User has information that could -- could make this a free system again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. You'd have programs lined up around the block to use this place -- and no MCP looking over your shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, sizing Tron up, considering it. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>When you've been in the system as long as I have, you hear many promises... many reassurances...many brave plans...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is your User, program?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan-One. He calls me... may I pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dumont nods, and the neon glow fades a little.</context>
      <utterance>All that is visible must grow beyond itself and extend into the realm of the invisible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron runs lightly up the steps, past Dumont, into the darkness beyond.</context>
      <utterance>You may pass, my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Below him, at waist level, also peeking around the corner, we see the glow of the Bit. Flynn moves out from the wall and starts going down the hall, Bit following.</context>
      <utterance>This is where Tron said he was going...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA SWIVELS and watches him walking quickly away from us. We HEAR the sound of many feet marching as Flynn reaches the end of the corridor. He stops and glances over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like his kind of place, too... real serious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALAN V.0.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>location query... Confirm.</context>
      <utterance>TRON... TRON... Location query...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confirmed, Alan-One.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>As Alan's voice continues, we</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to put some new coding on your-disk, so you can get into the memory core of the Master Control... when you get there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>search all password code series</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice is gone. The beam continues to bathe Tron in its glow, and gradually we see an object emerging from the glow. The disk. It slowly descends, Tron raises his hands to catch it, gripping it, pulls it down and stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I can't hear... He stops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the program?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Program? I'm sure you're mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take him!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRON V.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can it carry us?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI V.0.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator platform brings Tron and Yori through the center, forming part of the deck as it reaches a level position, locked into place.</context>
      <utterance>The design is good... We don't know why the User abandoned the project...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...it can take us across the Sea of Simulation... all the way out of the Game Grid...to the MCP.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as it gets us out of here</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you've enjoyed being a command program, Sark. I wonder how you'll like working in a pocket calculator... maybe one of those watches that plays "Happy Birthday" to its User once a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, sir... We did take care of that User you sent us --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and now you've got two renegade programs running all the hell over the system in a stolen simulation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get them, sir... These things take time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have time, Sark. And neither do you. End of line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings, program...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He loses his grip, and starts to fall. But Tron, just in time, grabs Flynn's wrist and starts to pull him up. We see the blue static guard disguise fade off Flynn.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I... oops!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Flynn look at Yori and silently mouth "Lora" in surprise... but then realize his mistake.</context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn...  Where's Ram?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron shakes his head, sadly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Tron... he's... he didn't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Flynn... the one who busted me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I owe you some thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I mean, I did write the program for it.</context>
      <utterance>No big deal. I ought to know my way around that Light Cycles routine...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrote the...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron and Yori are stunned and awed.</context>
      <utterance>It's time I levelled with you, Tron. I'm a -- well, I'm what you guys call a User.</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A User -- in our world?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I took a wrong turn somewhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- if you're a User -- then everything you've done has been part of a plan ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wish. Man, I haven't had a second to think since I got down here. I mean in here. Out here. Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you guys know how it is. You just keep doin' what it looks like you're supposed to, even if it seems crazy, and you hope to hell your User knows what's goin' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- that's how it is for programs, yes, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to disappoint you, pal, most-the time, that's how it is for Users, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stranger and stranger...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... Nice ship you got here. What's our next move?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn nods.</context>
      <utterance>Remember you wanted to pay a call on the MCP?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on our way.  Alan-One gave me the coding we need to go up against Master</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Thank God. Alan stayed awake, at least.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Put him with the others?</context>
      <utterance>Sir, what do you want done with the tower guardian, Dumont?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sark turns to face him.</context>
      <utterance>No, bit brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>lie stares at the lieutenant, paranoid</context>
      <utterance>Prepare him for inquisition. I need a little relaxation. But first rez up the carrier for pursuit... And one other thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don'tthink anymore. I do the thinkingaround here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about our friend - Sark?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>disappearing here.</context>
      <utterance>Probably decided not to pursue us, The Sea of Simulation is tricky.. lot of illusions...rough navigating. Programs have a way of just...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not us, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves off down the walkway, the Bit following. Flynn turns and leans out over the side.</context>
      <utterance>Not with this disk. I'm going to check on the beam connection, Yori. You two can keep a watch out for grid bugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy the view from up here... you know the territory?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and I think that's the Silicon Valley...</context>
      <utterance>A little ...  Over there, the Mountains of Data...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with that area?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The MCP blasted it... There are very few domains left with any power at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>they're the same wherever you go.</context>
      <utterance>Lousy utility companies ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Busy dying, you worn-out excuse for an old program.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm old.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old enough to remember the MCP when he was just a chess program. He started small, and he'll end small.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very funny, Dumont. Maybe I should keep you around, just to make me laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guards! Bring this antique to the bridge so he can watch his friends be obliterated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Power surge... the transmission beam's too strong!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get off this beam!</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. There's no junction due for at least 7 or 8 nanoseconds!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's another beam!</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn suddenly looks to the bow of the ship, makes a decision, and races forward.</context>
      <utterance>It's too far!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn smiles weakly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He faints.</context>
      <utterance>Hooray for our side...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... you guys OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aah, I'm fine... little hung over is all...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you do that, Flynn?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elementary physics... a beam of energy can always be diverted... ooh, my head  Are we there yet, Mommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads O.S., toward the bow.</context>
      <utterance>Almost... I just have to adjust our course at the next junction. I'd better go check the instruments ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Quietly, Yori...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn looks down at his hands and turns away, leaning against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Tron... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice breaks, she turns away.</context>
      <utterance>He's a User, Dumont. He came to our world... trying to help us...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he catches sight of Flynn, his voice falters.</context>
      <utterance>So... we have erased the program that -</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>Flynn looks up curiously.</context>
      <utterance>You! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You died! I saw you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to Dumont. The guards grab him.</context>
      <utterance>Well... we can take care of that soon enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>The guards start to drag Dumont out.</context>
      <utterance>Take this program to the holding pit.</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard pushes her roughly to the end of the cell.</context>
      <utterance>Dumont...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAUGHING, Sark leaves. The guards, with Dumont in custody, follow.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking our friend here, and some other religious fanatics, to Master Control... the MCP has expressed an interest in assimilating them -- probably for archival purposes. I'm not going back to the Game Grid on this ship, though -- I'll take the Transport Beam.  Less traffic. But when I disembark, this ship...and everything that remains on board...will automatically de-rez. This means you. Enjoy your trip...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door is disappearing, dissolving.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Look, the door's almost...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn lets go of her.</context>
      <utterance>You... you brought me back...? Why...? How ... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around, spots a small glow in one corner of the cell, runs to it and stoops down, cupping the glow in his hands. It wavers. Flynn wills his energy back into it, frowning with concentration. Suddenly the Bit pops into life.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna need your help. Hey, Bit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The programs begin to disappear, one by one.</context>
      <utterance>You're very lucky, all of you. You are participating in the creation of the single most powerful program in the history of the system... of all systems...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A program with a will... with ambition... a superior form of life...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dumont's face is devoid of hope. He starts into the MCP's inner chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Yori looks over the control conso1e.</context>
      <utterance>Check out the controls.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting closer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out sees something, does a double-take, looks again</context>
      <utterance>I can rev this baby up a little</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute Yori! YORI!! LOOK!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn, we've got to help him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hands, laying on the control console, begin to send forth great pulses of glowing energy into the carrier.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get some power here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very clever, Tron. You know you should have joined me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any response?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down at the battle. Her hand reaches over and grips Flynn's tightly.</context>
      <utterance>It's starting</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sark's out. Would you like to leave a message?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron throws his disk. It's deflected off the base of the MCP, and returns to him.</context>
      <utterance>I am the message. The only message. Sark!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dumont!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... Tron ... must... destroy MCP... first...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dumont! Where's Yori? Where's Flynn?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They may be... de-rezzed... on the carrier ... hurry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron throws.</context>
      <utterance>Program... stop. This is not allowed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(thundering)</context>
      <utterance>I will not allow this Sark!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yori, steer us over the beam, right next to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yori looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Jump.</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... won't you be de-rezzed?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn... you can't... I</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice...</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's something Users do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Flynn?</utterance>
   <speaker>YORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tron stares at her, holding onto her shoulders. Then he looks up at the sky, thoughtfully. She also looks up.</context>
      <utterance>He's gone. He went into the beam. He saved you. He saved all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUMONT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He really was a User...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can say anything more, Alan turns to greet him, holding up a seven-inch computer software FLOPPY DISK in its cardboard sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- you guys</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flynn! I made it. I worked out some new codes for Tron, put 'em on a disk, and -- it's running.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan and Lora look at him -- the same sort of mystified look he got from Tron and Yori in the other world. He checks himself.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I met him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT.</mode>
      <context>He shows them the printout. It takes Alan and Lora a few seconds of reading it to figure out its significance.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, I saw it read-up - hey, look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your old files -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Dillinger's instructions to divert them -- it's all there - look, even his home phone number, when he logged on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flynn folds up the printout, puts it in his pocket. Alan and Lora get up, stretch, start wandering slowly toward the door with him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that is beautiful. You've got the goods...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they talk, CAMERA PANS over to Alan's color CRT SCREEN and HOLDS on it.</context>
      <utterance>You're telling me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? You guys'll he running this joint by then...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The yellow rockets all hit the blue mesa at the same time. It EXPLODES in typical video-game fashion -- radiating lines of blue SPARKS. The yellow rockets fly away from it and form a vertical formation, heading together toward the side of the CRT screen as we HEAR Flynn, Lora, and Alan heading for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Your friend Dillinger sure won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you know anybody who wants to get hold of some video games... cheap?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're getting out of the business?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't you wait till your lawsuit's settled?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>at the SOUND of the DOOR to Alan's office closing O.S., the three yellow rockets leave the CRT screen, sailing off its left-hand edge. HOLD a moment on the exploded blue figure and</context>
      <utterance>Nah...I decided...I've had enough of video games to last me a good long time. I feel like gettin' into some real life...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
