<movie id="575" title="Twin Peaks">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHE'S MY MOTHER'S SISTER'S GIRL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cole holds four fingers in front of his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lil finishes her dance.</context>
      <utterance>Federal? Cole gives him the thumbs up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, Gordon. We'll be in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was really something. That dancing girl.  What did it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Code. If you work with Gordon you learn that right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond pulls his arm back so that only his fingers come out of his sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Code, I've heard a lot about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of shorthand.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shorthand. really?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're heading into a difficult situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you figure?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Desmond explains we -</context>
      <utterance>I'll explain it to you. Do you remember Lil's dance?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lil was wearing a sour face.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her face had a sour look... that means we're going to have trouble with the local authorities. They are not going to be receptive to the FBI.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IS HIS SISTER'S GIRL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Uncle.</context>
      <utterance>DESMOND  Cole said Lil was "his mother's sister's girl". What is missing in that sentence?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the uncle is missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Cole's Uncle but probably the sheriff's uncle in federal prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the sheriff had got an Uncle who's committed a serious crime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, which is probably why Lil was wearing a red wig meaning we are headed into a dangerous situation. Let me ask you something, Stanley, did you notice anything about the dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dress she was wearing had been altered to fit her. I noticed a different colored thread where the dress had been taken in. It wasn't her dress or she must have lost some weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordon said you were good. The tailored dress is our code for drugs. Did you notice what was pinned to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A blue rose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley rides along quietly for a while.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, but I can't tell you about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Gordon's tie mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? That's just Gordon's bad taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't he have just told you all these things?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talks loud. And he loves his code.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. He does talk loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordon would not have sent us to Deer Meadow without thinking it was a high priority situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be a high priority situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cliff just smiles for a long minute.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent Chet Desmond. I'd like to see Sheriff Cable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond stays standing and Stanley sits. After another long moment, Cliff joins the SECRETARY in a conspiratorial giggle over the long wait they are planning to give the FBI. In the middle of a giggle Cliff smiles up at Desmond. CLIFF (continued) Why don't you have some of that coffee. It was fresh two days ago. Cliff has a good laugh over this and leans again over the secretary pretending to look at some paper work. They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you folks have a seat. Make yourself at home. It's gonna be a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's it. I've had enough of the waiting room now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond walks towards the door that obviously must go to Sheriff Cable's office. Cliff blocks his way with his arm across the doorway, daring him to do something. While they stare eye to eye, Desmond's hand goes up slowly towards Cliff's face in a slow mesmerizing way. Cliff tries to knock Chet's hand away. Chet counters by grabbing Cliff's nose and pinches a nerve to its side injecting Cliff with a great amount of pain. CLIFF (continued)</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond stalks to Sheriff Cable's office. Stanley remains behind continuing to observe every detail.</context>
      <utterance>You can start that FRESH pot of coffee right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond shows his credentials.</context>
      <utterance>How the hell did you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cliff, still holding his nose, appears just behind Desmond, who turns to him. DESMOND (continued) That's all right, Deputy, Sheriff Cable can take it from here Cable signals Cliff to leave. DESMOND (continued) I'm here to investigate the murder of Teresa Banks.</context>
      <utterance>Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent Chet Desmond.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, little fella, we don't need any outside help here. I don't like you people sniffin' around my neck of the woods. In fact, when the state boys called me about a "J. Edgar" coming up I think I said, "So what?"</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your behavior is not funny and is wasting the time of the Federal Government.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lucky I am not wasting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cable retrieves a box with the paper work and some personal effects. He throws it to Desmond.</context>
      <utterance>Well, little fella, let me put it this way. The operative word here would be "Federal". With or without the semantics of all this, I am now ordering you to release all pertinent information concerning Teresa Banks, both while living and deceased.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A basic kill. Banks was a drifter and nobody knew her. My boys have been all over this. It's a dead end.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's the body?</context>
      <utterance>That's why we're here, Sheriff Cable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out back in our morgue Desmond starts to leave. CABLE  It's 4:30. We close at five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Desmond turns to leave he notices on the wall a framed Newspaper clipping with picture. The caption reads:</context>
      <utterance>We've got our own clock. We'll lock up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond looks up from his work and notices.</context>
      <utterance>Teresa Banks lived at the Canyon Trailer Park for a month. We'll check that. And worked as a waitress at Hap's Truck Stop. Worked the Night Shift. Good place for dinner when we're thru here, Sam.  No one came to claim the body and no known next of kin. As Desmond is doing this, Stanley takes out his SPECIAL MACHINE.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Solved the Whiteman Case with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one could find those splinters without a machine like this. And no one had a machine like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is good.  What do you think is in these other drawers?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, later we could take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Getting to work, Stanley's face goes right over Teresa's.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, but let's finish up with this first.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crushed skull. Probable cause repeated blows to the back of the head with an obtuse angled blunt object. Subject looks to be between 16 and 18 years of age.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley's eyes drift to Teresa's left hand.</context>
      <utterance>Cole said she was 17.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder where her ring is? Desmond notices the mark on her hand as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley picks up her left hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  Personal effects include a watch, under garments, and a blue waitress uniform... the ring is missing. It says the rest of her things haven't been removed yet from the trailer. Let's hope it's there.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT: BANKS LEFT HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Stanley's hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There appears to be a contusion under the ring finger of her left hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley peers underneath the fingernail.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley brings over his "Whiteman" instrument. Works the left hand under it.</context>
      <utterance>A laceration.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Accidental?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets whatever it is with a long set of tweezers.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Desmond, would you hold the finger for me. There's something up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a piece of paper with the letter "T" imprinted on it. Take a look. Desmond comes around and takes a look. On a piece of paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP: DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pondering what he has seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, Agent Desmond, it's three-thirty in the morning. Where are we going to sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not. You and I are going to get some food.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's been several hours since we've eaten. I didn't realize that so much time had past, did you, Agent Desmond? Desmond takes a long look at Stanley. STANLEY  You've got your own M.O., don't you, Agent Desmond? Desmond gets in and starts the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had the FBI here once before. Back in the fifties when Hap was running the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Hap?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead - good and dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't suffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to ask you a few questions about Teresa Banks</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff Cable's already asked me a few questions about Teresa Banks. She worked nights for a month. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever see her with someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she ever mention any friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures thru a door that leads out to the diner, pointing out a woman behind the counter. JACK (continued) Now, her name _is_ Irene and it _is_ night. Don't take it any further than that. There's nothin' good about it.</context>
      <utterance>No.  Ask Irene over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a good look around. There's nobody in this place - you're meetin' the reason why. What'll it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come Jack let's you work here?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack and I are united in holy matrimony.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley is casing the restaurant as Irene pours them a couple of cups of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Say no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack said you knew her. How well?</context>
      <utterance>Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent Chet Desmond. I'd like to ask you a few questions about Teresa Banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>girl. Never seemed to get here on time though. Ask me she had a little problem with -- She makes a sniff to indicate a "cocaine problem". IRENE (continued) Came looking for a job with a friend of hers. Pretty girl. Could've been her sister.</context>
      <utterance>She only worked here a month. Nice</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was only one job. Teresa took the job. Her friend took a hike. Never saw her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see Teresa take cocaine?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you take cocaine, Irene?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I do not. I never took cocaine or any other drugs. I don't take drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicotine is a drug. Caffeine is a drug.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Shorty? Those drugs are legal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's with me.  Anything you would like to tell us about Teresa Banks that would help us out?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've thought about that. I think her death is what you would call a "freak accident".</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An OLD GUY, long and skinny, smoking, gets Desmond's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talking about that little girl that was murdered?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have something to tell us?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond moves away from him.</context>
      <utterance>I can tell shit from shinolah. Gets me along way down that road.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond looks down at the coffee cup in Stanley's _left_hand_.</context>
      <utterance>You think we ought to question him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley checks his watch pouring hot coffee on himself.</context>
      <utterance>What time is it, Stanley?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond guides his laugh into a cough.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Desmond, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's late, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene comes up to them with her purse in her hand. She is going off duty.</context>
      <utterance>It's not late, it's early. Really early.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I never told anybody, but once for about three days, just before her time, Teresa's arm went completely dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her left arm. It was numb. She said she couldn't use it. Said it had no feeling. Probably from the drugs she was taking.  I just thought I ought to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley watches her leave.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt it was drugs, more likely a problem with a nerve. I could recheck the arm for injuries, but for real nerve work we are going to have to take the body back to Portland.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should see the sun rise at the Canyon Trailer Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you speaking to me in a code?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sam, I'm speaking plainly and I mean just exactly what I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irene walks past them and towards the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, we should go to the Canyon Trailer Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY AND DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Irene. Good...  Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank god it is morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both fumble for their badges as they hear the manager coming closer to the door. They meet the manager, CARL RODD.</context>
      <utterance>Nine's really late. We are really early.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in the middle of this when he sees the badges.</context>
      <utterance>God damn, this better be important.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent Chet Desmond and Agent Sam Stanley. Sorry to disturb you, but we would like to see Teresa Banks' trailer, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(takes one step out of his trailer)</context>
      <utterance>More popular than Uncle's Day at a whorehouse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she have someone with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. She had a friend with her. The friend took off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was there an argument?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I know of. But arguments do happen, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes they do. Did she have visitors?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(frustration rising)</context>
      <utterance>No, hey, I already told this whole damn thing to Sheriff "Not-Quite-Able"... Here's the trailer now. He swings open the door. CARL  And this is exactly the way she left it. I never touched a GOD DAMN THING.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She lived alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond notices her personal effects on the dresser, but no ring. DESMOND (continued) You better dust this place, Sam.</context>
      <utterance>She must have known someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get my kit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley studies it.</context>
      <utterance>She's wearing a ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess is there isn't enough detail in the photo to get an idea of the design on the ring, but we should do a blowup of this anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl leans in from the outside.</context>
      <utterance>May I see the magnifying glass, Agent Desmond?  There doesn't seem to be enough detail in the photo to ascertain the design on the ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both nod "yes".</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna make myself some Good Morning America. You want some?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't kiddin'. This stuff's got the sting of the forty-eight hour blend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. That's the best coffee you're gonna get around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WOMAN sticks her head into the trailer. She has an ice pack over one eye and a load of idle curiosity. Desmond notices her.</context>
      <utterance>We really do need a good "wake me up", don't we, Agent Desmond?  We really do need a good "wake me up", don't we, Agent Desmond?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just nods in the negative and leans back out. Behind her is Deputy Cliff, who looks into the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know Teresa Banks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how's J. Edgar doin'?  Bet you appreciate them bustin' your mornin' in half, eh, Carl? Bet they woke you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're only doing their job.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here in the trailer court, Deputy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I just live here, what do you think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you where you were the night Teresa Banks was murdered?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can tell J. Edgar that I was at a party and I got fifteen fuckin' witnesses.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you did a little less partyin' that little girl would still be alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right, Mr. Jack Daniels?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know Teresa Banks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a couple of cups of coffee at Hap's from her. That's it. By the way where do you get off questioning a lawman? I could ask you the same question.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chet steps towards Cliff who looses his balance and has to step off the trailer steps.</context>
      <utterance>No you couldn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a golf course around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond drops the ball in a plastic bag and gives it to Stanley who puts it in his kit. Desmond turns to Carl.</context>
      <utterance>Not a lot around here, no. Got some clubs, but not very many fellas with balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help, Carl. Sorry we woke you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond and Stanley nod to Carl and walk to their car.</context>
      <utterance>That's alright. I was having a bad dream. I was dreamin' about a joke with no punchline.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help but notice that you had a suspicion that Deputy Cliff was the murderer. You did think that, didn't you, Agent Desmond?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not the murderer.  But he's a bozo.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond walks around the car to the drivers' side and gets in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he is like a clown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that thing doing out there? You're not taking that body anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're taking the body back to Portland and there's not a thing you can do about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not _a_ thing, but maybe _two_ things.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teresa Banks had a ring. Any idea what happened to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a phone, here, that's got a little ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam, get the body and put it in the van.  Sheriff Cable, where were you the night Teresa Banks was murdered?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he says, "Discussion", how do you take that, Agent Desmond?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't take it, Sam. I give it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a steel bar and bends it ala the picture in his office.</context>
      <utterance>Now, J. Edgar, I'm going to take off my badge, here. Do you mind?  The only way you're going to get that body is over mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try that you little monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond takes his coat and badge off. Cable takes his shirt off and Desmond follows. Cable is bare-chested and Desmond is in FBI issue underwear. Desmond goes to pick up an iron bar and Cable hits him with a sucker punch. As Desmond bends away from this Cable rushes at him. Desmond stops him with a few well placed punches to his face. Cable falls down and Desmond stands over him. Chet picks up the steel bar and bends it. He then tosses the bar away. Cable stands up and rushes at Desmond who flips and flops him around. Cable tries one more grand roadhouse punch which Desmond expertly ducks.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'll take off my badge as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond blasts him in the jaw and Cable goes over - lights out, all systems down. The no longer giggling secretary and Cliff stand and stare. Desmond looks at them.</context>
      <utterance>This one's comin' from J. Edgar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment of unbearable humiliation they shuffle away.</context>
      <utterance>Who's next?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk towards the van until Stanley stops.</context>
      <utterance>Take the van back to Portland, Stanley. I'm going to take one more look at the trailer park.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing that has been troubling me. That lamp at the diner. Do you think they were working on it for esthetic reasons or was their work due to faulty wiring?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faulty wiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esthetics are subjective, aren't they, Agent Desmond?  I'm Sam Stanley. If you ever need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Sam, for the good work. You have a good eye for detail.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desmond smiles at Stanley as they shake.</context>
      <utterance>We do notice things, don't we, Agent Desmond? Are you going back to the trailer park for the Blue rose?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's Deputy Cliff's trailer over there. The red one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl walks away towards his trailer. Desmond walks over and around Cliff's red trailer. He gets a strange feeling. He looks past Teresa's trailer to the edge of the trailer park, where he sees a HAND appear in the window of a trailer. Then the hand disappears. Desmond walks to that trailer. He knocks on the door but no one answers. He looks under the trailer and sees a _mound_of_dirt_with_ _a_small_indentation_at_the_top_. In the indentation is _Teresa_ _Bank's_ring_. As he reaches out and touches it, _he_disappears_.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be in my trailer if you need me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Diane says something else that we cannot hear.</context>
      <utterance>I know you haven't changed your hair and I've seen that beautiful dress before, but I must say, Diane, you look sensational today.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Cole's stern look takes his smile away.</context>
      <utterance>No, I am not trying to buy time. It's Thursday and I know you have changed something in the room... and this time you've done very well...  And I am going to tell you exactly what it is... in a moment... you have moved...  Got it! It's the clock, you've moved it 12 inches to the left.  Another triumph for the dashing Agent Cooper. And you, Diane, now have to clean the coffee cup, get fresh ground coffee from Sally and make a damn great pot of coffee. Cooper with a triumphant smile walks over to join Cole and Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Gordon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which we did. It was 105 miles.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Chet said he wanted to check the trailer court one more time. He had me drive the van with the body back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Gordon show you a woman named Lil?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm up to speed, Stanley.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Chet wouldn't tell me what the Blue Rose meant.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And neither will I.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley turns to one of his work tables and shows Cooper the Whiteman machine.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, alright.  You know, I liked Agent Desmond. He had his own M.O.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cracked the Whiteman case with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stanley, I heard all about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one could've found those splinters without a machine like this and no one has a machine like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about the letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper looks under the microscope to see the letter they found on Teresa.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look at this. Chet and I found it under Teresa Banks' ring fingernail.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no one found the ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper straightens up from the microscope. Stanley extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir, we did not.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sam Stanley, if you ever need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>GOD. I'm beginning to lose faith in the United States Government and that includes the telephone system. Don't you folks talk to one another. That's her trailer there and I haven't touched a god damn thing. Agent Chet Desmond come by a second time and asked too see Deputy Cliff Howard's trailer  ...which I showed him. I went back to my trailer...  After that I never saw him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper starts walking in the opposite direction from Cliff's trailer picking up on the same odd vibe that struck Desmond.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the way to Cliff's trailer. I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not going to Cliff's trailer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am going over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper reaches a pack of dirt which is now creased with tire tracks.</context>
      <utterance>God damn, you people are confusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was here, Mr. Rodd?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trailer was here. What the hell do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and who stayed in the trailer?</context>
      <utterance>Can you tell me who's trailer it was...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An old woman and her grandson.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell me what their names were?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper kneels to examine the tracks left by the exited trailer. As he kneels and inspects the tracks he is overcome by the presence of SOMETHING. Cooper struggles to his feet and looks around. Under a tree and close to the tracks is a car.</context>
      <utterance>Chalfont. Weird. Chalfont was the name of the folks that rented the space before they did. Two Chalfonts.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Agent Desmond's vehicle?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper walks to it.</context>
      <utterance>Yep, it sure is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HEAD CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rings the bell. A BELLHOP appears. Young, sweating, and eager. Jeffries hands him the key.</context>
      <utterance>Here's your key, Mr. Jeffries. I hope you enjoy your stay here at The Palm Deluxe.  This is for you. The joven... ah... young lady... she left it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up Jeffries' bag and heads for the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>612 --- very nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffries moves into the room. Cooper steps into the office.</context>
      <utterance>Phillip?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phillip?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to talk about Judy. Keep Judy out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cole calms Cooper.</context>
      <utterance>But...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think that is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suffered some bumps on the old noggin', eh, Phil?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to tell you everything, but I don't have a lot to go on. But I'll tell you one thing: Judy is positive about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffries stumbles to a chair.</context>
      <utterance>How interesting. I thought we were going to keep Judy out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me carefully. I saw one of their meetings. It was above a convenience store.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's meeting? Where have you been?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a dream.  We live inside a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's raining Post Toasties.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sat quietly for hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FIRST WOODSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have descended from pure air.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going up and down. Intercourse between the two worlds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Light of new discoveries.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TREMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not be composed of materials and combinations of atoms?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TREMOND'S GRANDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is no accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches the table.</context>
      <utterance>This is a formica table. Green is its color.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST WOODSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With chrome. Any everything will proceed cyclically.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND WOODSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boneless.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob begins to scream with anger.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, find the middle place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TREMOND'S GRANDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man From Another Place raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Fell a victim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob claps his hand and a circle of fire appears in the room.</context>
      <utterance>Fire Walk With Me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire Walk With Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THROUGH THE CIRCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see the RED ROOM.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeffries begins to cry quietly at his table.</context>
      <utterance>I followed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ring... ring...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May? 1989?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP: JEFFRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Staring at the calendar. it is 1989.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I am going to get through math today, you're going to have to bring me up to speed quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't do your homework?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noooo...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, this test is going to be about the theorems I told you about last week. You remember the...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me now. Tell me right before the test. I won't be able to remember long enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You graduating this year will be proof that miracles happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura tweaks Donna's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James called me last night looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The usual, 9:15.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He probably wanted to drive over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you with Bobby? Or are you two still fighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, and yes. I don't know what I'm going to do about Bobby. I know he is seeing someone else and that's okay with me, and he thinks I'm seeing someone else and that's not okay with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to tell him about that "someone else"?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what your problem is?  You're just too adorable...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna grabs her and shakes her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I think you're right. I'm just too adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura Palmer, you're just too adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue up the sidewalk laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just too adorable. I'm just too adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMIRERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Donna as they continue down the hall. A cool MIKE NELSON snaps his fingers ala Bobby for Donna to come to him. Without missing a beat Donna changes directions. Mike has to hustle to catch up with her.</context>
      <utterance>"Laura... Donna... Laura... Donna..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you need a real man, Babe, you're tough to handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're the real man?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, I'll meet you at 2:30 after phys. ed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James smiles and walks off. Laura enters the girls' room.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, do you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I love you. I've told you, but it doesn't really matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? It does.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it doesn't... just kiss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does matter. We're in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James, you don't know what you are talking about. Quit trying to hold on so tight. I'm gone... long gone like a turkey through the corn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a turkey. A turkey is one of the dumbest birds on earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. She kisses him and he responds.</context>
      <utterance>Gobble, gobble, gobble.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura moves into him. A hopeless embrace. His eyes full of hope and Laura's empty. She pulls him to the floor to make love.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ever leave, Laura, ever. I'll never leave you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you for the last hour? I've been lookin' for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby grabs her roughly and spins her around. Students stop and stare.</context>
      <utterance>I was right behind you, but you're too dumb to turn around.  If he turned around he might get dizzy and fall down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? You'll be callin' soon and maybe I'm not gonna be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby can't hold onto his anger. Slowly a huge smile spreads across his face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, sweetie, give me one of your smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love ya, Babe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom H. Eileen motors out. DONNA   Are you going to see James tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nighttime is my time.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you suddenly so interested in who I am going to see at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me, but only because you never let me in on any of it... you're not going to see Bobby, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura looks at Donna.</context>
      <utterance>Because Bobby is a loser, you said so yourself. He's a goon.  James is the one.  He loves you with that "lasting love"... "true love".</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, James is very sweet. Why don't you get out your violin, Donna?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet? God, he's gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna drifts off.</context>
      <utterance>James is very sweet and very gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if Mike could ever write a poem? Both of them drift off. DONNA  Do you think that if you were falling in space you would slow down after a while or go faster and faster?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna studies her friend and thinks about what she has said. After a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Faster and faster. For a long time you wouldn't feel anything. Then you would burst into fire... forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I better start our homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I suppose I should go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. What do you want me to call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me anything just don't call me late for dinner. They laugh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura takes it out of her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Laura, honey...  Cigarette... Cigarette...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I take the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure honey, what's the hurry?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura runs from the house.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot my books at school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura looks back to see her mom dangling the car keys in front of her. Laura comes back to get the keys still holding the burning cigarette. Sarah sternly takes the cigarette from Laura's hand. As they make the exchange.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes a drag. With barely a nod, Laura is gone.</context>
      <utterance>You'll never be a smoker if you don't SARAH  start. I mean it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My secret diary. There are pages missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who would do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Bob isn't real.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pages are gone. That's real.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob is real. He's been "having" me since I was 12. Stunned, Harold doesn't know what to do. LAURA  The diary was hidden too well. He's the only one who could know where it was. He's getting to know me, now. He's real He speaks to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does Bob say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to be me... or he will kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... No...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura starts towards him frightening Harold.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes... yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She allows the feeling of Bob to come over her and she begins to scream. Harold steps back, but Laura grabs him. To his face with a horrifying expression on hers.</context>
      <utterance>What? Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FIRE WALK WITH ME.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She buries herself on his shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at Harold. Her eyes widen, terrified with suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>The trees... the trees... They break. LAURA  You have to hide the diary, Harold. You made me write it all down. He doesn't know about you. You'll be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not Bob are you, Harold? If you are, you can kill me right now. Kill me right now, if you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her.</context>
      <utterance>Laura, no, I'm not. I'm not Bob.  Poor Laura. I wish I could help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate him, I hate it. Sometimes I love it. But now I'm afraid. I am so afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>stronger than I... How can I help you? I can't. I can't even go outside. Laura reaches up and tenderly touches his cheek. HAROLD (continued) What about James? Can't James help you? You two are so in love.</context>
      <utterance>But you're strong Laura... so much</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in love with a girl who's dead.  It _is_ dangerous for you to have it. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him to her and kisses him passionately.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura slowly goes out the door. Harold can only watch.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know when I can come back. Maybe never.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lied to me about those school books. I found them upstairs on your bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you doing in my room?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was looking for that blue sweater that you borrowed which I found balled up in the bottom of your closet. Now why did you lie to me? Where did you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to see Bobby. I know you really don't like Bobby, but there was a problem and I didn't think you would understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, honey, you don't have to lie to me. Ever. You can tell me anything. I'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now hurry, dinner's almost ready. Your father says he's starving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Laura. Hello Sarah. Where's my axe?  "I'm hungry".</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Leland.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Translation is: How are you? My name is Leland Palmer. Laura and Sarah stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hyggelig a mote dem. Jeg Heter Leland Palmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Norwegians are coming next week and I want you to learn to say what I just learned in Norwegian. So you can talk to them. I want you to learn to say, "Hello, my name is Leland Palmer".</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But my name isn't Leland Palmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither is mine. And can't we talk about something serious for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland repeats his phrase for Sarah's benefit.</context>
      <utterance>This is serious. Mr. Benjamin Horne's got a delegation of Norwegians coming in next week and I want both of you to learn to introduce yourself. Sarah, you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stumbles through it.</context>
      <utterance>Hyggelig a mote dem. Jeg Heter Leland Palmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland repeats his phrase back to her. Extends his hand in a friendly handshake.</context>
      <utterance>Hyggelig a mote dem. Jeg Heter Sarah Palmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. We'll practice some more. Laura, now you try it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After Laura is done.</context>
      <utterance>Hyggelig a mote dem. Jeg Heter Laura Palmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland extends a hand to each of them. An air of insanity seems to come over the Palmer dining room as they all begin to laugh hysterically and talk in broken Norwegian.</context>
      <utterance>All together now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura begins to unbutton her blouse. Turns and sneaks a toot of cocaine. TRUCKER (continued) (catching her) Wait a minute. Leo says this is my party. Laura puts her hand between his legs.</context>
      <utterance>Friend of Leo's, right? Partyland?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Momentarily taken aback, the trucker stares at her. Laura takes his hand and puts it on the gear shift. LAURA (continued) You shift that one. This one's mine. She climbs over on top of him.</context>
      <utterance>If you can fuck and drive the party starts right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cooper, the ooze of mumbo jumbo is rising up above our heads. Do you honestly think Cole's practice of word association works?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The very fact that we are talking about word association means we are in a space that was opened up by our practice of word association. The world is a hologram, Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's a great big psychedelic circus ride, isn't it, Cooper?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said, "Teresa Banks", so you think something is going on somewhere in the world right now that is connected with her murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Either right now or right when I thought of it. The name and memory of Teresa Banks is haunting me. Lately I have been filled with a knowingness that the murderer will strike again. Because it is only a feeling, I am powerless to stop it. And another thing, Albert, when the next murder happens you will help me solve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's test it for the record. Will the next victim be a man or a woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What color hair will she have?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blonde.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me some other things about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in high school. She's sexually active. She's on drugs. She's crying out for some help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're describing half the high school girls in America.  What is she doing right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert lets go a small laugh of disbelief and shakes his head in exasperation.</context>
      <utterance>She is preparing a great abundance of food.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, would you give Laura a quick hand with the "Meals on Wheels"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm kind of busy, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a little squeeze of the hand and a gentle shove, Norma moves Shelly towards Laura who is at the end of the counter. The door opens to the Diner and ED and NADINE HURLEY come in. Nadine stops when she sees Norma.</context>
      <utterance>You're not busy, sweetheart, now go.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nadine goes out. As she walks past Ed he looks at Norma and makes a "What can I do" gesture.</context>
      <utterance>I changed my mind, I don't want any coffee, Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY AND LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly approaches sheepishly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I give you a hand getting the dinners together?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's alright, Shelly. I know you have better things to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma asked me to give you a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly gathers up a pile of the dinners and takes them out to the "Meals on Wheels" car.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You can help me carry them to the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TREMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Laura the picture. It is a picture of a room with flowered wallpaper and a dark doorway in its corner. Laura's study of it is interrupted by the grandson.</context>
      <utterance>This would look nice on your wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's looking for a book with pages torn out. He's walking towards the hiding place. He's moving under the fan now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shelly, you really can help me. I can't do the "Meals on Wheels" today. I just can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura runs off. Shelly puts her load into the car as she watches Laura.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura just took off. She asked me to do the run today. Should I do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with that Laura? Yeah, sure, take a look around. There's no one here anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. There's no one here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no one here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma just turns away and picks up some dirty dishes.</context>
      <utterance>Norma, are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back as soon as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Leo comes here, he won't believe that I am out doing the "Meals on Wheels".</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shelly leaves the diner.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Shelly, I'll handle Leo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP:  ON NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She starts to cry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A closer look reveals how upset Laura is.</context>
      <utterance>Laura...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura turns away so the woman can't see her crying. The woman takes a couple of steps off the sidewalk onto the grass.</context>
      <utterance>What... Laura are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura mimes that she has found her gold half-heart necklace. She pretends to be clasping her gold half-heart necklace which was already around her neck.</context>
      <utterance>I... lost my necklace... it must have fallen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woman moves back to the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, Laura stands and moves away - leaving Mrs. Tremond's picture on the grass under the tree.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm glad you found it, darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna, are you my best friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura dives toward Donna and into a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it Laura? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want a friend. Just one friend for just one minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, how about one friend for the rest of your whole life?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's what I want. Thanks D.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, L.  I am your friend... always. But sometimes... lately... I feel that you don't like being around me because I am so uptight.  No, I am uptight. I hate it... I don't want to be this way, but Laura I don't... I mean... I'm your friend no matter what way you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go in and sit down on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>You know, even when I think about your face I get happier.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She digs for a cigarette in her purse.</context>
      <utterance>No, I want to smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you think?</context>
      <utterance>I'm in a mess today, too.  I'm thinking about doing it with Mike.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donna, you are such a crack up. You don't even like Mike. Is this what you are going to do to show me you are not uptight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is about sex, not like.  Mom, Laura's here and I think I will have one of those huckleberry muffins.  You want a muffin?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I can smoke it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a muffin?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear DOC HAYWARD in the kitchen. He walks in with a magician's handkerchief. With a flourish he tries to pull something out of it. Instead he stands there empty handed.</context>
      <utterance>Donna, you are a muffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura finds a cigarette finally and lights it.</context>
      <utterance>The red rose. Where is the red rose?  You know the light at Sparkwood and 21? It worked right there. I just did it right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it that you can't smoke at your home and I'm a doctor and I don't allow smoking in my home and I let you smoke in my home?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you love me so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eileen Hayward brings out the muffins on her lap in her wheel chair. All four have muffins.</context>
      <utterance>I do love you, you little smoking whipper snapper.</utterance>
   <speaker>EILEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While eating Doc takes out a piece of paper and stares blankly at it. The girls exchange glances about what Dad is doing as they chew on the muffins. Doc is struggling.</context>
      <utterance>These muffins each have at least seven full huckleberries in them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, what in the world are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna peeks over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a prescription.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My handwriting is so bad that now I can't even read it. You girls better hurry up and graduate from high school so you can take care of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA AND LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go over to Doc and give him a knuckle rub. Eileen laughs along with the two girls. The phone rings and Doc gets it.</context>
      <utterance>We'll take care of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura goes tentatively to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Yep, she's right here, Leland...  It's for you. It's your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Time to come home for dinner, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna leads Laura to the door. There is something wrong and Donna is beginning to feel it. Donna tries to cheer her up.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Muffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura leaves. As Donna closes the door, Laura calls back to her.</context>
      <utterance>No, you're the muffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're right. I am the muffin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, honey, how's Donna?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>School?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...school's fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down... sit down... Are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From across the table Leland looks at her fingernails. He stands to come for a closer look.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't wash your hands before you sat down for dinner did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah, cigarette draped from her lips, is delivering some mashed potatoes to the table.</context>
      <utterance>Your hands are filthy... look, there is dirt way under this fingernail.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leland, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is looking at THE FINGER.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this finger here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leland...</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for it. Laura's hand flies up and stops him. Leland's other hand comes up and she lets him take the HALF HEART out.</context>
      <utterance>Laura didn't wash her hands before dinner.  And look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is this from a lover? Laura has no response. LELAND  Did you get this from your lover?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't call them lovers in high school, Leland.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby didn't give you this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland starts pinching Laura's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>How would you know if Bobby didn't give her that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Bobby give you that or is there someone new?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leland leave her alone... She doesn't like that. Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat then a return to what is normal.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know what she doesn't like?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Leland, sit down and eat you dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland sits stoically. Laura rises from the table.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll sit down, but none of us are going to start eating till Laura goes and washes her hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland can barely speak.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, Leland?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah goes to Leland. They embrace, tenderly, across the many years of their strained marriage.</context>
      <utterance>I can't remember the last time I told Laura that I loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, honey, go in and tell her now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura can hardly speak. She squeezes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Laura, honey... He moves to her and touches her face. LELAND  I love you. I love you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves the room. Laura watches the door close. She sits frozen for a moment, with a tear in her eye, then she remembers something.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Princess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you last night? We were supposed to get together. You didn't show up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to show up. Maybe I wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were supposed to be together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I be together if I'm not together?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on somethin' again, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland comes out the door of the house. Looks at Laura and James. Laura can feel him staring.</context>
      <utterance>When am I going to see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James just looks at her then guns his bike and roars away. Laura walks back to the front door where her father stands.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend from school.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura looks at her Dad, eyeball to eyeball for a moment. Then she walks past him to the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>A special friend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura's head snaps around.</context>
      <utterance>Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... No, go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you let me talk to you. You used to not let me talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away. I am not talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah Palmer is at the bottom of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura jumps.</context>
      <utterance>Laura?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, now I can't find that blue sweater. Did you take it again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah looks down. She is wearing the sweater that she is looking for.</context>
      <utterance>Mom... what are you wearing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My god, I am going to have another breakdown. God, god.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura starts down the stairs towards her mother.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura holds her mother.</context>
      <utterance>No, no... this can't be happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah pulls away from Laura and wanders into the living room. Laura watches her go feeling helpless.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, you're not having a nervous breakdown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone who knows how to clean knows where the object was before she started cleaning and then that object goes back to its exact same spot. Shelly, I know where everything in this house is. Sometimes on the road I mentally go through this whole house and picture where every item is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lay off the bennies, Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(shouting)</context>
      <utterance>Anybody can clean the surface of an object, but dirt can find its way anywhere. To really clean, you have to scrub below the surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHERE THE DIRT IS, SHELLY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He scrubs more. LEO  That's one thing you are going to learn, Shelly, - HOW TO CLEAN. It takes scrubbing, Shelly. There is no easy way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As if I didn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to show you how to wash this tile and then you're going to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come off it, Leo. I'm late for work...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo goes over the top pulls Shelly down to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gives her a good shot to the back of the head. Shelly falls to the floor. The phone rings. Leo gets up to get the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Shelly, I am not fooling around anymore. The first thing you've got to WORK on is a good attitude. That's the key. Anybody will tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even _think_ about going anywhere, Shelly. I'm not finished with you. He answers the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo looks over at Shelly suspiciously. (Did she hear him mention the five thousand?)</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing calling me here?... No way, you already owe me money... Five thousand, to be exact.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five Thousand???</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You interested or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby starts to write information down on a napkin.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe, Bobby, baby. Maybe. I have friend who has what you want. His stuff is the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jacques... you crazy Canadian. This sounds BIG...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No place, fast.  And you're not coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move back into the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Laura. I'm your best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't tonight the night you are going to do it with Mike?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura shoots her a look.</context>
      <utterance>Laura, aren't you going to fix me a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the Cookies?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Fred and Ginger?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna looks around at all the ashtrays filled to the brim with butts.</context>
      <utterance>Dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had a nickel for every cigarette your mom smoked, I'd be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta go, Donna. I'll call you tomorrow. Laura leaves the house. Donna trails behind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOG LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Log Lady touches her. Her hand is cooling on Laura's head. Laura moves in behind it. Pushing the cool hand into her face and forehead.</context>
      <utterance>When this kind of fire starts. it is very hard to put out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margaret?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOG LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look into each other's eyes. The Log Lady turns and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>The tender bows of innocence burn first and the wind rises - then all goodness is in jeopardy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go around the world, babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all take a drink.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't going to get you to Walla- Walla.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do go all the way, don't you, little girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura reaches below the table grabbing him hard by the balls.</context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trucker turns a couple of shades towards white. Donna comes in just as a beautiful song of lost love begins. Laura and Donna see each other -- As the truckers toss down bourbons and beer chasers, Laura gets _lost_in_the_song_and_starts_to_cry_. Donna just stares at her from the other side of the Roadhouse.</context>
      <utterance>You willing to go all the way? Huh? You wanna do it for me. All the way for me means all the way - DEAD.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's boogie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You part of the deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura and Donna stare at each other. For Donna's benefit, Laura turns and gives a big, juicy French kiss to one of the truckers.</context>
      <utterance>No, she isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was your name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donna grabs Buck's buddy, TOMMY, and gives him the same type kiss. LAURA (continued) (very serious) All right, Donna. Let's go.</context>
      <utterance>Buck, that was really nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura laughs at Donna then holds a beer up to show Donna, then turns and French kisses Buck. Donna reaches forward to the front dash and turns the radio up full blast. Buck and Tommy start to whoop and yodel like cowboys. Buck does an Indian whoop in Laura's face. Laura freezes in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  I don't need to take this to be you friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YES YOU DO, DONNA. What a downer you are!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tommy, Jacques beat us here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy stands in the lot with his back to them, pissing.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, I'm chokin' the farm fed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jacques Renault comes up to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Don't expect a turkey dog in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Laura up and gives her a big, sloppy wet kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, slow pokes, guess what? There's no tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, you know why? Cause it'll never get here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jacques...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No "Jacques". I am the Great Went.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am The Muffin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two truckers laugh with Jacques. He mimes a gun with his right hand and pointing it to his forehead pulls the trigger with a weak, slack cheeked puff sound.</context>
      <utterance>And what a muffin you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura winks at Buck as he SECRETLY drops a red depth charge into Donna's beer.</context>
      <utterance>I am as blank as a fart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the cowboys gather around and begin to chant, both Laura and Donna chug down their drinks. They finish and Laura smiles and pushes Donna out onto the dance floor. They start to dance expertly and smile at each other. Soon Buck and Tommy cut in separating the two. Buck dances Laura over to ANOTHER of his buddies. The two of them start to unbutton Laura's blouse as they dance. The hell-metal band kicks into high gear. In the pulsating red and black light Donna sees Laura now topless dancing and kissing with Buck and his friend. Donna stops. Jacques sweeps in.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Donna, chug-a-lug.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Laura's friend. I am "The Great Went". Jacques holds her head in his huge hands. JACQUES  There is no tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The room starts to spin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't seen you since I was thrown out of One Eyed Jacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jacques comes up to them.</context>
      <utterance>What else did we do together? Oh, I remember...  Hey, you know what? It's been a year. She's been dead a year... she's been dead a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them move around together.</context>
      <utterance>The party twins. My high school sandwich. Let's put some meat inside...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's been dead a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teresa...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teresa Banks? Yeah, a whole year.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she was going to get rich... she was blackmailing somebody...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. She called me. She even asked me what your fathers looked like...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? She asked about my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronette, Laura, and Jacques sway with distorted smiles.</context>
      <utterance>But it wasn't him... she was after a huge guy, six foot four with a broken nose. She said he looked just like a boxer. Speaking of sandwiches... I think Bobby was arranging something for you...  Speaking of arrangements...  SPEAKING OF ARRANGEMENTS... Why don't you two come up to the cabin this week? Leo and I know that Santy Claus is coming to town... Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE AND LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Jacques.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buck and another FRIEND move in on Laura and Ronette. Buck pushes Laura down on the carpet and gets on behind her. His friend does the same to Ronette. The two girls find themselves face to face.</context>
      <utterance>"The Great Went".</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go again. Like we're back at One Eyed Jacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronette looks over Laura's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, god. It sure is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura looks across the rug through dancing legs and sees Donna's head tilted way back with some NEW COWBOY on top of her.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, is that Donna Hayward?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP: LAURA'S FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seeing Donna.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACQUES...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rips her blouse off her waist. Donna is completely gone. Laura shakes her and screams into her face. LAURA (continued) Don't ever wear my stuff, don't ever wear my stuff. Never.</context>
      <utterance>Laura falls full of panic to Donna. LAURA  Donna, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I won't wear your stuff... Why can't I wear your stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jacques lifts Donna up and Laura follows Jacques and Donna out of Partyland. Donna continues to mumble.</context>
      <utterance>Jacques, help me get her home. NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't wear your stuff.  I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not you, Donna, not you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED...  ED.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed backs off and Nadine dives in slicing.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NADINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed slowly backs into the house.</context>
      <utterance>You were cutting this deer like a sissy... Sit down and watch while I do it. AGAIN. THIS YEAR.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Works every year...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPARKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure wouldn't work at my house. My wife couldn't take the wrapper of a twinkie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Josie, I think we should go public.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be wonderful, but it's only been a year since Andrew died.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you afraid of? What people think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to offend the customs of your country.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, Josie, you would not offend the customs of this country. For instance, I don't eat fish eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fish eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if it offended someone, I wouldn't eat a fish eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wouldn't you eat a fish eye, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw a guy eat a fish eye once in Seattle. He was digging through his food with his chopsticks for about five minutes till he found the fish eye and he dropped it into his throat. I guess it must have gotten stuck in his uvula because right away he started to have trouble. His throat began to flutter there like there was a wind blowing. And he couldn't swallow and they rushed to him and loosened his collar and they were asking him if he was alright and he started to turn blue and his eyes started to roll back into his head and he still couldn't get the fish eye out and they tried to do a Heimlich maneuver. I went over to him as they were preparing to do an emergency tracheotomy. They were over him with a knife when he suddenly shot the fish eye out of his throat and right onto the ceiling. Splat! It just stuck up there and spread out. It was about the size of a half dollar. And that's why I don't ever eat fish eyes. He plays the guitar for Josie. Then stops. TRUMAN  I'm not saying it's right or wrong, it's just the way I feel. It's the custom thing I was thinking of. In America we don't use any part of the fish but the meat just to the side of the insides. We throw away the tail, the rest of the insides and the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We throw away the _whole_ head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't remember anything about last night. Is there something I should remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you should forget about last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, I am your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you are and you don't have to do anything crazy to prove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not mad at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel so bad. I had nightmares all night long.  They all knew you at that place.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did the car get back here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WE got it back, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I get in the house? How did I get into my bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was I wearing something of yours and you got mad at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my things have me in them. I don't want you to be like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I love you, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I love you, too. But don't wear my stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you do it, Laura?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes Donna's head into her hands and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Cause I like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, honey... Laura turns to him with a start. LELAND  We're late to meet Mom for breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland and Laura leave.</context>
      <utterance>Catch you later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car that was tailing them races around them, races around the logging truck, and comes back around stopping on Leland's side of the car. Leland spots Gerard, the one armed man, behind the wheel - sweating like crazy. LAURA (continued) Something is burning. Leland starts to rev his engine while holding the brake with his left foot.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, is the engine on fire? Something is burning. Leland turns and gives her a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland is panicked. The car is slowly screeching towards the large lumber truck in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>You stole the corn. I had it canned above the store.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland turns to Laura. Sweat pours from his forehead. While Leland is turned away, Gerard holds up his hand with a ring on the little finger. He is shouting over the engine noise and the horn which Leland has begun to blow frantically.</context>
      <utterance>The thread will be torn, Mr. Palmer, the thread will be torn.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YOUNG MECHANIC runs up to their car.</context>
      <utterance>DAD!... What was that all about? Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr., Mr., you shouldn't do that to your engine. You ought to take it easy, Mr., you're going to burn your engine out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland stares at Laura trying to compose himself.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell was all that? Why doesn't someone do something about all of this. My god, that guy came out of nowhere. He was harassing my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, are you all right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CU TERESA BANKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is talking on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds like fun... Where did you see my picture?... Okay, come to the Blue Diamond City Motel... Yes, that's just your side of Blue Diamond City... I'll be there. Room one two three... Right, as in "Get Ready".</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On top of Teresa in bed. All whispers.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the next business trip, big fella?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon. How about next time we party with the girlfriends you told me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her and covers her eyes with a hand.</context>
      <utterance>I can arrange that. I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>End of flashback.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad... Dad... Who was that? How do you know him? He looked familiar. Have I met him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you haven't met him. Have you met him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're late to get to your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just sit here for a moment. You seem very upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy just pulls up out of the blue... I mean... what is this world coming to?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves a wad of money into her hand and practically runs away. Teresa cocks her head and wonders, while she watches him hurry away. End of Flashback.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, I chickened out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland pulls out onto the road. After they drive for a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you come home during the day last week?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I thought I saw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I did come home, come to think of it, on Thursday. I had a severe headache and I was driving in the neighborhood so I just darted in and out of the house.  Where were you, Laura? I didn't see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura studies the look in her father's eye as long as she dares and then turns away.</context>
      <utterance>I was down the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP: LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he drives along.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Teresa... what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does Ronette's father look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A short guy... heavy set... balding...</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does Laura Palmer's father look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very handsome... wavy black hair. He looks like a movie star.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Handsome, this is your little party girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura is jolted by Bob's Voice.</context>
      <utterance>The same ring...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not important. I will tell you what is important. The fan will soon be starting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? Who are you REALLY? BOB'S VOICE  I am the One who wants to breathe thru your nose and taste thru your mouth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm nearly out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's taken care of, babe. You and I are going to make a big score tonight.  This will tide you over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Bobby. A big score?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe our biggest. I'll see you two doors down from your place at 11:00.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off down the hall. Rounding another corner she sees James coming towards her. James looks around to see if the coast is clear and seeing it is, moves close to her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This afternoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.  Oh god, it's Johnny Horne's birthday today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny moves to one inch in front of Jerry's face.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben reacts to a huge moccasin print in the middle of the birthday cake in the middle of his office floor.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did we have to have the party here in my office?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Johnny wants it in your office. What's so "private" "private" about your office, anyway? Why can't we have the party in your precious office?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look down and see Johnny's foot completely ringed in white frosting roses. Frosted footprints trail behind him everywhere. Johnny goes one inch in front of Laura's picture.</context>
      <utterance>It's a lovely place for a party, Ben. And look at the new decorations Johnny's provided.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leland looks again at Laura's picture. He looks up at Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That sets Sylvia off again.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you have a picture of Audrey, Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have a picture of your own daughter, Ben? Where's Johnny's picture?  And where's _my_ picture I gave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny moves one inch in front of Ben.</context>
      <utterance>At the photographer's studio getting a gold frame with floral monograms of your birthday and our wedding vows.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, Johnny... let your Daddy and your Uncle and Leland talk.  Ben... Leland, we can play the French against the Norwegians. What do the French love more than anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boating?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiking?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eating?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're getting warmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trees?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get goofy over trees.</context>
      <utterance>Exactment. They are nuts about wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never heard anything like this before. The French liking wood anymore than anyone else likes wood. Are you three crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah's cousin is French and she can't stop talking about the trees around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>History is on our side, Ben. It's no accident that the great explorers were named Hennepin, Nicollet, Marquette.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were looking for wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they talk Johnny circles the blowup Indian and with a mighty bang pops it with his tomahawk. "Bang".</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey just called in. Bernie, the mule, left Canada about an hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then stop watching Jacques and let's set a trap for Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's coming in on foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Andy.  I guess you're saying there's an awful lot of trails for us to cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I was thinking what a long hike Bernie has to make.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to say, "Hello".</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(more)</context>
      <utterance>You missed the party. Look at my office. Come here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'd do a lot more than that for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssshhhh, your father's in the next office. You should've seen him get upset at Johnny's party about your photo here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves in closer and kisses him. He responds.</context>
      <utterance>He's always been jealous of you. You know that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pete. Can't believe your tank's dry up at the mill.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... hell, no. Just got in the truck, started drivin', looked down at the gauge and saw a big "E" starin' at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Ed's Gas Farm.</context>
      <utterance>You know what that Big "E" stands for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. You're right. That's why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fill 'er up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't got it yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did? I didn't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... look in here. Look at it from this angle. Ed puts his head inside the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete starts to clean the inside of his windshield while Ed returns to work on the outside.</context>
      <utterance>I see it.  Hell, it's on the inside, Pete.  The inside is your territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even this heavy work beats being at home with the old ball and chain.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brother, I hear you talkin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here he comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both start laughing again. They see a guy coming through the woods. We recognize him as the sullen deputy from Deer Meadow, Cliff Howard.</context>
      <utterance>Here he comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who sent you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jacques.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deputy takes out a very big bag of coke, showing it to them. LAURA (continued) Wow. Laura just grabs it out of his hand. The deputy takes out his gun. Bobby panics and pulls out his gun. BANG!! Bobby shoots the deputy in the shoulder, but the deputy still prepares to shoot at Bobby so Bobby shoots him again. This time in the chest. The deputy spins and tries to run, but Bobby shoots him in the back. He topples over dead. (more)</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With Laura's help they get the body back to the clearing. They fall down to their knees, out of breath, staring at what they have done. Their faces register the shock of having just killed someone. Laura looks at Bobby's stunned expression.</context>
      <utterance>I shot him. Oh, my god, I shot him. Bobby starts for the dead body. BOBBY  Come on, you gotta help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A laugh squirts out of Laura. Bobby turns to her in disbelief. LAURA (continued) Bobby, you killed Mike. Bobby stares at her for a second like Laura has gone insane.</context>
      <utterance>Look at your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't Mike.  Is this Mike?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby breaks. They begin to laugh uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>Bobby... ssshhhh... you killed Mike.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura stops cold on the stairway.</context>
      <utterance>I want to kill thru you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to kill _for_me_.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Never. You'll have to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to kill _for_me_.</utterance>
   <speaker>ECU: LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura looking up petrified.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babe, I'm on my way out to the woods to divvy up the product. Put this cash in your safety deposit box...  It's ten thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby is about to get really pissed when Laura starts laughing again. Bobby fights to stay in control.</context>
      <utterance>You killed Mike.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, you didn't come and see me today.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't it was Johnny Horne's birthday. I promised I'd be with him. I told you not to call me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little trouble with your parents is the least of your worries and something I am certainly willing to put up with.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you make me a tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already made you two tapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura, you have to deal with _all_ of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goodnight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm dealing with it, Doc. Big time. Maybe I'll make you a tape tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Send me a kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LELAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura. What's wrong this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Never taking her eyes off him, she works her way around him and leaves the room. We stay on Leland. His face changes. He knows she knows and he knows what he has to do.</context>
      <utterance>Stay away from me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>"LAST NIGHT"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura and her mother sit, eating alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate asparagus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They eat in silence for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you do, it's good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben asked him to stay late to plan for the Norwegians.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's okay with you I'm going to Bobby's to do my homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a school night... back by nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mrs. Briggs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Laura, Bobby's in the basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GARLAND BRIGGS chuckles off screen.</context>
      <utterance>Right where he belongs, right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura sits down next to him.</context>
      <utterance>What's up, Bobby?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad news, kid, it was baby laxative.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stuff we got last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby laxative? We can't snort baby laxative.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit...  We killed a guy for baby laxative.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the world coming to when you kill a guy for baby laxative?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get funny with me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not... Bobby I'm gonna need some more stuff. I mean it. I'm out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and I'm gonna need that ten thousand dollars back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, but I can't get it till after school tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's ditch this place and party.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight. Just give me something to take home to hold me over till tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura smiles and leans forward. She kisses him and he responds.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Why not? Where are you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss again. He looks up and listens for his parents.</context>
      <utterance>Bobby, I'm goin' home. To bed... my nice warm bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can do it right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby sees that she is not in the mood.</context>
      <utterance>Bobby...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches in his pocket and gives her a nice bag of coke plus pills. BOBBY (continued) Bobby's got it.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want me. You just want the stuff, don't ya? Laura stares at him. BOBBY  It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Bobby.  And my little round friends, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>August 8, 1991 114.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman hits the intercom button.</context>
      <utterance>Sheriff Truman?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Lucy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Packard called and said she heard what she thinks could be a prowler outside her house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases the intercom button. But Lucy continues to talk over the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Lucy. I better get on up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably raccoons which is what it was last week...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stay here and monitor the radio. Let me know right away, if you hear from Hawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And last week I thought of the same</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Sheriff Truman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman stands up, puts on his gun and leaves. Lucy's voice continues as we watch Andy sit there alone. LUCY'S VOICE (continued) She couldn't get rid of her raccoons because she made the big mistake of feeding them albacore tuna. I don't know why she fed them albacore tuna. And albacore tuna is so expensive. (voice raising an octave) Sheriff Truman how did you get up here? Over the intercom Andy hears Lucy make a small hysterical cry. He stands and runs from the room. Stay on the intercom. Lucy's voice continues. LUCY'S VOICE (continued) Andy? Are you there? I am very confused. Who am I talking to? Andy, are you there?</context>
      <utterance>Raccoons remind me of my aunt who lives in Wyoming where they have raccoons, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She races from her station and collides with Andy coming up from the interrogation room. They both scream.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'm alone.  Andy... where did Andy go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSEUP: LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hears James' bike coming in the distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James' bike sounds closer and closer. Leland turns, opens the front door and goes into the house. James drives up. Leland's face appears looking out the front window. Laura jumps on the bike behind James and off they go.</context>
      <utterance>Go inside... go inside...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. There's no place left to go is there, James?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it and I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with us?... We have everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything, but everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Oh, Laura..." She gives him a terrible slap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always hurt the ones you love.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the ones you pity.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say anything you want... I know you love me and I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do love you.  Let's get lost together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he finds out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby killed a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Bobby didn't kill anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to see...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura screams with agony and tries to get off as they approach the light. Laura falls off as they skid to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>The trees... the trees...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura crawls back up and puts her hands around James' neck.</context>
      <utterance>Laura...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on time, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buy me a ticket to The Great Went.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on our way, Baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pile into Leo's 'Vet and peel down the dirt road.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go _all_ the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a ghost Leland appears in the window. No one sees him. Laura continues to scream. Leo gets up and goes for the bottle of bourbon. He takes a swig and then steps back to Jacques and Laura.</context>
      <utterance>Bite the bullet, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me have a little of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACQUES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leo holds the bottle tight. Jacques stands up and decks Leo with his big French Canadian paw. He grabs the spilling bottle from the floor and stumbles outside.</context>
      <utterance>Let me have a little of that, baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GERARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob, I can hear you singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to kill me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Sheriff Truman just brought her in from Glastonbury Grove.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man From Another Place puts his hand in front of his lips and makes an Indian Whooping sound.</context>
      <utterance>Is it future? Or is it past?... Do you know who I am?... I am The Arm... And I sound like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is the ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone else has it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would indicate that it's the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The later events have never been kept a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I? And how can I leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN FROM ANOTHER PLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>You are here and there is no place to go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coop... Coop...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not getting any response Truman breaks open the door.</context>
      <utterance>Cooper are you alright?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I slipped and hit my head on the mirror. The glass broke as it struck my head.  It struck me as funny, Harry. Do you understand me, Harry, it struck me as funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc and Truman help Cooper up.</context>
      <utterance>You are going right back to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooper smiles at the uneasy pair.</context>
      <utterance>But I haven't brushed my teeth yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
