<movie id="578" title="Under Fire">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FREEZE FRAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE SOLDIERS RUN THROUGH THE GRASS FOLLOWING THEIR LEADER As they do, the platoon leader waves his arms again. FIVE ELEPHANTS CHARGE OUT OF THE SHRUBBERY Through a field of small mortar explosions.</context>
      <utterance>With a click-click of a camera -- still no fx.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREEZE FRAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE ELEPHANTS CHARGE OUT ACROSS THE PLAINS Each carries an enormous load of supplies, and each is ridden by a soldier with a rifle. A HELICOPTER GUNSHIP DIVES OUT OF THE SKY firing rockets at the soldiers and elephants. A tribal mask is painted on the nose of the chopper.</context>
      <utterance>With the click-click of a camera.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Morning, Jimmy, think you could squeeze me in?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is you would care to go at once, Mr. Price?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bang-bang.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price hands him a wad of bills.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy smiles broadly, nodding, then points to the sky.</context>
      <utterance>You're a thief, Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Booteeful picture, huh, snap-snap?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men get into the strange cab parked in front of an open marketplace just starting to come alive; the cab drives off.</context>
      <utterance>I don't do skies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers look over disinterestedly. Two dozen cases of Coca-Cola are tied to a stretcher among stacks of guns. As Price settles in for the ride, he begins pulling cameras from his bag. Quickly and automatically, rarely looking, he switches lenses, loads film, and prepares his cameras. He has done this a thousand times. A SINGLE WHITE SOLDIER -- OATES, rises from among the blacks, and shakily makes his way toward Price. A mercenary dressed in a ragged uniform of his own design, carries two machine guns and a .45. He smiles broadly, recognizing Price. HODGE slaps Price's hands as if they were teammates.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>G'damn, Price, you tuna sucking piece of raw meat -- whatchyou goin' to Zambeze for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I'd get some great shots of your head gettin' blown to smithereens.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smithereens?! Be a great fuckin' picture, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be a prize winner.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya think so?  Trade ya some greenies for a joint.  I gotta have a joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on the wagon, man, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod. He laughs obscenely and deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh. Dope-wise, this place sucks.  Lotta fuckin' coons around here, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were fighting for the Government?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. This is the Government.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the Rebels.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck they are. This is a Government convoy to Calunda.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>This is the Abou-Deian Revolutionary Front.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Finally Oates starts laughing uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>You're shitting me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These guys be pissed if they knew, eh?  This is the dumbest motherfucker I ever signed up for. Don't pay shit either.  Nicaragua. That's the spot. Cheap shrimp, lotta rays -- real thin in the spook department too, dig?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess we know where the Guvmint is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can walk to work from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates starts to walk away, then stops and speaks earnestly, as if trying to connect to a real world that doesn't exist.</context>
      <utterance>Convenient, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother just got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the distant roar of a jet. All the soldiers on the field scan the horizon; Price looks up. The air raid siren goes off.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know your brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price tries to read the writing on the back as Oates looks at a leaflet familiarly.</context>
      <utterance>Great shit, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>U.S. Gummint offers this house to any Cuban pilot flying Migs for the Rebels who chooses to defect to America with a Russian jet. We know they ain't gonna run off with no planes -- but the Rebs don't -- They're scared. They start thinking about that swimming pool. Damn near smell that chlorine. Starts workin' on 'em, and pretty soon they don't let the Cubies near a Mig. Use their own spook pilots and destroy their own air force in a week. Guaran-fuckin- teed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OATES shakes hands with Price who looks at the picture.</context>
      <utterance>Smartest guys in the world.  Hey, you gotta scoop here, eh? You'll be famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates heads off across the runway as papers continue blowing down out of the sky; Price looks up and speaks to himself.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta run... have a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love Africa.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up and rises more irritated than angered.</context>
      <utterance>"...The Battle for the Airfield at Abou Deia is just another chapter in this endless story. From Ndjamena, Chad, this is Claire Stryder."  No -- you didn't hear any music -- must be the connection. Okay? So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly expressed, her anger passes.</context>
      <utterance>Alex, don't play that God damn thing when I'm filing.  We're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my party -- we'll be late. You called it a "strange war" and an "endless story." If you filed that story for me, I'd say you were editorialishing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex loves to be melo-dramatic and is quite conscious of his ability to charm. He's also aware that it's worn off with her.</context>
      <utterance>I like to editorialize. You drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drunk? Only with the memories of making love with you on the plains of Fianga as the first Army of Liberation marched in and opened fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex raises a drink.</context>
      <utterance>And freed the Proletariat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves -- he quickly puts on his coat and follows her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to the party without you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I don't want to go to this stupid party. I'm bad at false modesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She straightens his half-tied tie in an act of familiar affection rather than motherliness. Nervousness. She speaks calmly -- this is ground they have already covered.</context>
      <utterance>You're great at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex, you're going to make a great anchorman in New York and undoubtedly I could be a Pulitzer Prize winning hostess -- but I'm not going with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can work out of the East Coast. We'll get a place on Long Island and burn our suitcases.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still like suitcases.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every Saturday night we'll have a party... invite all our friends, sit out on the veranda and interview each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've done all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't.  Well, God dammit, I'm getting tired of memorizing who's the president of the... Republic of Maldives.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mamoon Abdul Gayoom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile slightly as the elevator comes to a stop. The door doesn't open, and the light flickers.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he succeeded Mamoon Abdul Gayeem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs the door with his fist. It opens, and they enter a dismal hallway. The sounds of a party come from beyond.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm tired of Third World elevators.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't leave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they approach the door to the party, he speaks with new toughness.</context>
      <utterance>I already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Abou Deia and New York. I'm going to Nicaragua with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard it's a neat little war with a nice hotel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex climbs on a chair next to Price who puts his arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>Alex, get up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the man who gave me my first job, and fired me from my first job... and gave me my second job...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE FROM CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And fired you from your second job...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a few words, Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES FROM CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>However miserable, Alex shines in these situations. He raises his hand -- silence.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible! Can't be done! etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire slips to the side bar and pours herself a drink, watching Alex and shaking her head with some affection. JIMMY, THE CAB DRIVER, ENTERS WITH A CAKE covered with candles. The crowd parts for the cake shaped like the country of Chad. The crowd begins singing "Caravan" in a half-drunken tribute to a man they like and respect. PRICE MOVES AROUND THE ROOM TAKING PICTURES of the party; it is all casual, silly, fun. THROUGH CAMERA P.O.V.'S OF ALEX IN A PARTY HAT, whip pan to CABBY WITH THE CAKE, whip pan to DRUNKEN JOURNALISTS. THROUGH CAMERA P.O.V. OF CLAIRE -- FREEZE FRAME, pan follows her as she moves through the room -- FREEZE FRAME, she picks up another drink and leaves through a side door -- FREEZE</context>
      <utterance>You may be asking yourself what exactly are you doing here in this "strange war, just another chapter in an endless story... that grinds into its seventh year..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I didn't know you were here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you did. You were taking pictures of me all over the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... yeah... you looked great. Why aren't you partying?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices the picture she's looking at.</context>
      <utterance>In a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I printed that up for Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't be the greatest thing you could give him right now...  We just split up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I'm sorry. Who left who this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the villain... I thought it could be a little cleaner this time -- me in Central America, him in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's decided to go to Nicaragua too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To cover you or the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Price moves behind her and gently kisses her on the ear. She smiles quickly and nervously.</context>
      <utterance>To cover everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her on the neck.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sounds of the party can be heard. He ignores them and moves around her, trying to kiss her on the lips. She puts her hand over his mouth. Price reacts strongly, flaring slightly and withdrawing.</context>
      <utterance>For godsakes, Russell, listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to wait for you again. We've been circling each other since the Montreal Olympics.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads to the door; Price stays. She stops before getting there, hesitates, then pulls the PHOTO OF THE ELEPHANT from the string and returns to Price, handing him the photo.</context>
      <utterance>You're a genius of bad timing.  I'm going back to the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a great shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't respond. They stand for several moments -- the sounds of the party get louder. She turns and heads to Alex's celebration, leaving Price alone in the darkroom. PRICE LOOKS AT CLAIRE AS SHE LEAVES, stares aimlessly for several moments, then focuses back on his PHOTO OF THE</context>
      <utterance>I've heard the light in Nicaragua's even better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands warmly, and Price sits down. Price points to the cover as a beer is served.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Managua.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have something to do with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I thought of calling your photographs "Pictures from a Lost War"... I'm great at captions -- the New York editors loved it since none of them knew where the hell Chad was anyway -- it legitimized their ignorance, got you a cover, me a feature, and packaged a class struggle in two words. Nifty, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Russell acknowledges ISELA CRUZ sitting with Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Nifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Russell Price.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... this is Isela Cruz. She works for the hotel and helps out as a translator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE BACKGROUND CLAIRE WALKS INTO THE POOL-BAR AREA She carries her handbag and some papers -- she stops short seeing Price sitting with Alex. She hesitates, starts toward them, stops, and sits down at the bar at the opposite end of the pool. Price sees her, and she sees Price. They pretend they don't. Price turns to Isela and launches into a stream of broken, chauvinistic Spanish with his usual elegance.</context>
      <utterance>My pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you guys have a lot of bang-bang down here, eh? Little misunderstanding between the poets and the government?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Misunderstanding?!" "Down here" it's called a war. It started in nineteen thirty. Before you were born.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Spanish is a little out of shape -- what'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price looks at each of them and decides not to push.</context>
      <utterance>He said he considers it an honor to be able to photograph our war.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Russell's got a way with words.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a helluva translator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex stands to help Isela from her chair. Price presses on, instinctively and effortlessly.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm much in demand around here. Will you excuse me? If you have any questions, just ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is Rafael?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex turns to Isela, who stops as she rises.</context>
      <utterance>It depends who you ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rafael? Comandante Rafael. He is either a Marxist dupe of Russia and Cuba...  ...or the most popular leader of a most popular democratic revolution.  Take your pick.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then Price asks his question almost sexually, as if he thinks he could seduce Isela, Rafael, the whole war.</context>
      <utterance>I don't really give a damn... but the guy's got a great face.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would he like to be photographed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd never find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanta lay odds?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to leave again, and again he stops her.</context>
      <utterance>You would lose.  You must excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isela seems to welcome the question. Her tone is less flip, and she focuses hard on Price.</context>
      <utterance>Just one more thing -- is Rafael owned by the C.I.A. or the K.G.B.? I'll figure out the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his Time magazine, kisses Alex on the cheek, and floats magically through the pool area. Price frames her with his fingers as if composing a shot. P.O.V. OF ISELA THROUGH PRICE'S FINGERS Isela kisses another journalist, grabs someone's hand, and lands gracefully at another table.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Price... the world is not divided into East and West anymore. It is divided into North and South. By the time you people figure that out -- it will be too late.  Congratulations on your cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far this war's got it all over Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX PLACES HIS HAND OVER PRICE'S "FRAME" blocking out his view of the sexy Isela. Though Alex's tone is gentle, the threat is obvious.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna have a ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price takes the hint.</context>
      <utterance>Hands off. I need an interpreter more than you do right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex chooses his words carefully and speaks slowly.</context>
      <utterance>You still hanging in there with Claire?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence and an uneasiness that Alex intended. Price manages a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hanging in there like an interim post-war government waiting for the palace to be overrun... by younger men.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE RISES AT THE OPPOSITE BAR, picks up her papers, and heads straight for the two men with a bounce in her step. BOTH MEN ARE A BIT SURPRISED AT HER ENTRANCE and she hands a stack of mail to Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Younger men. Alex smiles disarmingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Alex... Russell! When did you get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes Price's hand in a friendly manner that comes out awkwardly, then races past the moment to address and entertain both men.</context>
      <utterance>Just now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to believe this -- I just beat you guys and everybody else here to a story...  ...exclusive... eat your heart out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd ya get?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just been promised a private interview with Tacho.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. The bastard won't talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to Price as if everyone knows who Tacho is.</context>
      <utterance>Who's Tacho?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's President Somoza's nickname.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who the players are yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bit of tension and awkwardness -- Claire quickly takes control and changes the tone.</context>
      <utterance>Want me to order you a hot dog and a program?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fellas! No fighting after six at night, all right? Curfew.  C'mon, we've all got something to celebrate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BOY PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three journalists relax their pose.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes it doesn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE BANDSTAND Daisy has just finished "San Francisco" and spots Alex, motioning to him.</context>
      <utterance>Let me look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daisy applauds lightly for Alex to join them. Alex is equally pleased and embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Ladeez and Gen'mun, hep me get Aaleex ov' here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not many piano bars left where I'm still welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex excuses himself and joins Daisy on the bandstand. Price and Claire are left alone in the booth as Price hands the repaired camera back to the boy. ALEX AT THE PIANO begins a slow, easy cocktail version of "Stardust," the song of his generation perhaps, and he seems happy, seduced by his own chords. PRICE AND CLAIRE RESUME THEIR POSE, and this time the camera FLASHES. Price pays for the picture from the boy. At first there is a moment of awkwardness between them.</context>
      <utterance>If she can't sing in the key of C I'm in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Well"... you finished your assignment in Chad?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and relaxes a bit at the typical Price remark.</context>
      <utterance>Got Africa all wrapped up and pouched to my editor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to love this war, Russell... there's good guys, bad guys, cheap shrimp...  And Alex is still singing in the background.  I missed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX BEGINS SINGING as he plays. He sings like a trumpet player -- no voice but great phrasing. He half smiles as he sings, enjoying the song and enjoying making them uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta get alone somewhere to talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... he's doing it on purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't really want to talk about Alex though his presence is unavoidable. Price changes gears, gets slightly goofy, and steers the conversation to more comfortable turf.</context>
      <utterance>Alex is one of the world's leading experts on military strategy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hell, I just got off the boat... gimme the scoop on Nicaragua...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... about sixty years ago the U.S. Marines invaded to protect American business interests and put down a peasant revolt led by a little man who wore a giant cowboy hat -- his name was Augusto Sandino... In nineteen thirty-four he was murdered at a peace conference, and the Somoza family has ruled ever since...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She knows what he means, but she wants to tease him a bit first.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no... I don't mean the stuff about the peasants -- I mean the real stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The "real" stuff?... you mean a history of class struggle in agrarian societies?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, c'mon!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay... well...  Just a couple things.  One -- there's only two kinds of beer available -- Tona and Victoria. Victoria's better.  And two -- if you see Miss Panama hanging around the hotel bar -- hot, hot, hot -- but don't touch. She belongs to Tacho, and if anybody gets caught with her then El Presidente has promised to personally cut off the guy's...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pecker?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... and throw it into Lake Managua.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price is impressed, and yet another new face drops by the booth -- they both recognize and see him coming, a contemporary of Price, REGIS FLYNN, a scraggly British journalist who heads over to their table holding three beers.</context>
      <utterance>And the lake's already polluted.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anybody here we don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Regis slides into their booth, happy to see them.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>G'damn, Price... kudos on the African snaps.  Jeez, Claire, I haven't seen you since...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three Mile Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods; they all sip beers and watch Alex sing.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... shit...  Holiday Inn, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... Louis Jordan walks in, and I'm sitting with the Everly Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you fall in love -- that's Marcel Jazy... friend of wine, women, and Somoza. They say he's a businessman...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a businessman in search of a business... he doesn't try very hard to cover up his connections to the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look at his moves -- can the C.I.A. light cigarettes like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE WAITER ARRIVES AT PRICE'S BOOTH and sets down three shrimp cocktails and more champagne, as:</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with the Everly Brothers?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUERRILLA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do not want to waste any ammunition on a head as empty as yours -- but we will.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUERRILLA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BUSINESSMAN refuses. The GUERRILLA LEADER takes a hand grenade from his pocket and pulls the pin without hesitation, then holds the grenade in front of him fearlessly, inches away from the Businessman's face. The Businessman rises slowly. The LEADER motions toward the back door of the club.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Get up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>TIME STRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's Charlie, from New York -- says that a terrorist bombing of a Central American restaurant isn't big enough to hold for the world section...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him we have pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG JOURNALIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him there were pieces of body in the piano, and somebody was singing, "I Left My Heart in San Francisco."  What's he got better than that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME STRINGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex grabs the phone in disgust and launches in.</context>
      <utterance>He's got the Pope visiting Egypt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Charlie argues on the other end of the phone, Alex initials papers and performs several jobs at once.</context>
      <utterance>Forget the Pope, Charlie. Every week you got the Pope somewhere. This is a very big story down here because it's the first sign of fighting in Managua.  Yeah, well get a map and look up Nicaragua -- ya drive to New Orleans and turn left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HUB KITTLE has been floating through the room and, upon hearing the word "fascist," takes offense and approaches Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Like hell I'm editorializing, the whole thing happened in a roomful of C.I.A. and press. What do you want?!  How do I know they were C.I.A.? They wore name tags, what do you think? We're backing a Fascist again -- I know that ain't news, but see if you can find an angle!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex ignores Hub though he is slightly pestered by him, and continues on the phone as he initials papers brought to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! There's fascists and then there's fascists, right? Be careful how you throw words like that around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex spots Price who is standing nearby, still eating a sandwich, still enjoying the high energy buzz of the room. Alex directs his next line so that Price cannot fail to get the message. Alex plays the moment coolly.</context>
      <utterance>We don't have any pictures of Rafael because nobody knows where the son of a bitch is, and anybody crazy enough to go after him...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hub nods seriously, in agreement. Price turns. Alex smiles. Price smiles. Alex hangs up, grumbling, then turns his attention to the persistent Hub Kittle.</context>
      <utterance>...is liable to get his nuts shot off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well g'bye...  Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex is irritated but fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>Hub Kittle. I'm with Lewitsky and Knupp -- New York. We have a client down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex is incredulous that Somoza employs a New York P.R. firm. Hub is professionally used to this reaction -- no panic.</context>
      <utterance>President Somoza.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex turns to leave; Hub corners him.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know...  But there's an untold story here. I mean, the man has a point of view too, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSEWHERE IN THE ROOM a young NICARAGUAN WOMAN, 18, is talking to Claire. She seems to be part of the local press.</context>
      <utterance>We got a national anthem contest going on right now, and you guys are ignoring it. Lotta human interest. Alex turns to other business though Hub persists.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to get me copies of the Government inventory lists of all captured Guerrilla weapons. I want to know if the guns are Israeli, Belgian, Russian, Cuban...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Guerrillas are not supplied by anybody from the outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TELEPHONE OPERATOR CALLS TO CLAIRE through the chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Fine -- give me proof.</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire sighs at the bad timing but seems delighted to be interrupted by her daughter, and brushes aside a Stringer forcing paperwork upon her. Claire takes the phone into a bare, adjacent hallway for some privacy. IN A BARE HALLWAY Claire talks to her daughter.</context>
      <utterance>Su hija, su hija! Your daughter from Los Angeles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>P.O.V. FROM THE TELEX ROOM TO CLAIRE Price knows this is not his world, and he wanders outside.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, baby! How are you?  Has Grandmother spoiled you silly by now? She has? Good.  Yes, I got your letter with the picture of your new boyfriend. He's very good looking... but he's a bit old, isn't he? No? Just how old is he?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuanto?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quince.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veinte.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs, declaring the negotiation ended, and leaves the room to change the dollar into cordobas. Price idly studies the pictures on the wall:</context>
      <utterance>Diezysiete.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Price pulls a thick passport and press credentials from a pocket, handing them to the Officer in charge.</context>
      <utterance>What is this? I'm a journalist!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer looks at Price's passport photo, studies it briefly and takes the passport. He nods. A rifle butt is jammed violently into Price's belly -- he doubles over. The Officer nods, and Price is led away. As the Guard hauls him outside, the OLD WOMAN appears in the doorway with a stack of local currency.</context>
      <utterance>Journalista, journalista!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guards laugh and leave. The Prisoner rises to his feet. Price keeps his distance. The Prisoner looks in bad shape.</context>
      <utterance>Padre Puta, Padre Puta, Padre Puta...  Here is a Priest for you to confess your sins.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price hands him a cigarette and lights it. A long, deep drag.</context>
      <utterance>Cigarillo?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Priest?   What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The government accused me of using the church to hide Rebels and guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Governments are always wrong, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This time they're right. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Un periodista.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose side are you on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't take sides. I take pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sides?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Prisoner Priest looks at Price with disdain.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Prisoner sits down in the corner ignoring Price who is surprised to be treated so despicably.</context>
      <utterance>Periodista Puta, todos periodistas son putas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldier whirls at Price in a rage out of all proportion to Price's tone, shouting:</context>
      <utterance>Mi amigo -- mala interpretacion, eh? Periodista, comprende? Famoso. Time magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price holds up his hands -- he may be fearless, but he's not stupid. The soldier pulls a knife, then pulls his own tongue from his mouth, and makes motions with the knife as if cutting out his tongue. The message is clear -- Price doesn't speak. The soldier walks up to the Waiter and points. The Waiter is frightened. Through the shadows we see an officer talking with a civilian in a hat. The civilian points to a door. THE WAITER IS LED AWAY THROUGH A DOOR protesting desperately as he goes. The soldier moves to the next prisoner -- he too is led away. This repeats itself until the soldier arrives at price.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soy un periodista.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR GUARD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Price... you must accept our deepest apologies for the misunderstanding. Somebody saw you taking photographs of terrorists hooligans in the parade and at the nightclub -- our young officers get carried away... they're always looking for traitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That film is half way to New York by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR GUARD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer reaches for one of Price's cameras and hands it to him, but as he does: THE CAMERA DROPS TO THE GROUND AND BREAKS -- SILENCE The Officer would love for Price to get angry.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know... It was all a misunderstanding... una mala interpretacion. Your cameras.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR GUARD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price smiles barely, and refuses to pop off.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price puts his cameras in his bag, and as he is shown from the room he notices a copy of the TIME MAGAZINE WITH ELEPHANT sitting on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR GUARD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price is shown to a door, handed over to a soldier, and led outside into the night.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You throw a journalist in jail -- it gets in the papers. You walk all over the same press credentials you pass out. I demand to speak to someone in authority or I'll go to Tacho myself... I don't understand you -- you're big and strong and handsome but you're not so smart!  You should be trying to seduce us!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE IS SHOWN OUT A DOOR IN THE BACKGROUND and sees her.</context>
      <utterance>Senora...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hurry toward each other and embrace briefly. The Guards watch it all curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Claire!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine -- what're you doing here? These guys are goons.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk away together.</context>
      <utterance>They love being beaten up by a woman  I've been looking for you all night -- why'd they lock you up?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Taking pictures. The usual. Jazy got me released.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jazy?! You think there's a story there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh... C.I.A. stories are all alike. I wanta find Rafael.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need help?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  When should we start.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure you probably want to do a little research on the history of Marcel Jazy's business connections in the third world countries with C.I.A. influence...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I assumed you'd just look him in the eye and say "Gimme a break, for crissakes, Marcel, are you a spy or aren't you?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...are you a spy or aren't you, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spy is such an odd word, Mr. Price... nobody is a... 'spy'... anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Russell prefers pictures to words...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to apologize... you're journalists.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're a businessman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A businessman? That sounds good. Okay, I'm a businessman.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he speaks, the questioning comes to a sudden halt as a SPECTACULAR LOOKING WOMAN emerges from the shadows of the house into the light of the courtyard. She is tall, Latin, and besides high heels wears only a shiny, high fashion swimsuit, cut high on the legs. Price, Claire, and Jazy stop to watch as the woman stops to look into the empty pool.</context>
      <utterance>Why was I arrested, and why did you get me released, and who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN SWIMSUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No agua.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No agua.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carries the glass of wine to the woman, smiling warmly.</context>
      <utterance>If she dove in, I assure you she wouldn't notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart, the Guerrillas knocked out the pumping station on the road to Masaya, and we must ration water for the time being. Next week maybe things will be better.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN SWIMSUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should go back to Panama.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jazy pushes a lounge chair over to her and hands her a glass of wine. The woman unfolds gracefully into a lounge chair in the sun. Very sexy. She reaches for and kisses Jazy's hand affectionately -- he kisses her forehead. She feels better now. Jazy motions for Claire and Price to follow him inside.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were arrested because the Guardia are clowns who specialize in excess. You were released because I told them to release you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at them directly.</context>
      <utterance>These are not the normal duties of a businessman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He refills their glasses.</context>
      <utterance>But they are the normal duties of a... spy, eh? You win, I'm a spy.  There, are you happy? I feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red light of her recorder is on. She smiles slightly, undisturbed, and turns it off.</context>
      <utterance>Now we can relax. You can turn off your little thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Claire are almost afraid to speak, afraid to interrupt this strange performance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I trust you won't say anything to hurt me. In some ways I'm a terrible spy. I used to be much better at it, but now it seems everyone knows who I am. I have too many girlfriends. I like to be photographed.  I talk too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always talk too much... but my girlfriends like that... No matter.  You know who she is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE AND PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Miss Panama. Do you know who that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE AND PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, yes, etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire interrupts with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>She's in love with me. I've got to get some water in the pool.  And once a week I have lunch with President Somoza to discuss security measures against the Sandinista insurgents, but all he wants to talk about is Miss Panama... he's worried about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jazy smiles slightly before confirming.</context>
      <utterance>Because he thinks she's seeing another man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all smile at this complication. Price is impressed. Jazy changes the subject with fluent and disturbing ease.</context>
      <utterance>...and he assigned me to find out who the man is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. They don't know how to respond.</context>
      <utterance>We all know the Revolutionaries are going to win, don't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a rumor about this picture. Some people say you're a genius -- that you invented this scheme.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was lots of people's idea... Have you been to Leon?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to Masaya... they say the Rebels have hit the cuartel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's supposed to be nasty there... a lotta people think Rafael's in the South. I want to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, it's not "nasty" yet. Another week maybe.  You would love Leon. A nice cathedral and beautiful light... et un peu de bang-bang.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not doing a travelogue, you understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, of course... only I have heard that Comandante Rafael has recently had his unit in the area.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rafael is near Leon?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice of Miss Panama.</context>
      <utterance>Well... it's a rumor, what do I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS PANAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Estoy desemperado!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's lonely!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let us stand in the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't wait for an answer, but excuses himself and goes out to tend to Miss Panama. P.O.V. OF JAZY AND MISS PANAMA BY THE EMPTY POOL as Jazy touches her, whispers, and she waves to Claire and Price.</context>
      <utterance>It's my job.  You think I talk too much?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you dream about Miss Panama last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dreamed about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a good time?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out and touches his band-aid.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... so'd you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And old war injury flaring up?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the tape on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was on the deck of the U.S.S. Pueblo catching some rays when the North Koreans attacked... took a bullet right in the chest, but by luck I had an extra roll of high speed ektachrome in this pocket right here... over the heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the bullet ricocheted off the film, grazed your cheek, and saved your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PASSING SHOT OF A CLUSTER OF ROADSIDE CROSSES marking a series of graves. Immediately the tone in Claire's voice changes, sobered by the reminder of war.</context>
      <utterance>You heard about it?! I was lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did anyone ever die next to you in combat?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>F.8 at a sixtieth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an old joke. My question was serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So was I.  You ever dream about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again their glibness is interrupted by what they came to see. Even as they joke, they watch the landscape with concern. REFUGEES ARE STREAMING OUT OF LEON, mostly women and children, some old men, carrying their possessions. Soldiers stand around.</context>
      <utterance>Fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm basically a coward, Russell, I hope you understand that. I hope we don't get shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was quiet here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price speaks in English knowing he can't be understood.</context>
      <utterance>You must leave the car here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thinking of scoring a Toyota?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price responds by flashing his light meter in the air, taking a quick, nervous reading.</context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful?! Where the fuck we going? Better light?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must come and help us... one more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the Sandinistas brings Pedro his rumpled baseball jersey from another room.</context>
      <utterance>No, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pedro sees Price and Claire and is more interested in them. He speaks in broken but understandable English.</context>
      <utterance>For Leon... for Nicaragua!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Americans? Journalists?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE AND PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pedro lights up, and runs to a shelf where he returns with a baseball he is signing.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah! I put my autograph on this ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pedro is more interested in the two Americans.</context>
      <utterance>Pedro! There is no time to waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pedro hands Claire the baseball as the Sandinistas plead with Pedro for his help. He is more interested in getting the baseball delivered to Tippy Martinez. Claire accepts the ball graciously, exchanges awkward glances with Price, and puts it in her shoulder bag.</context>
      <utterance>When you get back to the United States, I want you to give this ball to Tippy Martinez for me. He is from Nicaragua.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enrique is dead! Roberto has disappeared! The Guardia has the church, and we need you!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come, eh?  Can they come with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go to the door and open it a crack to look out. P.O.V. THE TANQUETTA PASSES as Soldiers kick open doors across the street. The Sandinistas go to a corner of the room and push a book shelf out of the way. A large hole has been broken in the wall. They climb through the hole into the living room of the next house; the woman pushes the shelf back over the hole with great effort.</context>
      <utterance>Come! Everybody come!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RED CROSS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a woman drag a body out into the street. The Red Cross man makes small stacks of bodies. He douses the bodies with gasoline and sets the pile aflame. Then continues.</context>
      <utterance>Hay heridas o muertes aqui? Hay heridas o muertes aqui?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED CROSS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price watches. He thinks he hears something, then dismisses it. Something else. A voice, almost a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Hay heridas o muertes aqui?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns. One of the bodies speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Price. You motherfucker, Price, I'm talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price looks out -- the Sandinistas are on the other side of the roof. This war gets stranger.</context>
      <utterance>Where are those bastards... are they away?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A body rolls out from under another body. Blood-splattered, smiling, wiping the blood from his face. It is Oates, the mercenary from Africa. He peeks out the window -- the Sandinistas are on the other side of the roof. He whispers.</context>
      <utterance>They're away.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment they understand that they are there for the same reason -- they make their livings off war. Oates peeks out the window nervously and repeatedly.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OATES readies his automatic weapon in case it's needed -- routine. Price doesn't know how to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Awright, awright -- you're lookin' good... how ya like Nicaragua?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates laughs quickly and softly -- he is tuned into the strangeness of Price's answer.</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shitload o' greasers though, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sandinistas seem to relax. The Sandinistas take pride in Pedro and pat his left arm for Price and Claire.</context>
      <utterance>You're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>San-dee Koufax, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si, Koufax.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They seem to want approval from the Americans.</context>
      <utterance>Es mejor que Koufax, eh?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sandinistas slap hands, familiar with the American gesture. The Six start walking across the plaza away from the church. In the b.g. we see piles of bodies burning; the Red Cross tends to the wounded locals. Spirits are high as they walk. The tiny red light glows on Claire's recorder.</context>
      <utterance>Much better than Koufax.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Koufax is okay... but Tippy Martinez, he is the best... he pitches for the Baltimore Orioles, and some day I will be the second man from Nicaragua to play in the major leagues...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All five of them agree that Pedro is the best; they slap his valued arm and relax for the first time all day.</context>
      <utterance>Tippy Martinez had a good fastball, but Pedro has a curveball and a screwball that are better.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will give my autographed baseball to Tippy and tell him in five years I will be pitching with him, okay? He better watch out for me, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too dangerous to return to Managua at night. You should stay at the house of hammocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gracias. Can they get into trouble for keeping us?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEDRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SHOT RINGS OUT, AND PEDRO'S CHEST EXPLODES in front of us. Sudden panic, rage, confusion -- the Sandinistas whirl and scan the building. P.O.V. OATES RACING ACROSS THE CATHEDRAL ROOFTOP into the night. PRICE GRABS PEDRO'S GUN AND WHIRLS to face the church; his action is instinctive, angry, and electric with energy. CLAIRE GRABS PEDRO'S ARM AND DRAGS THE BODY to safety, though there is no safety and the body is lifeless. Her actions are protective and automatic. THE SANDINISTAS TAKE CONTROL OF THE SITUATION and move quickly. Two of them fan out to cover the escape. Price screams in the direction of Oates,</context>
      <utterance>No, no... you are not combatants.  The Baltimore team is my team...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire drags the body near a bench under a tree.</context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sandinistas survey the cathedral and streets carefully, warily, upset at their nonchalance. They know the sniper is disappearing into the night, but they continue to look.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDINISTA #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Three Sandinistas fan out toward the church as it gets dark. PRICE AND CLAIRE STAND NEXT TO PEDRO, feeling helpless and ineffective. They both look at the body. Price realizes he's holding Pedro's gun and places it down next to the body. Price notices the tiny red light is still glowing on her tape recorder. He points it out to Claire. She turns it off.</context>
      <utterance>I will talk to Pedro's mother. You must go to the house of the hammocks if you want to be safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks Price bids the family farewell and comes into the room with Claire where he lies down in a hammock.</context>
      <utterance>Hello sweetheart, this is your mother. I'm in Leon and I miss you. Don't worry about me -- it's not dangerous at all. I guess you can't believe what you hear on the news. I'll put this this tape in the mail when I get back to Managua, but knowing what the mail service is like, I may be home before it arrives. I think about you all the time and hope I can make it back before you graduate from Jr. High.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire lies down on a mat, exhausted, after turning out the light. Several moments pass before Price speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I love you and I'll finish this letter when I get back to the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who shot Pedro. I knew somebody was in the tower.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell the guerrillas?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... then they would've killed him I guess. I didn't want to interfere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't an easy choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I think I made the wrong one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't take any pictures when it was over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't?  I picked up a gun. Jesus.  Is something happening to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. They lie for a long time in the dark. A light in the house is turned off. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you asleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price gets out of the hammock and lies down next to her. They don't speak. They kiss. She unbuttons his shirt. He unbuttons her blouse. They undress just enough to begin making love softly, quietly.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>G'morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She realizes what he's been doing.</context>
      <utterance>You look beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you been doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her sense of violation is balanced by this notion. For a moment we sense her attitude can go either way -- outrage or some sense of being flattered, however ill conceived. She chooses the latter.</context>
      <utterance>'Bout ten frames. Wait'll you see the pictures -- you look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet I look great -- give me the film.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After they're printed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price hands her the film and climbs back under the blanket with her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll develop them myself -- give it to me or I'll start taping what you say in your sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I talk in my sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They curl up together, holding onto each other. A small child crosses the courtyard, peeking at them. A rooster crows.</context>
      <utterance>Girl's names and F-stops. Terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The peacefulness is shaken by the roar of an engine close by. A HELICOPTER GUNSHIP PASSES OVER THE COURTYARD They look up, jolted out of the moment. The war is back.</context>
      <utterance>Call the office. I don't want to go to work today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was Matagalpa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINI-CAM CREW #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No bang-bang, Alex... none at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINI-CAM CREW #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small laugh. They continue on. Alex enters Claire's room.</context>
      <utterance>Half the press corps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.  How was Leon?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex finally acknowledges that it is over with Claire, but refuses to say it directly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I'll bet... Claire...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired of Nicaragua.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't been here very long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long enough, lets face it, you were right... everybody was right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My cheekbones. What do you think of 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like your cheekbones. Alex, are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a face made for television.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex nods, then seems to hit the end of his own resilience and gets vitriolic.</context>
      <utterance>You decided to go with the network.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he a good fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a simple monologue Alex goes from outrage to acknowledgment of what he already knew.</context>
      <utterance>Alex...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a reasonable question for a reporter to ask, isn't it?!  I shoulda never come down here, eh? This is the way it's going to be.  I'll make a shitload of money in television for just sitting there.  I'm gonna show up to work at Rockefeller Center every morning and they're gonna hand me the news with my coffee and toast.  I shoulda never come down here, eh? This war down here belongs to you guys, okay? I'm on tommorrow's plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to take me to the airport? It's okay.  I shoulda never come down here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price pulls a bottle of wine from his camera bag and sets three styrofoam cups on the cab roof. He hands the cork to Alex and shows him the label.</context>
      <utterance>Take this to check in. I'll be right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex does, and looks at the label.</context>
      <utterance>Sniff this sucker, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, where'd you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The C.I.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They toast and drink.</context>
      <utterance>Where else.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- I'll leave you guys alone, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, don't be ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward smile from Price.</context>
      <utterance>We're grownups, Russell...  Most of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price makes the motion of taking a picture. They look at him with affection, yet astounded again by his inappropriateness.</context>
      <utterance>You two wanta happy snap?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No happy snaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wanders away from the car to give them a moment alone, and as he does he pulls the light meter from his pocket, flipping it on and off nervously without looking at it. He wanders idly toward a Guardia soldier. The soldier gets nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...  I'll just... be over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex considers this -- he understands (whether he wants to or not). THE SOLDIER COMES FACE-TO-FACE with PRICE, WHO BACKS OFF</context>
      <utterance>For the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a personal friend of Tacho's.  The soldier stops at Tacho's name. Price turns.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, I'm a chicken, don't worry.  Alex, listen to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex is amused, Price is serious. The cabbie comes out and Alex heads into the airport.</context>
      <utterance>Within a year you're gonna be one of the "Ten Most Admired Men in America."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late to your own luncheon, Mr. President -- we can schedule this for another time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense -- let them wait. We are a stunning couple, eh? My stomach is very flat -- I've been working out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are a stunning couple. Mr. President, you own one fifth of all the land in Nicaragua, you own the shipping port, the national airlines, the Mercedes dealership...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand and leads her to two large portraits hanging on a wall -- his parents.</context>
      <utterance>I am on a salt free diet...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you always hold hands with reporters?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my mother and father. They were very special to me. Every Sunday morning I drive out to the cemetery and put flowers on their grave. I think people should know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somoza just smiles unaffected by her questions; she knows the game is undaunted.</context>
      <utterance>Would you care to comment on the fall of Leon to the rebels?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Russell, let's grow up. It's very easy to fall in love with the underdog, eh? But there's an upside and downside to this thing -- just wanta remind you... this stuff about a "Revolution of Poets" is crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's great P.R. So what's the upside?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price gives him a cigaret.</context>
      <utterance>Simple. And it could happen. Somoza destroys the terrorist insurgents, rebuilds the country, shitcans the purveyors of excess, stabilizes the cordoba, and is finally beloved as the savior of Nicaragua.  Our pal. Got a smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the downside?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's simple, and Hub is pleased with his presentation. A SOLDIER moves through the crowd looking quite out of place, finds Hub and hands him a note. Hub reads it, seems delighted, and excuses himself from the table.</context>
      <utterance>The Commies take over the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Regis look at each other strangely -- what's he talking about? They shrug, Regis bites into a papaya, and Hub hurries inside. Price and Regis watch the singer.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, gentlemen, but the war may be over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My people love me. My stomach is flat. Did I say that already? No matter. It is flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somoza ignores the question and reopens the window, flooding the room with the Tony Bennett classic.</context>
      <utterance>There are reports that the Guardia operates a torture chamber at Coyotepe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like this song.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since the earthquake in 1972 destroyed half of Managua, over three hundred million dollars in foreign relief aid have poured into the country, yet nothing has been re-built. It is said that the money has gone into your pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love the press, I really do. Some of my best friends are journalists.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HUB KITTLE AND AN OFFICER BURST INTO THE ROOM interrupting the interview. Something has happened. Somoza initially lashes out at them -- the first time we've seen him lose his cool -- then recovers.</context>
      <utterance>Ecuador, Mexico, Peru, Brazil, and Panama are reportedly on the verge of breaking off diplomatic relations with your regime. Would you comment?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire is left alone momentarily in Somoza's room. A soldier enters and accompanies her outside to the luncheon.</context>
      <utterance>Did he tell you about his parents in the graveyard, the flowers and all that?  Good, good...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friends... this gathering was not intended to be a press conference as much as a... "get-together"... but I have just been handed a piece of news. Somoza plays the moment with theatrical elan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has been killed in an ambush in the Cordillera mountains of the Jinotega district. Somoza points to a spot on the map as do his Officer. THE PRESS TABLE IS SHAKEN FROM ITS NONCHALANCE and several journalists immediately leap to their feet to question him.</context>
      <utterance>Rafael is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALISTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. President! Mr. President!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somoza hands the mike to an aide who returns it to the music stand. Almost immediately the music begins again. AT THE PRESS TABLE there is some confusion over the announcement. Some journalists hurry off to file the story, others just sit. Price seems alarmed by the announcement, confused. Slightly wired, he listens to Regis and OTHER JOURNALIST discuss it.</context>
      <utterance>Please my friends -- no questions. A press release is being prepared.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER JOURNALIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got Rafael? You believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE TRIES TO CORNER HUB KITTLE who is heading back inside. Hub disappears inside, Claire pressing after him. JAZY APPROACHES PRICE and leans in as if sharing a confidence. IN the b.g. the luncheon is breaking up.</context>
      <utterance>Every six months Tacho gives this speech -- maybe they finally lucked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price throws his camera bag over his shoulder, pulls out a camera, and follows Jazy. They walk toward the head table.</context>
      <utterance>Russell, excuse me... but I've just been put in a rather embarrassing position.  Mrs. Somoza would like her picture taken with Miss Panama. In color?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell could Tacho find Rafael.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Somoza and Miss Panama are waiting as Price and Jazy arrive. Price is automatically switching camera lenses, but he continues to grill Jazy.</context>
      <utterance>Russell, please... I have my hands full...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Jazy exchange glances as Somoza reluctantly joins the portrait. SOMOZA POSES WITH HIS WIFE AND HIS MISTRESS ON EACH ARM as Price flashes a light meter under their noses, then backs off to take the picture.</context>
      <utterance>Tacho, Tacho... venga, por favor!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Tacho lying again? They did kill him, didn't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price takes a picture, Somoza wants to leave and Jazy would just as soon have this awkward moment over with, but:</context>
      <utterance>Everybody smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly they pose again, and Price grills Jazy who is trapped.</context>
      <utterance>One more, please! Una mas, por favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jazy moves Miss Panama slightly, returning to Price.</context>
      <utterance>We help each other, right? Could you move your girlfriend into the sun...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Rafael alive or dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Somoza holds an interminable pose, Jazy launches into a speech, keeping his voice low enough so Tacho cannot hear.</context>
      <utterance>Just one more -- thank you.  I thought you knew everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I know, eh? Tacho needs a victory very badly... he needs to prove to Jimmy Carter that he is still winning. He thinks Rafael's death is the proof he needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter don't need proof. He just sent twenty-five million in new arms to Tacho.  I'm sorry... almost got it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no... the arms shipment has been delayed in New Orleans because Jimmy is getting nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jazy and Price motion for the posers to move a step over.</context>
      <utterance>The State Department's gonna pull the plug on Tacho?! Pardon my French -- but whose fucking side are you on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I work for everybody. If there is a transition of power, I facilitate a relationship with the new people. If there is not, I facilitate the status quo.  Either way, I facilitate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I send messages to Jimmy and I tell him that the Revolution is a flood that cannot be stopped but it can be controlled... nobody listens... I can't even get a little water in my pool.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price smiles to Somoza, Mrs. Somoza, and Miss Panama. Somoza hurries off from his uncomfortable position at last.</context>
      <utterance>Rough ain't it. Thank you everybody, very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think Rafael is dead. I'm gonna find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men share a smile.</context>
      <utterance>They say he's very handsome.  It would make a wonderful picture, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Con permiso -- who controls what today?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED CROSS WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Sandinistas hold the hills, the Guardia has everything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we find the guerillas?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED CROSS WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Va alli, dos o tres cuartos, doble la esquina al francotirador.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Regis and his crew don't like this at all. Price points.</context>
      <utterance>Go two or three blocks and turn right at the sniper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong way!</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not looking for the guerillas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car stops, the door opens, and:</context>
      <utterance>Then let us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldier seems sincere, but they don't want to take a chance.</context>
      <utterance>Lo siento!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CAR MOVES DEEPER INTO MATAGALPA, gradually moving among tanquettas patrolling the streets, coming to a barricade which they manuever past as Guardia soldiers look at them strangely. The car turns around -- it has come too far. A GUARDIA OFFICER SIGNALS FOR THEM TO GET OUT but the idea doesn't appeal to Regis and he whirls around, panicking slightly, and heads off in the other direction.</context>
      <utterance>Go one more block.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just wanted to see credentials, for crissakes, what're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE BARRICADE OFFICER SPEAKS IN A WALKIE TALKIE to a squadron leader a couple of blocks away as the car approaches. THE SECOND OFFICER WHISTLES FOR THE CAR TO STOP but it speeds up.</context>
      <utterance>We want out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Busca triquitraques?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow him up a hill.</context>
      <utterance>Venga.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are somewhat taken aback at her directness and information.</context>
      <utterance>You are looking for Rafael?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If it's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know why we're here... exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Price doesn't do anything before announcing it first in the bar.  It's a good story. You'll be more famous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price doesn't answer but continues taking it all in, and ISELA shouts to them to continue.</context>
      <utterance>Rafael's tent?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THEY CONTINUE INTO THE CAMP, BUT PRICE STOPS AGAIN Something has caught him, his sixth sense, a feeling -- he refuses to walk further for the moment. No glibness, just coolness.</context>
      <utterance>Venga, companeros.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price looks around, speaks quietly.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire looks around quickly. There is no evidence to her.</context>
      <utterance>Rafael is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can smell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue into the camp -- now Claire looks around nervously. Price mutters a half laugh, softly and strangely, as they are led to a makeshift table and offered food. In the b.g. Isela enters one of the tents. PRICE AND CLAIRE SIT DOWN TO EAT and Price continues scanning the camp as they talk.</context>
      <utterance>Venga por favor! Alli!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead. I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>P.O.V. FOUR FIGURES/CONFERRING IN FRONT OF A TENT Isela emerges and joins them. The others are: THE PRIEST FROM LEON,</context>
      <utterance>Then why did they bring us all the way here to see him? He doesn't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isela begins at once.</context>
      <utterance>This is Commandante Cinco. They all shake hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today we took Matagalpa. Leon is about to fall, and Masaya. And next week we could be in Managua but it is still possible to lose.  In the last days of our final offensive the people of Nicaragua must know that Rafael is alive and well.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDANTE CINCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queremos un fotografia.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a photograph.  Come with us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COMMANDANTE CINCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usted es un fotografo magnifico.  Queremos que vive.  Price laughs -- the request is ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is he laughing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cinco steps forward -- his presence commands attention. His delivery is forceful but not emotional. As he begins to speak, Price stops laughing.</context>
      <utterance>You're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses briefly.</context>
      <utterance>We have momentum, but many more lives will be lost. Even Washington is starting to admit that the butcher Somoza is not loved by his people. They have detained twenty-five million dollars in new arms shipments for Somoza at an airfield in Florida until they find out if Rafael is alive or dead. We know about these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Washington thinks Rafael is dead, they will ship the arms to Somoza. Do you understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CINCO attacks that defense with new vigor.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  Commandante... Soy un periodista.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE hesitates, his manner devoid of its usual cockiness.</context>
      <utterance>This has nothing to do with journalism -- there is more to the world than journalism. We are going to end this war with you or without you.  People don't really believe in Rafael -- they believe in the idea of Rafael, no? Because for now the idea of Rafael is enough for the people of Nicaragua. When the war is over -- none of this matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't do things... like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COMMANDANTE CINCO PLACES AN ARM ON PRICE'S SHOULDER and speaks in broken English.</context>
      <utterance>Enough lives have been lost already.  It's difficult, I know -- but you must do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the morning, eh? When there's better light!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods slightly.</context>
      <utterance>I spend my whole life separating how I feel from how I think and what I see from what I say -- that's called journalism, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's disciplined. It civilized. It involves distinctions. I'm great at distinctions. I wish I wasn't so good at them. Sometimes I envy you -- you don't make any -- it's very convenient.  The only time I don't worry about all those things is when I'm with my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or when you're in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!  My job is to find a story, then tell a story -- whatever it is -- because I believe that if enough people hear enough stories then somehow, through information alone, we all have a better chance to survive.  I believe in information.  That's a very romantic streak I have running through me -- maybe it's a weakness. Information is good -- lack of information is bad. Simple, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're God damn right it's not.  You take that picture you'll take it for all the right reasons -- I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fiddles with the cameras.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine for you. But do I go back and say I interviewed Rafael? Do I go back and say I missed the biggest story of the war? Or do I say Rafael was stone cold dead -- that's the information, isn't it? Or do I say he entertained us all in his inimitably charismatic manner around the ol' revolutionary campfire?  Can we throw up our arms and say we fell in love with the querillas because their cause was... sympathetic?  Journalists don't fall in love.  Which story do you want me to tell?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what you want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, what the fuck are we doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I want to be here.  With you.  What do you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Claire lies down on the cot. Exhausted but high. Price gets off the table and goes to her.</context>
      <utterance>I want this war to end.  I'm not going to tell the world that Rafael is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets on the cot with her. They kiss deeply, passionately, and begin making love.</context>
      <utterance>Don't think so much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the smoke in frame?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWMEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE STANDS TO THE OTHER SIDE with binoculars watching. She accepts a drink from Hub and speaks into her tape deck.</context>
      <utterance>Roll it...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fires down the drink and puts down the mike. She picks up the binoculars again and, glancing below, is shocked:</context>
      <utterance>Under a steel gray July sky... start again... under a gray steel Managuan sky... scratch it... In an extraordinary development in Managua, President Anastazio Somoza has ordered the Air Force to begin bombing his own capitol, under a sky... fuck it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price sees Alex at the same time. Alex waves to both of as he heads into the hotel. Price and Claire look at each other. Claire sits down at a table, stunned to see Alex. Price commandeers a waiter and joins her with a fresh tray of drinks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price joins her as other journalists jockey for position at the railing. He is equally upset and confused.</context>
      <utterance>A Scotch, please...  Double.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX COMES THROUGH THE DOOR with a couple journalists, sees Price and Claire and comes over to join them. A polite kiss on Claire's cheek, a handshake for Price. A moment of awkwardness.</context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what?! The Washington Post, the Times, networks, wire services -- everybody's picked up the picture. It's fabulous.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes... it's fabulous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unsure silence.</context>
      <utterance>Fabulous.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came back because of Russell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex enjoys the lunatic mixture of politics and popular culture.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... the whole fucking East Coast is falling in love with Rafael -- they were sure he was dead this time. Somebody wants to do a musical about him and his mug's on every T-shirt in Central Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire and Price struggle to enjoy this supremely uncomfortable moment. It's not easy to enter the game. Claire attempts to change the subject.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's bigger than Farrah Fawcett.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look good. Things're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happier in New York, sure, things are great. You guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No more games. Alex addresses Price with conviction.</context>
      <utterance>Terrific... now... I'm a little slow here, Alex... what exactly did you come back for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want to talk to Rafael... and you're the only man in the world that can take me to him. Price's and Claire's hearts sink. They look at each other. Alex, despite his reluctance to return to Nicaragua, seems genuinely enthused about the possible story. Before Price or Claire respond, Hub Kittle notices Alex and comes over with a tray of drinks, extending genuine greetings to the Senior Correspondent.</context>
      <utterance>It's a great story.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fresh round of drinks are put on the table. The sound of bombs ripping the capitol are the only thing we hear.</context>
      <utterance>Alex! Couldn't stay away, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to tell Alex what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell him. He deserves to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't owe him anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We owe him that!  He got you started in this business... he covered for your missed deadlines and made excuses for your unprofessional attitude before the world fell in love with your pictures...  Before kids fresh out of journalism school were rushing off to any war they could to interview bullets and take pictures of bodies -- like Price!  He took care of you before you were hot! Silence. She's hitting home but he doesn't want to acknowledge it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is something calculating in Price's tone, this is not the fearless, boyish innocent anymore.</context>
      <utterance>Before Nicaragua you wouldn't understand. I'm not sure I exactly understand.  What are we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire is disturbed at this compounding of the lie.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take Alex to find Rafael -- we'll go to Sebaco on the road to Matagalpa -- the Guardia heavily control the area and they're scared right now -- they'll never let us through. We won't be able to get near Rafael. Alex will understand -- and we'll turn around and drive back without a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lie!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. They are co-conspirators and they know it.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about lies!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to tell him either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We may not be able to find him, y'know...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A car is on fire by the side of the road. Price flies past; Alex watches curiously. Several people stand around the car.</context>
      <utterance>I've got supreme confidence in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claire looks good, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex isn't sure how to respond to this curious reply.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody looks good in the tropics.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price is nervous, wired, on edge.</context>
      <utterance>Since I haven't been able to find Isela since coming back, you're going to have to translate for me -- what the hell does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex takes this calmly -- it's not exactly new information.</context>
      <utterance>Alex... I love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she 'thinks' she loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex looks at the passing scenery -- he's in no hurry.</context>
      <utterance>It's past the thinking stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to know something -- it probably doesn't matter in the great final scheme of things... but I'm interested...  Did you ever lay a hand on her before she left me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is something desperate in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!  Alex -- we're friends!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are led to a shed by the roadside, A TIRE REPAIR SHOP, where they sit down in an oily, dusty shack. They watch the soldiers: P.O.V. THE SOLDIERS TEARING UP THE RENTAL CAR, pulling off door panels, looking for weapons.</context>
      <utterance>Venga.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you go through a few rental cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE AND ALEX JERK TO LIFE at the sound of screaming in the distance. A volley of gunfire follows. Price moves quickly into an adjoining shed and looks through a crack in the wall: P.O.V. AN EXECUTION SQUAD IN A FIELD as several bodies are being hauled away. Two soldiers reload their guns. PAN to a figure moving behind a wall -- OATES.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I put this in your name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates smiles half-way; Price looks around at the bodies.</context>
      <utterance>No pictures, eh? Might look bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get paid by the body or by the hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get paid the same way you do. What the fuck you doin' in Sebaco -- this place's about to blow... ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to nail Pedro.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex arrives and tries to pull Price back -- at the same time he sees the bodies and is sickened at the sight.</context>
      <utterance>Who's Pedro?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A body is carried through and loaded on a truck. Oates's tone is one of explanation rather than defense, very matter- of-fact.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price mumbles and wanders to the next truck a few feet away, and as he sees it he stops short, speechless. He points:</context>
      <utterance>There's a motherfucking war goin' on, pal... lotta sad stories.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates has to look to see who he's talking about, and Price loses his cool.</context>
      <utterance>Why them? Why them?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a cocksucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE GRABS OATES AND PUSHES HIM BACKWARDS but Oates responds like an animal. The two men go down in a heap and lash out at each other in the dust. Their fighting is largely ineffective, though very physical, until Oates asserts himself and knocks Price against a wall, breaking free to pick up his automatic rifle that he handles with one hand and shoves it into Price's face.</context>
      <utterance>I don't suck no dick, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd prefer not splattering your brains in a dump like this -- I got priorities.  Guy wants to be a hero, pops, get him outta here before he's a number.  Be a shitty little town to buy it in.  Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Russell, let's get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy's got a sense of humor, old man.  Got any dope? Tough place to find decent dope?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why them?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads them under an awning nearby where a couple soldiers sit. A small table, some weapons, two shallow boxes, food, beer. Oates rummages around to find what he wants, and pulls out: A HANDFUL OF PHOTOGRAPHS, mostly snapshots, odd sizes, with names written on them. He sifts through them quickly and we see an assortment of photographs of Nicaraguans. He finds what he's looking for and holds up: PRICE'S PHOTOGRAPH OF THE PRIEST AND THE BUSINESSMAN, the picture taken in Rafael's camp, blown up, cropped, and identified. The faces are circled.</context>
      <utterance>Them? C'mere. You too.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This information hits Price in the gut, and he is seized with fear.</context>
      <utterance>If your mug shows up in this box... and ya try to make it through Sebaco... I owe yer ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gives you the pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price turns, he doesn't want to face it.</context>
      <utterance>What's this, an interview? I ain't that dumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off the record.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates pulls another picture from a different box and holds it up:</context>
      <utterance>Off the record... some pachuco gives 'em to me. Ain't none of my business, but I heard he gets 'em from a Frog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex grabs Price and heads back toward the roadblock.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatya' expect? We're the ones gettin' our butts kicked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Some-motherfucker-took-my-fucking- pictures-I-don't-fucking-know-what- happened!  Fuck me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you ship the film to New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The car races.</context>
      <utterance>I developed it in my room.  Jesus Christ, Alex?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down.  It wasn't your fault if somebody stole your stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex doesn't force the issue, nor does he understand it entirely.</context>
      <utterance>It was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer -- the car races back to Managua. Alex stares at Price trying to figure out what is wrong.</context>
      <utterance>What about Rafael?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Algo no esta aqui. Fotografias.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's always a mess here. You should be neater.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The maid shrugs -- Price is crazy anyway, and: CLAIRE WALKS INTO THE ROOM She too looks shaken. He looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Negativos, negativos!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The maid starts crying. They look at her helplessly as she sobs, 'Cinco, Cinco...'</context>
      <utterance>Commandante Cinco's body was just found on the road to Matagalpa.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still no answer.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think it's Jazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price is impatient. He looks around nervously -- the Guards are out of view -- and he slides a knife into the latch, jimmying the lock. The door opens slowly -- an alarm goes off. Price and Claire duck inside quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Oates said it was a Frog. How many Frenchmen you know around here? Jazy ain't 'facilitating' shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price, momentarily comfortable with the danger, responds quickly and finds the alarm wire running along the door jamb. LA GUARDIA TROOPS NEARBY HEAR THE ALARM and head toward Jazy's. INSIDE THE HOUSE PRICE FINDS THE ALARM BOX which he pries open and expertly pulls two wires. The alarm stops. Immediately they begin going through drawers and cupboards. She pulls out some harmless snapshots of Miss Panama, replaces them.</context>
      <utterance>Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we looking for negs or prints?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They find nothing downstairs. The look up at the sound of distant gunfire. Suddenly: Loud banging at the front door -- La Guardia.</context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(What do you want?)</context>
      <utterance>Que quiere?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donde esta senor Jazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No esta aqui.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Who are you?)</context>
      <utterance>Que quienes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers look at each other curiously and push open the door to look in the house without entering -- respectful of Jazy.</context>
      <utterance>Una novia suya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers laugh and peer into the room. Claire forces the door closed on them, teasing slightly.</context>
      <utterance>El hombre tiene muchas novias, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Afraid to make a mistake with one of Jazy's sweethearts, they don't press the issue. The door closes shut.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A door off the bedroom is open -- light spills out. Claire stops cold at what she sees: PRICE STANDS IN A ROOM FULL OF PHOTOGRAPHS Hundreds of pictures of all sizes, photographic equipment, an enlarger, cameras and lenses, etc. Pictures of Sandino, newspaper photos, snapshots. P.O.V. OF RUSSELL'S PHOTOGRAPHS FROM RAFAEL'S CAMP cropped and blown up -- Commandante Cinco, the Priest of Leon, the Businessman, Isela. Photographs of other slain rebel leaders. The pictures include faces that have been circled with names written in -- exactly as in the pictures Oates possessed. They are both stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Russell?  Russell?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THEY HURRY DOWNSTAIRS and as they get to the front door -- the sound of somebody opening it. They freeze. THE DOOR OPENS AND MISS PANAMA ENTERS She smiles and greets them in a friendly, aloof manner, and continues toward the waterless pool.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS PANAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Claire return the greeting and continue out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hola.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start walking.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to talk to Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flags held high, they move nervously down the street into the ominous silence of the city.</context>
      <utterance>You think our flags are big enough?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what I want to show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We drove through three roadblocks a half hour before curfew so you could show me a statue of Tacho.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Alex knows Price too well -- it's a great story but that's not why they're here.</context>
      <utterance>It's not Tacho. It's Mussolini. Tacho went to Italy to commission a statue of himself, he found a warehouse full of Il Duces on horseback, got a great deal on one of 'em -- brought it back and switched heads.  Ya can't tell, can ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think what he's trying to say -- what we're trying to say -- is that things aren't exactly what they seem to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they don't "seem" to be that great so I can't wait for this one...  Hey, here we are! Two guys in the tropics in love with the same dame... bullets flying!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex! That's not why we're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Claire addresses Alex calmly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? I left the country because of him...  ...and I came back because of him...  And now the cutest couple in town has me looking up a horse's ass on a midnight tour of Managua.  What are we doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rafael is dead. Silence. Alex isn't quite sure he understood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the picture he's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. A bit of gallows laughter from Alex as he circles the statue. Price calms and tries to explain.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares how?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex... I think I finally saw one too many bodies.  Somoza is a killer.  I thought the war would end sooner.  How many reasons do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw too many bodies? That's a lot of bodies.  You stupid son of a bitch.  Did he talk you into it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I wanted Rafael to be alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In some way I understand him doing it, I don't like it but I understand... but you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex lets it all sink in. These two people about whom he has such passionate feelings have totally exposed themselves to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'd do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't respond -- he's right.</context>
      <utterance>You two have, of course, just served me up your balls -- if that's what they're called -- on a platter.  I can bury you both. You're handing me your careers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Jesus Christ... this is a motherfucking story, Russell...  What am I supposed to do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Small, tired gallows laughter from Alex. There is a long silence before Alex speaks, aware of the irony.</context>
      <utterance>Anything you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're holding the lead in the World section for Rafael.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's great stuff, isn't it? We'd go down in a blaze of glory.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah...  I don't know what to do.  I've gotta take some kind of a story back with me. Maybe Jazy, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little dangerous looking for Jazy at the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, danger -- I love it. You could ask the pointy-shoed little bastard about your pictures... and I could ask him whatever happened to Isela.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex is surprised slightly, but takes pleasure in revealing it.</context>
      <utterance>She's an officer in the Rafael army -- we saw her in Matagalpa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Claire exchange glances. Alex is dead serious.</context>
      <utterance>You mean I slept with a Sandinista?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess Rafael is alive, eh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out the window -- it never used to be this complicated.</context>
      <utterance>Damn air conditioning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I was home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mere. She goes to him, lies down, and they embrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A loud, long burst of automatic weapons fire is heard somewhere outside. Their eyes are open as they hold onto each other.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think it's almost over?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex... let's go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jazy's probably sitting in the bar laughing at us. Which way's the hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask her... be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Alex is out of the car at once, approaching the woman. Alex motions that "it's not necessary" and talks to the woman. We can't hear, but she points down the block. INSIDE THE CAR Price cranks film into place, his actions are automatic and nervous. When he looks up:</context>
      <utterance>Just a sec'... take a flag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops quickly as they see him, realizing how exposed he is. THE GUARDIA START FIRING AT HIM, realizing the murder was recorded.</context>
      <utterance>You fucks! You fucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARDIA SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fotografia!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shock wave goes through the room -- hands raised, questions.</context>
      <utterance>It is with grave concern that we announce that Alexander Grazier, senior American correspondent, has been murdered at the hands of terrorists...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMOZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somoza turns and leaves as Kittle passes out press statements.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kittle has prepared statements for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk is under attack.</context>
      <utterance>Get my bill and get me a cab, hey, amigo!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No cabs.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cabs!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No cabs!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes him away politely; she is single-minded now.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Claire...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard from Russell?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody has.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Regis looks at her like she's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Wanta help me find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hub Kittle enters the lobby, sees Claire and volunteers:</context>
      <utterance>Claire... it's on the weird side out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire is nearly in tears, but resists.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Claire, a human tragedy, what can I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck off, Hub, get outta my way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all point down a street. She shows them the polaroid of Price and her.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where the American journalist was killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They haven't and continue on their way. Claire walks in the direction they pointed -- no street fighting but many Guardia.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the best I can offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gracias.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esta alli?!  No answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SQUADRON LEADER HEADS TOWARD THE ROOM but as he does, the boy soldier appears in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Esta alli?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader grunts an order, and the squadron quickly heads to the next house. PRICE'S BODY SLUMPS AGAINST THE WALL EXHAUSTED, and the woman enters as soon as the last soldier has gone. Price's brief moment of peace is shattered by the screaming of Guardia troops and the explosions of rocket fire from the gunship. He looks outside. THE GUNSHIP FIRES INTO THE SHANTYTOWN killing several of its own Guardia troops. A GUARDIA OFFICER screams at the gunship and fires a hand gun at the giant chopper.</context>
      <utterance>No esta aqui.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE SEES HER, and races along a wall until they meet, grabbing her on the run -- each is panicky and frightened -- and they duck into very shallow cover, barely safe.</context>
      <utterance>Russell!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace quickly and tightly, but look around nervously as they do. Price isn't sure if anybody knows about Alex.</context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>P.O.V. A TANQUETTA PASSES ON THE NEXT STREET, visible through shattered holes in the buildings. A Guardia squadron passes. PRICE AND CLAIRE RUN DOWN THE STREET in the opposite direction, their path guided somewhat by an overturned bus in an intersection, abandoned barricades and roadblocks, and the rubble of street fighting.</context>
      <utterance>The Guardia did it -- I got pictures.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sandinista looks at his comrade, then looks around nervously, frightened, then shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Hola.  Do you control this area?</utterance>
   <speaker>DISCO SANDINISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price and Claire continue on down the street and simultaneously noticed something strange: THE DOOR TO JAZY'S HOUSE IS WIDE OPEN They approach carefully and look in a view to the court-yard. Claire sticks her head in the door slowly, and as she does: A GIANT HAND GUN IS STUCK IN HER TEMPLE as TWO MUCHACHOS quickly seize her and Price, dragging them inside.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. We kill them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guns are aimed back and forth in confusion -- Price and Claire don't have a chance to respond, and they're not sure what to say.</context>
      <utterance>No. Only him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Muchachos begin arguing rapidly among themselves; and as they do, Jazy addresses Price and Claire coolly.</context>
      <utterance>Him or him or her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here we are, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assassin! Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys are confused -- they think I had their family killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You murder people.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Murder" is a word for criminals. I have a job to protect the stability of a continent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pig! Hijo de puta!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is not begging for his life as much as for them to calm down.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got caught by some boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Poets too, I imagine.  Is your recorder on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Muchachos don't understand what he's saying, but they stop to listen to his style. The guns remained trained on all three.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I have a speech to make.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you people, but you are sentimental shits. You fall in love with the poets, the poets fall in love with the Marxists, the Marxists fall in love with themselves. The country is destroyed with rhetoric, and in the end we are stuck with tyrants.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jazy turns to the boy who jams the gun into his head and speaks with tired authority.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Un minuto, por favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Muchachos are immediately surprised and delighted, and one of them speaks in excited, broken English.</context>
      <utterance>They are journalists.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Muchachos quickly withdraw their guns from Price and Claire and aim them all at Jazy's head.</context>
      <utterance>Periodistas! Take this picture! I'm going to blow his head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somoza? He is a tyrant too, of course. A butcher.  But finally that is not the point, you see. If we wish to survive -- we have a choice of tyrants, and for all the right reasons, your poets choose the wrong side.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fotografia!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Your picture of Rafael was brilliant... but I am alive, and better looking. A good looking Frenchman with a sympathetic face is murdered in cold blood while fighting for the survival of Europe and America.  You will have another magazine cover!  Muy complicado, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You picked the wrong side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE TURNS AND WALKS AWAY, her back to the scene.</context>
      <utterance>In fifty years we will know who's right.  Are you going to take the picture as the bullet enters the skull or as it comes out? This wall's a nice color, eh? I can move into the sunlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE REMAINS AND STARES AT JAZY as the Muchachos grow increasingly impatient. Some part of him wants to take the picture.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a story!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUCHACHO #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRICE TURNS AND WALKS AWAY toward Claire. Still -- Jazy talks.</context>
      <utterance>They say that if somebody's holding a gun on you, you should never stop talking... that's the theory -- who knows?...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's a good thing that I talk too much...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?  Russell... what did Alex do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head and leans it against Price's shoulder but the distant popping of guns does not even allow her a moment of mourning. Their heads pop up nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. He asked for directions.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta get outta sight -- half the fucking army's looking for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>They're not looking for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price doesn't want her to go alone, but he's not that excited about hiding out in the middle of the city either.</context>
      <utterance>Let me have the film...  ...if I can't get to the hotel I'll come back here...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, Christ...  I've wrecked everything else, at least let me take care of you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows she's right. He loves her, and he's made enough disastrous decisions lately. He hesitates, then pops open his camera and removes the film. Price ties the film into the white flag that hangs from a stick stuck into her belt.</context>
      <utterance>Russell... it's more dangerous being with you than being alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss, and Claire runs out after a Red Cross truck. Price watches nervously until they turn a corner, out of sight, then goes back inside Jazy's courtyard. PRICE NEARLY STUMBLES OVER JAZY'S BODY, stops, stares -- he'd forgotten already. The body makes him uneasy, and after several moments he finds a sheet and covers Jazy. Price then sits down and waits nervously, sharing the courtyard with Jazy.</context>
      <utterance>That's great advice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a while for Claire to respond.</context>
      <utterance>Journalist?  You knew the man who was killed?  Fifty thousand Nicaraguans have died... and now one Yankee.  Perhaps now Americans will be outraged at what is happening here, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noise in the distance from mortars. The Doctor speaks calmly, without bitterness in the voice, but with total conviction.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... perhaps they will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>American journalist fifty years ago. Claire acknowledges the grim truth of the observation with a slight nod, and walks to the railing as: ALEX'S DEATH IS REPEATED IN FREEZE FRAME SEQUENCE over and over again as the Orderlies, Doctor, and patients gather to watch with fascination. CLAIRE STARES OUT AT THE CITY ON FIRE, when her eye catches something -- a light in the sky. She watches:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should have killed an</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen La Guardia?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN WITH CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Is the war over?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DISTANT, DRONING NOISE GETS STEADILY LOUDER. Claire looks around nervously.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHILD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>P.O.V. -- SEVERAL TANQUETTAS AND EARTH MOVERS coming over the hill in the distance. The Refugees look up fearfully and some hide. As the war machinery gets closer, we see that: SANDINISTAS ARE DRIVING THE MACHINES draped with red and black (F.S.L.N.), blue and white (Nicaraguan), and yellow and white (the Vatican) flags. Graffiti of victory covers the tanquettas. PEOPLE COME INTO THE STREET CHEERING, embracing, only gradually realizing what has happened.</context>
      <utterance>Tanquettas! Tanquettas!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN WITH CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the war over?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN WITH CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman continues with her children, her comment unemotional, and Claire smiles slightly and walks away, through a city awakening slowly to its victory. CLAIRE STOPS A RED CROSS TRUCK and shows the driver her picture of Price. The picture means nothing to the driver. Claire continues through the city, looking for Price.</context>
      <utterance>Es bueno.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>P.O.V. -- A HANDMADE CASKET SITTING IN THE LOBBY with the name, "A. Grazier" scrawled in felt pen. Price and Claire stand next to the box silently -- there is nothing to say -- but the silence is interrupted by a familiar voice that is polite, unforced, and sincere.</context>
      <utterance>Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OF HUB KITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward silence until they realize that he's sincere.</context>
      <utterance>It was the best I would do under the circumstances. The casket, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you help us ship it home?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the woman and little girls as Hub's family.</context>
      <utterance>I've already taken care of it.  I always liked the guy. I can't even get tickets for my own family, but I could get you two on the plane if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shared silence at the lunacy of the moment, interrupted by the tired voice of one of Hub's daughters.</context>
      <utterance>Tacho's in Miami.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB'S DAUGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hub goes over to take care of his family.</context>
      <utterance>I am sorry. I had a job to do -- that's all -- it put me in some unhappy situations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Price looks over to see the smiling Oates.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pricey...</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all over, eh? We made it. I like the singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oates holds up his Kodak Instamatic camera.</context>
      <utterance>Free country. Now it's free, anyway.  Nicalibre!</utterance>
   <speaker>OATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout a quickie?  No? Things are heating up in Thailand... thought I'd check it out.  You ain't gonna turn me in, are ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a plane to catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer -- a final complicated question from Claire -- they smile. Price waves for a cab which pulls over. They get in the cab and drive away.</context>
      <utterance>Did you get enough pictures?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
