<movie id="583" title="Virtuosity">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context>The guy pays little attention to the broadcast. He seems almost bored by it. Like this kind of news is commonplace. Or he's got more important things on his mind. Everybody is sweating. Including the two men struggling to swim upstream in the river of pedestrians. Their uniforms are freshly pressed. Their shoes just recently shined. Hair tightly cropped. Faces perfectly shaved. Clearly men proud to wear the badge of the Los Angeles Police Department. The guy in the lead is</context>
      <utterance>As L. A. P. D. officers gather evidence at this grisly crime scene, you can only ask yourselves —— what kind of lunatic would commit such unthinkable crimes?  The three adjectives which best describe this killer are sadistic, intelligent, and dangerous...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His partner is JOHN DONLEY, late 20s, eager to prove himself. He struggles to keep up with Parker. John accidently knocks over several pedestrians. They give no reaction, except to pick themselves up and continue on their way. Parker and John keep charging. Their conversation breathless:</context>
      <utterance>His body is a running back's. His endurance a marathoner's. His face one you'd want for your own. He's in his 30s. If he was in his 20s, you'd still be jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get over how different you look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker spots Sid 6.7 across the room. Without hesitation the hunter chases his prey. Gun out and firing. NOT what you would call Standard Police Procedure. Bullets riddle Sid 6.7's table as he dives from his chair. He lands next to a bowling ball bag, which sits beneath his table. John charges from the other direction until a WOMAN gets up from her chair, standing directly in John's line of fire.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon. May I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before she can do so, Sid 6.7 stands behind the Woman, grabbing her and throwing her across the table into Parker. CRASH! They tumble to the floor. In the same movement, Sid 6.7 removes a gun from inside his jacket and shoots John in the shoulder before he can fire. John's gun flies from his hand. Sid 6.7 advances toward him. Parker struggles to his feet. Aims his weapon. Sid 6.7 does the same, but without looking. BOOM! Parker gets a bullet through his shooting arm. His wound IDENTICAL to John's. Parker's weapon tumbles to the floor as his arm goes limp. Parker charges him wildly, but Sid 6.7 brutally kicks him in the stomach. In perfect rhythm with the symphony playing in the background. Parker doubles over, gasping for breath. Another kick drops Parker to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>Lady, move!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He carries John and the bowling ball bag into the kitchen. Parker scrambles to his gun, and races after Sid 6.7.</context>
      <utterance>If you get hungry, I'd recommend the escargot. They're delicious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's John?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Advancing up the aisle, Parker levels his gun at Sid 6.7 with his good arm. Now, all work comes to a stop as the Sous Chefs watch the showdown.</context>
      <utterance>Performing solo.  Enjoying the concert so far?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fires directly through the chest of the innocent Busboy hitting Sid 6.7. The Sous Chefs gasp in horror as the Busboy drops through Sid 6.7's grasp to the floor. Dead. Sid 6.7 stares at Parker in disbelief. Blood is now visible flowing from a bullet hole in Sid 6.7's shoulder, which was caused by the same bullet. Sid 6.7's arm dangles uselessly. His gun lies on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Recital's over, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker again pulls the trigger. Click. Click, click. No bullets.</context>
      <utterance>. You and me aren't so different, after all...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He takes off around the corner. Grabbing another clip from inside his uniform, Parker goes after him. Only to stumble over something. Sid 6.7's bowling bag. Blood flows through its zipper. You now realize the object inside is NOT a bowling ball. Beside the bowling bag lies John's body, which is convulsing. His hands have been tied to bare electrical wire. John is being electrocuted. Parker kicks away the wires, but not in time.</context>
      <utterance>Like a violin without strings...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Cox pull him out early for?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barnes used to work for him when he was still a cop in the field, remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The experience becomes real.</context>
      <utterance>Lindenmeyer developed neural connectors that tap directly into the nervous system. If the simulator isn't calibrated properly, experiencing death in this level of VR is like experiencing death within a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simulations are supposed to give participants practice in realistic, dangerous scenarios while protecting them from the risks they are exposed to in the real world.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was assured the problem was corrected.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did fix it.. I told you I did. I don't know why it happened again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again?!</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My first two pairs of convicts suffered the same fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't I told?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black book dollars, black book operation. You pay me for results, not how for how I get you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you one thing -— there is no way in hell we should allow any real officers to train in this damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After giving Wallace a cold, hard stare -- namely at his hand stitched lapel, his gold watch, and his diamond-studded cufflinks, she exits. Wallace follows after her quickly. You now notice that the chair Dr. Madison Carter had occupied is now empty. She left a while ago. Cox remains. Lindenmeyer hurriedly examines the simulator as if it were his child. There are several scratches, but no major damage. He looks relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Then about all I've spent $37 million developing is a very expensive way to control the prison population.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He...only had a year left on his sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you think I care? Parker, still not fully conscious, hurls himself at Lindenmeyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guards back off as Cox helps Parker to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I'll walk him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd.. .you pull me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps Parker toward the exit as he continues having difficulty with his balance.</context>
      <utterance>Donley started experiencing the attack for real. If I hadn't gotten you out, the same thing would have happened to you.  You may not believe this, Parker, but I still consider us friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell did you have to shoot the busboy for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a computer program for crissake.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to act as if everything was real.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real, my ass. It's an overblown game.  Anybody ever catch that fucking psycho?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you, nobody else had gotten close enough to Sid 6.7 to take a shot at him. Hell, nobody else had even been able to start tracking him before he got to them first.  New scar —— you making it okay in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts walking ahead of Cox. Distancing himself.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting by.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to know how I'm doing? Every day, I lose a little bit more of myself.  I'm becoming something else, and it scares the hell out of me. He turns back toward the transport. Cox follows. Two armed GUARDS open the back doors for Parker, then stand poised with weapons out and ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But with the six months off I get for being your guinea pig, I've only got to survive another 17 years, 5 months, and 23 days.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give up, Parker. Not ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know those cheesy Christmas cards of your family under that tree in your back yard you keep sending me every year?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor —— keep sending them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be angry with me, Daryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you recognize the son-of-a bitch who got away?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I have?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace enters briskly.</context>
      <utterance>Think hard -- it'll come to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You embarrassed me in front of the highest—ranking law enforcement official in the country.  Do you have any idea how much money you just cost me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reason you insisted on testing my system with prisoners is because of the increased risks involved with increased realism.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of the six prison inmates you've tested —— all of whom have had at least some military or survival training -— only Mr. Barnes is still breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still making adjustments...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are to turn over the Sid 6.7 program, and all its documentation, for immediate destruction. Is that understood?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace ignores him as he walks toward the door. On the monitors, Sid 6.7 starts walking toward you. Into a CLOSEUP.</context>
      <utterance>I understand... I understand perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace stops, staring at a monitor in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Wallace, you really think you can shut me down?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does he know who I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hears...everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits.</context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Wallace...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, little man, you're wrong. I think, therefore, I am. Click. Sid 6.7 hangs-up. Wallace stops, staring at his phone in disbelief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Red kicks in the door to the stall. Revealing a pair of shoes and socks stuffed with a prison shirt. Red hears something behind him. And turns around slowly. Parker stands barefooted and shirtless. SCARS are visible around each arm just below the elbow. You will learn what these represent momentarily. Parker is six inches shorter and 60 pounds lighter than Red. But the punch Parker delivers to Red's face makes you think it's the other way around. You HEAR the sound of metal crushing bone. Red is thrown backwards into the stall. Blood splatters from his mouth, adding another shade of redness to his face. Red's teeth stick out of Parker's fist. Parker pulls out the teeth. He does not bleed. Nor seem in pain. Metal is visible beneath the surface of his skin. For the first time, you notice SMALL TATTOOS on the outsides of his palms. They read: WENTLOW MODEL 17-L, and 17-R, followed by serial numbers. Red charges Parker wildly. Parker dodges him like a matador does a bull. Then brings his fists down savagely on the back of Red's head. His skull CRACKS. Red drops to the floor. Parker jumps on top of him, arms around his neck. Choking him. Red staggers to his feet. His eyes wide. His face now even redder. Parker maintains his mechanical grip. Red finally succumbs to the lack of oxygen. He drops to his knees. Parker does not relent until he feels the barrel of a gun at the back of his head.</context>
      <utterance>Time to hurt...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker lets go, dropping Red to the wet, filthy floor.</context>
      <utterance>Fun's over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sandpapers off the excess sealant. Then places his elbow into an electronic sensitivity adjuster.</context>
      <utterance>I still don't know why they wasted this fancy, new technology on you. Every time I fix you up, you only go and mess it up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pricks Parker's finger with a pin.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me how this feels...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does so, then pricks Parker's finger again. He grimaces in pain.</context>
      <utterance>I'll dial it down a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That about right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll never feel right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least they work. Would you rather have no hands at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pops the cork, and pours their glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Reilly...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the first LETAC engineer to go into production on prototypes.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as you keep overpaying me, I'll be the first to go into production on three, and four, as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Wallace, I could have 10 of them ready by tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they have to look so...robotic?</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He remote controls the robotic sentry to chase Wallace out of the station. Lindenmeyer can no longer be seen through the gap in the partition.</context>
      <utterance>At this stage, you either get form or function. You said she wanted function. I gave you function. What are you complaining about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All they want to produce around here is mediocrity!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True genius is rarely rewarded within its lifetime.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was you, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was me, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're the reason I got fired!</context>
      <utterance>You amped the neural connectors back up, didn't you?  You're the reason the convict died.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't just let them make you bring down my degree of difficulty. I'm a triple-twisting, double back flip off the high platform, not a swan dive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which God would that be, the one who created me, or the one who created you?  In your world, the Lord giveth, and the Lord taketh away. But in my world, the one who gave me life doesn't have the balls to stop a couple of bureaucratic assholes from taking it away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect me to do, put your character module in my pocket and just walk you out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindenmeyer arches an eyebrow, then picks up a phone and dials an extension.</context>
      <utterance>I had something a little different in mind.  Instead of just playing Peeping Tom with Reilly, why don't you get him to show you what he's been working on after hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Reilly, Sheila 3.2's been asking for you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cuffs won't be necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, ma'am, but I don't think that's such a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard removes Parker's cuffs, then exits, taking up his post outside the door. The skin around Parker's wrists is blue where the cuffs dug into his skin. Parker sits across from Madison. She places a micro—recorder in the middle of the table and presses RECORD.</context>
      <utterance>I would like the following three things in this order: your mouth shut, his cuffs off, and your ass outside the door. Any questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually listen to all those tapes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I just like the effect a tape recorder has on you.  How you feeling today?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little less than yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In other words, par for the course.  How do you feel about the simulation you participated in yesterday?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John died.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I was there. I saw the whole thing.  If I was your therapist, I would have advised you against putting yourself back into that kind of situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not my therapist. You're hear to study me. Face it —— I'm nothing more than a lab rat to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true, Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had died yesterday, you'd have already dissected my brain and analyzed it to see if I carry any genetic predisposition toward violence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was going through your mind when you killed the busboy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much. He was just a computer program. Nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't see the expression you had on your face when you pulled the trigger. But I did.  You kind of liked it, didn't you? That thrill of going over the edge again. Of taking out an innocent bystander or two, as long as you got the target...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just like before, wasn't it? Wasn't it?  But you are making progress. Instead of killing seven people to get the one you're after, this time there was only one other person involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard pokes his head in with concern.</context>
      <utterance>Enough!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know what snapped in you. What made you capable of it. You have to make me understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to do anything except survive. And it's taking everything I've got just to do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show's over unless I get to see what you've been working on after hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been working on anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I get to see it or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes out. Sid 6.7 appears on the various monitors next to Sheila 3.2. He kisses her cheek. Caresses her body. Sheila 3.2 enjoys the attention.</context>
      <utterance>Bastard...  Sheila, don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's some of your finest work, Daryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 continues appreciating Sheila 3.2. As Reilly races back in, the monitors then all go BLACK. Reilly, completely out of breath, holds a python by it's head. He dangles the snake right in front of Lindenmeyer's face. Terrifying him.</context>
      <utterance>All my work is my finest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get that fucking thing away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching your VR people Auto Reset gave me the idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Machines the size of molecules...</context>
      <utterance>It's nano—technology, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coordinated by polymer neural net.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels so.. .real.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's better than real. It's synthetic flesh. Synthetic blood. Synthetic organs...  It's a physiological machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is supposed to be years away.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As far as the public is concerned, it is. The reason you got fired, and I got my second demo into production, is I'm a lot smarter than you. I never give my best stuff away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you kill it?</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Using Lindenmeyer's scissors, he cuts off the snake's head and removes a small character module connected to the base of the neural net. The snake stops moving. It "dies."</context>
      <utterance>Separate the character module from the neural net...</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and you get nano—death.  Don't worry, I've got a bunch of other ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amazing. I hate to say it, but it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.  I'm ready to incubate something a little more advanced than a coldblooded reptile. If you want to experience the future, meet me in my office in 15 minutes. And bring the Sheila 3.2 character module with you... He exits. As Lindenmeyer reaches for the Sheila 3.2 character module, Sid 6.7 appears on the screen in front of him and winks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You catching my drift?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peeling the label off the Sid 6.7 character module, Lindenmeyer removes the module from its slot. Sid 6.7 disappears from the screen.</context>
      <utterance>I think I understand what you have in mind...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a maid.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes a tarp from a large, rectangular, metallic tank with a circular window in the middle of it. Clear, plastic tubing, which branches into hundreds of increasingly smaller and smaller branches, floats in electrified fluid. The tubing is a synthetic human nervous system.</context>
      <utterance>What I need is a nymphomaniac.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE REILLY'S OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reilly turns to Lindenmeyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindenmeyer hands him the label—less character module. Reilly opens the "incubator."</context>
      <utterance>Where's the Sheila 3.2 module?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell is this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hand as if to shake. Then grabs Reilly by the throat and chokes him. Hard.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Sid. Sid 6.7.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect me to do, thank him?</utterance>
   <speaker>REILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This... isn't.. .possible!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches Reilly's face with curiosity as the life drains from it. A puddle forms beneath him. He drops Reilly's body to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Sure it is —- and it's all thanks to the many long hours put in by you and Daryl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He then watches with interest as his wound regenerates, healing itself. The scar tissue is slightly off color.</context>
      <utterance>Tastes different, somehow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Glancing at Reilly's prone body, he then SLAMS the office door in our face.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm going to like it here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wasting your time. I'm not going to play any more of your goddam games.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker Barnes, I'd like you to meet Crime Czar Elizabeth Deane.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too early in the morning for me to be cordial. You got any coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I watched your simulation, Mr. Barnes. Very impressive. You know, you're the only one to ever go up against Sid 6.7 who is still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only because I got pulled out early.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker, looking at her incredulously, moves his index finger circularly, as in get on with it, already. Cox opens a folder and shows Parker several PHOTOGRAPHS of Reilly, or what was left of him.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody else ever got anywhere near him. Nobody else... understands him like you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These were taken inside LETAC an hour ago. Pretty pictures, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands a photograph of Sid 6.7 exiting LETAC to Parker.</context>
      <utterance>Name was Clyde Reilly. Hardware specialist.  LETAC surveillance cameras got a picture of the perp as he left the building.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know how, but Sid 6.7 made himself into an android.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean a nano—tech synthetic organism.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.  Can you kill it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can catch him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you can do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not from in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides an unsigned pardon across the table to Parker, making sure to stay beyond his arm's reach. Cox reveals a worn, L. A. P. D. badge. It was Parker's.</context>
      <utterance>This is a full pardon. It authorizes your immediate release.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recognize this? How would you like your old job back?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch him and your record's clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens if I can't catch him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Sid 6.7 hasn't killed you, we throw you back in here and you serve out the rest of your sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deane holds up a small device called a LOCATER IMPLANT. It is the size of a dime.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know I won't run?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the newest technology approved for general implementation. It's called a locater implant. Every parolee gets one.  We're going to know where you are every second for the rest of your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you try to run, I'll hunt you down and kill you myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes or no, Mr. Barnes?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's already a task force out looking for Lindenmeyer. Every other officer in the city will be hunting Sid right along with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker's expression is one of —— yeah, that figures. Madison enters. She cannot see Parker behind the barber.</context>
      <utterance>But only you will know he's not human.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Deane, you wanted to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have an emergency situation which requires somebody with expertise in criminal psychology. Under the authority vested in me by the President, I'm giving you temporary re—assignment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the assignment?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barber moves back from Parker, revealing his clean— shaven face. It takes Madison a moment to recognize him with his cleaned—up appearance.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to put your theories to practice. I'm sending you into the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite an improvement.  Hair well above the collar ——standard, L. A. P. D. regulation.  What exactly am I going to be doing in the field?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANESTHETIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are right on the border of his corpus callosuni.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is under, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANESTHETIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't stop him from dreaming, though... Parker's rapid eye movements tell you the anesthetist is correct. Parker is dreaming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context>The bright colors melt into darker, more brooding images. Flashes of men's faces. Melting into urban decay. Unhappiness. Technology.</context>
      <utterance>This is Parker with his wife and daughter. Beautiful young family, weren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0. CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Melancholy turns violent. Glimpses of weapons. Death. Explosions. Death. Blood. Death. Caskets. Tombstones. Images moving so fast, it's hard to tell what they are. Nothing literal.</context>
      <utterance>This is the group of cyber anarchists Parker was closing in on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0. CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Weapons firing. Bombs exploding. Images of rage in all its forms. Many of which you've already seen. Making one thing now clear: the paintings in Parker's cell represent his life. What he was. What he lost. And what he is.</context>
      <utterance>This is what Parker's wife and daughter looked like after they were kidnapped and executed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0. CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tears. Hopelessness. Detonation. And finally blackness. Complete and utter blackness.</context>
      <utterance>This is what the cyber anarchists and two people who just happened to be in the wrong club at the wrong time looked like after Parker finished with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter?</context>
      <utterance>That's also where Mr. Barnes lost his arms to Mathew Grimes' booby— trap. What's your point, Dr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Letting a lunatic like Parker Barnes loose in the free world is like lighting a fuse. At some point, he will go off -- you saw what happened in the simulator. The risk to the public is unacceptably dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you're with him every step of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man played judge, jury, and executioner with eight people's lives. He lost control and is capable of doing it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand the risks involved here. But there is nobody better qualified to go after Sid 6.7 than Barnes. And, there is nobody who knows him better than you. If a situation becomes volatile, you will find a way to quell it. I have complete confidence in you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need a baby—sitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you need is a collar.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's going to help you understand what makes Sid 6.7 tick.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cox hands Madison a thick folder.</context>
      <utterance>What she's going to do is get in my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the personnel file on the programmer, Lindenmeyer. There might be something in it you can use.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wasn't part of the deal, Cox.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His cellular phone RINGS, which he answers. As he listens to the call, his expression is one of growing concern. He clicks off the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Fine —— you want to stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Officers in Toluca Lake just found an affluent couple...completely gutted.  So were the first two cops to arrive on scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their weapons missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid 6.7 is now armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cox glances to Madison, then hands Parker a .45.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks around the car, brushing past her. Then drops to his knees at the side of the road. He puts his hands in the dirt, feeling the earth between his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day for the last five years, I told myself someday I would be out here again. No more bars. No more guards. No more fights just to stay alive.  Every day for the last five years, I told myself that lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't a lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking a deep breath, he wipes the dirt off his hands. Then stands.</context>
      <utterance>Every time I said it, it was. I never really thought I was going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets back in the vehicle. Off Madison's reaction, we</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Never felt better in my life.  See, I'm a good liar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker and Madison continue toward the house. Getting an increasing amount of attention, particularly from the other COPS. Some look on with awe. Some with disdain. But nobody is in between.</context>
      <utterance>Son...of...a...bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a brief smile. Which Madison does not return. One of the other policemen tentatively approaches Parker.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. If I can't handle it, I'll just kill everybody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was re—enacting Charles Manson's LaBianca murders.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manson didn't kill the first cops to arrive on the scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever did this wanted to do Charlie one better —— to improve upon what was already done.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie? You say that like you're close, personal friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've spent over 50 hours interviewing him.  Charlie killed Leno and Rosemary LaBianca because of the ugly way the members of his family had butchered Sharon Tate. After seeing the blood bath on television, he wanted to show them how it should be done.  The question is, what does Charlie have to do with Sid 6.7?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who would know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ignores her as they get out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>You drive well for somebody who hasn't done it in five years.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Learn anything from Lindenmeyer's file?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had a twin brother who was a musical child prodigy who died in an electrical accident at age eight. Lindenmeyer went into an emotional shell until was 17. All he did day and night was play the violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened when he was 17?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She approaches the cops, who remain in their car.</context>
      <utterance>Every music school in the country rejected him and he turned to computers.  Stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of Lindenmeyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERCOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None, yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if we take a look inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERCOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM! They all turn their heads to see Parker has kicked in Lindenmeyer's front door and is going inside.</context>
      <utterance>Not until somebody gets a search warrant signed. It's Sunday. I don't think they've even found a judge, yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDERCOVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna have to call this in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what you've got to do.  So will I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a problem with me carrying a gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker bolts through the duplex, storming into rooms furiously. His movements are aggressive. Madison searches other rooms methodically. She is not timid. Just inexperienced in the field. She passes a video camera mounted on a tripod. Pointed out the window at a neighbor's bathroom. Dozens of cassettes surround the tripod. The labels are dated —— covering every day of the last month. Parker and Madison enter opposite sides of the kitchen with their guns drawn, nearly shooting each other. Madison puts down her gun. Parker does not. The noise persists.</context>
      <utterance>Do me one favor —— if you shoot at anything, make sure I'm nowhere near it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles wickedly, and continues on. Madison takes a deep breath, then resumes her search. Parker and Madison end up</context>
      <utterance>Bang...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Checking my pulse. It's elevated.  You enjoy frightening me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've studied me, now I'm studying you. Seems only fair, don't you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Lindenmeyer's a real piece of work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs his finger along a book shelf, pausing at two books in particular. Their titles are: UNDERSTANDING THE CRIMINAL MIND, and CRIMINAL PURSUIT -- A PSYCHOLOGICAL GUIDE FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT. They were written by Dr. Madison Carter.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe after they catch him, you should write a book about him...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised you didn't write one about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noticing something on the floor, she picks up a bizarre looking synthesizer keyboard off the floor. You read its name: MAESTRO.</context>
      <utterance>I'm still working on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember a few years ago when music schools were using a computerized teaching tool that accidently started frying kids' brains?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been in prison, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The government must have figured there was no better person to create a psycho than a psycho.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison elects not to respond. She sits down at the computer, which rests between busts of Beethoven and Mozart, and begins typing at the computer. She works with efficiency. Knowing exactly what she's doing. She is now in her element. From a shelf, Parker picks up a moldy piece of licorice inserted into a half-eaten pudding cup. Then flips through one of the books written by Madison. Only half-interested.</context>
      <utterance>Just like they figured there was no better person to catch one...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the demon from the bottomless pit...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... here on earth to create havoc and terror. I am War, I am death. I am destruction. David Berkowitz,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For murder, though it have no tongue, will speak with most miraculous organ.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hamlet.  What's David Berkowitz got to do with Sid 6.7?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's part of the mix. Sid 6.7 is a composite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lindenmeyer put increasingly complex combinations of criminal psychological profiles together to develop the ultimate villain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Creating a whole far more dangerous than the sum of its parts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues opening the files of the higher versions of Sid. Version 5.9 consists of 67 different profiles. The visualized psychological battle is intense. And extremely violent. The 6.7 version, with 183 profiles, is even worse.</context>
      <utterance>But rather than selecting pieces from each individual, he simply let the stronger traits of each individual cannibalize the weaker ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Attempting to open the files of the composite profiles, Madison discovers they are protected by encryption.</context>
      <utterance>It's a good bet a couple of the dominant personalities teamed up to overpower the others.  The question is, which one of the dominants then finally managed to take control?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is getting you pumped up, isn't it? This is like the World Series to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker points to a name on the screen: JEFFREY DAHMER.</context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the bowling ball bag Sid carried with him in virtual reality?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dahmer carried the head of one of his victims in a bowling bag for over a week. Kept it in his locker while he was at work in a candy factory.  We need to get a look at Sid 6.7's final profile.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we need to do is stop playing with computers and go catch the son—of-a-bitch before he kills anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In order to find him, we have to understand what makes him tick...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell us what's on the disc?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you can get into the program?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should see what he's been up to recently.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever have one of those days where you decide something important about yourself? You know, where you say, "I'm not just what I've been programmed to be. I can do what I want, when I want, how I want, because I'm my own person?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You one of them New Age assholes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robo-Tender rolls over to Sid 6.7.</context>
      <utterance>Just a soul on a personal journey. What I've realized is that I'm capable of anything. I have to start expanding my horizons...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBO-TENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want...a...drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots the Robo—Tender between his mechanical eyes. The businessman smiles, like he's thought about doing exactly the same thing.</context>
      <utterance>To think you constitute one of my ancestors——</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 thinks about it. Long and hard.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, buddy...thinking big is fine.. .but you shouldn't forget where you come from, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a table with several other BUSINESSMEN.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you're absolutely right.  Would you mind sitting over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the businessman off his bar stool and carries him to the table.</context>
      <utterance>Every orchestra is divided into sections. Like instruments sit with like instruments. Now be a good instrument and sit with your kind...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing in Los Feliz?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madison lives two blocks from their present location.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would they be going there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish we could hear them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Cox's look, we</context>
      <utterance>My engineers say the audio tap should be ready to field test in six months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker stops in front of a modest, but well—kept, house.</context>
      <utterance>Not this one, but the next one. The one with the bicycle out front...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison pockets the car keys, then reveals a pair of handcuffs. She latches one cuff to the steering wheel, and holds up the other toward Parker.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wait out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a goddam break. I'm not going to go anywhere alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker relents, and holds up his wrist. Madison places the cuff around it, then gets out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm going to make sure of it.  Give me your wrist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INSIDE HER BEDROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madison stares gravely into the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grimes, you better not be the dominant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told you I wasn't going to go anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she unlocks the handcuffs from the steering wheel, Parker wiggles his mechanical hand in front of her face.</context>
      <utterance>How did you get your hand out?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annoyed, Madison tosses him the car keys. He starts the engine and drives.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes, I like being part machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me you had a daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I prefer keeping my professional life separate from my personal life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's beautiful, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns on the police radio.</context>
      <utterance>Thank-you.  Her name is Karin.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to tell me the real reason we stopped at your house?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, it was on the way and I wanted to change clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should practice lying more often. You're awful at it.  Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid 6.7 is no longer bound by his programming.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that he's in the real world, there are no longer limitations on his behavior like there were in virtual reality. Sid is going to evolve.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds to me like a well—educated way of saying you have no idea what to do next.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I do know is that whatever he's becoming, Sid 6.7 is going to be even worse than he was before.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns up the police radio.</context>
      <utterance>Then all we can do is stay mobile and alert. He's got to make a move sometime, and we've got to be ready when he does.  Welcome to police work. You better like coffee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fires his gun just above her head. She SCREAMS in terror.</context>
      <utterance>Good... Very good... Nice...  You -- in the middle -- don't hold back. Give it to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He continues aiming his gun from face to face, seeking ever increasing emotional responses from his "instruments." A guy entering the bar does a quick about face. Gone by the time Sid 6.7 glances at the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's better...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once again, from the top—— BOOM! He shoots again, just missing a man's foot.</context>
      <utterance>God, I hate interruptions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot what real coffee tastes like...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, considering you've only been out of prison for seven hours, you're re—adapting quite well.  Wait, I didn't mean that the way it sounded. I meant...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit, I hate sounding so clinical all the time. All I meant to say was I thought you were doing well, but then I...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax. I know what you meant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ruin so many moments by analyzing them when I should just be living them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison stops herself from speaking. It isn't easy for her. Parker cracks a faint smile. YOU HEAR the police radio.</context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you start practicing and keep your mouth shut for a while?</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCHER</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...report of a possible hostage situation inside a bar on the corner of Figueroa and Sixth. Description of the perp matches the surveillance photographs from LETAC taken this morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's only a couple blocks from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tossing his coffee out the window, he opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll meet you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get out of the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out, running down the sidewalk. He flies past the cars inching down the block.</context>
      <utterance>Stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs into the driver's seat, spilling hot coffee on herself.</context>
      <utterance>Parker! PARKER!  Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just love how responsive you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP L</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>TWO COPS stand in the doorway, weapons aimed at Sid 6.7. The Cops inch closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ushers were not supposed to seat you until intermission.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 spins around and fires twice before he can finish his sentence. Both Cops receive IDENTICAL wounds in their shooting arms, reminding you of the wounds Parker and John first received in the opening virtual reality sequence. Sid 6.7 takes a bow, as if on stage.</context>
      <utterance>Put the gun down, nice and...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he walks toward the exit, he admires himself in the mirror behind the bar. Sid 6.7 has never seen his own image in the real world before. He likes what he sees.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, you've been a real pleasure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INSIDE THE COPS' VEHICLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid 6.7 looks pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRACK! A bullet spiderwebs the rear window. Sid 6.7 punches the gas, taking off in a hurry.</context>
      <utterance>Well, look who it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps behind the wheel, flooring the accelerator. Speeding through the already frightened motorists. Madison is pinned to the back of her seat. Looking out the window, she looks at the motorists.</context>
      <utterance>This is my area of expertise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do to those people?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INSIDE PARKER'S VEHICLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>determination. Madison's eyes are a mixture of fear and excitement. She holds onto the door handle for dear life.</context>
      <utterance>Parker's eyes are locked to the road with fierce</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being on the street's a little different than sitting in an office all day, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enjoying yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a game, Parker!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That who I think it is? Parker turns to her, then picks up the radio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The symphony of collision...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing I want to hear is your silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must make them very nervous if they let you out of prison.  You know, we have so much in common —— we have such history together ——I've been thinking we should become friends. Madison's anxiety tanks are hitting capacity.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and me have nothing in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker glances at his mechanical hands gripping the wheel. Madison can't believe he is able to carry on a conversation while driving like this.</context>
      <utterance>Who else do you know who touches the world with synthetic hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Madison clicks off the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Who else do you know who's been locked out of the real world for years, and is now just learning to be free?  Who else do you know is a multiple murderer just like you? Who else...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand to her wrist -- checking her pulse.</context>
      <utterance>You have nothing in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison takes out her weapon. Her hands are shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Enough with your pulse already.  Still got your gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me you can use it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRAFFIC COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better be a cop, pal!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My badge is in my jacket. Left pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAFFIC COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 slowly reaches inside his jacket and fires his weapon through it. He only gets a hole in his jacket. The Traffic Cop gets a hole through his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Show me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He aims his weapon at Parker's oncoming vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>God, some people are stupid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison's determination battles her inexperience. Sid 6.7 gets off the first shot. CRACK! That was the windshield by Parker's head. He ducks down, driving blind.</context>
      <utterance>Nail the fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Madison fires. Nowhere close. She adjusts her sights and fires again. The result is the same.</context>
      <utterance>Any time now...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOOM! That was Sid 6.7 shooting their front left tire. Parker loses control of the vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm doing the best I can!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... illegal search of Lindenmeyer' s duplex. Eleven civilian vehicles damaged or destroyed. Twenty—four citizen complaints. And the calls are just starting to come in...  I forgot what it's like to have you on the streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of Lindenmeyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None. He could be hiding, he could be helping Sid, or could be in little pieces on Santa Monica beach.  Any idea what Sid's going to do next?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until we know what new influences are affecting him, we can't be sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In other words, we collectively don't know shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes me nervous just seeing him in a uniform.  I will never forget the first time I saw the photos from the crime scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither will the public.  The media has caught wind of his pardon. Unless Mr. Barnes starts giving me some tangible results, I'm going to put him back in his cage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next.  Did you know those aren't even baked? They're chemically—risen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off the cashier's look, we</context>
      <utterance>So was I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER AND MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on the speakerphone inside Cox's Office.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you able to get into the program?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But then I tripped over an erasure mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In English, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker and Madison turn to each other -— shit.</context>
      <utterance>I accidently triggered a protection mechanism which erased the entire program.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIEV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was very well—hidden. There was no way to see it until it was too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault. We appreciate you trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 changes the channel to a different news broadcast. Parker's Folsom County Prison I. D. photograph is shown alongside a photograph of Madison from one of her book covers.</context>
      <utterance>... commuters travelling anywhere near the Biltmore Hotel downtown tomorrow evening should allow themselves at least 30 extra minutes to get home. Security for the Mayor Bennett's Re—Election Rally is going to be so tight that all bus and subway routes passing through the area are being re—routed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He changes the channel back to the first news broadcast. A reporter stands amid the chaos outside the bar where Sid 6.7 had terrified the patrons. Sid 6.7 turns to the other CUSTOMERS in the store. Most of them are watching other channels. He goes over to a control pad on a counter and presses several buttons. Now EVERY TV in the store has the news with the reporter outside the bar on. A SKINHEAD, sporting numerous Nazi swastika tattoos, manually changes the channel on one of the TVs to a Dodger baseball game. Sid 6.7 walks over to the Skinhead and changes the channel back to the news.</context>
      <utterance>We really do have so much in common. But I refuse to be upstaged...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the next TV over and changes the channel to the baseball game. Sid 6.7 moves over with him, standing directly behind the Skinhead as if also interested in the Dodgers.</context>
      <utterance>You don't wanna fuck with me, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places his hands on the Skinhead's head and efficiently snaps his head around, breaking his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Take me out to the ball game... Take me out for the fun...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He drops the Skinhead to the floor, never once taking his eyes off the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Buy me some peanuts and Cracker Jack... I don't care if I ever come back...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WE PULL BACK TO REVEAL you're now watching a recording of Sid 6.7 on videotape, along with Parker, Madison, and a dozen other COPS, inside the Electronics Store an hour later. The tape is re—wound.</context>
      <utterance>But rest assured...  A star is born.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever he was doing here was only the start.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves closer to the screen as the tape is played back. Madison studies Sid 6.7 intently.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, yet. What we do know is his performances are increasing in scale, not decreasing.  Whatever it is, he isn't finished...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>0. 5.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But rest assured...  A star is born.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her request is obliged.</context>
      <utterance>You mind playing that part again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at Sid 6.7, who is looking directly at her.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze it there——</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Her attention turns to the upper right corner of the screen, where onlookers are visible watching Sid 6.7. Their faces blurry. But even out of focus, it isn't hard to recognize Lindenmeyer.</context>
      <utterance>You've discovered media, haven't you? You like the attention...the power...You like being a star. What are you going to do next, star? What are you going to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She points to Lindenmeyer, then makes her way over to Parker, who's standing exactly where Sid 6.7 was when he killed the Skinhead. Parker does not look at Madison. His eyes are fixed on the TV in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>You do like to watch, don't you?  If any of you are looking for Daryl Lindenmeyer, that's him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just Sid 6.7's performances that are increasing. Stars need bigger and bigger audiences.  Whatever Sid is going to do next, it's going to involve media.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like baseball?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, whoever's operating the stadium's closed—circuit cameras must have fallen in love because that beauty in J Section has been on the stadium's big screen for over a minute now...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE THE ELECTRONICS STORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grabs a police radio from a nearby OFFICER.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Officer Parker Barnes. Get every able body you can to Dodger Stadium -- J Section.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Live execution.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>react with horror. But nobody turns away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! Somebody stop him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real effective security...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have just flashed him your badge, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to a fork: one tunnel goes to east/west trains, the other to north/south.</context>
      <utterance>Authority still makes me nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races down the tunnel to the north/south trains. Madison heads down the other. Her determination beginning to win out over her inexperience.</context>
      <utterance>Both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PASSENGER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady, you gotta stop him! He's gone crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just shot an innocent bystander!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker gets to his feet. Madison doesn't take her eyes off him.</context>
      <utterance>What were you shooting at?</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did —— I saw it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads toward the up escalator. His back now to Madison. She aims her gun at him.</context>
      <utterance>Sid's getting away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker -— stop! STOP! Don't make me shoot you——</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps right on going up the escalator.</context>
      <utterance>If you're gonna do it, better do it now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He collapses in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Let me help you...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEGE STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clearly versed in emergency medical treatment, Madison attends to his wound. Parker returns.</context>
      <utterance>What did I do?...I didn't do anything...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison backs away in fear. Parker rises gradually.</context>
      <utterance>That's Grimes...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Parker advances toward Madison, who continues backing away.</context>
      <utterance>The man who killed my wife...who killed my daughter...who ruined my life used to taunt me with that line...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grimes is back! He's back! He's come back!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to grab him by the shoulders. Parker blocks her arms away.</context>
      <utterance>No! Grimes isn't back. He's only one part of Sid. Sid 6.7 is a hell of a lot worse than Grimes ever was.  Get a hold of yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>You've known all along and didn't</context>
      <utterance>God, you fucking know-it-all!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Is that what you were afraid of?!</context>
      <utterance>tell me! Why?! Were you afraid I'd lose it?! Go over the edge?! Huh?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker slowly raises his hands in the air. A Guard relieves him of his weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Hands up! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going back where he belongs. Deane and Cox step out of the police vehicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But his mind is way off elsewhere.</context>
      <utterance>You were right, Dr. Carter. Letting a lunatic like Barnes loose in the real world did pose an unacceptably dangerous risk to the public.  I should have never tried to solve one problem by allowing the creation of another.  Chief Cox will give you a ride back to the station. You will provide him with any and all information you have developed thus far.  Enjoy the rest of your sentence, Mr. Barnes. She exits. Cox and Parker stand facing each other. Cox wishes there was something he could do. Parker looks completely out of it. Cox extends his hand. After a moment, Parker takes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison looks on as Parker is herded roughly into the back of the prison transport.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker shuts her up with a look. There is nothing that can be said. The prison transport doors are SLAMMED shut. The vehicle takes off.</context>
      <utterance>Parker...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have told him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't blame yourself. In your shoes, I don't think I would have told Parker, either.  So do you think Grimes has become the dominant personality?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. My guess is that's what Sid wants us to think.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he's smart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I'm afraid of how smart Sid 6.7 is.  But I'm even more afraid of what's he's becoming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really are pathetic, you know that? Mathew Grimes is only one letter in my alphabet. He is nothing compared to me. Parker is completely spent. Mentally and physically. He slumps in a corner. Out of breath. Bleeding. Sore. All he can do is stare out through the portal's mesh at Sid 6.7.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He releases the rear door lock.</context>
      <utterance>You could say thank—you, you know? I'm giving you your freedom, short— lived though it may be.  A little known fact about the locater implants prison inmates now receive upon release is that they contain a pinhead capsule of neural toxin. The satellite they use to track you can also trigger release of the toxin with microwaves. After transmission, the implant's host dies within 30 seconds.  It won't take long for them to get your termination authorized once they learn of your escape. Now who would you rather go after, killer, them or me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Aide exits.</context>
      <utterance>Parker Barnes just escaped from the prison transport. Both of the guards are dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barnes wouldn't kill two innocent guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He would slaughter eight people sitting in a room, but not two prison guards?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I need to remind you what happened to his wife? To his daughter?  I will stake my reputation that Barnes didn't kill those guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You already have staked your reputation.  Mayor Bennett and I have been friends a long time. Since Grimes tried to kill him, it doesn't take a rocket scientist to come to the conclusion that Sid 6.7 might go after him, too.  Bennett's Re-Election Rally is tomorrow night and we already have enough trouble on our hands with one psychotic on the loose.  The fail-safe on—line, yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On—line and at your disposal.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What fail—safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace exits the room. Cox has no idea what is going on. And Deane is not about to tell him.</context>
      <utterance>This had better work, Mr. Wallace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no way Parker killed those guards. No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we both know who did.  What's so urgent?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking him by the arm, she leads him into an elevator going down just before its doors close.</context>
      <utterance>I need your help--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't anybody tell me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a security key out of his pocket and uses it to gain access to a subterranean floor.</context>
      <utterance>I don't set policy.  You have the key?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit quickly. Cox leads Madison</context>
      <utterance>This is a police department. I'll be damned if this is going to go on without my knowledge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me 30 seconds, then flip every switch you can reach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are we going to fry?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cox enters, concerning Wallace.</context>
      <utterance>Just an unrepentant criminal who is apparently going to die from a previously undiagnosed brain tumor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He surveys the electronic map, locating Parker. Just as the lights go BLACK. Wallace and the technician immediately panic.</context>
      <utterance>Just paying my last respects.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. We've lost all power!</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace and the technician rush out of the room, up the emergency stairs. Cox sets to work ripping out the console's circuitry. By the time he's finished, the equipment in here won't be able to toast a piece of bread.</context>
      <utterance>The heat's been causing brown out's all over the city. Get above ground until it's restored.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know you didn't kill those guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to fry me for it, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches, holding the Circuits he ripped out of the Locator Transmission Room.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody's going to fry anybody...</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, they have no idea where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son—of—a—bitch. How could you let them put the implant in my head? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't know about the neural toxin.  I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew the entire time? Can you give me one good reason why I shouldn't kill you right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She saved your life, Parker. She didn't have to, but she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I guess we're even.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you find out about the toxin?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid 6.7 told me after he killed the two guards. He suggested I kill you rather than him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not capable of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pose an unacceptable danger to the public, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She means it. Parker turns away, looking at his wife's headstone.</context>
      <utterance>I was wrong.  And I was wrong not to tell you Grimes was part of Sid. I should have told you. I won't make the same mistake again.</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker turns toward him slowly. Emotion beginning to return to his face.</context>
      <utterance>The son—of—a-bitch is still out there, Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When this is over, will you get this goddam thing out of my head?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On my life, I promise you I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're lying, I'll hunt you down and kill you myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots the Foreman in the chest. Sid 6.7 relieves him of his keys and heads to an explosives storage shed.</context>
      <utterance>Someone who appreciates the artistic value of high—explosives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rally's a little obvious as a target, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you before, Grimes liked to be obvious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid 6.7 isn't Grimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Various faces in the crowd on the sidewalk. In the vehicles passing on the street. On the bridge crossing the street down the block further away from the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>Part of him is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we find Sid, Lindenmeyer won't be far behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think he's keeping track of his creation?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That, or living through him...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>puts down his binoculars. Madison does not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to what she's looking at. Looking through his binoculars, he still can't see what she means. She helps him aim his binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure...on the bridge...the guy at the payphone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move briskly down the block toward the bridge. Quickly climbing a set of stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SNIPER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look who we have here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SNIPER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker Barnes is heading south toward the bridge. If anybody can get a clean shot at him, take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SNIPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker stands frozen, staring at Sid 6.7 through his gun sight. Looking for just an inch of him to stick out from behind Madison's terrified face.</context>
      <utterance>Say good—bye, Parker Barnes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't pull the trigger if I were you——</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cox advances toward Sid 6.7 from the side of the bridge. Cox's gun out and ready. His finger on the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 turns his head in surprise toward Cox as a rifle is FIRED in the distance. Cox steps directly in the sniper's line-of-fire and takes the bullet meant for Parker through the chest. Cox drops to the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sid, what were you planning on doing with the C-4?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker ignores them. He bolts across the street, moving in the same direction as the bus below. Through speeding traffic. Bullets fly. Parker keeps charging. Right in front of a moving van barreling across the bridge. The cops lose sight of Parker.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think he made it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What C-4...was Cox talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me put it to you this way... whether I'm here...or whether I'm not...I'm leaving an indelible mark on the world tomorrow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He should concentrate more on fighting, and less on asking questions, because he's losing. Parker takes a wicked shot to the face, and then the groin. Sid 6.7 holds Parker's head between the compactor's jaws. Which are closing. With every last ounce of effort he has, Parker hurls his legs up into Sid 6.7. Which throws Sid 6.7 into the compactor. The steel jaws immediately close in on Sid 6.7, who frantically tries to climb out. He gets his hands out. Then his head. But that's about it. Without emphasizing graphic detail, Sid 6.7 is decapitated. His lifeless body drops back into the compactor. His head tumbles to the street. The force of the impact causes the Sid 6.7 character module to separate from the neural net. The character module scatters into the street. Parker immediately jumps off the truck after it.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you plant the C-4?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find out anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bomb's going off tomorrow night, but I have no idea where.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean there's something you haven't asked me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've already fulfilled the terms of your pardon. You stopped Sid 6.7 and you've got his module. You're free to go —— right now.  Why are you going to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I'm asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because this pain—in—the—ass criminal psychology expert has helped me understand what I'm capable of. And what I'm not.  And better than anyone else, I am capable of stopping Sid 6.7.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sanitation worker at the wheel of the truck has no idea whatsoever what is happening on top of his truck. Parker and Sid 6.7 battle next to the compactor's lethal jaws. The machine makes an awful, grinding sound. Not unlike the sounds Parker and Sid 6.7 are making. The fight is primal. Savage. And moving at 30 miles-per—hour.</context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you, I do enjoy you, Parker. I really don't want to have to kill you...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What C-4...was Cox talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me put it to you this way... whether I'm here... or whether I'm not...I'm leaving an indelible mark on the world tomorrow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He should concentrate more on fighting, and less on asking questions, because he's losing. Parker takes a wicked shot to the face, and but then blocks the anticipated shot to his gun. Sid 6.7 still manages to put Parker's head between the compactor's jaws. Which are closing. With every last ounce of effort he has, Parker hurls his legs up into Sid 6.7. Which throws Sid 6.7 into the compactor. Sid 6.7 frantically tries to climb out of the compactor as the steel jaws close in on him. He gets his hands out. Then his head... Except Parker now does something different. Just before Sid 6.7 is decapitated, Parker jams a metal rod between the compactor's steel teeth. Then grabs Sid 6.7 by the throat.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you plant the C-4?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't die until you tell me where the C-4 is. Where is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SLAMS the back of his head into Parker's nose. Breaking it. Parker reels back in pain. Sid 6.7 squeezes out from within the steel teeth. The jagged metal cutting into him, striping him with blood. The blood then begins to retract. Sid 6.7's wounds, once again, heal themselves.</context>
      <utterance>My...secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As the truck slows at an intersection, he jumps to the street. Parker goes after him. Still in excruciating pain. WE PULL BACK TO REVEAL what you are seeing is</context>
      <utterance>Too bad you can't regenerate...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you this would work.. By setting back the clocks, he has absolutely no idea he's in virtual reality. He still thinks he's in the real world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How should I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder how that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lindenmeyer adjusts the sensory level back down to 100%.</context>
      <utterance>Turn it down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lindenmeyer checks several readings on his console.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's developing a hemisphere imbalance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk so I can understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't adjust the level of neural information each side of his brain is receiving, he won't be able to walk when I take him out of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lindenmeyer moves to Parker, Madison stays right with him. Her gun aimed at Lindenmeyer's head. Lindenmeyer carefully removes one of the neural connectors from Parker's skull cap. Before removing another, he looks for a safe place to put the connector.</context>
      <utterance>Then fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison is reluctant, but doesn't know what else to do. Lindenmeyer slowly gives the neural connector to her free hand.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to hold this. It can't get any dirt on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT ' D</mode>
      <context>She clutches the needle in her left hand while aiming her gun with her right. Lindenmeyer removes a second neural connector from Parker's skull. Holding this second needle at the base, Lindenmeyer makes several adjustments on the neural management computer, then moves slowly back to Madison.</context>
      <utterance>All you have to do is hold the needle at the base. Just make sure not to jab yourself with the point...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He suddenly jabs his neural connector into Madison's right forearm. Madison has no time to react. 10,000 volts of electricity instantly courses through her body. Madison drops to the floor, unconscious. The needle she had been holding falls from her grasp, breaking the circuit. She stops being electrocuted. Which saves her life.</context>
      <utterance>Hand me the connector nice and...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context>He sits back down at the simulator's main console, and starts to type commands. On the monitor, Parker is visible exiting the shopping mall.</context>
      <utterance>God, some people are stupid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks the weapon down the sidewalk, then points his gun at Parker's head.</context>
      <utterance>So close, and yet, so far...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really too bad you have to miss the Grand Finale.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 pauses to think about it.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you liked me being in the audience. Don't you want me to see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots Parker in his other knee cap, rendering both of his legs useless.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I do want you to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to have a bird's eye view...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go —— best seat in the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are going after Mayor Bennett.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks toward an open stairway door behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just say I'm sending a very clear message to his Re—Election Rally...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you going to watch with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got some final preparations to take care of—— Checking his watch, he stops suddenly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank-you, Daryl.  You had me going for quite a while there, sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His body DISINTEGRATES before your eyes. It's electronic particles form into an amorphous cloud. Which disappears from view.</context>
      <utterance>I really did think I was still in reality. At least, until now.  Beam me up, Scotty!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madison, get me out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am beautiful, aren't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 wades through the trash toward Lindenmeyer.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I ever thank—you for bringing me back to life a second time, Daryl?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out to give Lindenmeyer a hand, then grabs him by the throat. Choking him. Lindenmeyer can't believe what is happening.</context>
      <utterance>Glad to...</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid 6.7 takes Lindenmeyer's face gently in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>What...are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made me a composite of 183 of the most vicious people who ever lived.  What do you think I'm doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LINDENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm begging you...please don't kill me! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lindenmeyer begins to scream, we</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Through me, you will live forever...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mustering her strength, she manages to crawl behind several of the computers which make up the simulator. Sid 6.7 advances calmly toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Carter —— I've been hoping we'd get a moment together...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks behind the computers where you last saw Madison. She is no longer there. Sid 6.7 begins searching for her. He passes a virtual reality monitor on which Parker can be seen clinging for life.</context>
      <utterance>You know so much about me, I was hoping to learn a little bit about you. You see, I'm doing research, too...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>On the monitor, Parker looks all around him, trying to determine the voice's origin. Madison crawls out of Lindenmeyer's station. Sid 6.7 just catches sight of her, and goes after her.</context>
      <utterance>Hang in there, Parker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I think so...You?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More or less.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lindenmeyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several engineers peek in curiously at them.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She helps Parker to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>INSIDE COX'S OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth Deane picks up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barnes, where the hell have you been?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying to find out where the bomb is. Where the hell have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you find out?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call off the manhunt looking for me. I didn't kill the transport guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already been called off. Witnesses confirmed you weren't the shooter.  Did you find out where the bomb is?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I've confirmed the reelection rally is the target.  How much C-4 is missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough to level an entire city block.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I were you, I'd get every demolition team in the city searching in and around the Biltmore Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Demolition teams have searched everywhere in and around the hotel. I don't know where...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid is smart enough to know you'd check everywhere in the immediate area. Whatever the device is, he's probably got it timed to move into position just before it detonates.  Have the demo teams check every subway tunnel, water pipe, gas pipe, and sewer pipe that goes under, over, or into the arena.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how much man power you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You're the highest law enforcement official in the country. Use the fucking army if you need to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This better not be a wild goose chase.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or what, you'll authorize my death a second time today?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget, convict, if this psycho isn't stopped, you go right back to rotting in a prison cell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him a break, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is demo team 27 leader. I think we just found what we've been looking for...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAM LEADER</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then again, maybe we ought to hold off for just a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker grabs the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You've got a phone call.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son-of—a—bitch, I'm going to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIEV</speaker>
      <mode>V. 0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? What did I do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I thought you were somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXIEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've discovered something about Lindenmeyer'5 Maestro teaching tool I thought you should know...  The harm done to the music students who used the device —— it was not by accident. The machine was designed explicitly for that purpose. Lindenmeyer intended to hurt the kids using it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.  I know who the dominant personality is.  Lindenmeyer. Madison's reaction is one of panic. She bolts toward their squad car with all the speed she has. Parker chases after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets into the driver's seat. Parker the passenger's. Madison punches the gas.</context>
      <utterance>Lindenmeyer never got over wanting to kill kids with more musical than he had...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evacuate everybody!</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, a bomb is planted somewhere in the Hollywood Bowl!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, I don't have the authorization to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then put somebody on who does!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's seems to be the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to stop the concert! A bomb is going to go off!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, the concert has already started.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SID 6.7</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...ruined...I'M GOING TO KILL</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, is that any way to talk to an old friend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves around, trying to get a clean shot at Sid 6.7. Which she does not have.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Parker...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your pulse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then shoot him already.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without hesitation, Parker hits the deck. Leaving Sid 6.7 completely exposed. Madison steadies her sight.</context>
      <utterance>Duck!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does so. Parker reaches OUT OF FRAME to remove the Sid 6.7 character module from within his skull. Then reveals the character module in hand.</context>
      <utterance>You won't want to watch. Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glancing in the flatbed of a truck, Parker gets an idea, and knocks on the driver's window. As the DRIVER rolls down his window, classic ROCK &amp; ROLL MUSIC can be heard from inside.</context>
      <utterance>What should we do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I borrow a couple of your tools for a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker removes two sledgehammers from the back of the truck. He offers one to Madison.</context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madison gladly accepts takes the sledgehammer. Parker drops the Sid 6.7 character module onto the pavement. And together, they start pounding the shit out of it. WHAM! WHAM! In perfect time with the music. Which the driver cranks even louder. As we ROLL CREDITS.</context>
      <utterance>Care to join me?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
