<movie id="586" title="War Horse">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men hold the mare firmly, but clearly this is a difficult birth.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, easy, girl. Easy, girl. Easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a stubborn one, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moments later - the summer's sun glints off the wet, sticky hide of the foal (JOEY) - red hide, four white socks and a distinctive white cross on its forehead. Soon the creature is attempting its first clumsy steps. It is both awesome and comical to see the new born creature struggle to his feet, but eventually, he succeeds. Title: WAR HORSE</context>
      <utterance>There we go. Who's a clever girl?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AUCTION MAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One man grabs Joey and pulls him out of the pen. Suddenly there is a look of horror on his face. His terrified mother realises they are being separated. Joey panics and desperately tries to get back to his mother, he rises up throwing the man who is leading him aside. Joey is out of control. The man regains control of Joey.</context>
      <utterance>Get the colt...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTION MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Joey away from his mother, who lets out a heart- rending cry, paws the ground, and crashes her foreleg against the fence. Joey remains disoriented in the midst of the market day chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTION MAN 3</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's a beauty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(points to a plow horse next to</context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Ted. He's half thoroughbred and not got a day's work in him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In contrast to Joey, the solid and bulky plow horse stands like a rock. But Dad remains fixated on Joey.</context>
      <utterance>Now, there... There's your ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look at him, Si. Look at that creature.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be daft. You need something solid to plow a field.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright gentlemen - settle down - settle down - horses on my right - men with money in their pockets on my left - it's the perfect combination. Is Fred Goddard here? FRED shouts his reply from the crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YES! I's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good - more money than sense. Dave Hill?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here. Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad notices a figure across the ring, LYONS, clearly a man of money. You can see something light up in Dad's eyes - a combination of dislike and alcohol. Joey is led into the auction pen.</context>
      <utterance>Bugger off, you tight bastard - you've been coming here for 20 years - never bought so much as a pork scratching. The crowd are loving all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay - first up today - a gorgeous young horse - prettiest thing I've seen since my wife on our wedding day. Let's get going, shall we? Who wants this wonderful creature. But no-one bids.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One guinea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey is still trying to get back to his mother. A voice from the crowd pipes up:</context>
      <utterance>Any advance on one guinea? Any advance on one guinea?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two guineas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three!</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lyons whispers to his son, DAVID, 15, next to him. David eyes Joey skeptically.</context>
      <utterance>Ted Narracott - it's completely the wrong animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si Easton - I'm not gonna let that bastard see me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five guineas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six!</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey is straining to get to his mother, the men are pulling him back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh for the love of...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greedy sod thinks he can just buy anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>BIDDING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lyons looks over. There is now tension in the crowd as they sense a Battle Royal for the horse.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it - he's your landlord - you can't be picking fights with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smirks at Dad.</context>
      <utterance>Ten guineas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't got the money. Let's go home - let's have a pint.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at Lyons in his suit and bowler hat.</context>
      <utterance>Eleven guineas, sir, from as good a man as any in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I hear twelve guineas? Twelve guineas?</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's top price for a workin' animal. Ted! Save it for the shire!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are big days and there are small days. Which will it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes are on Lyons and his son - David is 15, smartly dressed.</context>
      <utterance>Do I hear any advance on eleven guineas?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lyons isn't listening to David; he's looking hard at Ted.</context>
      <utterance>Just let him go, dad, I don't care for him, he's too... jumpy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd gasps. This is clearly personal.</context>
      <utterance>Shall we say - twenty five?</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's got you there. Nice try, Ted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But when he looks at Ted, Ted's eyes are locked into the eyes of his rival.</context>
      <utterance>You were great, Mr N. Gave him a run for his money.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going, going...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Total silence. He stares hard at Lyons. Who simply smiles, raises an eyebrow, tips his hat and walks away. It dawns on Dad that he's won the auction. He breaks into a sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty. Thirty guineas!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs his gavel. It's a done deal.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty guineas. Thirty guineas. Going going gone - to Mister Ted Narracott.</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moments later - Ted stands staring at Joey, who looks back. Ted holds his reins numbly, accepts his receipt from the auction man in a kind of daze. Suddenly, Lyons appears at Dad's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done, Ted? What have you done? Dad doesn't acknowledge Si.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad does not acknowledge Lyons. Lyons smiles and walks away with son David, and his cronies. Si shakes his head at Dad.</context>
      <utterance>Quite a beast, there. But what you gonna do with him - on a working farm? I hope you got the rent, Ted. I'll be around for it when it comes due.</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fool, Ted. And our Rosie'll never forgive you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad stands shamefaced as Albert - the boy we have already met - runs out of the house to join them.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Mooney's colt!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to buy a plow horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bought him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert is totally taken by the horse.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you pay for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much, Ted Narracott?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't tell you a lie - though I would love to. Thirty guineas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is stunned. She looks at Ted - and he just nods.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty guineas!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not worth ten! Are you out of your mind? What about the rent?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a strong one, Rosie. Look at the way he holds his head!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell are we gonna pull anything with that? Ted - you have to take him back. You have to take him back right now now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey bridles at the raised voices but Albert takes the rope and tries to calm him.</context>
      <utterance>You have to get down on your knees and beg for our money back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly we see Dad's dejection. He is a man lost.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, please don't take him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't take him back till he's broken in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how are you gonna train a horse with that leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll train him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you stay out of this, Albie. You don't know nothing about horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Mum. Please let me. I can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to keep him. We've no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Well... you've got one month to break him in or I'm taking him back myself.  How did you get to thirty - what other fool bid you up that high?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Narracott turns back towards the house, then stops, dazed, speaking almost to herself.</context>
      <utterance>It was Lyons.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back to the others - the weight of the mistake heavy on their shoulders - but Albert quickly steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>We're gonna lose everything. After all we've been through - we're gonna lose it all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Albert approaches, Joey nervously runs in circles, then stops on a dime, looking at Albert suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Let's make a start then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert squats down. He shows the food. Joey catches the scent on the air, but still hesitates and shies away.</context>
      <utterance>It's oats. Very tasty, that is. It's beef and gravy to us!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This time, Albert takes a new tact, almost turning his body fully away from Joey, but keeping the bucket extended. Albert slowly backs towards Joey, speaking gently all the while.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Feeling safer, Joey moves toward the bucket of oats and starts to eat.</context>
      <utterance>I bet you're missing your mother. Look at you... first time without your mum. First time away from home. But you're not alone, are you. In fact. Cos I'm `ere...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright. It's alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Of course when Albert walks away, Joey follows. A game of "Grandma's footsteps" ensues as Albert patiently places Joey then walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. I want you to stay there, Joey. Stay. That's it. Good boy. That's it, you've got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert patiently leads Joey back to his starting position.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look at him, Albie. He's playing "Grandma's Footsteps."</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come on. Back you go.</context>
      <utterance>Right, come on, Joey. Back you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert walks away again.</context>
      <utterance>You're all right. That's it. Good boy. Right. You've gotta stay there, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finally Joey stays put. Andrew smiles, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Good boy. You've got it. Good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good boy. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode>TO ALBERT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now call him. Whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert whistles like an owl. Joey stands completely still.</context>
      <utterance>Come now, Joey. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He whistles again. Joey remains still.</context>
      <utterance>You can come now, Joey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert walks back to Joey, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Don't think he fancies your owls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gently strokes Joey's nose.</context>
      <utterance>No, I read it in a story. It's how the Indians used to summon their horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Joey, when I whistle, you've gotta come, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad had a dog who stayed when you called him. He used to run up behind you when you weren't looking, and uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not a dog. He's just puzzling it through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the basis established, Albert begins to train Joey to react to the owl whistle without his prompting. It's not all easy going - sometimes Albert makes progress, sometimes not. QUICK MONTAGE - Mrs. Narracott fills a bucket at the pump, then promptly spills it when Joey trots past her in response to an owl whistle. She calls off, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. Look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad heads out to the fields with a rake on his shoulder. There's an owl call and Joey trots past him in the background. Dad sees Albert welcome Joey by the haystacks, stroking his nose affectionately. Dad walks on, his expression inscrutable. Joey trots up a path, pursuing another owl call. After several more calls, he still can't spot Albert, until he cranes his neck up and sees Albert sitting in a nearby tree. Albert laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Albie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only fifteen here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know by rights I could take this farm back today, don't you? And I'm a great believer in my rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lyons begins loading up his ledger into his bag.</context>
      <utterance>If you drank less beer and bought fewer horses you might be able to look your landlord in the eye, Narracott.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I'll pay you. We got to plant the bottom field.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bottom field's rock hard. Only stones down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we're going to plow it. Just give me `til the autumn. I'll pay every penny I owe you. With interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you going to plow it? Not with that fancy animal of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll not get that one in a harness, let alone pulling a plow. Even drunk on a Tuesday night, you know that. And I can't wait for the money - there's a war coming. Dad stands up from his chair, resolute.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise you that field will be plowed. We'll plant it with turnips. And the money will be yours when harvest comes. Mrs. Narracott interjects, desperate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lyons takes his time. He looks at them both - Ted and Rosie, almost beaten.</context>
      <utterance>Please, sir. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lyons heads for the door, but Albert stands in his way.</context>
      <utterance>Very well - if that fancy plows that field I'll give you till October to set things straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if he doesn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the horse on the day he fails.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lyons tries to move past, but Albert grabs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>And I'll take your father's farm and give it to working men who can hold their pints and hold their heads high in decent company.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, please. Sir, you can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert knows he has to back down. Lyons walks past him and leaves with David and his cronies.</context>
      <utterance>Now, now, now, lad. What - are you bladdered as well?! Ted Narracott - I got you down in my book!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't harness him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad starts to grapple with Joey desperately flailing in an attempt to get the harness onto Joey. Joey is completely confused and frightened.</context>
      <utterance>He's got to be collared.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can't. Look, you're scaring him, Dad. You're scaring him. He...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>DESPERATE</mode>
      <context>Joey tries to push Dad out of the way, Dad frustrated by this hits Joey hard with the harness.</context>
      <utterance>He can't take a plow!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got to plow!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey rears up and kicks Dad. Who falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>He won't be able to do it - he's too young - he's not even been backed yet....</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert grabs Joey's bridle. Joey wrestles with Albert.</context>
      <utterance>Ted!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad is mad with anger and frustration - and in pain. He staggers to his feet and leaves. Albert calms Joey down. Mrs. Narracott returns the harness to its hook.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright, boy. It's alright. It's alright. It's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then she notices Dad has returned. He has a gun.</context>
      <utterance>I knew this would happen soon as I laid eyes on him....</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted. No. Ted, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's worth nothing to me! If he won't take the collar, he's not worth a damn thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad? He grabs the rifle, but Dad shoves him away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad raises the rifle, but Albert wrestles for it again.</context>
      <utterance>Move aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious with frustration Dad throws Albert to the ground and takes aim at the horse. Mrs. Narracott quickly pulls the gun aside.</context>
      <utterance>Dad. Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shoot that horse we have nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad looks at him, frozen. Mrs. Narracott eases the gun away from him -</context>
      <utterance>You were right what you said, Dad. "He'll do it," you told Lyons, "He'll plow that field." And he will! You'll see. He'll show you. We'll show you. We'll get it done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- and hands it to Albert, telling him -</context>
      <utterance>Let go. Let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Albert leaves, Ted takes out his flask. But Rosie takes it from him gently. He doesn't resist.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit the stable together, leaving Joey in his stall.</context>
      <utterance>Here, here. Some days are best forgotten. Today ain't one of them. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey instinctively balks, but Albert is stern with him.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I'm gonna teach you how to plow and you're gonna learn. Is that understood? And then we can be together, which is how I believe things are meant to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As he approaches Joey with the harness, Harold the goose enters the stable to watch. Albert approaches gently and slowly puts the harness over his own neck and shoulders to demonstrate -</context>
      <utterance>Boy. Steady, boy. Here we go. Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>It is a moment between them. The horse looks Albert in the eye, then yields. Albert comforts him and show there is nothing to fear. Finally he gets the harness in place.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, easy... Look at me, Joey. See? See? You've just gotta put your nose through.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert leads Joey out across the yard, through the broken gate.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. See? You've got it. You've got it. Good boy. There... Harold honks his approval.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet he will, I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're interrupted by the honk of a horn as Lyons and David pull up in a car. Lyons and David get out. Their driver remains inside.</context>
      <utterance>You'd swear he'd sprout wings and fly if Albert had told you so.  It's a fine thing, loyal to your mate. Even if he is a bit barmy. A team of two might manage, given a month and good weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted too squeamish to watch, is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Si nods in the direction of the house. Albert steadies Joey and starts to tie on the heavy plow. It just seems too big and bulky for Joey's sleek frame. Albert sets Joey right and fixes the plow. Lyons, David, Si, and Andrew walk towards Dad, who looks on anxiously from a nearby hedgerow. Lyons gestures at David to stay back and walks over to Ted alone. He stands beside him and begins to talk gently.</context>
      <utterance>`Course he's watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down in the field, Albert continues to prep the plow.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you've raised him up a true Narracott, Ted, picture of his father, he is: not a dollop of ordinary sense but that thick stubbornness that'll lead him to insist on the impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't a farmer in Devon didn't admire you, myself among `em, leaving your brothers that fine farm and setting yourself at this stoney patch of unpromising ground. You've fettle enough for twenty men, but with a gimpy leg and the drinking - for the pain, isn't it, that you drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert has been meticulously preparing everything, positioning Joey, checking the tethers, digging the rusty plow in the earth. He takes his position behind the plow, throwing the rear leather harness over his own neck.</context>
      <utterance>And now your son's sinking into the selfsame bog that's swallowing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert gently snaps the reins. Joey doesn't move, confused by the whole affair.</context>
      <utterance>See Joey - I got the collar, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, boy. Walk on. That's it. Walk on! Walk on, Joey. Come on, boy, walk on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be better off startin' at the top of the hill and goin' down! Gravity's the only friend you're gonna have today, young lad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the house, Mrs. Narracott opens an upstairs window to look on, anxiously. Ted, standing alone by the fence, only looks at Albert.</context>
      <utterance>Walk on, Joey! Walk on! Come on, Joey, walk on. Walk on, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk on. Come on, walk on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT - Mrs. Narracott looks on from the house. He glances back at her. Her face is full of angry concern for their son. Townsfolk begin arriving, climbing the hill to the lower field. Ted looks down, ashamed. Mrs. Narracott looks back at Albert, mortified, bruised, setting the plow right again. Mrs. Narracott moves away from the window, takes a seat, and picks up her knitting. Later - Albert has made no progress. Joey is moving, but only in a useless circle.</context>
      <utterance>Bravo! You've reached the top of the hill! Off you go again, boy! You'll make even better time comin' down!! He continues past Dad, laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More townsfolk clamor to the fence. Andrew calls out.</context>
      <utterance>Good boy. Good lad. Good lad. Now walk on. Good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert tries to encourage him forward but Joey still isn't pulling sufficiently. The plow skips uselessly over the surface stones.</context>
      <utterance>Albie, we're all with ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Albert struggles with the plow, he sees Dad walking up the hill behind the spectators. He doesn't even turn to his son.</context>
      <utterance>Look look look! The plow hasn't even cut yet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plow skips and Albert falls. Joey's legs buckle and he goes to his knees. Albert rushes to his side.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know - I believe we can do it, Joey. I knew when I first saw you that you'd be the best of us. That's why he bought you. He knows you've all the courage he never had. I knew when I first saw you that you'd be the one who'd save us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lyons calls from the crowd as rain starts to fall.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert examines the collar - he sees it is ripping into Joey's flesh. He grabs his shirt, tears a piece off it, tenderly folds it and puts it between Joey's shoulder and the collar.</context>
      <utterance>You've got no chance, lad. He'll not turn over half an acre. Give it up now. You've done well. You've tried hard. You're more of a man than your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on now, Mr. Lyons, that's a bit rough, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode>A SHRUG:</mode>
      <context>The crowd's beginning to disperse. One of Lyons' cronies holds his umbrella as he returns to his car. He passes Ted.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he'll destroy that horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Narracott emerges from the house and heads to the fence - holding her knitting in the rain, ignoring the leaving crowds. A SYMPATHETIC NEIGHBOR hands her:</context>
      <utterance>I'll be over Thursday. Give you a day to close it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NEIGHBOUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your wool.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOUR</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context>Lyons passes behind her, almost speaks, but then thinks better of it. As the rain intensifies, Albert digs his toe into the wet soil and notices how it has softened. Suddenly something flashes through Albert's mind. He leaps into action, runs through the rain to shout at Joey.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Rosie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races back to the plow and sets himself.</context>
      <utterance>Now, boy! You've got to do it, Joey. You don't know, so I'm gonna have to do the knowing for you when the rest of our lives depend on this! So get set to pull - and pull straight! And pull hard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey pulls firmly and finally the inertia is broken - the rain has softened the earth.</context>
      <utterance>Now, boy! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finally, the plow bites deep into the soil.</context>
      <utterance>Walk on, Joey! Walk on! That's it! Good boy, Joey! Good boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the fence, Mrs. Narracott looks on in amazement. Albert notices a large rock in their path. Andrew sees it, too.</context>
      <utterance>Walk on! Walk on! Walk on! Walk on, Joey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - YELLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go around it!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, Joey! Whoa, Joey! Joey! Joey, whoa whoa whoa! Joey, stop! You'll break the blade -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LYONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Narracott brandishes her knitting needles, backing him up.</context>
      <utterance>I'd not let a child of mine slip in the mud alongside a plow blade. He could lose a foot!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad sits nearby, watching this exchange with silent approval. Lyons stares at her, gape-mouthed, as she turns her attention back to Albert.</context>
      <utterance>You'll likelier lose an eye, Mr. Lyons, if you carry on prating at me how to manage my son! Or my plow, or my horse, or my field, or my farm!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rain becomes torrential. Lyons turns towards the car - gestures, frustrated, to his driver, who runs forward with the umbrella to shield his boss from the rain. David remains on the running board, watching Albert plowing. The plow speeds through the earth. The boy and the horse are working as one. It is a moment of triumph.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Albie! Push on through!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get it done, Albie! Get it done!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're as battered and bloodied as he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where's Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still in the bottom field.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stumbling about, I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the drink, Albert, that makes him stumble -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>ABRUPTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He drinks, mum.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, so might you if you'd been where he's been, seen what he's seen!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he don't talk to me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie stalks over to a pile of broken equipment in a corner of the stables. She rummages until she finds a waterstained brown paper parcel tied with yarn. She brushes away some mouse turds.</context>
      <utterance>He don't talk about it because he can't. There aren't words for some things. Come here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They sit together on a step. As she begins to untie the yarn, a change comes over her: her irritated determination gives way to sadness. Albert comes to her and kneels beside her as she gently opens the paper. Inside there's a red and tan pennant, knotted and fringed at both ends.</context>
      <utterance>The mice've been at it. Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then with great care she unfolds the sash to reveal two silver medals. The first, with the profile of Victoria, hangs from a red, blue and orange ribbon.</context>
      <utterance>Here. It's his campaign pennant. He were Sergeant, Seventh Battalion, Imperial Yeomanry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up the other medal, hanging from a red and black ribbon.</context>
      <utterance>And that is the Queen's South Africa Medal. Every man who fought in the Boer War got one of those. But this...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the Distinguished Conduct Medal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not dad's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert nods, looking at the medal and campaign pennant. She takes the medal back, puts it in the sash, and begins to wrap it again.</context>
      <utterance>Well it ain't mine, dear. He got that after the fighting at Transvaal. After he'd been hurt, and he'd saved some other lads, and well... I don't know what else, he won't tell me either. But the first day he got home he just... tossed them out. First day he could walk, he threw `em straight in the dustbin, and wouldn't hear a word I said not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She returns the things in the footlocker, closes it.</context>
      <utterance>See, what you done today, you and Joey, you're chuffed up now, and so you should be, my splendid boy. It's good to be proud when you done something good. But what he done, in Africa, whatever it was, he takes no pride in it. Hard as it surely was, and however much pain it's cost him, he refuses to be proud of killing, I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED:</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be proud. If I'd gone off to war. If I'd gone and saved my mates, and -</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads back to Albert, pennant in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well, whether or not you think you'd do the same thing as him... Think how brave he is for refusing to be proud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As she leaves, she drapes the pennant over Albert's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, your dad makes mistakes. And he drinks to forget the mistakes that he's made - but he never gave up and he does that for us. And today, you showed the world it's all been worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert looks again at the pennant.</context>
      <utterance>You keep looking after Joey and he'll always be looking after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>SOFTLY:</mode>
      <context>Albert holds the pennant in wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, Seventh Battalion, Imperial Yeomanry.  You see this, Joey? It's been through an entire war.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not stealing it. I'll give it back to him, someday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, I'm the only boy that drives in the village. No one else drives but me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert urges Joey to go faster, till they're neck and neck beside the car, racing it. David Lyons looks to see Albert and Joey running alongside his car. He feigns disinterest. Albert glances at David, but he's much more interested in the very pretty young woman seated next to David, her hands trying to control her hair, flying in the wind. Forgetting himself momentarily, Albert stares at her, dazzled. The woman turns to David:</context>
      <utterance>That's right and this is my dad's car. You're lucky that you're in it. I'm not normally allowed to drive it `cause it's so -</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at Albert, encouraging him. David Lyons, annoyed, pushes the accelerator down, and the car edges ahead of Joey. But not for long. The sound of the acceleration and Albert's eagerness to impress the young woman make Joey go faster, and again he moves out ahead of the car. The young woman grins at Albert. Up ahead Albert sees that the wall alongside of which he's been racing turns the corner, presenting him and Joey with an obstacle. Albert encourages Joey to go faster.</context>
      <utterance>Is he a friend of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head right for the wall, but at the very last moment, Joey balks and comes to a dead standstill, sending Albert sailing over the wall. Back in the car, the girl gasps and covers her mouth, concerned. David says nothing, but allows himself a small smile. On the other side of the wall, Albert stands a bit battered, but unfazed.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, boy, let's show her how to fly!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad doesn't answer. He shakes his head and limps away.</context>
      <utterance>We can try planting something else, or we could hire ourselves out to Uncle Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ted doesn't turn around.</context>
      <utterance>How else we gonna pay Mr. Lyons' rent?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. NARRACOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to believe that God gave each man his fair portion of bad luck. I don't feel that any more. I've had more than my share.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOTORBIKE RIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bike comes to a stop in the market place. The rider takes off his goggles. Men of the village start to flock around the machine, with great curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>It's war!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTORBIKE RIDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shock and amazement. The rider takes off his goggles:</context>
      <utterance>We are at War with Germany. You hear? England is at war with Germany.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTORBIKE RIDER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to ring the bells at six o'clock - and then never ring them again until the war is over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert opens the doors and stops dead. He looks at the empty stables.</context>
      <utterance>Look smart, Joey lad, it's the Tavistock Fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT./ INT. KITCHEN / YARD. DAY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes into the kitchen. His mother stares out the window. She has been crying.</context>
      <utterance>Albert runs out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says nothing, but her face gives everything away. Albert in a panic turns and runs out into the lane. Mrs. Narracott tears up again.</context>
      <utterance>What has he done with him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Nicholls has immediately connected with Joey and puts him at his ease. SAM PERKINS, a tough sergeant, is physically inspecting Joey.</context>
      <utterance>Take my word for it - finest horse in the parish. Goes like a racer, strong, decent, very fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No curbs, no splints, good feet and teeth. He's as sound as a bell, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how much are you charging, sir - for this strong, decent, and very fine animal?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you twenty and not a penny more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty is no good to me, Captain. Thirty five and he's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know how he rides.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he rides... Splendidly. You'll be astonished. I promise you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>(his heart's in his throat, fighting back GRIEF)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finest horse in all of Devon. Finest horse I ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert races towards Joey. Ted grabs him. Albert fights to get free. He looks at his father in anger and betrayal.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't! You can't, he's mine! I trained him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert is hysterical.</context>
      <utterance>Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't have him. He's my horse, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's too late, lad. I've just paid thirty guineas for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>TO TED:</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, I'll get you money. I will, I'll get you money. I'll...I'll work for it! I'll work for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert snaps to attention.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if Joey's going, I'm going, too. I'm volunteering.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. What's your name, lad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how old are you, Albert?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nineteen, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir. But, but I look nineteen and I'm bigger than most nineteen-year- olds, sir! And I'm strong, sir! And I...I'm not afraid of anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he removes his cap,</context>
      <utterance>I don't doubt your qualifications, Albert, but the law is very clear about the proper age for soldiering, and your father's done what he had to do. You know that. Thirty guineas isn't nearly enough to purchase a horse as fine as your Joey, I know that. But it's all I've got. Will you lease him to me, Albert, to be my own mount?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARNEST)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert looks at him. Although Nicholls speaks with authority he has a kindness which Albert recognizes.</context>
      <utterance>I promise you, man to man, that I'll look after him as closely as you've done, I'll respect him and all the care that you've taken with him. And if I can - I'll return him to your care.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert kisses Joey.</context>
      <utterance>Now say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But at that moment, Sam Perkins pulls Joey away:</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, turn it in, eh? That's enough. He's a horse, not a dog. Now, on your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode>TO JOEY</mode>
      <context>Nicholls walks away into the crowd. The Sergeant pulls Joey, but Joey does not want to be separated from Albert. His reaction is implacable, reminiscent to the separation from his mother. Perkins leads Joey away. They disappear into the crowd and Rosie is suddenly there. Ted senses her silent judgment.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to lose the farm, Rose?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the way you did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we're at war.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- and tucks the pennant into Joey's halter.</context>
      <utterance>Joey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Nicholls intervenes from his car.</context>
      <utterance>Here now, I've told you - sling your hook!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him be, Perkins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then they are past him, leaving him behind. As Perkins leads Joey across a stone bridge, Albert watches from the bank of the stream. Joey balks one last time -</context>
      <utterance>This isn't the end. This isn't the end, my brother... I, Albert Narracott, solemnly swear we will be together again. Wherever you are, I will find you. And I will bring you home!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bucks, throwing the groom to the ground, and gallops away. But Perkins cuts him off, grabs his halter, and jerks him back to attention.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa whoa. Easy easy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes him into his stall, next to Major Stewart's horse, a magnificent black stallion, TOPTHORN.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa whoa, Joey! Stop muckin' about, you hear? Yer in the army now, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey rears up in his stall.</context>
      <utterance>Good boy, good boy. Steady steady... Easy. Relax. Easy easy, back up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This is the first time that Joey has had to deal with another horse since his mother - the beginning of one of the most important relationships in his life.</context>
      <utterance>Joey - meet Topthorn. Topthorn - this is Joey. Sort out who's in charge between the two of you, you hear? If you want to fight, you get it over with - `cause once we're over there, you're gonna need everything you've got for Fritz!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gently, Perkins. I don't want to sour him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'll be nothing gentle about the war, sir. And there'll be nothing gentle about this one either!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that, Sergeant, but I want him fit and shining. He's my horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicholls is joined by his friend LIEUTENANT CHARLIE WAVERLY. He is sweet and friendly - upper class but completely benign.</context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scares the living daylights out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're both joined by a tall, confident officer, MAJOR JAMIE STEWART. He sizes up Joey.</context>
      <utterance>Perkins. Glad he's on our side.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. Not bad at all. Still not a patch on my Topthorn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be so sure. I think he's got potential. He's certainly got the bit between his teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I actually think my Blenheim is faster than the pair of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly turns from the joking into the efficient senior officer he is.</context>
      <utterance>Clear off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Perkins...</context>
      <utterance>All right, gentlemen, listen here. Everything tells us the same story, from Waterloo to Omdurman, from Pickett's Charge to the Battle of Mars La Tours - the first attack can and should be the decisive one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No excuses, no mistakes - every horse groomed and fit for presentation! I want a full practice charge tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM PERKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave.</context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you two had bottled out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicholls looks at his friend tolerantly.</context>
      <utterance>As if.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, then, let's see what you two jokers are made of, shall we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what quiet confidence looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicholls and Stewart and Charlie prepare themselves for the charge. Joey and Topthorn size up to one another.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wait for you two at the Duke of York.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Topthorn bristles at Joey. Everyone is highly charged. The competition between Stewart and Nicholls seems to have been absorbed between the horses. Topthorn and Joey square up for the practice charge like two athletes before a race.</context>
      <utterance>Over to you, Captain Nicholls.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicholls raises his sword. It glints in the summer air. It seems to hang there forever. Every man follows suit. Topthorn and Joey glance at each other, ready to charge.</context>
      <utterance>Draw...swords!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Every sword is pointed directly ahead at arm's length.</context>
      <utterance>Give...point!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A roar goes up from the men and a deafening pounding of hooves breaks the silence. The huge line of horses start running straight ahead of them. Joey and Topthorn run off at top speed. Dust and earth rise up behind them. Bugles, the deafening thunder of hooves. It is exhilarating. We see the scale of the operation, we enjoy the speed and the splendor of the mass of men and horses. The soldiers shout in glee and excitement. Each man pushes his horse to out-run those around him, Nicholls and Stewart seem locked in mortal combat. Nicholls smiles at Stewart, confidently. Topthorn starts to pull away, ahead of all the other horses in the line. Nicholls pushes Joey on. Topthorn seems too strong, Joey will never catch them. Nicholls is determined not to be beaten.</context>
      <utterance>Charge!!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pushes Joey on. Joey digs in and finds hidden strength and speed. He starts to catch up with Topthorn and draws along side. Nicholls and Stewart exchange tense looks.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Joey. I know you've got it. Come on, boy! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stewart is amazed and pushes Topthorn harder. Now both riders are going at their top speed. They are neck and neck - they fight for every inch of advantage, every fibre of their being invested in the race. Nicholls pushes Joey on and Joey pulls away. Joey inches forward till he is almost a length ahead of Topthorn. The effort is enormous. Nicholls looks back at Stewart, very happy. Stewart's frustration shows. He knows he is beaten. Then suddenly they race over the line. Nicholls spears a ring decorated with a blue ribbon and pulls Joey to a halt. They have crossed the enemy line. Nicholls is ecstatic. Topthorn comes to Joey's side.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicholls laughs, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horses are nose to nose, snorting, we sense the heat, the exertion. Topthorn and Joey are brought together by the effort. We sense Topthorn's newly minted respect for Joey. And Joey is no soft touch - he slightly holds his head up in victory, letting Topthorn know that he knows he won. The other horses come charging in. There is a real sense of achievement and congratulation amongst the regiment.</context>
      <utterance>Nice of you to turn up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got speed...I'll give him that. But has he got stamina?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men enjoy the moment of rivalry and the exhilaration of it all. The two horses, face to face rub against each other for the first time. A bond has been formed...</context>
      <utterance>He has everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm writing a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a picture in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's to the boy who owned Joey. I want to show him how wonderful he's looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we take him away across the Channel to face a million Germans guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Before that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4 a.m. start tomorrow - travelling with the Dragoon Guards and the Royals. Transport detachment - they'll need to be at the docks at 5 am. Check all kit. Battle orders: no polishing - buttons, helmet buckles, stirrup irons - let `em all go dull. I want nothing to flash in the sun and give us away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Stewart leaves, he passes Charlie. He casually acknowledges him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jamie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>43.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie checks his new cap in the mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows the bright red lining to Nicholls.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think of the cap?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silk lining. I quite like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure it's going to make a lot of difference to the Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know about that. Think about it - you're a Boche, just working out which of two chaps to shoot - and you thought - "Good Lord - one of them really is wearing a very stylish cap indeed!" You might shoot the other one instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or, alternatively, think - "I fancy that cap" and kill you first of all. Pause. Charlie removes the cap.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicholls returns to his sketch.</context>
      <utterance>Hadn't thought of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SGT. MAJOR SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is our target - the German 11th Division - at the moment bivouacked three miles to the east of the Menin Road. We have been watching them and they have pitched tents for the night and lit cooking fires. Knock them out - and we could slide in behind the German lines and come at them from the South at Geluveld.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Numbers?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. MAJOR SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About six hundred. Infantry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twice our size...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In regiments of horse and men, the advantage is ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. MAJOR SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our officers just have a second to take in the news. The day has suddenly arrived. The day they have worked for, for so long.</context>
      <utterance>And we have surprise on our side. But the sooner we move, the better - we have no assurance they'll still be there tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie - tell the men.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Good. So - today it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salisbury formation?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salisbury formation. We'll charge through them and secure the ground behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. MAJOR SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The grass to the left is taller than we are - it's perfect cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Stewart departs:</context>
      <utterance>Excellent work, Sergeant Major. Time spent on reconnaissance is rarely wasted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Singh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CALLING AFTER</mode>
      <context>Nicholls catches up to Stewart, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Jamie!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have no idea we're coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not having scruples, are you, Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicholls notices Charlie nervously attending his horse.</context>
      <utterance>No. I understand the surprise is everything. But if it must be done, let's do it quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright, Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE WAVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stewart rides through the lines astride Topthorn.</context>
      <utterance>Never been better. Literally, never better. We worry for him - he is afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the cry is echoed throughout the regiment, Nicholls accepts Joey from an attending soldier.</context>
      <utterance>Prepare to mount! Mount!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Standley.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode>TO JOEY</mode>
      <context>Nicholls takes the red campaign pennant from his pocket and threads it through Joey's reins. Minutes later - Stewart addresses the men.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Joey. My bonny boy. You're all right, aren't you, Joey? Hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentleman. It is an honour to ride beside you. Make the Kaiser rue the day he dared to cross swords with us. Let every man make himself, his King, his country, and his fallen comrades proud! Be brave. Fear God. Honor the King!</utterance>
   <speaker>TROOPERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear God. Honor the King!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men draw their sabres in silence. The birds chirping, oblivious. Then Nicholls just turns to his two friends and almost whispers...</context>
      <utterance>Draw swords!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN NICHOLLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats Joey's side. And then...</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forward, to walk! Walk...march! The regiment begins moving through the field.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAJOR STEWART</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The men start to float over the grass - swept along by their invisible horses, until... Suddenly they emerge from the tall grass - the immense power of the galloping horses - silence explodes into a violent crashing of hooves. The noise is immense, swords are flying in the air. Hundreds of horses racing towards the German encampment. On the German side, TWO SOLDIERS wake to the sound of hoofbeats. They pull their tent flap aside to find the invincible charge coming towards them. The Germans are totally unprepared. We see them scramble back towards tents, rush towards their guns - one man pulling up his trousers rushes for cover. One German drops some dirty dishes into a wash pot, screaming:</context>
      <utterance>Forward to canter! Canter...march!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Topthorn and Joey race each other like a rerun of their practice on Salisbury Plain. The swords and uniforms glint in the sun, the German troops look terrified - some run in panic, others prepare to stand their ground.</context>
      <utterance>Kavallerie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JUNIOR GERMAN OFFICER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do with the horses?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they're injured, shoot them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the others, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The others you round up and take to base camp - they will pull guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never get fancy horses like these to pull guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunther, the young private, now standing behind them, interjects.</context>
      <utterance>Then shoot them also.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir - perhaps we could use some of them with the ambulances - to get the injured men off the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will they take the harness?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers move away - that's enough talk about horses... CUT ON - Gunther is now with Joey and Topthorn. Near a wooden ambulance - which is like a giant wagon to carry humans. He is with MICHAEL, a very young soldier, his brother - possibly as young as 14.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to try, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't work - they're cavalry</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's try.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't get the harness on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Topthorn balks violently.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Easy now, easy.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa. Easy, now, easy now, Englishman... Whoa, whoa, whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And suddenly Joey moves up and presents himself, with his strange self assurance and self sacrifice. And instinct for survival. He sniffs the harness and places his head through it, which helps to calm Topthorn enough that Gunther can slip the collar onto the big black horse. Gunther turns to Joey, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Gunther! It's hopeless - we can't help them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunther spots the red ribbon in Joey's saddle, removes it, folds it, and places it in his pocket. Later - Gunther and Michael are returning from the battlefield with Topthorn and Joey, pulling an ambulance with British and German wounded. Amongst the wounded, we see a hand gripping a battered, silk lined hat. It is Waverly, wounded but alive.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, look at you. Whoever taught you this has just saved your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello the farm!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looking up, wiping her</utterance>
   <speaker>BROW)</speaker>
      <mode> BROW)</mode>
      <context>Albert passes carrying a crate laden with turnips, but pulls up short when he hears:</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Si Easton!</utterance>
   <speaker>SI EASTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was at the post office and while I was there, Mrs. Allen said a parcel had come for Albert, from the, from the, from over there - and I thought I could go up that way in the morning. And - here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who'd be sending me a parcel over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert opens the parcel and pulls out a leather sketchbook...</context>
      <utterance>Well, open it and see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See that? That's a picture of Joey!</context>
      <utterance>It's a sketchbook...  That's Captain Nicholls' sketchbook!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a picture of Joey. Well, I never!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>EXCITED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's a letter...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, go on then, go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>READING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Dear Albert Narracott.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Si Easton drops his head guiltily. Rosie catches this.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Nicholls, who died...Captain Nicholls, who died in action today left you this. Yours, Sergeant Sam Perkins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't to know it was bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was riding Joey when he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know that he was riding him...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody falls silent. Albert goes to the fence and looks down at the sketches of Joey. Rosie looks at her son, her heart breaking for him. Dad returns to the harvest without a word. Albert looks off to the horizon and - over there.</context>
      <utterance>"In action," it says.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the soldiers hop to their orders, the officer turns to -</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen! We move forward to the frontline tonight. Full marching orders. Get moving!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both Michael and Gunther turn to him. But it's Gunther the Officer wants to talk to.</context>
      <utterance>Schroeder! Schroeder!</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not you - you. Come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm keeping you here. You are best with the horses and we need to move the camp quickly if the enemy continue to push through from the west.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're pushing through?</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm told. We will move later when we find where the horses are needed most.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Perhaps I can keep my brother here with me, he's also very good with horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no no. Not necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>TO MICHAEL</mode>
      <context>He walks away. Gunther is stricken by the news, but Michael is excited. As he leads Joey past his brother:</context>
      <utterance>Get moving. We leave tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunther can't really speak. Michael is just a boy.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Gunther.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not going. I'll tell them you are only fourteen, that you're a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father signed me in. He knew my age -and so do they.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother obviously never taught you how to fold a shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans close to Michael, talking in almost a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Of course she did. I just wasn't listening. But you need to listen now! I promised her, I made her a solemn promise, that you would be safe with me. With me, Michael!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll never make a head count. There are too many of us. You can stay here - slip underneath the bed - until they move out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael carries on with his packing.</context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And now the case is packed. Gunther heads to the tent opening.</context>
      <utterance>Gunther, it will be fine. And when all the machines break down and they call up the horses, I'll see you at the front. We'll be together again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Looking round, the tent is now empty. The moment to leave has come. Gunther pulls the red pennant from his pocket and follows Michael out of the tent to where the soldiers are lining up in the road.</context>
      <utterance>Gunther...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunther ties the pennant to the back of Michael's pack as he forms up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm giving this to you. For luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To keep you safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We settle on young Michael - in line - he passes Gunther. He remains eager. But it is goodbye. These soldiers moving into the darkness and towards death. Gunther looks on - tears in his eyes. The two horses are uneasy - sensing tension. A few minutes later - Gunther grabs a saddle and throws it onto Joey's back. Back to the soldiers. Suddenly we see the galloping legs of two horses. They whip past the back of the line of marching soldiers. It's clear what is happening - Gunther is on Topthorn - and has hold of Joey, on a loose rope, galloping beside him. Gunther, galloping along the line of soldiers, spots what he is looking for, a red pennant unfurled and flapping in the wind, tied onto Michael's pack. Gunther speeds toward him. This was his plan all along. And in an instant he is beside him and without Michael ever realizing, he suddenly finds his arms and legs akimbo, as he is yanked out of the line and dragged along the ground, desperately close to Joey's pounding hooves. Michael looks at the soldiers beside him - he looks at the skyline of violence ahead...but before he can decide, he feels his brother's arm - pulling him upwards. And now, the two of them are fully on Topthorn. They leave a jumble of soldiers in their wake as the officers try to restore order.</context>
      <utterance>Im schnellschritt! Marsch...links! Zwei, drei, vier!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back in line! Line!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry. Did you bring food?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael fingers the pennant on Joey's reins. Then...</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will Father be ashamed?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will pretend to be. Maybe at first he will be. But in the end, he will be glad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunther looks at him - but doesn't reply. As Michael removes</context>
      <utterance>And us? What about us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(after a beat, in a very</context>
      <utterance>I was ready to go. I was proud to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMALL VOICE)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Later - They sit in silence, waiting for sleep.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The food in Italy is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the women?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not as good as the food.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because...they've eaten too much of the food?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunther laughingly pushes him over.</context>
      <utterance>You are too young for war. And you're too young for women!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel so young. Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jokingly strokes Michael's cheek. Michael swats him away, but as he settles in the hay:</context>
      <utterance>Go to sleep - we have a big night of riding ahead. Goodnight, Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night night, Gunther.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys spring up, speaking in terrified whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Hei! In die windmhle!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go, go, go...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schroeder.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's offering an excuse, but -</context>
      <utterance>A mistake?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer accepts this grimly, nods.</context>
      <utterance>A promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE CAMP OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the boys are taken away, he lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Ja...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads towards the side-board, dumps the two bags and lifts the first handful of fruits on to the counter. She empties her clean berries into a bowl. Notes the explosions outside.</context>
      <utterance>Grandpre.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's closer today.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wind plays tricks with the noise - it's moving away from us.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can hear it, Grandpre, and there is no wind. You shouldn't lie to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. There is no wind here. But over there - a wind so strong it will lift you off the ground...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He retrieves a bottle of medicine from the mantle.</context>
      <utterance>You lie about everything. You say you aren't worried but it's clear you are. I know the war is approaching but you say, "Oh, it's just a trick of the wind."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>SMILING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours a load of sugar into a bowl with the fruit.</context>
      <utterance>You started lying when Mama and Papa went away.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're dead. But you won't say so. Do you think I'll die if you tell me the truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth is - He feeds her a spoonful of the medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sticks her wet finger in the sugar and sucks it to help with the taste of the medicine.</context>
      <utterance>- you should speak to your elders with respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you tell me the truth about the war, I will tell you the truth about the big horses I've been keeping in the windmill.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now - who is the one telling lies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the windmill?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. They were standing in the windmill waiting for Don Quixote. This is Franois  and this is Claude .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I named them after two boys who broke my heart last Summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must belong to someone. Horses like this don't just appear from a fairy-tale.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes - I know, Grandpre. They are not unicorns - so I will be fair and wait -- one day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emilie... Emilie...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if no one comes to get them by night-time, then they belong to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emilie. Look at me. You cannot ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother used to tell me how my bones would give way with the slightest bump or fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his cheek --</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's right. So it is settled?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>-- but then calmly leads the horses back to the windmill.</context>
      <utterance>Good girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will only be settled when I decide which one to ride first.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's - Over my dead body!</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least I won't have long to wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Outside, Emilie has fashioned two jumps. The big one for Joey and a little demonstration obstacle for herself. She leads Joey to a starting point about 30 yards in front of some crates supporting a stick about four feet off the ground. The red pennant hangs from the stick. Joey stands quietly as Emilie hobbles to the big jump, making a jumping gesture with her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Eyes on me. No talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grandfather chuckles. Emilie indicates the larger barrier.</context>
      <utterance>Today we learn to jump. Did you know the French cleared one meter eighty- five at the Paris Olympics to win the gold medal? Today we will beat that record.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She claps, but Joey doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>This is your jump. When I call you....be very brave and leap over it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns to her demonstration jump and easily steps over her six-inch high barrier.</context>
      <utterance>Leap over it! Watch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns to find Joey already stepping over her mini-jump, stopping in front of her. He's only interested in the apple in her hand. She takes a bite herself.</context>
      <utterance>And now it's your --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie unfolds the ladder beside Joey and shakily starts climbing to the top of it.</context>
      <utterance>He doesn't think we can do it. But we will show him, won't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>(Emilie looking down at how far off the ground SHE IS)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are...very tall.</utterance>
   <speaker>64.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before she can swing her leg over Joey's back -</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie turns, and there, blocking the hurdle, now standing hands on hips, is Grandfather.</context>
      <utterance>You'll kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you get in my way to make me fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SOUND from far down the road. Grandfather looks. Emilie turns to look too. Two trucks led by a German motorcycle are approaching the farm.</context>
      <utterance>Oh please, come off the ladd--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Emilie races off with the horses, Grandfather pushes over the jumps and jams the pennant into his pocket. The bikes arrive first, just missing Emilie as she leads the horses behind the house. The trucks arrive, pull round - one of the soldiers in the front jumps out and opens the back.</context>
      <utterance>Find somewhere to hide them. And do it quickly!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The people - 20 of them, all seeming to be poor French peasants, mainly women, move out of the truck. As they walk past, they avoid the eye of the Grandfather, who approaches the soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>Halt! Und aussteigen!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Bonnard - this is my land. Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And suddenly we see what is going to happen - the 20 peasants spread out and move through the field - with either bags, or using the aprons they wear - picking all the fruits - at just the moment all the work has brought forth fruit - and the new year's crop is ready.</context>
      <utterance>Food for the soldiers at the front. Everyone must give their share.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>They are taking everything. Where are the horses?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of jars breaking draws Grandfather and Emilie into the kitchen, where the Germans continue to raid their other supplies. One German picks up waterbath canner -- inspecting it.</context>
      <utterance>What horses?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave it if you don't know what it's for.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brandt sits quietly, casually using his finger to scoop jam from an open jar.</context>
      <utterance>A pot is a pot. We'll find some use for it. Sir, where's the livestock?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I make jam. We have no animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie enters, overhearing.</context>
      <utterance>But there's fresh hay in your barn.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We use it to replace the mattress stuffings.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her grandfather?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are her parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>BREAKING IN</mode>
      <context>The German nods and is about to take his leave, putting the pot back where he found it, when a clumping noise from somewhere in the house begins.</context>
      <utterance>They're dead. They died.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brandt licks his finger and tests:</context>
      <utterance>The wind. It plays tricks in the attic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An old house creaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>TO EMILIE</mode>
      <context>Emilie runs out of the room. The soldier picks up the medicine bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Go - close the shutters.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's sickly, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldier looks shocked and then begins to laugh. He slaps the medicine flask into Grandfather's chest.</context>
      <utterance>If you or any of your friends harm her, as old as I am, I will kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slings the huge pot he had put back up on his shoulder and leaves the house with the other soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I was going to give you back your pot. But now I'm going to keep it. For soup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandfather doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me what happened to them. To my mother and father.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you would tell me how they died. On my birthday. And tomorrow's my birthday! They died fighting, didn't they? But when the soldiers</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- you do nothing. You are a coward, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes. It was your parents who were brave. I make jams.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eases himself into a chair and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>And you've never done a brave thing in your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe there are different ways to be brave. Did you know the French have the best carrier pigeons? And this could be the difference in the war - our messages getting through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear about the birds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie sheds a single tear.</context>
      <utterance>They are released at the front and told to go home - this is all they know. But to get there they must fly over a war. Can you imagine such a thing? Here you are flying over so much pain and terror - and you know you can never look down. You have to look forward or you'll never get home. I ask you - what could be braver than that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie moves toward the object that is covered.</context>
      <utterance>A present.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you have not bought me a disgusting dress that I then have to wear like last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was disgusting?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I looked like an ugly nun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The grandfather smiles and gives Emily a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Give me your hand.  Grandpre, we have no money. When the war is over, then you can buy me jewels and carriages.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves the room. Now Emilie is alone and she can't help it when she brings her eyes back to the object covered by the rug. She looks back over her shoulder to make sure she's not being watched and then lifts one corner of the rug. Her face explodes with a gorgeous smile. She pulls off the rug that is covering the big thing and...it is a gorgeous old saddle. She runs her hand along the saddle -- can hardly believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Anything you say, my sweet one. Anything-you-say! You are, of course, the boss. It's just an old thing I found - don't worry yourself - leave it, I'll put it back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was your mother's. I hid it, so as not to encourage you. Emilie, I want you to ride very slowly, very carefully. And promise me you won't go far --</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Okay, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the top of the hill and straight back again.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie unties her hair and tosses the red pennant to Grandfather, releasing her hair to spill down her back and shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sets off on Joey - and quickly spurs him to a gallop.</context>
      <utterance>My hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rides - past the windmill - and then over the top of a nearby hill - she speeds over it and out of sight. Back to the hill - a sudden change of mood. An empty shot. No movement, no returning girl.</context>
      <utterance>Slowly...slowly...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cut again to the top of the hill, then back to the Grandfather, very worried.</context>
      <utterance>Emilie!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Topthorn suddenly rears up - and charges off following, sensing danger. Grandfather starts to run in the direction of the hill. Topthorn charging over the brow of the hill. The Grandfather running - out of breath. He hears an indistinct scream from Emilie! He reaches the top of the hill - comes over the brow - and there is not the fallen body of Emilie, which he has been fearing, but a brutal line of German soldiers - and motorbikes. It is like a line of Indians in a Western - total, alien fear. And there amongst them is Emilie, astride a panicked Joey, surrounded by soldiers. Another one holds Topthorn, who bucks and rears, but to no avail. Grandfather starts down the hill towards his granddaughter.</context>
      <utterance>Emilie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brandt approaches. Emilie screams at him, in tears.</context>
      <utterance>She is my granddaughter! Emilie, stop! Don't hurt her, please! Don't hurt her. A soldier roughly shoves Emilie at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie is still sobbing. Grandfather hugs her - in horror that she is now struggling so hard for breath.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need them! There are so many others!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, take the bigger one and leave the smaller one. You are breaking my granddaughter's heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode>LEAVING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war has taken everything from everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CALLING AFTER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will happen to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will pull artillery until they</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode>COUGHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Franois!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- or until the war is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will never be over!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The motorbikes start up and drive off. The Grandfather hugging tiny Emilie as she coughs.</context>
      <utterance>You have your answer then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heiglemann - these are yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRIEDRICH is an unprepossessing, chubby man. He marvels at Topthorn.</context>
      <utterance>They look strong - should last a month or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then he looks to the other horses penned nearby, haggard and weak. He turns to Joey.</context>
      <utterance>You are beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He takes the leads of the pair of them. He sighs...</context>
      <utterance>It's a pity they found you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In a strange way, there are many humans Joey meets, but also just one, the spirit of goodness and consideration for animals, joined by little echoes throughout the film. And then they go over a ridge - and we suddenly see the explanation of Friedrich's comment. The road they can see below them is the main through road of the area - and it is a scene of horse horror - huge, massive guns and cannons and artillery being dragged by teams of horses that are in a terrible condition. For Joey and Topthorn, this is a moment like when soldiers arrived to liberate the prisoners who had been kept in Changi prison by the Japanese during World War 2. They have never seen horses in this condition. You can see in their eyes the confusion. This is a whole different world, where horses can turn into creatures that look like this.</context>
      <utterance>Such a pity...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A soldier calls from the front of the heavy cannon - pulled by a particularly wretched group of horses.</context>
      <utterance>Pull together!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lower down the hill, Friedrich waves down the rest of the column.</context>
      <utterance>Halt! Halt! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the front of the Morser, one of the lead horses collapses - he will never get up again. Brandt steps up, pulls a revolver out of his pocket and shoots the horse dead. It has come to this. Joey, Topthorn, and all the other horses are spooked by the pistol shot. Brandt shouts to Friedrich from the road.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heiglemann, bring up another one!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heiglemann, bring up another horse!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Friedrich begins leading Joey up the hill, but --</context>
      <utterance>That one!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Friedrich hauls Topthorn, hesitantly, while Joey watches.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. The big black one!</utterance>
   <speaker>74.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he reaches Brandt:</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good horse, sir. But if you move him up to the heavy gun, he will be no use at all. Prince is already losing condition. His leg, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have given them names?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should never give a name to anything you are certain to lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His leg is not good enough, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Private, you will do as you are told.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode>CALLING OFF</mode>
      <context>Friedrich has no choice but as he starts to lead Topthorn, Joey rears up and escapes his groom. He gallops up the hill to the gun - offering himself up to save Topthorn. It is his "Tale of Two Cities" moment - giving up his life to save his friend. He bucks and rears. Friedrich turns to Brandt.</context>
      <utterance>Hook him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brandt takes up Friedrich, and Joey's, offer -</context>
      <utterance>As you see, sir, this one is stronger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRANDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Joey is hooked to the gun, he looks back to Friedrich who leads Topthorn back down the hill.</context>
      <utterance>Hook him up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Halt! Halt! Take the horses away!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Friedrich observes with Topthorn as a giant shell is carried to the gun's breech.</context>
      <utterance>Shell!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The men wrestle it into place -</context>
      <utterance>And load!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>- and secure it.</context>
      <utterance>Back! Case!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The barrel of the giant gun ratchets upward.</context>
      <utterance>Position!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTILLERY OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The shell explodes from the barrel. And then from another. And another. For the first time we see the big picture - the line of assembled cannons of which they were just one tiny part.</context>
      <utterance>And...fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SERGEANT MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert and Andrew move down the trench in a line of soldiers who are given ammo belts and grenades. Albert gets his grenades and walks further along the trenches. We follow him in real time as he passes a bunch of soldiers who are kneeling in the ankle deep water, a PADRE is giving them communion. The deafening noise of shelling all around.</context>
      <utterance>Valuables in the bucket, lads. If you live, you'll get them back. If you live, you'll get them back. Good lads.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We keep following Albert's progress in real time - further on there is a post box where they all put their final letters home in identical green envelopes. We see Albert's letter addressed to "Ted and Rose Narracott" in Devon. He posts it in a battered metal post box.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's a drill, Albie. Maybe it's a drill like last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>77.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An officer approaches:</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is David - Lyon's son - now in charge of this small group of men. Still arrogant - looking older than Albert in his uniform - and clearly enjoying his superior rank.</context>
      <utterance>That's my business.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert ignores him. Andrew can't help but giggle.</context>
      <utterance>I hear you and your mate were doing bird imitations again. You gonna write a letter to your horse?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>David takes up a bucket and walks down the line of soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>After you find your horse, I've lost my needle in a haystack, and I could use some help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything valuable. Anyone who comes back gets to share it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>TO ANDREW</mode>
      <context>Albert follows David down the trench.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember that day me and Joey raced you in your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember you somersaulting through the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that girl you were with?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert nods.</context>
      <utterance>There was a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was. Don't you remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrew laughs amiably. David points to him, smirking.</context>
      <utterance>It was just some girl, I suppose. I don't recall which one. I do remember you falling on your bum in a ditch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As David walks on, Andrew smiles at Albert.</context>
      <utterance>You see? Always entertaining, Narracott, I'll give you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert leaves without answering. Andrew keeps smiling until a large shell explodes nearby. Troops surge towards their ladders as officers scream indistinct orders. Now David leads his troop through the trenches to the front line where they stop, lean against the enemy-side wall nervously and wait - each man in private contemplation. Sergeant Martin moves along the lines, pushing men forward.</context>
      <utterance>You did that? You fell on your bum?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David calls out from atop a trench ladder.</context>
      <utterance>Be ready! Be ready! Let's go, men, get ready to go! Get ready to move out! Stay in position!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The echo of `fix bayonets' goes down the line - and every man fixes the brutal shining bayonet to the end of his gun. Then Albert turns to Andrew.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your nerve, boys. Remember, it's not far to go. There's a way through.  Run fast, keep your wits about you, keep your eyes open and God and the King will keep an eye on you. Company will fix bayonets! Fix bayonets!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what it reminds me of out there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bloody impossible lower field the day me and Joey plowed it. Best day of my life that was and you were there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods at David Lyons, who gives instructions to another soldier.</context>
      <utterance>And this here is the worst day of my life, about to begin, and you're here cheering me on. Us two, always. And him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once you're in no man's land, go to the flanks. Stay on the flanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David turns to Albert and Andrew.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, boys, come on. To the ladder!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>TO ANDREW</mode>
      <context>They both smile. And then the fear takes over again. Andrew particularly feels as though he is on the very edge now. David urges them forward.</context>
      <utterance>Stick close to the gentry, that's our ticket, yeah? We have the pluck but they have the luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, too, Narracott.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>TO ANDREW</mode>
      <context>Andrew and Albert pass by the bucket. They throw some valuables in. But a moment later, Albert goes back to the bucket and pulls something out - a worn piece of paper - he unfolds it - it is the little sketch that Captain Nicholls drew of Joey the night before they left for France. He slips it inside his shirt, next to his heart.</context>
      <utterance>And you, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Andrew turns towards a ladder. As fate and placement would have it - he is first in line. He puts his foot on the ladder, when suddenly the Sergeant stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, on your ladders, boy. On your ladders. In you go, in you go. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Andrew aside, speaking so that everyone can hear.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to your sergeant!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If anybody turns back, if any one of our boys come running towards you - you take this rifle and you shoot them dead. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant pushes in on Andrew, private and intense.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrew looks ready to cry, but manages to nod. Albert turns to him, only to be pushed back by the sergeant.</context>
      <utterance>Do you understand me? Do you understand what I'm telling you, son? You take this rifle and you shoot them dead. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert looks nervously back at Albert, comforting.</context>
      <utterance>Up there, son. Up your ladder. Up your ladder to your work!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COMMANDER arrives, checks the time on his AIDE's watch, mounts his ladder and blows a whistle to signal the charge. A BAGPIPER plays as the men go over the top. David now heads up the ladder first. Gun fire overhead, Albert steels himself, then hauls himself over the top, followed by the next man and the next.</context>
      <utterance>It's good. Andrew, it's good. Andrew! Nobody's retreating today. Andrew! Andrew! Nobody. Is retreating. Today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert instinctively goes to help. Bullets shower all around him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm shot! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert grabs him and drags him onwards with him - David screaming at the pain - Albert grimly determined. Shells explode around them as they stumble on. Other men are running and falling. Albert sees cover in a huge shell-hole so dives into it for a moment's reprieve from the gun fire. He sits in still terror for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Just leave me. Leave me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be all right here. You'll be safe. Someone'll come for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert. Albert, listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David looks at Albert as though seeing him for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. It's all right. We're Devon boys, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert races onward. Back at the trench, Andrew waits - terrified - and then, back out of the mist step two men - heading back towards him. Then a third. They suddenly catch sight of Andrew waiting there with his gun pointed towards them. They slow down - in the terror of the assault, they had forgotten that death was waiting for them if they turned back.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Andrew grabs Albert and holds him up, embracing him. Albert can barely whisper:</context>
      <utterance>Albie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment later, the pair of them hurry through the trenches. Albert spots more comrades around a corner and calls ahead to Andrew.</context>
      <utterance>We made it. We made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly ANOTHER SOLDIER leaps from a trench branch between them, shouting in panic.</context>
      <utterance>Andrew, this way out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An instant later, a gas cloud blasts through the trench. Andrew and Albert look in horror. It spreads towards them, too powerful to avoid. Andrew is closest, turns to Albert with a helpless -</context>
      <utterance>Gas! Gas! Gas!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- before he takes the full power of it. An instant later, the white, deadly cloud encompasses Albert, too...</context>
      <utterance>Albie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, there's something wrong. This one needs to rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instead, Friedrich leads the horses under the cover of a low bridge for a brief respite. A moment later, Topthorn collapses.</context>
      <utterance>There's no rest for them. Move them along. Move them along!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Friedrich tries to help Topthorn valiantly struggling to get up but finally sinks to the ground again. This time he lies semi-conscious. He is dying.</context>
      <utterance>Please, please, please. Stay on your feet. No, please. No no no...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey deeply upset nuzzles his nose into Topthorn but the life drains out him. Friedrich is in panic at Topthorn's quick</context>
      <utterance>Please please... Stay on your feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Friedrich continues to stroke Topthorn's head. Joey pushes Topthorn as if to stop him falling into unconsciousness. For a moment we think Topthorn will come round but he slips away and all life leaves his body. Friedrich solemnly strokes the horse, knowing all is lost. Joey does not understand. He pulls at Topthorn's reins, as if trying to pull him upright. Topthorn's body is inert, his head falls to the earth. Joey will not give up, he pulls at him desperately not understanding that Topthorn has died. Suddenly, Friedrich looks around. Chaos - all the German soldiers stream back past their position, scrambling to get their guns and helmets. An officer charges down the bank next to the bridge, screaming orders at Friedrich.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Please please...</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Friedrich tries to pull Joey away to safety but Joey will not leave Topthorn's body. Friedrich pulls at Joey, but Joey is too lost in his grief to care about or even notice the danger.</context>
      <utterance>They're coming! Leave it, private!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave it! Come with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer nods to two other soldiers who pull Friedrich to safety. As he's dragged away, he screams at Joey:</context>
      <utterance>Go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEDRICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But this is all background noise to Joey's profound refusal to accept Topthorn is dead. He paws at the ground next to Topthorn, a horse standing over his best friend in a field, and he will never leave him. And then suddenly - from around a blind turn in the streambed, a huge, remorseless tank turns, heading right for Joey. He bolts, galloping down the streambed, until he reaches a barbed wire barrier - a dead end. He attempts to run up the banks, but they're blocked, as well. He rears up, but the tank keeps advancing. The tank is about to crush Joey. He has left it too late. He is about to die. But then, counter-intuitively, he runs straight towards the tank and...leaps over it - a leap he learnt from Emilie. Then scrambles up and over it and leaps down behind. Joey keeps on running. He is wild, frightened.</context>
      <utterance>Run. Run! Run! Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GEORDIE SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A young soldier, a Geordie, is on look-out duty. He looks through a periscope. He alerts his colleague in his thick, northern, Newcastle accent.</context>
      <utterance>Stand to, stand to -</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He passes the periscope to the second soldier.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like a cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see what he sees - nothing but morning mist on the surreal landscape - and something strange. It is Joey in the distance</context>
      <utterance>What the hell would a cow be doing out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That definitely isn't a cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SECOND GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be a horse. Nothing alive could be out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first German looks through his periscope. We see what he sees - Joey in the mist:</context>
      <utterance>It isn't a horse. It isn't a horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second German looks through the periscope, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Yes - it's a horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a horse. A third German  lowers his binoculars.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's a horse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRITISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, bugger me. It's a horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lads, we should call him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie starts clicking his tongue, followed by all of his comrades. They all try to attract Joey's attention with tongue clicks.</context>
      <utterance>How do you call a horse?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORDIE SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordie climbs up the side of the trench, and waves a white handkerchief tied to the end of his bayonet.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sod it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordie, not receiving fire, is emboldened to stand up.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing? Get back, do you hear me? Corporal, that's an order! Get back!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves the handkerchief to clearly signal he is no threat.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to him, sir. We can't leave him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second German cocks his rifle and starts to take aim.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think so. I think he's trying to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second German takes a shot aimed over the Geordie's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Scare him back into his hole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Georgie marshals his courage and stands again, waving the handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>It's a white flag, ent it? You see the white flag!? I'm just after tending to this here horse, is all!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRITISH CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no fire from the German trenches. Muttering to himself, the Geordie marches forward towards Joey:</context>
      <utterance>Get back, you stupid git!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie walks very slowly across the mud - there are bodies - the ground squelches beneath his feet. He waves his handkerchief as he walks. He crosses a narrow bridge that spans a flooded bomb crater. Joey, lying on his side, wrapped head to toe in barbed wire, covered in mud, watches Geordie approach. When Geordie gets too close, Joey freaks out and begins thrashing about. Joey whinnies a high scream of pain, because wire is cutting into his hide in several places, and as he thrashes it cuts him deeper. Particularly worrisome is a strand that's wrapped around his head, crossing right over his eye, threatening to slash it. The Geordie calls out in a soothing voice:</context>
      <utterance>The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want, he leadeth me into green pastures, he lay me down beside the still waters...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joey calms a little, still moving his head up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Poor beastie. Poor babbie. It's alright. It's alright. Don't buck and wriggle so, you're only shredding yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He reaches Joey and surveys the formidable tangle of wire in which Joey's bundled. The Geordie soothes and at the same time gingerly tests other strands, trying to figure out where to begin.</context>
      <utterance>You'll blind yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out the wire cutters. The Geordie, still frightened, stares stupidly at them.</context>
      <utterance>I thought perhaps you might need these.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the barbed wire?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out and takes the proffered cutters.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah I... Ummm, thanks. Cheers. Cheers...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He returns to Joey, nervous about turning his back. He tries to figure out where to begin cutting. He lifts a long strand of wire that wraps around Joey's neck, stretches across his shoulder and torso and around one of his front legs. He puts the wire in the crux of the cutters and is preparing to snip when Peter steps closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a wire wrapped around the wire the Geordie's lifting. Then he points to two other wires, similarly</context>
      <utterance>That...That's a very long strand. When you cut it, it's going to release this -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- and this, and this, and they'll coil back rather violently, which I'm afraid will only wound the poor fellow further.</utterance>
   <speaker>91.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Geordie nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak good English.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie hands them over and Peter surveys the wires.</context>
      <utterance>I speak English well.  May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we cut his head free first? So he won't try to stand up and blind himself? And then -</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to one of the wires entangled with the strand he'd been prepared to cut. Peter stands and shouts in the direction of his trench.</context>
      <utterance>Pity you didn't bring a second pair. Then I could cut the wire here -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could -</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they reposition themselves, the Geordie says to Joey:</context>
      <utterance>Say no more, I'm right behind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Geordie looks into Joey's huge eye as he and Peter get to work on their cutting. Joey returns his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>And you understand what's happening, do you not, O Best Beloved? That you must lay so very nice and still. There's a lad, you're a remarkable horse, you are, helping us help you. There's a lad. There's a remarkable lad.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's things in yonder trench?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delightful. We read, we knit sweaters, and we train our rats to perform circus tricks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if ever you need any more rats, we can always send ours over. `Cause we've more than we need, strictly speaking. Besides, they scare off all the pretty girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our girls aren't afraid of rats.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Big strapping German girls, eh? Kind what gives robust massages?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men smile at this while Joey is completely still; they work quickly, in concert, cutting the horse's head free of the wire.</context>
      <utterance>Every Thursday! And they bring rum cake on your birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Runnin' away from danger.</context>
      <utterance>Look at that horse! Look at the muscles he's got, them long legs. They're made for running, horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Running away is all they have.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet we taught `em opposite. Running into the fray.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>War horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie grabs hold of Joey's halter, though Joey shows no sign of running. Joey is finally free. The two men look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. War horse. And there he is. What a strange beast you've become.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take him back with me, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I supplied the cutters, the horse is mine. This is fair, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a pig's eye. He's English, plain to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean because he's so filthy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he's so smart. And you're none too clean yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie smiles.</context>
      <utterance>We could box. And the winner gets the horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks, pet. Must be careful not to start a war.  Do you have a coin of any sort?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coin toss?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a coin from his pocket, hands it to the Geordie, who looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He flips the coin back to Peter.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Fritz - you're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is not Fritz - it is Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter - I'm Colin.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call it, Colin.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter spins it in the air and lets it fall into the mud. They look down. Peter shakes his head, resigned.</context>
      <utterance>Heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They collect their helmets as snow begins to blow around them.</context>
      <utterance>That's the face of my Kaiser and he does not look pleased with me. The horse is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone quiet, hasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wait half an hour and we'll be shooting again.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a terrible shot, Pete, don't believe I'll ever hit the target. He hands back the cutters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices the Geordie has offered his hand, as well. A beat, then Peter shakes with him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheerio, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>RE JOEY:</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll take good care of him, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our strange beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter tosses Geordie his cutters.</context>
      <utterance>And you take care of your own strange self.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colin! A pair of German cutters - in memory of your handsome friend from Dusseldorf.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter nods, and walks back to his trench. As he goes, the Geordie calls after him:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As he walks away, Peter turns back briefly, calling:</context>
      <utterance>I'll use `em back in the garden in South Shields. You keep your head down, now, Pete me lad!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie leads Joey towards the British trenches.</context>
      <utterance>Remarkable! A remarkable horse!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SERGEANT MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David is seated next to Albert, who now seems in worse condition. His eyes are bandaged and he's wheezing. Andrew is nowhere to be seen. As a MEDICAL OFFICER checks Albert:.</context>
      <utterance>We're full up. Move on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The medic moves to Sergeant Martin, looking stricken.</context>
      <utterance>The gas got him - we had to wait till morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDICAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This can't be all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is all.  All walking wounded, away to the dressing station! Away to the dressing station!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a vet, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no vets. We've scarcely any horses left.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordie strokes Joey as the Doctor examines him.</context>
      <utterance>He's cut all over, but this leg here's got the worst of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably tetanus. It's no good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor heads back into the hospital, dismissive.</context>
      <utterance>Please, sir -</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've all these men to take care of, corporal, you can see that, can't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor absorbs his earnest appeal.</context>
      <utterance>Please, sir, this horse can pull through anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AN ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a horse they found, wandering about in No Man's Land.</utterance>
   <speaker>AN ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode>(easing him back onto a COT)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of an horse?</utterance>
   <speaker>AN ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert lies there, but can't let go of the thought:</context>
      <utterance>Bloody miraculous kind of an horse, be my guess. Nothing makes it out of No Man's Land.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miraculous horse...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was alive, y'see, sir, where nothing survives, so to me and me mates, to the men, sir, he's - Well, we have high hopes for him -</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie is broken hearted.</context>
      <utterance>You should shoot him now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'd be a mercy, lad, that leg's not going to mend. The Doctor sadly addresses a nearby Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant. Put him out of his misery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Total silence from the crowd who have gathered. They thought they were there to see something wonderful. And now they find that they've gathered for an execution - but can't take their eyes off it. The Sergeant waves them back.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies, if you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Geordie is the last to step away from Joey. The sergeant draws breath - before he steps forward to take aim. Joey is totally still, sensing the atmosphere. The sergeant cocks his pistol. Suddenly there is a strange owl like whistle from fifty yards away. Joey looks around startled. The sergeant turns Joey's head back around, raises his pistol once more. Then, the whistle again. Even the doctor notices this time. Joey turns. Slowly, the crowd parts - another owl whistle - and we see Albert, his eyes bandaged - walking forward blindly - guided by the hands of the crowd. One soldier urges Albert gently.</context>
      <utterance>All right, back off. Back off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One more whistle.</context>
      <utterance>Go on. Do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this time, Joey trots over to Albert. The horse nuzzles into him. Albert can't see Joey but he touches him.</context>
      <utterance>Joey?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SOFTLY:</mode>
      <context>He strokes Joey's mane. Joey responds, becoming very still. The Doctor approaches with the Geordie.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Joey. Hello boy. Where you been then, hey? Where in the world you been?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie shakes his head, no. The Doctor speaks to Albert, gently; clearly he thinks he's dealing with a traumatized, possibly crazy soldier.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert, realizing he's being addressed, turns to the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Narracott, Private Albert Narracott, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a random horse, Narracott, and too badly injured.  Is this man in your care?</utterance>
   <speaker>AN ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not random at all, sir! He's my horse, I raised him, in Devon. Sir, look at his legs! He's got four white socks, he's brown all over -</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>(points to his own FOREHEAD)</mode>
      <context>He makes the shape of a diamond with his hands. The doctor turns to the orderly.</context>
      <utterance>- and he has a white mark here - like so...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>AN ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie looks around, spots a bucket of water, grabs it and uses a rag to clean Joey's legs, revealing the socks. The Geordie looks at the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! You can't see `cause of the mud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The doctor takes a rag himself and wipes Joey's snout, revealing the white diamond mark. The Sergeant takes this in...and holsters his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Four white socks!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, break it up. Clear off, the lot of ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor steps up to him.</context>
      <utterance>You see, sir? He's not random at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will attend to your horse. Patch him up best we can. Treat him like the soldier he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one last amazed look at Albert and Joey, the doctor returns to the hospital area. Moments later - Albert, the Geordie, and Sergeant Fry all lead Joey through the snowy street together.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shock from the troops. Strangely muted. Not the explosion of emotion you might have expected. Albert enters, his eyes still red, but no longer bandaged.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen! Gentlemen! It falls on me to give you some important news. At eleven o'clock today, in two minutes time - the War will come to an end.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King and Queen thank you for your service. We have been victorious - even if at a higher price than many of us might have imagined.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR TOMPKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Officers' horses only. All other horses are to be auctioned immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is a complete and bloody outrage. It's the lad's horse, sir, from Devon. He raised him up from a pup, he did. Trained him right up to the day when the army came to town.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR TOMPKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These aren't my orders, sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR TOMPKINS</speaker>
      <mode>TO ALBERT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to take him to market. That's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does the Major know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Geordie flashes a sly wink.</context>
      <utterance>The Major put in ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns to indicate David Lyons, who nods at Albert solemnly.</context>
      <utterance>Mum's the word where the Major's concerned. Your friend on the crutches over there -</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Albert is amazed. He is about to show his gratitude when the sergeant major shouts:</context>
      <utterance>- even asked the Major to say that Joey was his, an officer's horse, so that he could go back with the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert snaps to attention and begins to lead Joey out of the parade ground with the other horses. As they walk off, the sergeant silently adds some of his own money to the notes in Albert's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Narracott! Get a move on. We don't want to miss the show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A groom leads Joey to the auction pen with other horses.</context>
      <utterance>Seven pounds! Seven pounds there! Seven pounds! Eight pounds here!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight pounds! Ten pounds here! Any advance? Sold!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're alright. Nobody's gonna bid more than fifteen for a thoroughbred. They want work horses. The auctioneer starts the bidding on Joey.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The farmers seem disinterested, shaking of heads. The bidding starts. Five pounds, six, seven, now it goes slowly, eight, nine, ten. Albert looks pleased at how it's going. He feels the cash in his hand. It seems to stick on ten, then a new hand comes up at the back of the auction - it is a nasty looking moustached man.</context>
      <utterance>Next one. We start at four pounds. Four pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sergeant Fry scowls.</context>
      <utterance>Eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the butcher from Cambrai. He's been bidding for the best all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eleven. Eleven pounds. Eleven pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty of your English pounds. And let THAT be the end of it, my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty Five.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty five pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty Six.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men are all looking very worried... There's not much left.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty six pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty eight pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT FRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, from the back, another, new French voice...</context>
      <utterance>Any advance at thirty pounds?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINAL BIDDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps to the front of the crowd, and suddenly we see who it is. It is Emilie's Grandfather.</context>
      <utterance>One hundred pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>reeling. He hears the auctioneer repeat the final amount and brings down his gavel.</context>
      <utterance>And sir, if you bid against me, I will sell the coat on my back and bid to one hundred and ten. And if you bid against me again, I will sell my farm and bid to a thousand. Everyone looks at Albert who is devastated. Albert is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'll give you all your money. Everything you paid when we get back to England. I'll give you twice -</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know anything about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but you're wrong, sir, I know everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you found him! I heard you found a horse in the wire between the armies -</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Grandfather goes to Joey and takes his reins.</context>
      <utterance>No, I found him, he raised him -</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, briefly, to collect himself.</context>
      <utterance>When I heard about the miracle horse, I traveled three days because I knew whose horse it was. My granddaughter's. She saved his life! He was everything to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is your granddaughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Grandfather leads Joey away. Joey pulls, firmly but not wildly, on the rein the grandfather's holding. The grandfather lets go.</context>
      <utterance>The war has taken everything from everyone. He is all that I have left of her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandfather softens and begins to wonder about this soldier.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be worried, boy, when I go. I won't worry over you none. Hey, I found you, didn't I, and you found me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He leads Joey back to the Grandfather.</context>
      <utterance>And we'll both... we'll both know that we made it through. Now go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He quietly hands over the reins.</context>
      <utterance>We're the lucky ones. Always have been. Lucky since the day I met you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The grandfather looks at Albert, then takes the regimental pennant from his pocket:</context>
      <utterance>God be with you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert's amazed.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandfather hands Albert the pennant.</context>
      <utterance>It's my father's. It's his regimental pennant. How did you come by this, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert takes the pennant and looks at it, his eyes filling with tears.</context>
      <utterance>You may have this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you ever so much for this, sir...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Albert Joey's reins. Albert turns to face him, almost mute with disbelief. He reaches for his money.</context>
      <utterance>... And this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grandfather laughs, then turns and slowly walks away.</context>
      <utterance>No no, not necessary. He belongs to you. That is, of course, what my little girl would have wanted. And she was the boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDFATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert gently embraces Joey.</context>
      <utterance>Emilie.  Her name is Emilie.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
