<movie id="588" title="Warrior">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy gives a drunken, crooked smile.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just passing through. Figured why not have a belt with the old man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she's hanging in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy grins uncomfortably. Lets the remark go and climbs the stairs as Tommy reaches into his duffel bag and produces a fresh BOTTLE of Jameson. He offers it to Paddy.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you always did take good care of her. Paddy Conlon. Man of priorities.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a little something for ya. Mom always said never go anywhere empty handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did. But that's not for me anymore, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy shakes his head. Tommy looks at him. Paddy Conlon not drinking? What gives?</context>
      <utterance>What? You change brands?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy pats his son on the back and heads for the door as a confused Tommy follows.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, let's go inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The sound of glasses CLINKING in the kitchen as Tommy takes off his watch cap and begins to look around his old home. He glances down at a BIBLE on a table beside a weathered Barca lounge chair.</context>
      <utterance>Appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not much of a woman's touch around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more women for me, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy takes another swig from his bottle and looks at a series of old PHOTOGRAPHS lining the walls as Paddy walks into the room carrying a coffee pot and saucers on an old wicker tray. Tommy looks at him, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Must be hard to find a girl who can take a punch nowadays.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee? You haven't seen a guy in 14 years and you're not gonna have a drink with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm off it. I'm coming up on a thousand days.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, just one drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy shrugs. Takes another pull from his bottle and turns back to the photos. He takes them in.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - OFF PICTURE</mode>
      <context>Tommy's face registers surprise.</context>
      <utterance>He's a school teacher down in Philly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy turns back to the photos and looks at another one of the woman. Obviously his MOTHER. He puts it down, glances at the bible, then stares hard at Paddy.</context>
      <utterance>Remember Tess? They've got two beautiful little girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy sips his coffee. Says nothing. Tommy keeps pressing.</context>
      <utterance>So you found God, huh? That's awesome. Mom kept calling for him, but he wasn't around. I guess Jesus was down at the mill forgiving all the drunks. Who knew?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you gonna ask about her, or you just gonna sit there all sober?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know? What do you know? Do you know it wasn't enough just to drive west to get away from you? When we hit the water we drove north, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I got sober I hired a man to find you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that one of the 12 steps? Or does a guy like you get 24?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the 12.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your guy tell you what you needed to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just that your mother died in Tacoma. And you were in the Marines. That was all. That was enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy plops himself into a recliner. Glances at the coffee table, where a stack of classic books on tape sits. CRIME AND</context>
      <utterance>That's too bad. You could've gotten some good details.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could've heard about her coughing up blood in a shit box with no heat. Having me rub her down with holy water, because she didn't have no insurance. All the while waiting for your pal Jesus to save her. Did your man tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy chokes up. Tommy looks at him. Closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>It's good to know you're sorry, Pop. Goes a long way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>An overwhelmed Paddy sips his coffee and looks at Tommy, who is fading. The pills are kicking in. He tries to open his eyes, but it's no use, and after a few moments he's out.</context>
      <utterance>I think I liked you better when you were a drunk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess laughs. Brendan looks at her with a "Help me out here" expression.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not sure, but I think Daddy is now a princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The make-over ends abruptly at the mention of "presents." Emily, little sister in tow, runs over to a table filled with gifts as PARENTS and CHILDREN gather around. Brendan gets out of the lawn chair and follows Tess over to the gift table. Amidst all the presents is one BOX, covered in pink wrapping paper, that is far larger than the rest.</context>
      <utterance>Em, you want to open your presents?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This an awfully big box.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess turns the video camera toward Brendan again. He couldn't look more ridiculous. And he obviously didn't clear the gift with his wife. He grins at her as she lowers the camera.</context>
      <utterance>It's her birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They just need a bath.</context>
      <utterance>Hey babe, I'm late. Mom's saying goodbye to the girls. She's gotta get on the road. They've been fed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan kisses Tess. Looks at her outfit.</context>
      <utterance>Can you get them down at a reasonable time tonight? They're exhausted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the rest of that skirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, if any guys give you a hassle in that joint tonight you give me a call, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Just like you gave me a call when those Temple frat boys decided to smash up your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, most nights I sit on the stool and grade papers, but every now and then I need some action.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess smiles flirtatiously and and heads for the car.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, well wait up for me tonight. I'll see what I can do about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promises, promises.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JON ANIK</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we return here on MMA Live, Jon Anik alongside billionaire fight promoter J.J. Riley. The Tapout crew is also here. Punk and Skrape are in the building. Now J.J., what led to this project that is redefining Mixed Martial Arts here in the States?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.J. RILEY</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mixed Martial Arts is a sport that I've always been incredibly passionate about. As for where the idea for Sparta came from, I've always kind of dug the Grand Prix format, so I tracked these guys down to help me out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PUNKASS</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When J.J. came to us he said he wanted to create the Super Bowl of Mixed Martial Arts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKRAPE</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he decided to put up the five million dollar purse, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JON ANIK</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context>As Fenroy watches them talk about the upcoming Sparta tournament, Tommy walks into the gym, surveys the room with curiosity, and approaches the front desk.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there you have it. It shall be done. Hedge fund king J.J. Riley, going from the lion's den of Wall Street to the cage, promoting the biggest winner-take-all tournament in MMA history. Sparta.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fitzy still own this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FENROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fenroy goes back to his computer. Tommy stands there. Notices a Sparta POSTER on the wall reading: "THE WAR ON THE SHORE.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know no Fitzy. Colt Boyd owns this gym.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FENROY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you with something?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it work here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FENROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You wanna join?</context>
      <utterance>Thirty five a month with locker. We're open at 7, lights out at 11.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fenroy grabs a pencil and an index card and puts them on the counter in front of Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FENROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your name and contact info on the card.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa whoa! There's a lesson in this too, OK? Listen up. So we have a body at rest, and you have the bat which needs--</utterance>
   <speaker>TITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acceleration.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan, sleeves rolled up and a bemused look on his face, watches as Tito brings the bat down on the wood. As it CRACKS in half, the other students cheer wildly. Tito smiles and leans the bat against a blackboard with "NEWTON'S 2nd LAW OF MOTION" printed on it.</context>
      <utterance>Acceleration, right. If you have enough acceleration, you have might have a chance to break the body at rest. OK. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Tito high-fives his way back through the group, things settle down and the kids take their seats.</context>
      <utterance>There we go. Alright Tito, well done. Remind not to mess with you. Sit down everybody. Dial it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A room full of affirmatives, with the cocky voice of NASH, a skinny white kid in a Flyers jersey, standing out.</context>
      <utterance>So, have we got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Force equals mass times acceleration. We got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A black student, STEPHON, looks up from his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. The third law--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STEPHON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many laws this dude got?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHING</mode>
      <context>Brendan looks toward the classroom door, where two red-and- white clad CHEERLEADERS are peering in, then walks over to KC, a blonde cheerleader seated in his class. She is working a Blackberry and doesn't notice him approaching.</context>
      <utterance>The dude? The dude has three. Newton the dude says that for every action, there's an equal and opposite reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brendan stands directly in front of her desk. She quickly shoves the Blackberry under a stack of books.</context>
      <utterance>For example, if KC does not stop the action of sending texts in class...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns and shoos away the two cheerleaders peering in the window.</context>
      <utterance>...and tell her posse outside to beat it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...then my reaction might be to send her down to Principal Zito's office. Thus setting our world back in proper balance.</utterance>
   <speaker>KC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class busts on KC as Brendan walks back to his desk and sits on top of it. It's clear from the vibe in the room that he's a very popular teacher. Then the BELL rings.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. C, I put it away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, before you go, I have your tests from last week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAD DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colt climbs into the ring and looks at the fallen fighter. Glances at Mad Dog.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you find these girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a tournament coming up. You gonna kill every guy in the `Burgh?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode>TO FENROY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fenroy. Get me some ice. And call that Puerto Rican kid, the one that fights outa the Bottoms. If he's here in 20 minutes, he gets 200 bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colt turns around and looks at Tommy. As does Mad Dog, who smiles down at him from inside the ring.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, I'll fight him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy walks back to his bag. Mad Dog smiles. Looks at Tommy's outfit.</context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor guy, go back to your bag. We don't need anybody else getting hurt. G'head. Take a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAD DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy stops. Walks back to the ring as Fenroy approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Yo Rock, what happened? You leave Mick and Paulie at home today?</utterance>
   <speaker>FENROY</speaker>
      <mode>TO COLT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His phone's disconnected.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then go through the list. Get me Joe Bones.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>TO COLT</mode>
      <context>Colt looks at Mad Dog. What do you think? The Mohawked fighter looks at Tommy. Shrugs. It's his funeral.</context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is if you need somebody to help you, I'm happy to keep your boy warm for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever fought before?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colt studies Tommy. Sees he's serious. Gives in.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode>TO FENROY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy sign a waiver?</utterance>
   <speaker>FENROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All good.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get tuned up in here, it's on you, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colt Boyd waves Tommy into the ring. Mad Dog's entourage starts whispering amongst themselves. Snickering at what lays in wait for Tommy as the fallen sparring partner is helped out of the ring. A TRAINER tapes Tommy's hands and gives him some MMA gloves. He slips them on, then at the sound of a BUZZER he starts moving toward Mad Dog, who smirks at Tommy's aggression and then starts circling him. Tommy nails him with a front kick to the chest. Grimes staggers back and shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAD DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crouches down, gets serious. He throws a right. Blocked. A leg kick. Blocked. Tommy snaps his head with a jab. Then he does it again. And again. Then he DECKS HIM with a hard right, sending Mad Dog to the canvas to the shock of his entourage and Colt Boyd. Fenroy looks up from his post and walks over to the ring. Within moments everyone in the gym stops what they're doing and watches as Tommy grabs the back of Mad Dog's head, hauls it down, and launches knee after knee into his face. Tommy starts throwing Mad Dog around like a rag doll, striking him with vicious punches and kicks, as Fenroy pulls out his CELL PHONE and starts filming the action. As Colt Boyd screams at Mad Dog to cover up, Tommy shoves him against the ropes and blasts away. Tommy continues to pound. It's a full-fledged beating going on in there. Finally, he crushes Mad Dog with a vicious left hook and sends him sprawling through the ropes, UNCONSCIOUS. SILENCE in the gym. What the hell just happened here? The entourage rushes to Mad Dog's aid, but he's out cold. Colt Boyd looks on in disbelief as Tommy walks across the ring and approaches him.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna be a hero? Alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me two hundred bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the new appraisal figure, and this is how it effects the monthly. As you can see, that puts you upside down on your mortgage. That's the problem. It's the country that did the assessment, not the bank. So, the numbers are what they are, Mr. Conlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The numbers are what they are, Brendan. I mean, you're a Math teacher, you can appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I teach Physics.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Physics. OK. But the bank has got to go by the new appraisal figures. According to these figures, you're upside down on your mortgage--</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said that three times already. I get that. But I'm asking you if there's something else you can do. Not the bank, you. Can you shift things around, restructure--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you've already refinanced twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you advised us to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It was your choice.</context>
      <utterance>I presented you with that option.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm also showing you netted a substantial payout with the refi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor looks at Brendan. Takes him a second to remember.</context>
      <utterance>We had that conversation. I was paying medical bills. Is that in your file?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. Sorry. Your daughter's...kidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heart, right.  Lot of stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>16.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan glares at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So my option is I've got no options? You're not even gonna try to help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am trying, Brendan. Look, I can get you 90 days to get even--</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>90 days is not enough. My wife and I have three jobs between us and that doesn't cut it. So, what do you suggest?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you a question: have you considered bankruptcy? It's a viable option. There's no shame in it these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not how I do things.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then you're looking at foreclosure. Brendan gets up and storms out of the office.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER #1</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Utter domination by Tommy Conlon, the undefeated freshman from Pittsburgh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER #2</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy trained by his father since the age of five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER #1</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking about Paddy Conlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER #2</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The controversial Paddy Conlon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER #2</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Paddy watches, the DOORBELL RINGS. He makes his way to the door as the tape continues to play.</context>
      <utterance>There's just no limit to what the future holds for this kid!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER #1</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Paddy opens the door to find Colt Boyd standing on the stoop.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy told me that he's chasing the record of Theogenes, apparently a mythical Greek fighter said to be unbeaten in over 1400 bouts...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy registers the name "Riordan."</context>
      <utterance>How you doin,' sir? I'm looking for Tommy Riordan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Riordan? My name's Colt Boyd.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What business you got with Tommy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colt looks at Paddy. Jams his hands in his pockets. He's obviously waiting for an invite inside. It doesn't come.</context>
      <utterance>None yet. That's why I'm here. I manage fighters.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy's been working out at my gym. He put a beating on the number one middleweight contender in the world today. I want to know more about the guy. Maybe help him out. I have a lot of contacts, Mr. Riordan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Conlon. Name's Conlon. And anything you want to know about Tommy, you gotta ask him yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just looking for some general information here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, anything you want to know about Tommy, you gotta ask him yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't mean to interrupt your night. He put this address down when he signed up at the gym.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy closes the door on a frustrated Colt.</context>
      <utterance>He doesn't live here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen kiddo, I need you put Mommy back on, OK? I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'm just pulling in. Huh? Oh, they've got this open mic night thing. Should be a quiet one. Sleep well. You too. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some hollers from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>It's time for our next contest! Introducing first, fighting out of the red corner, from Ripley, West Virginia, please welcome Mike "The Mutilator" Moore!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And in the blue corner. He fights out of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Please welcome "Irish" Brendan Conlon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan reaches out to touch gloves with Mike Moore, but his opponent snubs him and storms back to his corner. He means business. Brendan, looking less sure of himself, retreats to his corner.</context>
      <utterance>Fighters to the center! I want you to obey my commands at all times. If you have no questions, touch gloves, back up, and wait for my signal. Come out fighting!</utterance>
   <speaker>REFEREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The bikers raise hell as the BELL sounds. Moore comes out bombing. Brendan dodges a couple of wild haymakers, then gets caught in the side of the head with a right hand. He stumbles back into the ropes and Moore presses into him, swatting at him with his huge hands. Brendan absorbs the blows, ducks down, grabs Moore by the legs, lifts him, and dumps him on the mat with a resounding THUD. Obviously bull strong and with tremendous punching skills, Brendan sits on his opponent's chest and starts raining down shots, banging and banging, pulverizing his face and body. It's a full on ass-whooping going on in there until finally, mercifully, the referee stops the butchery amidst a mixture of CHEERS from the crowd and BOOS from the bikers. A winded Brendan walks to his corner, touches the side of his head, wipes a small amount of blood on his shorts, and climbs out of the ring, where a PROMOTER approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Fighters, are you ready? Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROMOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice fight. Two more wins and you take home the bacon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>SLEEPY</mode>
      <context>Brendan doesn't answer. Tess slowly wakes up. As she does, she gets a look at his face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey babe. How was work?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess studies his face. Brendan looks at her. Reaches into his pocket and hands her $500 in cash.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. What happened? You said it was going to be a slow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not bouncing at a club.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. Looks at the money. Puts it together.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean you're not bouncing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been lying to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess can't believe what she's hearing.</context>
      <utterance>I went in to apply. They were only paying nine bucks an hour. Then I saw a sign for this other thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're putting us out of the house in three months, we're running out</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna start fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't play babe in the woods with me. I know that guy from the gym came to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colt Boyd? I didn't tell him anything, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We wouldn't be sitting here now if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>23.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy grabs a fry off Paddy's plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paddy tries to tether it down, but he's happy. Tommy looks at him sternly.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Look. There's this tournament. A big tournament. Top sixteen middleweights in the world. Single elimination. Winner take all for a lot of money. I'm gonna do that. But if I'm doin' it, then I'm gonna need a trainer. Now that much you were good at.  No, no, no. This doesn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. We train. That's it. I don't wanna hear a word about anything but training, you understand? You wanna tell your war stories, you can take `em down to the VFW. You can take `em to a meeting, or church, or wherever the hell it is you go nowadays.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Colt Boyd?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him? I told him I don't train with people I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the devil you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The devil you know is better than the devil you don't. Tommy looks at him. Grins for the first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chasing Theogenes. It'll be kinda like old times.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>ANGRY</mode>
      <context>Paddy calmly sips his coffee, then leans in on Tommy with a stern look. The old lion's got a few teeth left.</context>
      <utterance>I just told you, this doesn't mean anything. You get that through your skull right now or I'm walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy gives him a hard look, but the old man doesn't shy away.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Alright. But you get something through your skull, too. You called me. So don't go threatening to walk every five minutes. And since this is about training, you dump whatever it is you need to dump as far as those pills are concerned. I don't want to see `em.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, hand `em over right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Tommy considers, then reaches into his pocket and slides two bottles across the table.</context>
      <utterance>I know they're on you, Tommy. You sounded like a goddamn maraca coming through the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>SHAKING BOTTLES</mode>
      <context>Tommy looks at him. Fishes another bottle out of his pocket and flips it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>When you came through that door it was chhh-chhh-chhh.  Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And another thing, you don't eat crap like this. This is for losers and old men.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're gonna have to bunk up. If we're gonna do this right, you gotta stay at the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The two men stare at each other. Tommy looks furious, but he doesn't get up. A silent, tenuous agreement is reached.</context>
      <utterance>I watch your diet, we follow the old regimen. You copy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother said he was at the strip club and saw Mr. C fighting MMA---</utterance>
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's MMA?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mixed Martial Arts. Like, different styles of fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>KC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan enters the room. The kids look at him. Holy shit. It's true.</context>
      <utterance>Your brother's a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan puts his bag down on his desk and faces the class. He is not amused by the murmuring in there.</context>
      <utterance>Take your seats.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The kids pipe down. Then Tito speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Now, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Mr. C. My brother was at the titty bar last night and said you was choking brothers out. What's up? Is it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Mr. C. I mean, did you really work on some fools or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>KC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Brendan can answer, he sees PRINCIPAL JOE ZITO (50s) gesturing to him through the window of the classroom. Zito taps his watch and points. Come see me after class.</context>
      <utterance>You have to tell us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, it's not as bad as it looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you being literal or figurative? Because literally it looks bad. And figuratively it looks even worse. The superintendent's coming by in a few minutes. So gimme a little help here, Brendan. Can you explain to me what the hell you were doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need the money, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zito stands up and runs his hands across his head.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but we can't have this. This isn't moonlighting at Applebee's for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Brendan. Leaving everything else aside, which we can't, are you out of your mind? You're gonna get yourself killed. I mean, you're a goddamn teacher.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got no business in the ring with those animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zito looks at Brendan. Puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I used to be one of those animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fought for a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I forgot to put that down on my application.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zito sits back down.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry, Joe. It's just--</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, the school district's not going to tolerate school teachers cockfighting in strip clubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the parking lot of a strip club.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zito sees the SUPERINTENDENT enter the foyer outside his office. He's looking none too pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Wherever it was, you can't be doing it, alright? I mean this is a serious--shit, he's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a serious problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy hasn't been inside a school since 9-11.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say yes, sir. And you say no, sir. And you say it'll never happen again, sir. And then we just pray to God he's in a good mood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UFC?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan nods. Joe shakes his head. Impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sonofabitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF PIANO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girls have an important piano recital in the morning. Got an equipment malfunction.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna review your case at the end of the semester, but until then you're suspended without pay. Joe gave me the number of his attorney.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess crouches down and enters the tiny room. She sits on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>How the hell are we gonna pay for an attorney?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talked to me for free. As a favor to Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said there's no precedent for this. You'll be back by next semester.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tess sighs. They sit in silence. There are no easy solutions. Finally, Brendan speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Next semester?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Tess. They have these smoker fights all over. There's one in Lancaster next week. There's two in Dover the week after. Wilmington. Camden. Baltimore. It could keep us afloat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna put yourself through this over and over, for five hundred bucks a pop?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of them pay a little more than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Brendan looks at his wife.</context>
      <utterance>I would have had to bounce for a month to make what I made in two hours last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess sits quietly. Knows they have limited options.</context>
      <utterance>And these guys, they're not real fighters. They're just guys who have seen too much UFC on TV. If you have a better solution, I'm all ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we gonna tell the girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. No choice. This is the plan.</context>
      <utterance>It'll be fine. I'll just leave the house as usual, except now I'll be going to the gym.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy says nothing. Not a nostalgic bone in his body. The dreams on that poster are long gone.</context>
      <utterance>Look what I found in that disaster of a basement. Whattya say we sit down and update this sometime? You can fill me in on how close you got to that record.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you continue wrestling after you left with your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Tommy. Tell me something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy's stung but covers it amiably.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'll tell ya something. You can take that thing back to where you found it. And you can leave the coffee in the pot. I can pour that myself. I can wake myself up, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. Hurt my knees coming up and down those stairs anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARINE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LANCE CORPORAL MARK BRADFORD (20s) walks up to see what the commotion is all about.</context>
      <utterance>Damn dude, that's brutal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mad Dog" Grimes gettin' tuned up by some dude in a gym in Pittsburgh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's "Mad Dog" Grimes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Bradford. The stuff you don't know amazes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE #2</speaker>
      <mode>OFF COMPUTER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god, did you see that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>AV, I need to see the tape!</utterance>
   <speaker>AV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AV drops his cards, rushes to his bunk, pulls out a steel container loaded with VIDEOTAPES and sifts through it. They are labeled by day and month. AV finds what he's looking for, loads it into the camera, and hits PLAY.</context>
      <utterance>The tape.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AV holds the "Pause" button down as Bradford looks at the screen in disbelief. It's definitely Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him. That's him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They embrace warmly.</context>
      <utterance>Do I know you? I think I know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long time, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liking the place, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm training him for Sparta.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, brother.  You see this beast? Marco Santos?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amazing, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two head for the offices at the back of the gym.</context>
      <utterance>Come on back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look good, brother. How're the girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Good. I had another little one. Rosie.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I should have called.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Johnny C. told me she was in the hospital for a bit. I was gonna call, but then time went by. I don't know. I'm a piece of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Brendan. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all good. She's good now. Frank looks at his old friend. Smiles warmly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's great to see you, man. So everything's going good?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank considers what he's hearing.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well, I've got a little problem. The guys at the bank want to take my house away. That's kind of why I came to see you, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got most of my dough tied up in this joint, but how much do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't come here for a loan, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you'd train me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Train you for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank starts smiling. Leans back in his seat. Then he sees Brendan is not smiling with him.</context>
      <utterance>I want to get back in the cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just won an event the other night.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, you won an event.  That's what this is. Let me guess, it was in a parking lot. DJ from the local radio station. Couple of ring card girls you wouldn't bang on a dare. Am I right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ish. Brendan. I love you. I do. But why would I train you? When you were in shape and on the right side of 30 you were barely a .500 fighter. You never listened to me. You never listened to anyone. These guys are animals. I mean, you're a teacher, right? What're you gonna do? You're gonna come down here for a couple days a week after detention? You're gonna skip out of the girl's volleyball game early?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got loads of time. Time's not an issue. The parking lot thing kinda got me suspended. I need to keep working the smokers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You remember that?</context>
      <utterance>Tess know about this?  Yeah? `Cause the last time you fought, I got read the riot act sitting in a hospital waiting room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two friends share a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>No. I was unconscious.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not gonna come down here with the two puppies, screaming at Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whattya say, Frank?</context>
      <utterance>It's not gonna happen. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I say? What am I gonna say to you? No? I mean, all my time is wrapped up with Marco. You come down, I'll throw you in the rotation, you spar with these guys, no problem. But I can't promise you much more than that, Brendan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan stands up. Shakes Frank's hand.</context>
      <utterance>That's all I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me know when you're coming down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>WALKING AWAY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm just gonna go get my stuff from the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan puts his dukes up and smiles as Frank shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Brendan. It's me, Pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have some news for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy shakes his head, unsure what he means.</context>
      <utterance>Something wrong with your hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's nothing wrong with your hands then there's no reason for you not to phone. That's the deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I forgot--</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy holds his hands out, palms down.</context>
      <utterance>Phone or mail, Pop. Non negotiable.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Brendan, have you ever seen my hands so steady? Have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a thousand days. A thousand days sober today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's great, Pop. But it doesn't change anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy's words set Brendan off. A side of him we haven't seen before emerges. He approaches his father fiercely.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean it doesn't change anything? Have a heart, Brendan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You listen to me. You take your have-a-heart bullshit and you run it down the road. Run it out on someone who doesn't know you like I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Brendan. I thought maybe we could break bread. Open some lines of communication.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got two lines of communication, the telephone and the post office. Just because you decide it's a special day, it doesn't make it one for me. I got a wife and kids inside and they're waiting for me, so I don't have time for whatever this is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you got a wife and kids in there. I got a grand-daughter I haven't seen in three years and another I haven't even ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy nods. Casts his eyes down in shame.</context>
      <utterance>Why is that, Pop? Why is that? Do you remember having anything to do with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brendan looks at the reformed Paddy, a measure of sympathy on his face. Then he heads for the house.</context>
      <utterance>That shit you pulled. Never again. And all the shit I saw growing up? That doesn't happen here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As he's halfway through the yard, Paddy calls out.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan stops in his tracks. He turns and looks at his Dad.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy's back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in the `Burgh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy's in Pittsburgh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came to see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan walks closer. Incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>He's over at the house. We're doing a little training at Fitzy's. Remember Fitzy's? It ain't Fitzy's anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Tommy are training together?</utterance>
   <speaker>39.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paddy nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Conlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Riordan. He's using your mother's maiden name now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what her name is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd want to know he's back. That's why I drove all the way over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you came to break bread over a thousand days?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan looks at him. Considers.</context>
      <utterance>That too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say if he wants to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't say much. He's just not that happy kid he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, look at you. Mister inside man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Tommy training together like nothing ever happened. This is unbelievable. Now I know what you're really doing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came to gloat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not come to gloat. I came to get my son back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there you go. You got your son back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about you, Bren--</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan starts to walk away, then turns around again.</context>
      <utterance>You got your son back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, part of the reason I stuck around was `cause I thought I'd finally get you all to myself. But you didn't have any interest in training me. Tommy was the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Brendan. I was a drunk. I mean, you know. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. You were always a front runner. You never had any interest in underdogs. But I was your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you are. I'm just asking you to find just a little space in your heart to forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Alright. I forgive you. But I do not trust you. Tell Tommy this is where I am if he wants to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. But they're not different things. You've gotta trust to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan keeps walking. Opens his door to step inside.</context>
      <utterance>My God, is that Emily? Boy, she's grown, Brendan. Is that Rosie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan closes the door, leaving the heartbroken Paddy alone in the yard.</context>
      <utterance>Just some nice old man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JON ANIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mad Dog Grimes trains furiously under the watchful eye of Colt Boyd. When Colt sees Tommy approaching, he turns his attention away from Mad Dog.</context>
      <utterance>Huge news breaking here at ESPN. Koba is coming to America and will fight at Sparta. Universally considered to be the greatest pound for pound fighter that ever lived, the mighty, mythical Russian has never fought on U.S. soil in his legendary career...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy? Got some news for ya. I got you into Sparta. Took some doing, but I made it happen..  Thank you and 10 percent is customary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bueno?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pilar. It's Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy! Dios mio! I can't believe it! How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good good. How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. You know me, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was getting really worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're things? Kids are good?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're good. Maria's getting so big. She looks more like Manny every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's little man?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's good. He's a good kid, Tommy. Takes care of his sister. He's a great kid. Everyone's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Pilar, I haven't forgotten for one minute what I promised you. What I promised Manny. I've got an opportunity coming up to help you guys out. To take care of you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you can do, Tommy. I know Manny would really appreciate it. You worry too much. It's OK. We're hanging in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JON ANIK</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., we've never seen this kind of Grand Prix tournament in the country before. Tell us, why the unique format?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.J. RILEY</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Jon, you know as well as anyone that in Mixed Martial Arts, anyone can beat anyone on a given night...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JON ANIK</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only five weeks left `til Sparta and the hype continues for the War on the Shore. Fourth of July weekend in Atlantic City and you know what that means: the great Koba, bringing his act stateside. Let me ask you about the other guys. What are they thinking entering a winner take all tournament against a guy that seemingly can't be beat?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASHOD EVANS</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context>Tess comes back down the stairs and looks at the screen, concern on her face.</context>
      <utterance>They're thinking five million dollars, and five million dollars is a lot of money, but they've gotta remember one thing: they're going against Koba. Mission impossible. Game over. Go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JON ANIK</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The `Pittsburgh Beatdown' has become one of the most watched videos on YouTube this year. Now joining us via satellite is the victim of the infamous incident, Mad Dog Grimes. Mad Dog, what is your response to all the hoopla surrounding the video and Tommy Riordan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAD DOG</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's a nobody. It was just a sparring session. It is what it is, and he's gonna pay for it next month in Atlantic City.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan turns Marco and gets him in a knee bar. Marco has nowhere to go and is forced to TAP. Frank jumps in the ring, all smiles, and slaps Brendan on the chest.</context>
      <utterance>You set the rhythm. Feel the Beethoven. Be smarter than him. More patient. Wait for him to make a mistake. And when he does, that's your moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No he did not tap you! Physics teacher! That's the best in the world there, son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna be OK? Wanna grab a bite?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank heads off through the lot. Brendan reaches his car, stops, considers. Calls out to Frank while jogging toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. I'm gonna head home. I gotta call the boys and break the news. I'll call you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan looks hopefully at Frank, who shakes his head as he begins to open the door of his `70 Ford Bronco.</context>
      <utterance>Coach! Hey, I know this isn't a great time. And it's too bad about Marco. But what about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talking about Sparta? Brendan, please. You got a better chance of starting a boy band. I'll talk to you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks at him. Sees how serious Brendan is.</context>
      <utterance>It's a grand prix tournament. Which means anything can happen. You know that as well as I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll have to kill me to get me out of that cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm afraid of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, I need this. You're real tight with those guys. You call them, they'll listen to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You realize what you're asking me to do here, Brendan? We go down to AC and you get tapped out in five seconds, how does that benefit either one of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not gonna happen. Wish I had a nickel for every time I heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>SMILING</mode>
      <context>Frank breaks. Smiles. How can he say no?</context>
      <utterance>It's not gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan grins and walks back toward his car.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love my coach!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the girls are good. They're good. Yeah, you should. You've been spending so much time with Brendan these days it's like you're part of the family or something. Yeah, he's right here.  It's your boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Brendan hangs up the phone. Looks at Tess.</context>
      <utterance>That's unbelievable. I can't thank you enough. I don't know what to say. Alright, listen, I've gotta call you back. Alright, bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A look of serious concern crosses Tess's face. She puts her hands on her hips.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in. I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan doesn't say anything. Knows she's right. And that he's about to get laid into.</context>
      <utterance>Really? So that's your decision? You decided? `Cause I really enjoyed that conversation we just had about making that decision together.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me you were gonna fight guys that watched too much UFC. I saw that Koba dude on TV, and he's the guy they're watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a lot of money, Tess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a shit about the money, Brendan. I told you that. We're gonna end up cashing in your life insurance policy before we pick up that prize money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you can get killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna get killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, you're not going to get killed. But can you promise me you're not going to get hurt? You're not gonna end up in the hospital? You're not gonna end up paralyzed? We'll have no prize money. No house. Payments for</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Tess, who has tears in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Tess, I can promise you this: if I don't try, they're gonna take the house. How's that for a promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess looks at her husband. Wants to support him, but can't.</context>
      <utterance>So, I'm gonna go, OK? But I'd really love it if you'd be with me on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna watch you fight again. I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Tess starts walking back toward the house. She marches up the lawn without turning back, leaving Brendan, alone, in front of his house. He looks at the toys strewn across the yard. Surveys the neighborhood. He's going to Sparta.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get the girls breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourth of July weekend doesn't officially start until tomorrow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., you've made a fortune with your hedge funds, yet you turned your back on Wall Street and dedicated your life to making Sparta happen. Tell us, why is this tournament so important to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.J. RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Growing up, we all wanted to know who the toughest kid in the neighborhood was, right? I wanna know who the toughest man on the planet is. That's why I put this together, that's what all these people are here to see, and come Saturday night, that's what we're gonna find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The great and mighty KOBA emerges from a white stretch limo, trailed by his ENTOURAGE of tough-looking RUSSIANS. FLASHBULBS pop. REPORTERS swarm. It looks like a movie premiere out there and Koba's the star.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, J.J. And here's something fans never thought they'd see: Koba is here! The legend arriving to fight on U.S. soil for the very first time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MICHELLE MOONEY</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paddy stares at the screen intently.</context>
      <utterance>Lance Corporal Mark Bradford's web testimony to Riordan, who saved his life earlier this year in Iraq, is spreading like wildfire throughout the media.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy walks into the room from the door of an adjoining suite and stares at the TV.</context>
      <utterance>We were all drowning, man. It was a death trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADFORD</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paddy is dumbfounded and looks at Tommy, who glances at him and back at the TV before heading toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't have had more than another minute. Suddenly the back ramp gets ripped off, and there he was. Before I could get out and thank him, he was gone. He just vanished like a ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm takin' a walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How's it going?</context>
      <utterance>Been looking all over for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking maybe we could grab a coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't drink coffee. Whattya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to go sit down somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm good right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Tommy. How was I supposed to know I was never gonna see you guys again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were briefed. You had the information. You chose the old man and the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan reaches into his pocket and removes a recent Christmas PHOTO of Tess, Emily, and Rosie from his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't some girl. I married her. She's my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy glances at the photo impasssively and hands it back.</context>
      <utterance>That's Tess. And that's Emily and Rosie. They're your nieces, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know `em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you don't know them. Of course you don't know them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why am I looking at pictures of people I don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that's my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who are you exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your brother, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were in the Corps?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I didn't know you were in the Corps.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't in the Corps.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Tommy walks briskly away from Brendan and up the beach. His brother runs after him.</context>
      <utterance>Then you ain't no brother to me. My brother was in the Corps.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Tommy. I was a 16 year old kid. What the hell did I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you know. Why don't you go ask your girlfriend about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Tommy. He's a wall.</context>
      <utterance>She's my wife, Tommy. So that's it? I stay with Tess and I never get to see you guys again? Not a single phone call? Nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, man, I don't understand this. You won't forgive me, but you'll forgive Pop?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. He's just some old vet I train with. He means nothing to me. From what I hear he means nothing to you, either, so you got balls talking about forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy smirks. Walks away again.</context>
      <utterance>That's got nothing to do with forgiveness. I've got a family to protect. Everything I do is for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I forgave Pop. Just like I forgave you and Mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>TURNING AROUND</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forgave us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not surprised you made the tournament, Brendan. You got some stones.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fell in love, Tommy. What the hell was I supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words hit Brendan hard.</context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to stick to the plan. You were supposed to come with us. Mom needed you. I needed you. You were my big brother and you bailed on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm glad you stayed and everything worked out for you, Brendan. See, you leave, you get the opposite. You leave, you get to bury people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not the only one who suffered, Tommy. I didn't even know she was sick. I never even got the chance to say goodbye to my own mother. You had no right to keep that from me! That was not your decision to make!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy and Brendan are right in each other's faces. Standing on the knife's edge of violence. They hold the stare down for a few long seconds, like two fighters about to go to war.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? You walk around with your pictures in your wallet and you're all, I forgive you, I forgive Pop. I forgive everyone. But you know what? You're full of shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All four of them laugh nervously. Working their way up to something.</context>
      <utterance>You realize you're supposed to seek my wise counsel when school's actually in session, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want to use the auditorium this weekend to watch Mr. C in Sparta.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get this straight. You want to use the auditorium to watch a suspended teacher engage in the activity he was suspended for? Am I hearing this correctly?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta talk to your parents. You guys might need to be in summer school after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But everyone wants to see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The gym's the only place that's big enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's never gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we get a petition?</utterance>
   <speaker>TITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We'll get the whole school to sign it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The power of democracy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zito turns and heads back to his desk. The kids, dejected, leave the office and walk off down the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I appreciate that you guys love your teacher. I really do. But there is nothing I can do for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, I'm Bryan Callen along with best-selling fight author Sam Sheridan. Sam, when J.J. Riley conceived Sparta he wanted to create, quite simply, the biggest Mixed Martial Arts spectacle in history.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five million dollars, Bryan. Five million dollars. J.J. Riley put his money where his mouth is and put up the biggest purse this sport has ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's unprecedented, Sam. As is the hoopla surrounding Tommy Riordan, the war hero who has become an overnight sensation...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Riordan's captured the media's attention, but the question still remains: who is this guy? And more importantly, can he compete in this talent pool? Can he win?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tommy continues to storm toward the cage with a furious and focused look on his face. He seems to want nothing to do with Paddy. Training is over. It's time to fight.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I knew, Bryan. I wish I knew who he was, and I've gotta say the fact that I don't know is strange. In an internet age where there are no secrets, this guy is a complete mystery. I can't find out anything about him. Tommy Riordan is officially Google proof.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta love this guy, Sam. No walk out music, no sponsors, no interviews. He skipped out on the press conference. Wouldn't have his picture take for the program. He's breaking every rule!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only reason that Tommy is even in this tournament is because of a video showing him beating up Mad Dog Grimes in the gym.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the reason a lot of his fans are in the stands is because of another video, which is even more stunning than the Mad Dog Grimes video. Let me describe it for you folks for the few who haven't seen it, and I don't know anyone who hasn't, but Tommy Riordan ripped the door off a tank in the heat of battle, saving lives in the process, and then walked away without claiming a medal. He ripped the door off a tank!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tommy stands outside the cage and has Vaseline applied to his face. He looks like he's ready to murder someone.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy Riordan is a genuine war hero, I'm not taking anything away from the guy. He's a very, very tough guy, Bryan, but the tank don't hit back. We've seen YouTube sensations fail on the big stage before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam. He ripped the door off a tank!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Riordan definitely has his hands full in his first opponent, Francisco Barbosa. Barbosa is nothing to scoff at.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's the real deal. Very tough guy. Very high caliber fighter. Tommy Riordan came out of nowhere, and I imagine he's going to disappear just as quickly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the crowd, two sections of MARINES in full dress uniforms wave flags and raise about as much hell as humanly possible for Tommy, who returns to his corner. Paddy attempts to give him some advice, but Tommy is not listening.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, you've been given your instructions. I expect a clean fight. Obey my commands at all times. Defend yourselves at all times. Touch gloves, go back, let's do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The bell rings. DING! And Tommy comes out fast and hard.</context>
      <utterance>We're about to get the big answer to the big question: is Tommy Riordan for real? And here we go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barbosa's gonna be looking for a take down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There will not be a take down. Tommy ducks a blow, then levels Barbosa with a massive and brutal LEFT HOOK. The Brazilian's head snaps sideways, his MOUTHPIECE goes flying, and he does a face plant on to the canvas. It's over.</context>
      <utterance>Definitely gonna be looking for a take down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the crowd erupts and Josh Rosenthal waves to Barbosa's corner to get a medic in there, Tommy marches out of the cage without waiting for an official announcement.</context>
      <utterance>Barbosa is down! Barbosa has been knocked out! Tommy Riordan is most definitely for real!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the TV monitor, Tommy's annihilating knockout of Francisco Barbosa plays. Then, in the distance, the strains of CLASSICAL MUSIC can be heard. Brendan looks at Frank, who smiles and puts his hands on Brendan's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Show time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the nervous Brendan's head between his hands.</context>
      <utterance>You can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to hear you say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's go do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan and Frank walk down the tunnel toward the arena, where Paddy is waiting, his All Access pass around his neck. Brendan notices the old man as he approaches.</context>
      <utterance>And he chose Brendan Conlon, which quite frankly is something I just don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan barely acknowledges Paddy and keeps walking. Frank looks at Brendan with a "Who the hell is that?" expression. As they approach the dark lights of the arena, Beethoven continues to BOOM out over the loud speakers.</context>
      <utterance>Go get `em, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can understand coming out to no music, by why in the world would you choose classical music for your entrance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Beethoven, Bryan. This is Ode to Joy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My apologies, Mr. Renaissance man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan and Frank make their way through the crowd and toward cageside, where Bryan Callen reaches beneath his seat.</context>
      <utterance>You want to talk about renaissance men, you gotta talk about Frank Campana. Very unorthodox trainer, and one of the best in the game. He's well known for using classical music to train his fighters to remain calm, to remain patient, and to remain composed under pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Callen holds up a plastic bag with water and a GOLDFISH inside.</context>
      <utterance>Classical music is about as fitting to this setting as Brendan Conlon is to this tournament. In fact, let me show you something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brendan gets greased up, then climbs into the cage.</context>
      <utterance>This is Brendan Conlon. He's a feeder fish, and he's about to get dropped into a shark tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was in the UFC. We remember him.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, give the guy a break. At least we've seen him fight before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember him, too. I remember him being very unmemorable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midnight Le getting ready to climb into the cage and go to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan stands in the corner and looks at the massive Midnight Le. Frank smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>When the brackets were announced, Midnight thought he'd be going up against Marco Santos. He's gotta be thrilled to be seeing Brendan Conlon standing across from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan grins and looks out at the rabid crowd.</context>
      <utterance>You asked for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan retired from fighting some years ago, he's actually a high school Physics teacher now, and Midnight had some fun with that at the press conference.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Josh Rosenthal waves the two fighters into the center of the cage for instructions.</context>
      <utterance>He said he was gonna give the teacher a serious lesson, and that getting killed was no way to spend a summer vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fighters head to their corners and wait for the bell.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, gentleman, you've been given your instructions, I expect a clean fight. Obey my commands at all times. Defend yourselves at all times. Touch gloves, go back, let's do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the sound of the bell, "Midnight" Le comes out hard and strong. He repeatedly KICKS Brendan in the leg and batters him with STRIKES. His power is overwhelming Brendan.</context>
      <utterance>Have some fun, baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midnight is all over Brendan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Zito leans forward. He looks as if he's going to have a heart attack.</context>
      <utterance>This can't last much longer. This won't last much longer. The teacher just has no answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Brendan, get outta there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan tries to pry Midnight's hands off him. No use.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of there! Get out of there!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now he's got the hooks in. 20 seconds left.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Midnight squeezes for all it's worth as Frank screams at Brendan, imploring him not to tap.</context>
      <utterance>The end is near. Can he make it to the end of the round is the question.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan is on the verge of going unconscious, but he refuses to tap out. Then the HORN blows ending the round. The crowd can't believe Brendan hung in there, and neither can Midnight Le, who slams the canvas in frustration. As Midnight walks back toward his angry TRAINER, who expected him to finish Brendan early, the teacher heads toward a smiling Frank.</context>
      <utterance>10 seconds left, and Brendan's face is turning purple. Conlon's whole world is about to go from day to night.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan grins at Frank's positive spin on things, then looks across the cage at Midnight Le, who glares at Brendan.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful! Beautiful! He doesn't know what hit him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a Kimura locked in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midnight is in big trouble!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think he's got anywhere to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Midnight TAPS and the crowd EXPLODES. Shock and mayhem throughout the arena.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't happening! This can't happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just did, Bryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan Conlon tapped Midnight! I can't believe it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what makes Mixed Martial Arts so great. There's so many ways to lose. One tiny miscalculation at any time and that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank Campana embracing his man, Brendan Conlon. I don't think either one of them can believe what just happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great show of sportsmanship from the teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a hallmark of Frank Campana's philosophy right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midnight Le is shocked. He thought he had a free pass into the second round, but instead he's going home. He dominated the fight the entire way, but fell prey to a very technical finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A jubilant Brendan raises his arms in victory. The crowd responds to the gutsy underdog.</context>
      <utterance>Very technical finish, but come on, that's a fluke.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call it a fluke. I call it a guy maintaining composure and waiting for his opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the celebration continues, Callen looks at Sheridan and shakes his head. Was he ever wrong.</context>
      <utterance>Conlon beats Midnight!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you got a receipt for your goldfish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Once again, Koba does not break a sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid he might have broken something else, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Koba moving on to tomorrow night.</context>
      <utterance>It's certainly possible, Bryan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here comes the underdog, Brendan Conlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Paddy stands amidst the crowd in the tunnel and gives Brendan a thumbs-up.</context>
      <utterance>The teacher miraculously passed his first test, but now he's gotta face The Dane.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan glares at him and marches toward the cage.</context>
      <utterance>You can do it, Brendan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Halfway through round three now and the beating continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I honestly don't know how Brendan Conlon is still standing, Sam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it one time, it's a fluke, do it twice, that's something else!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull the bandwagon over, I think I'm hopping on! I think I'm a believer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to go, Brendan!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd doing this!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bell RINGS and Tommy goes right after Santana and starts administering a beating. He bullies him into the cage and starts raining BLOWS all over him.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, you ready? You ready? Let's go to war!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tommy is all over Diego Santana!</context>
      <utterance>Here he comes again like a buzzsaw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tommy marches past Paddy again, then off through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>There he goes again! Storming right out of the cage!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The arena is on its collective feet CHANTING "Tommy! Tommy! Tommy!" As Paddy looks on and Tommy disappears into the darkness of the tunnel, the sound of cheering fades.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy Riordan marching through the crowd, and straight into the final four!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy feeds the machine and pulls. Says nothing. Paddy sits down in front of a slot machine next to Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>Can't sleep, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that other thing's bothering the hell out of you, but I'm proud of you. What you did for that kid in the tank? That was really something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about deserting my unit? Is that really something, too? Yeah. I was on my way outta country when I came across those guys. What was I supposed to do, let `em drown?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy starts putting things together.</context>
      <utterance>What'd I do? I took off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>That's why you go by Riordan. That's why the press can't find your service records.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened over there, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is none of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, kiddo. I've been there. I've done it. I've seen it. You can trust me. I'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spare me the compassionate father routine, Pop. The suit don't fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really trying here, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paddy's shaken. He can't fathom the anger in Tommy, yet he knows he's responsible. It's written all over him. Tears well up in his eyes. They seem to make Tommy madder.</context>
      <utterance>You're trying? Now? Where were you when it mattered? I needed this guy back when I was a kid. I don't need you now. It's too late now. Everything's already happened. You and Brendan don't seem to understand that. Let me explain something to you: the only thing I have in common with Brendan Conlon is that we have absolutely no use for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy reaches down and picks up a plastic CUP made for holding coins and dips it into his tray, filling it with</context>
      <utterance>Look at you. Yeah, I was right. I think I liked you better when you were a drunk. At least you had some balls then. Not like now. Tip toeing around like some beggar with your cup out. Take it somewhere else, old man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back to the room and listen to some more fish stories no one gives a shit about. Go on, get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Tommy whips the bucket toward his father, splashing COINS into his face. A stunned Paddy, tears streaming down his face, walks off. A handful of late-night GAMBLERS look at Tommy, who stares angrily ahead and bounces a quarter off his slot machine as his destroyed father limps away.</context>
      <utterance>Get the fuck outta here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He staggers around the room, giving a fragmented soliloquy to no audience.</context>
      <utterance>God pity `em! All shall perish except me! You bastards! Stop the ship, you bastards!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly the adjoining door swings open. Tommy, hair disheveled, looks in and sees Paddy's state. The old man thrusts his hand up in the air and screams at Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>Ishmael! God pity `em! Stop the ship! Please stop the ship! Somebody help `em!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paddy staggers over and gets in Tommy's face, his own face blotched and contorted. The old Paddy Conlon revealed. The monster from the past.</context>
      <utterance>Ahab! You Godless sonofabitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stop the ship, you Godless sonofabitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The old man is running out of steam. He begins WEEPING.</context>
      <utterance>Captain. Oh captain. Stop the ship. For the love of God. We're lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paddy wobbles, tears streaming down his face. Tommy looks at him. The first time we've seen anything resembling compassion on that relentless face of his. He HUGS his father and pries the whiskey bottle from his hand</context>
      <utterance>Please stop the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy pulls his father back on to the bed. Puts his arms around his chest and tries to quiet the old man. It's a tender moment, and it seems as if Tommy is only able to relate to the brutal, former version of the father he knew.</context>
      <utterance>We're lost. We're all lost, Tommy. We'll never make it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - MUMBLING</mode>
      <context>Tommy continues to hold his father as sunlight streams into the room. The end of a very long night.</context>
      <utterance>I always loved you. You know that, don't you Tommy? I always loved you. You and your brother. My two boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once again, no walk out music.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't say no walk out music, Sam. Listen to this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mad Dog Grimes has been looking for revenge ever since the day Tommy Riordan walked into his gym in Pittsburgh and turned his life upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a very long, very miserable few months for Mad Dog to say the least.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Marines hoot and holler at Mad Dog as Josh Rosenthal goes over his instructions with the two fighters.</context>
      <utterance>Mad Dog mocking Tommy with a camouflage motif for his mohawk tonight and the Marines are really letting Mad Dog have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the center of the cage, Mad Dog is practically spitting in Tommy's face. Tommy's eyelids droop. He could not be less intimidated.</context>
      <utterance>Alright gentlemen, you've been given your instructions. I expect a clean fight. Obey my commands at all times. Defend yourselves at all times. Touch gloves, go back, let's do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAD DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Callen and Sheridan look on as the two fighters retreat to their corners. The anticipation in the arena is incredible.</context>
      <utterance>It's not gonna happen again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mad Dog predicted an early knockout. Said he was gonna knock Tommy out with one punch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Josh Rosenthal looks at Tommy and Mad Dog.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see what Tommy has to say about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's go to war!</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, you ready? You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tommy goes after Mad Dog like it's the last night on earth. What Tommy did to him at Colt's Gym was an exercise in restraint compared to what's happening in that cage.</context>
      <utterance>And they are off!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He's raining blows!</context>
      <utterance>Tommy tackles him and he's on top!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mad Dog is on his back and being pounded on. Tommy's rage is shocking, even by his own brutal standards. From cageside, Colt Boyd SCREAMS at Josh Rosenthal.</context>
      <utterance>Someone has to stop this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLT BOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's such a savage beating, so malicious, that Rosenthal has to climb on Tommy's back to get him off of Mad Dog. If his mother is indeed in the crowd, she couldn't recognize him now. Beaten to an absolute pulp.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Stop the fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the fastest knockout I think I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He is not moving.</context>
      <utterance>Mad Dog Grimes has been poleaxed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan Conlon came into this tournament as a 1000 to 1 underdog, and now here he is in the final four. The crowd's showing their appreciation. They're giving him quite the reception.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan stands in the corner. Frank leans over the railing of the cage and smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>He's getting a huge reception. I mean, this guy shocked everybody last night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzzing in the arena. The lights about to go down for the entrance of Koba. Before they do, Brendan looks up to see a familiar face at cageside. Tess. He can't believe his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You've got a visitor. Second row, 10 o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brendan looks at his wife. She smiles broadly. Mouths the words "I love you." Brendan grins. Kisses his glove and presses it against the cage. As he does, the lights go out inside the arena and ominous RUSSIAN MUSIC BLARES.</context>
      <utterance>You alright with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here comes the great Russian Koba.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The crowd strains to get a look at the legend as he makes his way toward the cage. Brendan watches. So does Frank. Tess takes a quick glance at Koba, then looks away. She can't bear it.</context>
      <utterance>Koba is so intimidating. His reputation is larger than life.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan nods, then looks at Tess. Drawing strength. Frank leans over the railing and taps fists with his fighter.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to look right at him when he comes in here. Don't take your eyes off him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Finally, the creepy music subsides, and the great Russian climbs into the cage. He's massive, and the crowd stares at him like an exotic animal. Josh Rosenthal calls Brendan and Koba to the center of the cage. The Russian looks at Brendan with the cold, dispassionate eyes of a killer. Brendan does his best to hold his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>I'm proud of you brother. This is your cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, gentlemen, you've been given your instructions. I expect a clean fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brendan retreats to his corner. Takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Obey my commands at all times. Defend yourselves at all times. Touch gloves, go back, let's do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I be nervous for Brendan? `Cause I am. I want to stop the fight before it even begins.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koba comes straight at Brendan. His speed and strength are astonishing.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, you ready? You ready? Let's go to war!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Franks screams at Brendan to keep his distance. Tess watches through her fingers. And Koba keeps coming, snapping Brendan's head back with a jab and bludgeoning him with an uppercut to the chin. The Russian is doing whatever he wants to Brendan. He slices him up with strikes. Bruises his legs with kicks. Works him against the fence. Power slams him.</context>
      <utterance>Now the question is, how long can Brendan Conlon stay alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Koba just pounding on Brendan Conlon! He's pounding on him like a side of beef!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank Campana has to think seriously about stopping this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The minutes passes in no time. It's time to go again.</context>
      <utterance>Seriously, Sam. How much abuse can one man take?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koba comes right after Brendan, and it's soon more of the same. Power slams. Brutal strikes. Brendan's face is carved up and battered. He tries to go for a take down, but Koba snuffs it, then lifts Brendan off the mat again and carries him through the air. Frank screams, but there's nothing he can do. Brendan is brutally SLAMMED into the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to war!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh oh, Brendan's going for ride!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Brendan writhes on the ground, Koba grabs him and slings him against the fence like it's nothing. Brendan flies through the air and RATTLES against the cage. Then Koba climbs on top of him and starts whaling away. Tess can't even watch it. Once again, just as Rosenthal is about to stop the fight, the HORN sounds.</context>
      <utterance>That one shook the entire building!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone has gotta be concerned about Brendan Conlon's bravery getting him into trouble here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan drags himself off the ground and limps to his stool. Frank enters the cage. His usual positive attitude is gone. He comes at Brendan with aggression instead.</context>
      <utterance>His bravery can get him killed, Sam. He's got nothing more to prove. He's already lasted two rounds against Koba, which is more than anyone else can say. You wonder what's keeping this guy up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josh Rosenthal claps his hands. Frank takes his cue to leave, but not before giving Brendan one last look. It's now or never. Brendan looks across the cage at Koba. Steels himself.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down. Breathe.  Look at me! Look at me! Why are we here, Brendan? Why are we here? Are we here to win this fight? You tell me, `cause if we're not, I'll throw in the towel right now. We'll get Tess and we will go home. You don't knock him out, you lose the fight. Understand me? You don't knock him out, you don't have a home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan comes out and meets Koba in the center of the cage, but the Russian resumes his supremacy.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to war!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Koba roughs the battered Brendan up some more, but then Brendan starts responding. Throws a couple effective leg kicks. A decent punch or two.</context>
      <utterance>Conlon somehow answering the bell for round three, but Koba's all over him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brendan's giving back, Bryan. There are signs of life in Brendan Conlon. He's starting to mix it up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Frank screams at Brendan to stay calm. To wait for his moment. Koba continues to squeeze. Brendan's face turns more and more red. Finally, he grabs Koba's shorts, musters up all the strength he has left, and TOSSES the Russian on his back, freeing himself from the choke in the process.</context>
      <utterance>Koba's got him caught in an iron vice, squeezing for all it's worth and trying to choke the teacher out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan jumps on Koba and attempts his own choke.</context>
      <utterance>He just launched Koba! Can you believe this? Conlon just shook off a guillotine!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Koba shakes off Brendan's submission attempt and stands. Brendan stands with him and they exchange a vicious round of blows. Brendan's giving as good as he's getting.</context>
      <utterance>Conlon's staying after him! He's squeezing him! The tables have turned, and the boy scout is squeezing the bear!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Conlon standing and trading with the Russian! I've never seen this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan snaps Koba's head back with a left, but the Russian responds with a combination. Brendan stumbles backwards, and Koba grabs him and tries to take him down. Brendan throws a left ELBOW that connects with Koba's temple. The Russian is momentarily STUNNED, long enough for Brendan to take him to the ground and wrap his arms around Koba's KNEE.</context>
      <utterance>This is a fight! We've got ourselves a fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Conlon going for a knee bar! He's got it very deep!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan wrenches his body for all it's worth. Frank pounds on the apron of the cage.</context>
      <utterance>He's deep on that knee bar!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Russian tries to squirm away, but he can't. His face is contorted in PAIN. The cageside OFFICIAL indicates there's only 10 seconds left in the fight.</context>
      <utterance>Crank it! Crank it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Four. Three. Koba struggles. Grimaces in agony. Brendan keeps wrenching his knee. Two. He can't take it. One. He TAPS!</context>
      <utterance>Brendan Conlon wrenching that knee for all it's worth! He's putting everything he has in it, and Koba is screaming in pain!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did it! Brendan Conlon has tapped Koba! I can't believe it! He can't believe it! Frank Campana can't believe it! This whole place can't believe it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bombs started dropping. They were coming from U.S. planes. Tommy and Manny were waving their flags to let them know they were Americans, but they didn't stop. Everyone died. Everyone except Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILAR</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, my Manny used to say Tommy was the brother he never had.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode>TO BRENDAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna fight him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Rosenthal finishes his instructions, Brendan peers into Tommy's empty corner.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, this is the final. Five rounds. I expect a clean fight. Obey my commands at all times. Defend yourselves at all times. Touch gloves, go back, let's do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy turns without answering. All business. Brendan returns to his corner. Looks at Tess. So much emotion on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Pop?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan lays on the ground as Josh Rosenthal pulls Tommy off him and admonishes him for the cheap shot. Tommy stares at Brendan. You want more? Frank runs into the cage with the stool and Brendan limps over to him and sits down. Brendan stares at Tommy, who paces in his corner like a caged animal.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Josh!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down. Look at me. Look at me, Brendan! Let it go! Breathe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beethoven. He's coming hard, just like we planned. I want you to angle out, hit, and move.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angle out, hit, and move.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josh Rosenthal claps his hands. It's time. Frank glares at him as he picks up the stool.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Breathe. Relax. He's not your brother, right? He's just a guy who's in the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tess sits uncomfortably in her chair. Her husband's face is a mess. In front of her, Callen and Sheridan commiserate. J.J., the TapouT crew, and Colt Boyd look on. The electricity in the crowd is greater than ever. They want a champion.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking a little more time for the cheap shot! Do your job, Josh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy tries to pound Brendan out, but Brendan latches on to Tommy's arm, wraps his legs around him, and REVERSES position, just as he did with Midnight, the Dane, and Koba. Tommy is in deep trouble. Brendan pushes him face down on the canvas and cranks his shoulder. There's no escape.</context>
      <utterance>Switch! Switch!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIDAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, that's a deep omoplata!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brendan applies intense pressure. Tommy's shoulder is contorted, WRENCHED backwards, and his face is a mask of pain. Tommy's in agony, but he won't give in.</context>
      <utterance>He's doing it again! Conlon's doing it again! This is going to be over!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy SHRIEKS like an animal, but still won't quit. In fact, he elbows Brendan in the face in defiance. Brendan in turn cranks the shoulder even more. It's at the breaking point.</context>
      <utterance>Tap, Tommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The shoulder twists. Twists. And then, audible only to Tommy and Brendan, CRACK. Dislocated. Then the HORN ending the round.</context>
      <utterance>Tap!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I popped his shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard it tear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is not what Brendan wants to hear. He looks over to Josh Rosenthal.</context>
      <utterance>You popped his shoulder? Good. I want you to pop his other shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Josh!</utterance>
   <speaker>100.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank snaps. Grabs Brendan by the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosenthal claps his hands. Frank exits the cage. The wounded Tommy stands in his corner, his ruined left arm hanging low. Brendan makes eye contact with him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! No Josh! Look at me! You got two rounds left! You need both rounds! Go in there, kick him in the head, take him down, and finish him!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy! What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! C'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you that crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL sounds. Round Four begins. Tommy throws useless right jabs. He's one handed and has no chance. Brendan stays away from him, not wanting to hurt his brother.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to war!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank screams at Brendan from cageside to take the wounded Tommy out, but Brendan is reluctant.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? It's over!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy and Brendan circle each other. Tommy throwing rights and wincing in agony at any movement. Brendan stares at him. Everything about him says "Quit, Tommy." But Tommy won't.</context>
      <utterance>It's over, Tommy. C'mon. We don't have to do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy keeps throwing defiant right jabs at Brendan. Finally, with no choice, Brendan fires back. He batters the defenseless Tommy up against the cage and POUNDS away at him, blasting his left shoulder with punches that make Tommy wince in pain. It's anyone's guess how he can take it. Brendan presses his brother up against the cage. Begging him to quit. But Tommy merely responds by elbowing Brendan in the face again. This sets the older brother off, and he resumes pounding on Tommy until the HORN sounds and Rosenthal pulls Brendan away.</context>
      <utterance>Finish him! You finish him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSH ROSENTHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brendan heads back to his stool as Tommy leans against the cage in agony. The Marines scream for him, but his eyes are glazed over. It's unthinkable that he hasn't broken yet. From near cageside, Paddy looks to the corner and makes eye contact with Brendan. They exchange a small look of understanding. A NOD. They both know what needs to be done.</context>
      <utterance>Break! Break!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy continues to struggle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Tommy! I'm sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tears pour down Tommy's face. Brendan is crushing his wind pipe. Tommy's eyes bulge.</context>
      <utterance>Tap, Tommy! Tap!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tommy, about to pass out, no more air to breathe, slowly opens his left hand, looks at Brendan, and TAPS his shoulder on the Conlon family crest. Finally submitting.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Tommy! I love you!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
