<movie id="595" title="White Jazz">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I reach into a dresser drawer, pull out a yellowed black &amp; white picture of HER: this beatific blonde, sleeping. Below me is a week-old L.A. Times with the headline: Matriarch of Television Series, Empire Ridge, Retires. The Matriarch's picture in the middle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm old. And all I have left is the will to remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Slide HER over the Matriarch's picture: the Matriarch 30 years younger now. Lift my eyes back to my reflection.</context>
      <utterance>...and the fear I'll forget...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Legend: Los Angeles, Fall 1958</context>
      <utterance>I killed innocent men. I betrayed sacred oaths. I reaped profit from horror. The names are dead or too guilty to tell. The events so brutal they beg to be re-told...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior Stemmons. A partner I never asked for. The scowl meant to hide a shit-scared kid who'd been teaching evidence classes three months ago. His Old-Man was an LAPD lifer who never got past Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should make our move now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mid-fight? Look at the crowd: you wanna be at the center of a riot?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I point at the bantam Black:</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna be here when Noonan and the Feds show up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior eyes the exits clockwise, nervous, waiting for `Untouchables' to break the doors down. I hate the way panic smells when I stand this close to it.</context>
      <utterance>We let Sanderline finish this beating, we get his gratitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna let Rock-a-bye fight too-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-relax Junior.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sanderline, I'm Lieutenant Klein of the LAPD and a real big fan-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sanderline spooks, steps back. Turn and make sure Junior sees the fire in my eyes, keep staring at Junior as I speak to Sanderline again:</context>
      <utterance>-you're under arrest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you're not. Reuben is-</utterance>
   <speaker>REUBEN RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Lieutenant Dave why you arrest-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-for being a ranked fighter who still steals hubcaps. Shut up.  If I was gonna arrest you, I wouldn't have let you finish: and that hook-uppercut combo you got is something special.  Reuben's in custody. But you could be our Guest. Whaddya say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RING ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-BOOS drown the PA. Beer and lit cigars shell the Announcer. Fights erupt in the stands. I can't stifle a chuckle. Three exits down: day late-dollar short Feds. WELLES NOONAN, elbows- out, surveying the scene like a half-assed Rommel.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentleman...due to circumstances beyond our control, Rock-A-Bye Ruiz will not fight this-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Move faster.</context>
      <utterance>Welles Noonan, US Attorney. Ivy League Crimefighter. Launching a big boxing probe as a way to begin prying into everything else crooked and corrupt in LA.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As we near the side exit I stop. Junior pauses, less than a foot from my face, pointing up at Noonan, pure panic.</context>
      <utterance>Unaware the LAPD was walking away with his two big witnesses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sanderline digs the digs: sports the Ambassador robe over his street clothes, reading the Bible.</context>
      <utterance>Hungry Sanderline?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERLINE JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they got shrimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shrimp cocktail.  You want something Reuben?</utterance>
   <speaker>REUBEN RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To know why the fuck I'm here-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-mind your tone, Shitbird...</utterance>
   <speaker>REUBEN RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You get your badge in a cereal box?</context>
      <utterance>Shitbird went out with Vaudeville.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're here because we want you to remember where you live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SANDERLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>City of Angels.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent Sanderline.</utterance>
   <speaker>REUBEN RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz turns `caught-me' pink...I nod to Junior: split `em. Playing adjoining hotel rooms like sweat boxes.</context>
      <utterance>You live in LA, Asshole. You do not live in `Federal Government.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get to spend time alone now.</utterance>
   <speaker>REUBEN RUIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior shoves Ruiz through the inner-door connecting the rooms. Sanderline giggles. Close the door behind them. Sit down inches from Sanderline, change my tone:</context>
      <utterance>Want some perfume?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instant quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Stop laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sanderline staying silent...</context>
      <utterance>What were you gonna tell Welles Noonan?  He has a subpoena with your name on it, Sanderline. Why would someone like you need to talk to the U.S. Attorney?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a legbreaker for the Mob. I know the Men that pay you for that will murder you if they hear you're about to talk to the U.S.-</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERLINE JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-but they don't know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-phone rings. Sanderline flinches for the second time.</context>
      <utterance>And they don't have to. Now tell me what you were gonna tell Noonan-</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERLINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I stand, step, answer it:</context>
      <utterance>Bet you they ran outta shrimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIDENTIFIED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mild shock. Catalogue potential "who's"...</context>
      <utterance>The Spook with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIDENTIFIED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, we know he is. We're just trying to be mysterious-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-who's `we?'</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIDENTIFIED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and Sam G.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>G for `Giancana.' I owe him favors for the rest of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIDENTIFIED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're out at the place in Palm Springs. You should come out for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell Sam if I get minute-</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIDENTIFIED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-yer gonna have to make a minute for him. Now. See, we think the Spade might testify that Sam owns him and how we was grooming him for a title shot he was gonna tank. A fight everybody woulda' got flush off of, including the Spade.  Have him look out the window Klein.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trusting puppy Sanderline steps to the window:</context>
      <utterance>Sanderline, you gotta see this...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDERLINE JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-smash his head against the frame using his forward motion. He loses muscle control for the split-second it takes me to pitch his legs up and out. My face a quick-change evil mask. Feature Sanderline's nine-story fall. That Ambassador Hotel robe billows behind him like a cape. He detonates an overhead streetlight with a bomb sound, then hits the driveway. Unzip my fly, hustle into the bathroom, screams from outside now. Flush the toilet as Junior and Ruiz pile through the door. Step out, play it baffled: look at the bed where Sanderline sat, then the open window, screams floating up...</context>
      <utterance>What'm I-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>8.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ME   Boyce Bradley, Chief of Detectives. Smartest man in town. And one of the richest: Dad was a Real Estate Developer who owned a strip of land that's now known as the Santa Monica Freeway. On either side, Bradley's book-ends: D.A. Bob Gallaudet, not the smartest man in town: `Gas Chamber' Bob cribbed my notes at USC Law. And Tom Bethune, running for a City Council seat that'll decide if this Mexican slum called Chavez Ravine gets bulldozed and renamed `Dodger Stadium.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethune leaps like a lapdog, hits the power.</context>
      <utterance>Turn it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley picks up a newspaper:</context>
      <utterance>I was pissing. He was jumping.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`US Attorney Noonan is accusing the Los Angeles Police Department in general, and Lt. David Klein in particular, of murder at worst, gross incompetence at best...'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noonan had Sanderline scared. After he sang to me he panicked &amp; jumped.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM BETHUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did spend a month in Camarillo Mental Hospital last year-</utterance>
   <speaker>GAS CHAMBER BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-and wearing that hotel robe over his clothes makes him look even more looney-bin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM BETHUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, Reuben Ruiz recanted. So Noonan's Boxing Probe is dead. He's got nothing-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-but time, a mandate and new targets...I need to speak to the Lieutenant alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Describe to me your duty, as you understood it, regarding Sanderline Johnson and Reuben Ruiz.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take both men into custody before Noonan and the Feds could, and find out what they were going to tell-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-and why did I choose you for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm a Cop with a law degree, and you thought my legal-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-because your a thug with a law degree. Because I thought by now you'd be so indebted to this Department for not indicting and/or imprisoning you, that diligent, honest discharge of duty would be assured.  And I made a horrible misjudgment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bethune and Gallaudet don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob's happy because he wants to be State Attorney General and his most likely opponent will be Welles Noonan. Tom's happy because Morton Diskant, who's leading their City Council race, is endorsed by Noonan. Thus, they're not seeing the larger play.  Noonan's new target will likely be the LAPD itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I wave it all off:</context>
      <utterance>Because that's where I would aim: a subpoenaed Federal witness plummets to his death in the company of two LAPD detectives?  This screams Police Corruption. This offers Noonan the possibility of payback in the form of national headlines.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-and Bradley drops his bomb: Coroner's file. I stare...guess the contents...try to keep my heart rate in-check...</context>
      <utterance>Johnson did that stint at the Nut House -- leak his file to your friends at the times-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friends would be more interested in this.  Coroner's preliminary: white paint chips found embedded in Sanderline Johnson's scalp. A matching dent on the white window sill. I checked with the hotel switchboard and found a call was patched to your room at about the same time Johnson flew out of it.  It shocks and sickens me that your allegiance to the Chicago mob would take precedence over the LAPD.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Where's this going?  Gun? Shield? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The appearance of disciplinary measures taken against you are mandated post-Sanderline Johnson, so your suspension will be recorded but sealed...and kept quiet for now-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if the papers or Noonan come sniffing around-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-we can provide adequate proof of your dismissal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're not dismissing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Since I misjudged the Cop I thought you were, I'm going to leverage the Cop that you are. Bradley slides the morning paper over. Front page: `Candidate Diskant Hears The Hue and Cry of The Underclass...' The photo shows a smiling Diskant, rolled shirt-sleeves, in the middle of a sea of LA Immigrants, all smiling back.</context>
      <utterance>Just on paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morton Diskant is to be removed from the City Council race. The means and methods implemented to that end I will entrust to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to torpedo Diskant so your buddy Bethune can win a City Council seat uncontested-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I stare back. Feel myself getting fitted for strings...</context>
      <utterance>-or spend the next month in lock-up before being arraigned on charges of gross misconduct and dereliction of duty. The preamble before you face life in prison for murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bradley waves me out. I intentionally drag my badge back across the desk, scratching his Mahogany heirloom.</context>
      <utterance>Diskant works Saturdays. Late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Traffic teeming up Fairfax, tourettes-like glances in my rear- view...a Black Buick...maybe mirroring my lane changes.</context>
      <utterance>Bradley's stooge now. A smart play suspending me: a built-in shield for him if things go sideways.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brake hard. They hang a left on Fountain.</context>
      <utterance>Black Buick...five Cars back...feels like a tail...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cruising up Nichols Canyon to the pad, cameras and copywriters loom on my front lawn.</context>
      <utterance>...or maybe I just need sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Slouch in the seat, accelerate, keep looking back...dig that geek from the Hearld pissing in my hedges.</context>
      <utterance>Press camped out post-Sanderline, looking for quotes to hang me with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Scoop Meg's LA Herald of the ground. Headlines condemn me. Tuck it under my arm as Meg opens the door:</context>
      <utterance>Retreat to Meg's. My kid sister and only living family. Mom and Pop died in `51 when their first plane ride became their last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already got the Times inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much is true?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times have I lied to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrug. Play aloof. Hope it suffices.</context>
      <utterance>Zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've always liked your Men mean. She looks up at me. Feels the shame I shun...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would Mom and Dad say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands, goes to the stove.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. That's where I learned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meg stares darts. I smile to defuse.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, pour me...a cup please. Black, no sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She fetches cups and saucers.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Pete?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Pete Bondurant. One-time LA Sheriff. Bounced when he beat-dead a Prisoner who spit at him. A duly impressed Howard Hughes hired him on as his full-time muscle. My Sister's new Hump. My oldest living Friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meg cackles.</context>
      <utterance>You look like Death taking a shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still got that MGM-face.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still the only guy who ever traded movie-potential for Police work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because in the movies they make you pull your punches.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>15.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drain my mug. To Pete:</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna do LAPD a favor tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-Pete puts an extended index finger in front of Meg's lips, which she bends backwards.</context>
      <utterance>No. We're going to the Cocoanut-</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Favor' mean `free?'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Means $500 an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme the phone so I can find another Date-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-you're the only Woman I know who calls Men-</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete laughs, then:</context>
      <utterance>-you're the only Man I know who doesn't call Women.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior brought along because he begged. Already hip to how many ways you can make money with a badge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a birthday coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the 16th, right? How old?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Head down, scribbling mid-sentence, makes me wait a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Old. What are you writing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just notes...about work-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-what `work'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Street work versus textbook-</context>
      <utterance>Mostly compare and contrast stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior's look practiced in a mirror: clicks the pen, slides the steno away.</context>
      <utterance>-chapter 1: don't write shit down. Chapter 2: or other Cops might kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bait him, see if he bites.</context>
      <utterance>So you think Noonan will come after you for the Sanderline thing? He seems like a real hard charger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard he was coming after both of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>17.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feature real concern from Junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indictments. Prison time. Whole nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy Jesus. Is this true?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior goes sour...gets he's being goosed. I laugh, glance out the windshield: see Diskant finally exiting the office.</context>
      <utterance>I'm seriously thinking about turning Junior...testifying against you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I start the car, slow-roll up the street. My Hamilton says 11:04 PM. Streets deserted. Pete walking in Diskant's direction now as I continue to roll toward both. Pete close, dig his giant head nodding `hello.'</context>
      <utterance>Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pete suddenly puts his back into an left hook: hammers Diskant from nowhere as they pass. Instant-ugly crumble.</context>
      <utterance>Seen Pete do this a dozen times and every time the same thought:</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pete hoists Diskant by his waist-band, tosses him in the backseat. I accelerate out, obeying every law.</context>
      <utterance>God help me if he ever hits me like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Quiff nervous but cooing, dick out, on Diskant's thigh. Junior just as nervous...reloading a camera.</context>
      <utterance>Junior picked up this Quiff jocking other Fags in a Men's Room. But Quiff was a Law Student who wanted his record kept clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A baffled moment as the comment registers.</context>
      <utterance>He should suck his dick. Y'know? Put the icing on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me that wouldn't sell it...plus he's a Communist.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Diskant finally speaks: marble-mouthed. Pushes Quiff away:</context>
      <utterance>We're ruining his career, not his soul. Reload the camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTON DISKANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't waste a second: grab Diskant by the hair, narrate his immediate future.</context>
      <utterance>Off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Diskant rips his head free. Rage. Blood from his mouth. Scanning the room, sizing up the situation, then:</context>
      <utterance>Drop out of the City Council race or I send these pictures to the papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTON DISKANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll fight you rotten-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-and maybe salvage something that's a close cousin to `respect.' But what about your wife and kid getting hold of those pictures?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the Quiff home.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Franklin-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior pulls Quiff out the door. By his hand. Just Pete, Me, and Diskant now. Silent moments drag sour...</context>
      <utterance>-of course it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a nod from you Morton, let's me know you get it-</utterance>
   <speaker>DISKANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-don't say my name...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gets it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Pete and I turn to leave:</context>
      <utterance>Someone from the Times will call for a quote. Whatever your reason for dropping out make it real.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISKANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long moment on me and Pete. Blunted by what we just heard.</context>
      <utterance>You eventually lose the ability to reconcile the things you've done to people. That's Hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-no thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop pretending you're not a pig for all this, Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still got a day job, Pete-</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I wait too long, answer in too high a voice:</context>
      <utterance>-tossing more Bantamweights out windows?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Mutt jumped.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stop in front of Meg's place. Pete leaves the engine running, jumps out.</context>
      <utterance>Not even the people who don't know you believe that. If somebody from the DA's office decides to dig, you could fry Boy-o. Be nice to be in with a billionaire who's got a fleet of planes, fly you outta the country on a moment's notice.  C'mon -- it's a cake legal gig. He just wants you to burn some actress that stopped fucking him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I watch Pete go into Meg's place. Drive on. Stop sign. A block away: Black Buick parallel to me. Exhaust plumes. Like they're waiting. I keep my eyes on the rear-view as I pass...but it just stays put...idling.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow. Hughes Aircraft, 7pm It'll be worth it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klein-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-you know who Hector Magdalena is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yeah...Narco's Snitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's missing. His home was broken into at some point within the last hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So send Robbery.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing taken was him. Wilshire Station is on-scene. Get over there right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call it penance.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought that's what Morton Diskant was-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-that makes one of us. 1284 South Tremaine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>22.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I hear the first split-second of Bradley smashing his phone down. Click my own cradle. Wipe my face. Dial another number.</context>
      <utterance>BRADLEY   This kind of timing makes for disasters, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior. Meet me at 1284 South Tremaine. 20 minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Dan Wilhite, Head of the LAPD Narcotics Division. A Michigan Catholic poisoned by 25 years in this desert. Recently divorced despite seven kids with his Ex.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell like bourbon Wilhite-</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-fuck off. This is handled. And pull your idiot partner out of there-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Junior's already here-</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-push past him, toward the house.</context>
      <utterance>-Magdalena was my Snitch, so it's my scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then get Bradley on the horn, so you can relay that order. I'm here on his word. Now, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guard dogs are dead. Magdalena's missing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And presumed what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could give a shit. I just want to this case to get a quick burial.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet. Who made the call?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some old broad heard an `argument' and buzzed Wilshire Station.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the family?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wife and daughter were in Santa Barbara. Just got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At 2 AM?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Wife said she got into a fight with her Parents, left ASAP.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't Hector with `em?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think they were fighting about? Santa Barbara Wasps don't fancy dope-pushing Wetbacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the Son?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy. Make him your 1 suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a mean streak. And he and Hector had been at each others throats for months. Have Tommy picked up. He likes to loaf at those nigger jazz joints in Watts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhite gets close, still sneering:</context>
      <utterance>Alright, you better cut out before people start asking why the head of Narco is at a missing persons.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a conviction. Grab Tommy and pin this thing fast or you'll have a whole division of disgraced cops at your front door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about Wilhite?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhite bolts. I pause. Clarity finally dissolving the bloodshot: this is the disaster Bradley was talking about:</context>
      <utterance>You queered the Fed's Fight Probe by killing that boxer and they already had a hard-on for the LAPD- Bradley sent you down here as damaged goods...think about it. Everybody sees what's coming.  Now close this quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The God-sized problems I triggered tossing Sanderline take shape: the LAPD's sanctioned dope-pusher vanishes -- that's a pretty juicy spot to stick a new probe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BIDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-shifty...colored...y'know Negros are planning an invasion! After our white women and our water supply-</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-where was this Peeper you saw?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BIDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bushes. Spyin' on Lucille. Seen him there before! He's a black saboteur looking for fertile white wombs. Wanna breed a mulatto master race- -cut into the crazy:</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Six-Pack crosses to confer.</context>
      <utterance>Officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides bat-shit insanity, is there anything else about her that rings true?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard an argument, loud, maybe a minute or two, then silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this `Peeper' riff she's on?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She saw someone in the bushes earlier. She's reported that kind of thing a dozen other times. She's also reported flying saucers, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roam. A hallway. Junior the grim-faced professional, He's got that damn steno out, scribbling like he's on a deadline.</context>
      <utterance>See if any of the other Neighbors can verify this `Peeper' thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's hovering over a lake of blood, drag marks originating in that lake lead out to the garage. Junior sees me. See him startle, then jut his tough-guy chin on reflex:</context>
      <utterance>No one touch a thing `til I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Lieutenant Klein. I said `meet me' in twenty minutes' not `go in without me.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I've been doing-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pull Junior aside, impart the following tightly:</context>
      <utterance>-is stepping on dicks. You don't know the history, the players or the play.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Department gave Magdalena a monopoly on the LA dope trade decades ago-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-what Department?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Us Pollyanna -- LAPD. We bullet- proofed him in exchange for 60% of his profit and a promise he only deal drugs in Darktown and East LA-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Black and Mexican-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-give the man a prize. He'd also rat his competition and kill the ones we couldn't convict. Now keep your mouth shut and stay on my hip.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want to bounce his head off the wall. I continue my tour instead. Follow the blood-trail out into the garage where it ends in another smaller lake of blood.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loaded him into a car-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-are all the Magdalena vehicles accounted for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for the Son's: Tommy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OFFICER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he pokes his head around the corner:</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old lady hear dogs barking? Gunshots?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Examine the wounds closer. Catch myself petting the deceased pooches. To Junior:</context>
      <utterance>No, I asked. Just the yelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't hear barking...so they were either lousy guard dogs...or they knew the Killer.  You can't hit something this clean unless you're point blank. He could've been petting them when he fired: look at the burn pattern-  Like when you shoot something with a silencer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've shot things with silencers... And the old lady didn't hear any gunshots.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy?</context>
      <utterance>You make a family member for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to issue an APB?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Update.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The house is intact.</context>
      <utterance>Hector's gone. Blood that may or may not be his leads out to the garage. Two guard dogs shot dead but no other signs of a struggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Family?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wife and Daughter are here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Describe their state.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother Madge aggrieved.  Daughter Lucille...indifferent. The son is persona non grata and a strong early suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Including all police personnel.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, kick everyone out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't question me. Is your partner on hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have him bag and seal everything and bring it to Wilshire Station. Find Tommy Magdalena post-haste and take him into custody. No APB's, nothing to alert Noonan and the FBI to this situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. Second time he's hung up on me in an hour. Pull Junior to me just as he's going through a stack of mail:</context>
      <utterance>-no more information over an open line. I'll be at the Bethune event later on today. Find me there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big brown-nose nods from an aim-to-please Junior.</context>
      <utterance>I'm giving you on-scene command. Bradley wants everyone removed from the premises and the entire house bagged for evidence and brought to Wilshire Station.  Can you handle this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Entirely. Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To find Tommy Magdalena.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Glance street-side: Sanderline smiling blood in a wind blown bathrobe. Blink and he's gone, replaced by a kid hawking the Times. Pull-over. Toss the kid a coin. Front page: LEADING CANDIDATE BOWS FROM CITY COUNCIL RACE, next to a picture of Diskant. Pissed for reasons I won't name. Back to the Car. A Black Buick passes, slower than the rest of traffic, act like I'm oblivious. It turns. I slide in, start my Pontiac.</context>
      <utterance>Big yawns. Half haze from no sleep. Buzz dispatch. A message from Pete. `Reminder: Hughes aircraft, 7 PM.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another Black Buick. Call it a Fed Tail. Noonan already up my ass.  Let's see if they got guts enough to keep following me South.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Check my mirrors. That Black Buick hangs way back. Cruise past jazz clubs: The Savoy, Joe Morris's Plantation, Shepp's Playhouse, the Down Beat...no sign of a Ford Deuce. Pull up to the Club Alabam. Valets stare: a white man in Watts at this hour can only be Cop. Park. Half-a-block back: buzzcuts in that black Buick.</context>
      <utterance>Dispatch gave me Tommy's make and model: A `32 Ford Deuce with a bent eight. Hot-rodder Tommy liked to goose the cops into giving chase.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Smile big, give `em a thumbs-up.</context>
      <utterance>Noonan tail confirmed: Fed faces glow like Martians this far down Crenshaw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender glowers, grabs a bottle, pours, hands the size of catcher's mitts. He slides the glass. I sip.</context>
      <utterance>Get Lester and get me a scotch straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He vanishes behind a stained curtain. Feel those voodoo stares from behind...and I switch the scotch glass to my left hand as nonchalant as possible. Bartender reappears, motions me back. I follow. Backstage. I see a figure stretched prone, ice-pack pressed to his face, rolled reefer between his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Sanderline Johnson was my second cousin, Peckerwood. I wouldn't drink that with my gun hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Only as I get closer do I see the badly swollen black eye. He looks up at me. A voice like sand-paper left out in the sun:</context>
      <utterance>Lester Lake. One-time velvet voiced crooner. But a dabble in the dope trade cost him a set of slashed vocal cords at the hands of none other than Hector Magdalena.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant Dave Klein. Slayer of Sanderline Johnson...y'got stones showing up this far South.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Mag wanted to make sure I understood something he was saying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Left an hour ago. Emptied my safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. He's wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lester hands me the reefer, take it, toke geeky, belch smoke.</context>
      <utterance>To what? You looking for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lester takes it back, draws deep.</context>
      <utterance>Just never got this...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now watch Lester's attitude improve toot sweet:</context>
      <utterance>Too white to appreciate good grass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spurts smoke, sits up like a shot, beams.</context>
      <utterance>Hector Magdalena is missing, presumed dead. Tommy is our sole suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If only I'd known this an hour ago.</context>
      <utterance>Muthafucker -- there is a God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heartbreaker, huh? You let him gig here last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't let him, he just does. Nails on a chalkboard too. He rushed the stage last week when we had Charlie Mingus drop in for a set. Mingus looked at this half-Mex greaser kid trying to play `Round Midnight,' said that fool couldn't find them keys with a flashlight.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy's playing days are over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallelujah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time did he show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Around four. Him and these Pachucos poppin' switchblades like punks.  The only thing that was keepin' him `untouched' was Hector...  Is he really dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's blood all over his house, seems to belong to him. There's just no body. Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feature Tommy for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that? How many times has he been in here, busted you up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but he ain't got the salt to truly take a Man's life. Especially not Hector's...he was scared of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`Cuz Hector been whippin' Tommy's ass from the time he could talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the Wife? Beat her too?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We used to call that old bitch `the Burglar'...eyes were so black, it looked like she had a mask on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the daughter? Lucille?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things up off the street. Rumors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector had turned her out. Using her the way the Romans used to use their daughters when they did business: Some pussy to sweeten the pot. Rumor was she got picked up in this trick sweep few weeks back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector was whoring her?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Lester tilts his neck back, points to a long keloid scar that stretches across his throat...</context>
      <utterance>Hector was an evil Muthafucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...born with ruthless bones.  And if he really is dead and gone, this game `bout to explode.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What game?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drugs. Especially here in South Central. Hector ran it uncontested. Lotta cats gonna rush in now, try to plant a flag.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy can't hold the throne?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy couldn't hold his pecker without Hector's help and he knows that. He's gonna bury himself like a tick. Good luck turning him up, he took six or seven grand out the safe tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eyes and ears for me Lester. He turns up, you get in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't kill him first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Councilman Bethune, was Mr. Diskant dropping out the only way you could have won this race?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM BETHUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethune's beam twitches when he sees me weaving past. Give him a quick nod, get nothing back: he can't be seen this close to the turd in the punch bowl. Moving by:</context>
      <utterance>Not at all. My message of civic advancement manifested in that beautiful blue baseball team was starting to hit home.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything you'd like to say to future constituents?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM BETHUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley at one of the front tables confabbing with DA Gas Chamber Bob Gallaudet. As I aim their way, one of my favorite men aims at me, wearing this Great White grin: FRITZ KOENIG.</context>
      <utterance>I like my Dodger Dogs with mustard and relish!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fritz Koenig. German born. Former US Spymaster, current Head of the LAPD's Intelligence Division. He and Bradley in the middle of their own Cold War -- each fighting to be the second most important member of the LAPD behind Chief Parker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These functions aren't normally open to Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone with your accent should never be allowed to say `Jew' again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That accent allowed me to execute many a Nazi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we're both Traitors: Ellis Island said Grandpa's `Kleinsasser' was two syllables too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have expected so public a showing after Sanderline Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig flashes that grin again.</context>
      <utterance>He jumped Fritz.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure he did. And where is your young partner this day?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working his first big job.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My eyes narrow but stay smiling:</context>
      <utterance>Might the job involve the LAPD's most important missing Wetback, Hector Magdalena?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig nods, casts his gaze out over the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>It does.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've known Stemmons since the academy. He was a top pupil. A peculiar little pain in the ass, but very good with details.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig roars this big frightening laugh of his.</context>
      <utterance>Kid might have some climb in him.  Reminds me of another pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm puzzled as to why the Bradley would assign you to the Magdalena case when you're neither Homicide nor Robbery...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no body, and nothing was taken except Hector.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does know how to delegate doesn't he...and also I'm sure that poor Negro's nosedive has put you squarely in his debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep me abreast will you? Chief Parker is understandably nervous. Situations like these tend to yield grief...and we've the FBI poking around our garden patch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig's big laugh again. Moving toward Bradley now. Then flashbulbs pop-blind. Panic: snapping pix of me? Relief: not me. Hollywood types: this Buff McMan Meat-type and Her. I go slack inches from the Press that yesterday wanted to roll in my guts...but now they're just as entranced with her as I am. She and McMan Meat continue past as I stare, she answers his questions for him. I think her eyes see mine. Then I realize where I'm standing. Bradley waiting. Focused on me and not her -- God-damned Eunuch. I step over, speak without preface:</context>
      <utterance>My ass first Fritz, yours second.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Magdalena has gone to ground and he's got a war chest to keep him there. The only way we take him quickly is to issue a citywide APB-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-no. We can't risk that. Do you make him for the murderer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Hector's disappearance is definitely an inside job. That whole family feels hinky. The daughter was all bruises and no tears and Hector's hop-head wife looks part punching bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you suspect either of the women?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to Wilhite, they were in Santa Barbara at the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Verify that. Where is your partner?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vouching in evidence at Wilshire Station.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep him on that. He had excellent ratings as an evidence teacher and I trust him more than you.  Find Tommy Magdalena. Focus everything on that effort &amp; I want him apprehended Klein, not killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Hector? Still missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And most likely dead. Find the Son. Stakeout the residence. Put tails on both the mother and daughter -- I want this investigation working quietly, and around the clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do we do if Hector turns up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's alive, bring him to me. If he's dead, have him John Doe'd at the morgue until Noonan can be drawn off and this FBI situation sorted out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilhite. He was operating Hector-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swallow my sneer. Push through the service doors. Hard. Headed back toward the kitchen, an exit sign. I pass an alcove: Her. Alone. Smoke break. Beauty you almost never get to examine up close. I stop, stammer, she gives me a once- over, thinks I'm a Reporter...</context>
      <utterance>-don't worry about Dan Wilhite. You deal directly with me. Now go out the back. I don't want the press recognizing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a light?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I fumble for a Chesterfield. She pulls a Zippo slow.</context>
      <utterance>You got a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I smile too wide -- fuck. I kill it, try to gather up the bits of `cool' that shattered with the sophomore smile.</context>
      <utterance>If you snap a picture of me, I get to set you on fire. Fair?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't look like you were all that upset with the attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thing you're not a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your power of observation leaves lots to be desired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't thank me: these things are bad for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stubs her cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>You believe everything you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts walking back the way I came.</context>
      <utterance>You believe anything you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you eat Dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I can't stop watching her, even after she pushes back through the double doors, re-entering the fray head-first. I step after her. A reporter finally makes me. Random catcalls of `Klein! `Hey, Enforcer!' Shutterbugs beeline my way, firing flashbulbs from the hip. Close the door quick and bolt.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a note: steal Bethune's guest- list, then go door-to-door until you find her again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything worthwhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you tell the Watch Commander upstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That this was a random drug seizure. I'm not using names and I'm number coding everything. A load of interesting stuff too.  I got unregistered fire-arms, more dope than I've ever seen, and some mail from business associates that seems hinky. We should follow up-  -here, this one, `Hurwitz Holdings' Hector had some real estate dealings-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-bag it until Bradley orders us otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you solve a case when the evidence is in bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't. Our job is to find Tommy.  And why is that out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm making notes separate from-  -I thought we were investigating Magdalena's disappearance-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Don't write shit down. What do you need Kid? A little bouncing ball, bottom of the screen?  Magdalena is twenty years dirty with this Department...do you think a word of that exists on paper?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior tucks the steno away, chastened.</context>
      <utterance>And there's reasons. Respect them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Junior jacks his chin just high enough to save face, tucks that steno away, this X-Ray stare.</context>
      <utterance>Now we need surveillance set up on the house and revolving tails on both Madge and Lucille Magdalena. Their alibi is they were in Santa Barbara when Hector vanished. Find out if that's real. The tails and the stakeout start tonight.  Can you manage this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Startle, check my watch: 7:17 pm.</context>
      <utterance>Police blotter gets me bupkis. Buzz dispatch. Looking for license hits on that `32 Ford Deuce. Nothing. Zoom Darktown again. Zilch. Tommy dug in deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howard Hughes. Billionaire germ freak. Boob man. Pete's prime benefactor. Nobody had seen him in years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>43.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small, effete blonde man: GEOFFREY MILTEER extends his tiny hand, plastic-cordial, rubbed raw from waiting...</context>
      <utterance>ME   Now he only communicated through a small standing army of lapdog lawyers he kept on staff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gregory Milteer. Attorney-at-Law. A pleasure Lt. Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave. Sorry I'm late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We sit at a huge drafting table. I shoot a sidelong to Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Indeed.  Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your time on a Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Mr. Hughes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unavailable. Unfortunately. But I've been given full authority to-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete hate scowls me: have your fun, Asshole...</context>
      <utterance>-I'm not contagious...if that's what he's worried about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't find that the least bit humorous Lt. Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milteer looks at Pete. Pete half-shrugs. Back to me now:</context>
      <utterance>Yes you do. What's your pitch Mr. Milteer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An `Actress' named Glenda Bledsoe signed a Service Contract that she's now willfully violating by acting in a Z-grade horror picture presently `shooting' in Griffith Park. Despite entreaties for her to cease participation in this absurdity, she continues to revel in her outlaw status with us. Thus we would like her destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think I can do a better job than your people?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bondurant says you're one of the smarter people he knows-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something like that?</context>
      <utterance>-dubious honor if you knew the other people Pete knows.  So you want to catch her in violation of her Service Contract?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. The morality clause in particular as the damage to her reputation would be most devastating: Nymphomaniac, Criminal, Communist...anything along these lines. Once you visit the set of her `Attack of the Atomic Vampires,' you'll see the void that is her character. We haven't a photograph handy, but she's playing the lead female role.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete laughs out loud. Milteer goes frigid.</context>
      <utterance>I'm happy to help. But my price is $10,000. Not 5.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>$10,000 should buy more than help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long, cold moment drags...</context>
      <utterance>For 10 give it any name you want. I'm a salaried employee of LAPD, that means I'll have to find time off hours to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed. Start tonight. Someone's been stealing groceries from our talent domiciles. There's no proof that it's her, but it's her. Peter will provide you addresses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We look forward to your updates.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I hang up, step out, yawn.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, pass a message to Stemmons: I want him to meet me at the one-thousand block of South Tremaine tonight at 11 and at some point between now and then, I'll need him to do a preliminary work- up on a woman named Glenda Bledsoe.  B-L-E-D-S-O-E. Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Winos vibe LAPD, make a hole as I approach:</context>
      <utterance>Mickey Cohen: one-time LA crime kingpin and West Coast Mob heavy who now trawls for loose change.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cecil B. Demoted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where Klein goes tsuris follows. This is what I hate about being down, lip from the likes of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this is `down' I never want to see `out.' How the mighty have fallen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one of us are you talking about Klein? Word is the Federal Bureau is all hot and bothered with you Gonif. Hey, I hear J. Edgar schtups his personal assistant and makes him wear ladies hose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else are you hearing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That this Welles Noonan character has developed quite a crush. That you might want to consider relocating to Dogdick, Delaware.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been a marked man for years Mick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-follow Mickey's gaze over to ROCK ROCKWELL. Buff McMan Meat- the guy with Glenda at the Bethune party. He's primping with other boys decked in surplus SS uniforms, checking the side mirror of one of the `Alien craft' before his big close-up.</context>
      <utterance>But the bullseye on your back's never been quite so big...if you need a new line of work, I got this faygele leading man needs replacing-</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His agent told me he could play straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His agent lied.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But I am interested in your leading lady. Bradley sent me. Saw her at the Bethune-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-not a chance. I'm still trying to play hide the submarine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want Chief Bradley angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten years ago I could call for that little Pisher's head on a stick.  And now...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's her name, Mick?</context>
      <utterance>And now the only thing you're putting on sticks are corn dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenda.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why was she there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY COHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Low-budget strategy: I send Glenda and Rock to any event where there's cameras -- Glenda gets guest-a'- honor treatment everywhere with that shape a' her's...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What she drive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee's in the kitchen. Let's go over this quick because I'm beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're set on a place where we can stash you and Rock. It's in Topanga Canyon, two weeks-</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-two weeks? My body'll fall apart-</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-think of it as 14 days of push-ups-  Are you sure about this Sid? Seems shaky. Was this Mickey's idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I think it's brilliant! Inspired! The two leads of Mickey Cohen's magnum opus get kidnapped! The press'll eat it up! They'll write about `Gangster Mickey,' the glory days. Couple a' headlines like that and interest in Atomic Vampires will go through the roof!  Who's gonna grab you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A charmer I knew in another life...George Ainge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SID FRIZELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he okay with making it look real-</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-he can't hit me in the face! That's a deal-breaker!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be thrilled to knock me around. Plus he's holding something of mine, so we can kill two birds. He'll grab us Tuesday in front of the Pacific Dining Car.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Hughes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him? That angle can only help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID FRIZELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dying to know...was he the Spruce Goose between the sheets?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hung like a newborn and he called my tits `propellers.' Belly laughter from inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The real howler: fake kidnappings always bomb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Toss the envelope into the glove-box, slam it shut. Scan. Two heads in one of the unmarked patrol cars I ordered. Cursory nods as they pass. Tail-lights fade. Dead quiet save my low Jazz. Fighting my drift. Check my Hamilton. 10:00. Grimace.</context>
      <utterance>Thinking I could tip Milteer off to the kidnap plot and pick up the other half of my payment...  Thinking I should just give the first half back now...'cuz I know right now I'll never hurt her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Yawn. Look up...Lucille Magdalena at her window. Sudden. Startling: no blouse, pig-tails, big silver-dollar nipples touch/steam glass. Pushes the curtains back even further. Adrenaline cuts through the lactic acid: wide awake now. I see her eyes aren't sex-placid or rolled back -- they're scanning -- hopeful to glimpse someone outside looking back.</context>
      <utterance>No sense of time. Exhaustion steals it. A full hour earlier than I told Junior to meet me. I need sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She holds her scan for a blink, a different smile, eyes sex- placid now, rolled-back now -- she just saw what she was looking for: hidden eyes staring back at her. I look to where I saw her gaze kink...unholster my .45. Get out quiet.</context>
      <utterance>This routine had been done before. That old broad babbling about a Peeper. The only other link to Hector Magdalena's disappearance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-what were you firing at?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only lead on Magdalena -- we're after the same guy you idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sag under the weight of my own insomnia-fed stupidity.</context>
      <utterance>-write that name down: `Magda-LEE- na' or `Magda-LAY-na.'  No, we were after you. But thanks for the name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Raise my face now, eyes intent, chin out.</context>
      <utterance>Assumed the Feds were smart. Assumed they were ready to stick a new probe into the LAPD's deal with Hector, like Bradley warned, like everyone feared. But they had no clue and I just handed them the whole God damn thing.  Like I said: I need sleep...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Noonan stops, turns back to me: blazing.</context>
      <utterance>First punch you ever thrown Noonan? Your Mom have to teach you how because Dad was the same no-chin, Connecticut Faggot you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He winds up an overhand right: a big-bright flash, then darkness that feels like lying down on a sunlit lawn.</context>
      <utterance>I think I hit the Noonan family dynamic, dead-on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERBY #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to take him in?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>BLACK dissolves to something LIGHTER, then:</context>
      <utterance>I only want to bring him in when I know he'll never leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toss the dress shirt to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Ice. Bradley's on his way down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's mine...you needed some mopping up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who found me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. I got there at eleven like you said, right as two black &amp; white's pulled up: you were out cold in a gutter `round the block.  Did Noonan knock you out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hit me with his car first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Captain was the only one here at this hour... Look from Junior and Koenig to the window behind him -- Bradley steam-rolling our way. To Koenig, conspiratorial:</utterance>
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I need your help later on, can I count on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take the pitcher from him, drop my head, douse myself, the cold cuts cobwebs. Bradley walks in, imperious. Koenig moves past -- ice forms between the two.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lieutenant was thirsty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I point to Junior -- happy to play teacher's pet:</context>
      <utterance>Progress on Magdalena.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-rubbing the back of my head where the Peeper bashed me-</context>
      <utterance>No fingerprints. Clean crime scene. Canvassed the neighborhood. A senile neighbor did report a possible Peeper-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley turns to me:</context>
      <utterance>-confirmed Peeper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that who knocked you out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noonan knocked me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's having you tailed then...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he knows the Magdalena name and that I was chasing a suspect -- the Peeper Lucille strips for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knows someone watches?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who he is. She has to.  I want access to her juvie sheet or whatever arrest records exist. Rumor was Hector whored her out to dealers he did business with.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's immaterial.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is if you're eliminating her as a suspect-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Point to the ever-studious Junior.</context>
      <utterance>-did you confirm their alibi?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I spoke with a Mr. and Mrs. Preston Mott of Santa Barbara, the parents of Madge Magdalena nee Mott and they've confirmed their visit and also corroborated the argument that resulted in them leaving early.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One alteration to my previous orders-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley conjures the Roman visage...then slowly opens the door, staring holes in me.</context>
      <utterance>-previous orders being what? Assign the Cop Noonan blames for his dead boxing probe to the case that's becoming his new crusade?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior balks, looks my way: tries to mimic my sneer. I stand and shove him toward the door. His look back at me: Judas. Bradley closes the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Step out Stemmons.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No direct approach on the mother or the daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Madge was a battered wife and Lucille was a suborned whore. If that's not motive, what is? You want answers then we brace those two hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you do so directly, if they're formally questioned then Noonan may find out and go after them with Federal warrants.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noonan will figure out who and what Hector was sooner or later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes he will, so we buy time, keep him busy-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-until when?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until Tom Bethune votes on the floor of the city council in two days, ratifying the official start of construction on Dodger stadium-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-this is bigger than a fucking ballpark! Hector Magdalena and Narco is the powder-keg, blows the whole Department to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be dramatic, it looks weak. Right now, Noonan needs a pursuit, so I supply him with one-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-me. You want me to draw him off-</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley walks. Watch him disappear down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>-you've been drawing him off. And the more he sees you the less he'll think of anything other than getting you. Now find Tommy and take him alive. Do not let Noonan get to him. As a potential major case witness against the LAPD, Tommy Magdalena isn't just a powder- keg, he's an atom bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bradley has a bigger angle and I'm getting close to it...I just haven't hit home. Yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior bitchy, like some broad you stood up:</context>
      <utterance>Seltzer will take the blood out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give you the shirt off my back and you bash me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior balls the shirt, stuffs it in his desk drawer. Takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>When a Superior Officer tells you to leave the room, you leave the fucking room.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The one you asked about.</context>
      <utterance>I made a file on the Bledsoe broad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. But forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reminded, glance at my hand: "A I N G E" in smeared ink. Junior rips open a file, blathers Bledsoe preliminaries:</context>
      <utterance>I spent a whole day putting it together and this skirt's got skeletons.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoplifting in Bakersfield at 17. Prostitution arrest at 21. Known associate of a Kern County homicide victim, this convicted pimp named Dwight Gillette, probably her pimp. Stabbed to death in his home, weapon never recovered-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take the file from him, flip through; thorough, detailed. Glenda priors scream back instant conviction.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. Burn it, s'not important now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Plant the file in his chest as my answer.</context>
      <utterance>Why is it not important?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need an address on a guy named Ainge, George Ainge-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My temper turning threadbare.</context>
      <utterance>-what about Magdalena?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-after you get the Ainge address, get back to the Magda-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snap-grit-grab him: buttons from his shirt pop, bounce.</context>
      <utterance>-is Ainge related to this Cunt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dig Junior trying to hide tears now behind that mad-dog glare: makes me want to break the bones in his face.</context>
      <utterance>We're partners in name only. You want to stay in the room next time, Junior? Do something to impress me: like finding that address.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Run a red light at Rossmore, leave the Packard behind.</context>
      <utterance>Noonan replaced the Buick with a Packard and a better Shadow-Man. But I could still spot the tail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This jet-engine urge to see her. Needing it like a junkie does. No logic. Just the push.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My heart jammed up into my throat. Push past it.</context>
      <utterance>Better looking than the last guy Howard hired. Once you heal.  Wait a minute. You were there, the other night, the Bethune Party...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey told me this `Bent Cop' everybody used to call-  -`The Enforcer' was asking about me. Told me to be careful. So you're LAPD after all...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In theory.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to arrest me for breaking and entering?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends.  Those Howard's?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's Howard's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just shop here now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of our extras haven't had a vegetable since Truman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attack of the Atomic Vampires...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Plus it pays bills.</context>
      <utterance>We can't all be Audrey Hepburn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than a billionaire does? Go make amends and finish out your service contract Ms. Bledsoe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if there was just one day left on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drop that coffee cup from the other night into her bag. She's beat, but bluffs by.</context>
      <utterance>You're also better than a starring role in schlock horror flick that'll never see a screen, regardless if it's leading lady gets `kidnapped' or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't the first time you've spied on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nor the second.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you've got me all giftwrapped, Enforcer-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Dave. You're on Hughes' bad side Ms. Bledsoe. It's not a bright place to be. So please go-</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she twirls off, gone...watch her go...my radio buzzes.</context>
      <utterance>-Glenda.  And tell Howard I'll take my chances with the fake vampires.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klein. Go ahead...</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignition. Gas. Tires catch smoke as I peel away.</context>
      <utterance>Message from a Lester Lake: asked that you contact him immediately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-click. Fuck. Fish for another slug. Redial. One ring. Picked up, same background din-</context>
      <utterance>Get me Lester. This is Lieutenant Klein, LAPD-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A muffled back and forth before Lester comes on the line:</context>
      <utterance>-this is LAPD-put Lester on the phone or I'll have your liquor license and after-hours permits yanked inside the hour...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girl that works here, gigs the late sets, the torch stuff Fridays and Saturdays, name of Tilly Hopwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw her singing the other night.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's been truckin' with Tommy Mag. Got pipes like Ella but she's a junk fiend: caught her mainlining in the ladies room a month back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heroin? Tommy get her hooked?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunno, but when he'd get drunk, he'd trade Horse for blowjobs out back a' the club.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's this girl now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't show up for work last night. Called a friend of hers, a waitress that works here too, said she was at Bido Lito's in Hollywood. Said she was `hiding out.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She actually said `hiding out?'</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTER LAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-Hang up. Paw the phone book. Tear out the address for Bido Lito's.</context>
      <utterance>Then she got off the phone. Fast. If Tilly's running with that demon, you gotta get her out of there. She got a lot more good in her than not-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhite rips free. Beet-red.</context>
      <utterance>Did he kill your piece-a'-shit pimp Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or was it that Peeper across the street that jacks off to your sad little shows-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At Wilhite:</context>
      <utterance>Dave, please! CHIEF BRADLEY!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Magdalena's body!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you- -shove him, show him the brass knucks-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior beating on the door.</context>
      <utterance>-you're gonna shell it out for me or I'm gonna kick your teeth in...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brass knucks gleam, get close, kow him completely.</context>
      <utterance>I outrank you Klein! Are you out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fingered Tommy for his father's disappearance and pressed me to do the same to cover your ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the prime suspec-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-he was screaming about `set-ups,' and about how a `Cop' killed Hector --he thought I was you Wilhite.  The gray Packard that gunned him down showed up three minutes after my dispatch call...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-so cops killed him too, is that the kind of bullshit you wa-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-not just cops. Narcotics Cops. You clip Hector, then his kid becomes collateral &amp; you gotta clip him too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-you're paddlin' air pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I? Where's Hector? You can't file murder charges without a corpse. Who knows this? Cops know this- You would know this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-I'm going to the review board and have you cited for- -keep him off balance. Big curveball-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Read it: that stung him...</context>
      <utterance>-When'd Hector start pimping Lucille?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--When did he start whoring out his own daughter to sweeten business deals?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no fucking idea what you're-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watch his face. Something flickers.</context>
      <utterance>-he ever offer her to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm married!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stare it out of him...already pink features go fuchsia.</context>
      <utterance>And about to be divorced. Have you ever fucked Lucille?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Red and blue light strobe from outside. Look: an unmarked caravan arrives. Bradley leading the charge, leaping from his sedan. Wilhite gets a split-second's worth of gloat/glee.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care where you get your dick wet Wilhite. I care that you're covering. Twenty years dirty with this fucked-up family...your secrets must stink like rot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're worried about every wrong thing Klein. Bradley's tee'ing you up to take a big fat fall-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhite focuses, sees the Feds inside, snapping pictures of the Magdalena home...</context>
      <utterance>-then we'll hold hands on the way down: look further up the street.  The Black Buick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Wilhite wide-eyed. Slouching/sinking down onto the toilet. Somebody beating on the bathroom door hard. Bradley's voice behind it.</context>
      <utterance>Feds. They're all over this. You think I'm the only one that burns? Two decades worth of twisted shit between your division and the biggest dope dealer in LA?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Open the door.</context>
      <utterance>I know I'm going down Dan...that's the difference between you and me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said `no direct approach!'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were instructed to take Tommy Magdalena alive. Do I have to remind you of the coroner's file-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-enough of your `Sanderline' bullshit.  I'll checkmate with an admission of guilt to Noonan himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your voice down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley stoic, assessing me...sees only `fuck-you' resolve.</context>
      <utterance>I'll bargain immunity in exchange for testimony on how the LAPD really runs: Magdalena dope profit kickbacks, Diskant run out of the city council race on your word, suspended cops pulling shakedowns. I'll give Noonan a dozen new probes for the one I killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm assuming command of this investigation myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What investigation? Tommy's murder? Hector's disappearance? What are you investigating?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Go right at him, cut his steam.</context>
      <utterance>You're on one month's unpaid leave as of this moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're scamming something big.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See red. Launch. Try to wrap my hands around his throat. Watch him feather back just out of reach. Junior and a pair of six-packs restrain me.</context>
      <utterance>-if you make any further inquiries into this case I'll strip you of rank, have your pension revoked and walk that coroner's file into the Times myself...stay away from this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes beam back doom.</context>
      <utterance>What's your fucking angle Bradley!?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're done Klein. Soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave listen: don't do anything else to jeopardize yourself...I can protect you...I've been putting some things together- Rip my radio, punch the call button.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Static. Wait. Anger make my eyes ache, fuzz my focus.</context>
      <utterance>Central, this is Klein, I need an update on that overdose I called in. What's the girl's condition?</utterance>
   <speaker>DISPATCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rage flares, slam the radio into the dash console, crushing it- fists flex, blood seeps from a battered knuckle, look at my hands: blood drool over the faint remains of the pen- scrawled `A I N G E'...Glare up at Junior:</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant Klein, the girl, Tilda Hopwell was pronounced D.O.A. at Hollywood Presbyterian Hospital-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George Ainge's address.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in no state to conduct yourself as a Police Offic-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLACK. Then a light turns on somewhere: my gun in a round man's face just through his front door. GEORGE AINGE.</context>
      <utterance>-shut up. Don't identify yourself, don't badge him, don't talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior's `betrayed' look: this guy is tied to that Cooze.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know Glenda Bledsoe?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knew that whore'd try to muscle me-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughs in my face:</context>
      <utterance>-don't call her a whore again.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-I grab a chair cushion, put the .45 against it, fire a muffled round that blows Ainge's hair back as it passes. Junior twitches hard enough to spot himself. Ainge jabbers:</context>
      <utterance>If you gave her as many paychecks as me, you'd know `whore' fits like a fuckin glov-</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She fucked for a fee! Jesus Christ she's a pro! What is she paying to get that blade back-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What `blade?'</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Junior banana peels it -- deliberately:</context>
      <utterance>What's she paying you to recover her knife?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hate-scowl for Junior: trying to put enough heat behind it to melt his head. Ainge lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all are Cops!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ainge sees me bent on Glenda. Looks past me, past the gun in his face, aims right at Junior.</context>
      <utterance>Shut your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior fixes me, pulls that steno, starts scribbling openly -- I grab it, shred it. Ainge grins at the voodoo between us.</context>
      <utterance>Back in `50, Glenda the Good Witch put a blade in her pimp `bout as deep as I put my pink in her, this mongrel named Dwight Gillette.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could use a couple LAPD favors, and ain't guttin' a pimp still a crime?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Capitol crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE AINGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess who she asked to hold the knife? Guess why she brought me in on this kidnap thing? It was her way a' buying it back-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-show it to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flip the mattress. Teen Tit mags and jack-off socks fly with it. Ainge under pine slats. Panic. I put my foot through, bash his gut -- rip him out from underneath.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not arresting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ainge unable to speak, gasping for air. Step to his closet: shred hinges when I open it. Rip the clothes rod down: nothing. Pull shelves from the wall: a Louisville Slugger falls at my feet. I smile. Ainge goes frightwig. Step to him.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-go black. Then eyes open...out for hours/days/months...what? Feel. Hangman's bruise forming around my neck. Junior and Ainge gone. Floorboards under Ainge's bed pried-up. Crawl to the hole: a hiding spot, empty of whatever was in it.</context>
      <utterance>Last time you push me out a door! For a dirty split-tail! You're-  -not dragging me down! If Bradley doesn't get you, Noonan will! And-  -you're gonna burn all by yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I check my watch: 11 PM.</context>
      <utterance>Call it: the knife was here. Ainge was crawling under his bed not to escape me, but to hand it over. Too hate-wired to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior the Player. Junior the Underestimated. Junior the Former Evidence Teacher: a murder weapon, a witness, a two-hour head-start.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Rip at a locked return, jimmy the desk drawers, feel the underside for a key -- zilch. Slide under, looking...nothing. Sit up, grab his phone, dial out...</context>
      <utterance>Everything inspection neat. No mail, no personal items. Eagle scout perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meg wake up Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Rustling and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>...Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take some pills, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a grand to locate and tail Junior Stemmons.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Find a letter opener, fuck it -- pry the drawer loose.</context>
      <utterance>Your partner?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Past tense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Pop. The lock snaps. Ease it open...</context>
      <utterance>Two grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look inside. Red steno pads. A small orderly pile. Pull one, thumb it-- blank.</context>
      <utterance>Done. Tell me what he does, who he talks to, where he goes, and if he's got this mutt named George Ainge stashed somewhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Stemmons' address?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hang up. Voices arrive. Hustle to my desk, sit, grab a reverse directory, fake flip through it as Fritz Koenig and two Robbery Blueshirts arrive, seizure bags over their shoulders. I clear sweat and leftover blood with my sleeve, trying to look busy as Koenig sidles up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm working on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You moonlighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing some ad hoc dope seizures for Dan Wilhite.  Still love taking the occasional door down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were born for the street Fritz. I never featured you for the suit and tie set.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're of a common bloodline Boy-o.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get that haul?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig, his knuckles and fingernails caked with blood, pulls a three-pound brick of heroin from the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Some reformed spic dope dealers that normally dabble in reefer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scramble a joke to keep Koenig from looking at me too closely...</context>
      <utterance>Seized from Chavez Ravine. Thirty pounds. The City is cracking down on the dreaded to make room for their beloved Dodgers. They remove the Mexicans, we remove the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig laughs big, re-shoulders the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Why? They could hawk heroin right along with peanuts and hot dogs. Have the whole bleacher section goofing on horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new found dedication these days? What's prompting such odd hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Playing catch-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boy Chief seems to be running both of us ragged.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He currying favor with Chief Parker with this Chavez Ravine sweep?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker appreciates Bradley's political skills...and the addition of a professional Ball-club to our fare city fulfills his own personal mandate of a cleaner, brighter, LA.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds boring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look up. Let him see it in my face: humorless and half lit.</context>
      <utterance>Stale milk to me too. And how are you faring? Is our visiting U.S. Attorney still in hot pursuit?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Borrowed time Fritz.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything I can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...a small favor.  Stemmons home address if you have it. He's in a bit of a bind.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bigger than your own?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot bigger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>3160 Rossmore. Apartment 6.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you want me to clip Stemmons?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. By now, he's stashed Ainge, so he's travelling solo.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this `Ainge' clown anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not important.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Milteer wants a progress report on the Movie Broad -- Bledsoe- -hang up. Roll to my car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could say something witty about "gentleman callers at this hour, covered in blood" but-- No time to trade repartee. Out with it:</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes rigid, clutches her robe.</context>
      <utterance>George Ainge.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that his?  Is he dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like I punched her in the mouth. Her face: embarrassment cut with confusion. She recovers quick, steels herself.</context>
      <utterance>No. But I know about Dwight Gillette and the knife you're trying to barter back. All of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you here? Y'should be picking up a paycheck from Hughes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not watching you for him anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're planning on shaking me down for `favors,' go pick-up your paycheck Mr. Klein. Or are you being a policeman right now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps closer. I can smell her.</context>
      <utterance>The good ones are called `Policemen.' The bad ones are called `Cops.' I'm a Cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another `cop' has this information on you. He has the murder weapon too. He might use it against you before I can stop him. Can you go somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're protecting me? You don't even know me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, drifts somewhere, a part of her life thought dead, threatening everything again...</context>
      <utterance>Just the parts you wish I didn't. The place in Topanga Canyon where your going to hole up for the kidnapping thing. Is it safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your coat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Ainge know about this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I didn't want to tell him till after.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Put the car into `park.' Idle. She looks over, her eyes asking something. I hold her gaze, hesitate, then:</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She frets with her hair, her eyes glassy.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing's going to happen to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat...I want to grab her and kiss her. I convince myself otherwise, grab a card from my coat and a pen, scrawl.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna let it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hand her the card. We touch. I linger. So does she.</context>
      <utterance>This is my sister's number. Name is Meg. Call if there are problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Continue past. Those Process Geeks keep buzzing my doorbell.</context>
      <utterance>Bradley trying to bury me too. That subpoena means my fifteen year career with the LAPD just went up in smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey-</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Junior's left the fucking planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I swung by his apartment, car was out front. I scoped it: a sawed- off shotgun in front, canned tuna in the back seat. Think he's living outta that car. After he left, I tried to get inside his place: The front door is triple pad-locked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That knife is in there-</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shit. Ignore it, maybe Pete will too.</context>
      <utterance>-the what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me down the street from his place. You got bolt cutters?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bring `em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's car is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long story.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior looked real skeezed this morning. Like he was on a dope jag.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweated up like a stuck pig. And be careful. He was fucking around with his front door before he left. I don't know what he was doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two honks if he shows. Then meet me in the alley, back of his place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milteer has called me twice.</context>
      <utterance>What about this Bledsoe broad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing at a time pal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bear traps barely hidden under sheets. Rat-traps garnished with razor blades across the floor. Smell rotten flowers: his shirt that I wore/bled-on crumpled on his pillow -- yellowed jizz stains cover black blood stains. Stifle a gag. Card table: an empty green-banded evidence bag. Gape at it. Then walk over, read the abstracts: 1284 South Tremaine.</context>
      <utterance>Junior the Insane: You couldn't hide what he was hiding in 1958 LA, and not have it rot your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior stealing evidence from the Magdalena crime scene.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Civil servants can't afford manicures?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breaking and entering, theft, and willful destruction of private property...and I'll add attempted murder to the current first degree murder charge I'm about to file against you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proof. If you had it, you wouldn't be fucking around with shitty shakedown routine -- you'd file. Coercion equals confession. So let's see you pound it out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the files you stole from Sergeant Richard Stemmons.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior. Your secret weapon right? I mean, I know J. Edgar is a slanted fuck, but traditionally `vicious fags' don't make the best major case witnesses.  I'm worried those burning dildos may have damaged his credibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I don't need his testimony Klein. I'll just force yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you had the next hundred years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sanderline Johnson, your links to Sam Giancana to Mickey Cohen, extortion, bribes, murder-for-hire. I'll put you in every pair of cross- hairs I can find. I'll torch everything you've ever touched. You have no idea how deep I run Klein. And how far I'm willing to go to fuck you-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-everyone knows I'm a piece-a-shit. What are you proving? Bradley's the guy flanking you right now. The guy who's vulnerable right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all angles and graft Klein. Why trust a God damn word that comes out of your-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-you done anything with the Magdalena case?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prelims: drug pusher gone missing, presumed dead, we're investigat-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Dealing drugs for 20 years! Arrested once. Hall a' fame career! You photographed the head of Narco in-front of his house...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tell me where Stemmons' files are.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you'd turn. Treacherous yes, traitorous no.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bring them to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving here Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noonan stands, firm:</context>
      <utterance>Then like I said: you only get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way out I speak fast -- the last ace in my deck:</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noonan at the door: please bite-please bite...but he just smirks, walks out. Real panic now: no ideas on what comes next. 15 seconds. Door opens again: one of Noonan's deputies pushes a sheet. Scan it: Federal Witness Agreement. Noonan back: two cups of coffee. Read it over.</context>
      <utterance>I give you the body of Dan Wilhite, head of LAPD's Narcotics Division. Proof of a 20-year criminal collusion between his department and Hector Magdalena and my testimony to link the dots.  Then I leave LA for good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Wilhite?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignore him. Sign the agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Like Sanderline Johnson?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Gulp the coffee back, the burn feels good.</context>
      <utterance>Get me Stemmons files and Wilhite's body by noon tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more tails. I don't want anyone else incriminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get a copy of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stand-nod-take my coffee-leave. Door closes. Noonan shreds the Witness agreement. Tosses it in the trash. Off the baffled Deputy.</context>
      <utterance>After a judge signs it. Now Leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We wait for him to deliver, then we arrest him. You never saw that agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tail him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELLES NOONAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Let him get comfortable...let him believe me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah and they made me leaving the scene. Had to barter out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barter what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete drops the drill.</context>
      <utterance>My Testimony. I signed a Federal Witness Agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bullshit. Noonan's got no intention of honoring it.  They want Stemmons files though. I think Junior's been working angles for awhile, doing his own investigations.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do to his place? Nice quiet neighborhood one minute, Nagasaki the next.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had a hand grenade tied to that.  How much longer do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Few more hours. Maybe. Junior didn't skimp on this thing. I gotta bore right through the face plate.  You got some time now, why don't you get Milteer off my back and go work that Bledsoe broad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You read my mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Label her surprise, her brow that furrows and unfurrows just as quickly. A long moment as she waivers...commits:</context>
      <utterance>Tell me anything. Tell me everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would I start?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why L.A.?  Why is anybody here? Want the rest of the world to know who they are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Me watching her...tucks her hair back over his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>No...I don't think so.  I just love it. I grew up in Seattle. My aunt, every week, she'd take me to the movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The idea that you can outlive yourself...that a part of you goes on, long after you're gone.  Sounds silly doesn't it? `Attack of the Atomic Vampires' being-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Make her laugh. Swear a thousand silent oaths to protect her. He face slowly goes dark.</context>
      <utterance>-your ticket to immortality?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hughes told me he could get me in for this screen test two years ago. Movie with Gregory Peck at Universal. He thought he was humoring me...until I got it. They offered me the role...there in the room. So Howard, who I'm sure never thought in a million years I'd land that part, makes some phone calls and just like that they don't want me anymore.  Nobody calls now. I can't get in to see any studio casting people. He's ruined me in those circles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you still want it-</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-bad enough to put on a silly cheerleading skirt and try to make the most god-awful dialogue sound decent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surrounded by winos in werewolf suits.  That's...dedication.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laughter ebbs, her eyes still shine.</context>
      <utterance>Or desperation. Depends on the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I let the silence take...try not to shatter it with:</context>
      <utterance>I'll get there though.  I'll get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't blanch.</context>
      <utterance>Dwight Gillette.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She actually gets closer, I can feel her breath on me.</context>
      <utterance>He asked me to take his `niece and nephew' to their cousin in Oxnard. These beautiful, funny little kids.  I dropped them off. Didn't ask any questions -- I believed Dwight. A week later I saw their pictures in the Post Office. A week after that their little bodies came in on the tide near San Pedro.  I'll never shake the thought that maybe those poor kids thought I was part of it. That I knew what was going to happen to them. So I pray to God that he let them look in when I put that knife into Dwight.  But I'll never ask his forgiveness for doing it...  Why do they call you `Enforcer?'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've killed 44 men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>33 for War. 2 for principle. 9 for profit -- mostly. Why did you sign with Hughes, knowing what he was?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. A feeling like: `and there we are...'</context>
      <utterance>`For profit -- mostly.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not much good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches my quake. Two breaths with her hand on mine and it all goes quiet: the shakes, the images, the fear. She takes my head, pulls me to her bare breasts. The only things audible: my breathing, a clock ticking. Both slowly fade out.</context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>I don't turn. Pete sits next to me. Sets a shotgun down.</context>
      <utterance>The Knife ain't there. File on top of that middle pile: George Ainge in an `undisclosed locale.'</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior documented everything like a fucking Monk.  Like here: `has evidence' you murdered Sanderline Johnson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>103.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look at Pete. Dark rings, deathbed eyes.</context>
      <utterance>PETE  Kept track of `suspected contract killings' you pulled for the mob.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been up all night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In-case Stemmons made a house-call. He's got every goddamn address of everybody you know...  And you should've told me about the Bledsoe broad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feature Pete, righteously pissed:</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then call Milteer about this dead Pimp Gillette. I'm no legal mind like you, but I'll bet a murder beef would violate her morals clause quick.  Collect the rest of your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want it anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then give that five grand back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete pauses, scoffs, turns back toward Meg's bedroom walks:</context>
      <utterance>Junior stole it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUBSEQUENT TO HER FATAL STABBING OF DWIGHT Gillette, MISS BLEDSOE</context>
      <utterance>People are gonna start lining-up to see you bleed, Pal. Door closes. I flip through Junior's files: the same architect-neat block printing. Find a Glenda entry:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teeth grit. Hide it. Let Koenig talk.</context>
      <utterance>Your young partner called me at my home, early this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavily inebriated. Speaking inarticulately of `betrayal,' &amp; how the LAPD was set to be `blitzed by justice.' Is this the `bind' of which we spoke earlier?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And his apartment -- there was some type of disturbance? A fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig looks back at me. Give nothing away...one gesture that doesn't read right and he'll know. He lets more seconds pass than he should. Trying to shake me.</context>
      <utterance>That's why I needed his address. I was trying to help him before something like this happened. The kid snapped-in-half Fritz. He's literally lost it.  He say anything else to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only that he was in possession of materials that might deeply damage Chief Bradley...and yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said Fritz, he's flipped his lid. I don't want to go to Internal Affairs but I'm afraid Junior might've forced just that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me try to locate the lad first Dave. Be a shame to ruin such a young career so soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spin, press on toward Bradley's office.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful Fritz. He's dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Reach Bradley's office, burst in. Empty. To his Secretary:</context>
      <utterance>Fritz Koenig, the best inspector in the LAPD, digging. He'll find Junior and when he does he'll find Ainge...then Glenda...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out at the Ravine Lieutenant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Reporters press. Bradley handles them with ease and aplomb.</context>
      <utterance>Bradley doing damage control, the forced relocation of the Ravine's immigrants has the press in a feeding frenzy. Reuben Ruiz forced along as the token Mexican mouthpiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-this area has long been rife with crime and venality, but with a brand new Stadium, we can make this horrible blight a bright spot and give our Los Angeles Dodgers the home they deserve.  Reuben Ruiz can tell you of his travails growing up in this horrible slum and why now is the time to `Redeem The Ravine.'</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief Bradley, U.S. Attorney Noonan has promised to deliver surprise witnesses before the Federal Grand jury on- -Bradley, this brilliant rebuke:</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Bradley sees me. His press-friendly face contorts, the shift startling: if only a flashbulb could've framed it. He shifts back from snarl to smile...</context>
      <utterance>-Welles Noonan is an unscrupulous hack politician whose smear campaign against us will fail, for he has grievously underestimated the moral rectitude of the Los Angeles Police Department.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ruiz begins his forced/coerced/do-it-or-we'll-fuck-you sob story as Bradley steps away from the glare. I follow. Get right on his heels.</context>
      <utterance>Now if you'll excuse me, I'll leave you with Reuben Ruiz.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley spins back.</context>
      <utterance>Your subpoena hasn't caught up to me yet, Chief...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bradley blanches, buckles. I see it. Before he can play stupid with: `What?'</context>
      <utterance>Hurwitz Holdings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bradley removes his glasses, staring at documentation that dooms both his immediate and distant future...</context>
      <utterance>You, Bethune, and Gallaudet bought big chunks of Chavez Ravine over the past two years through a shell company called Hurwitz Holdings.  If the Dodgers move here the value of the land booms...you could sell it off for a fortune -- or hang onto it and make even more. The parking lots alone would make you all multi-millionaires.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slap another file over the one he's reading.</context>
      <utterance>Word gets out that the three City Officials who were pushing hardest for a Stadium also stood to gain a mint -- might color public opinion. Might color it even more to know that the LAPD's Chief of Detectives was trying to purchase a huge tract of that land from the biggest dope dealer in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector Magdalena owned ten and half acres of this land.  You didn't give a shit about solving his disappearance. You were worried that your real estate deal was going south.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>108.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All Bradley can muster is:</context>
      <utterance>ME  That's why you wanted Tommy found, not because he was a murder suspect or you were concerned that Noonan might tap him as a federal witness...you needed him to finalize your fucking land grab. To sign paperwork in place of his dead Dad. That's why you've got Madge and Lucille in custody now.  Maybe I'll let your subpoena find me now Chief, maybe I'll walk right into it...the tales I could tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior Stemmons. The ex-evidence teacher. His `excellent ratings' didn't stop him from stealing the Magdalena seizure and doing his own investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hand him Noonan's business card: dig the big Federal Eagle in American Blue.</context>
      <utterance>Why would he investigate me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. I smile wide at it. Bradley, scrambling.</context>
      <utterance>That was stapled to the cover.  Why would Noonan worry about a Turd like me now...when a high profile target like you can be taken down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Stemmons?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley readjusts his glasses.</context>
      <utterance>No idea. If you haven't spoken to Internal Affairs today, I'm sure they've called. Junior's apartment caught fire. Deeply deviant material inside. Round him up-  -and anyone he's got with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll issue an A.P.B. saying Stemmons is a known deviant targeting kindergarten children.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley's reaction: Feature the angler getting angled.</context>
      <utterance>Now, quid pro quo...you subpoenaed Wilhite too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do y-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley says nothing. Then, like a klieg-light, it hits me.</context>
      <utterance>-don't worry `how.' Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going after Narco yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exposing the corrupt parts of the LAPD will redeem the whole. I'll prove that Police can police themselves-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-so you show-up Noonan...co-opt his crusade and condemn your own before he can...Jesus Christ can you turn lemons to lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Cop will testify against other Cops. This is why Wilhite has suddenly disappeared.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how.  So where do we go now Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are other forces at work here...faces we need to identify. Names we need to know. A third party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>110.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BRADLEY  Find out who Klein and I'll reinstate you, rescind that subpoena &amp; burn the coroner's report on Sanderline-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-that report is only useful to Noonan now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off, imperious, impervious, gets engulfed by the press ranks once again.</context>
      <utterance>No. It ensures our mutual destruction should you choose to share the contents of that Stemmons file. Which I know you won't do until you figure out how it will best benefit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Back to the Powerhawk, fresh-scrubbed six-packs standing near it, the trunk stink ripe past the point of concealment. They see me, deferential nods. One squeaky wheel offers:</context>
      <utterance>A mistake to underestimate me now Chief. The price to keep your secrets is steep...and you're going to pay up. Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIX-PACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something in your trunk smells to high hell Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter. Easily amused academy types. Brush by grinning, give `em an "Enforcer" story to tell the other rookies. I jump in the Powerhawk and tear off.</context>
      <utterance>Dead body.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Borrowed time burning fast. My days are done. Only hours remain. Whatever moves I have left...make them now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meg wanders in, dressed for work.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking Christ. You can't keep that car in the garage, the smell's coming into the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open the windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not gonna help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a couple bottles of bleach, pour it over the trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you got in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My foreseeable future.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses me on my head. I turn:</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You taking her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meg walks out. Pete lingers. I'm starting to sour him. Not smart. He stares. I look up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hughes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is almost over Pete -- I'll give Milteer the five-grand back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll square it. It's my thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you made mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Pete sketches me head to toe.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look as bad as I've ever seen you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete exhales. Stalks off. I keep scribbling.</context>
      <utterance>Things are as bad as they've ever been...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Meg's phone blares, I answer it on reflex.</context>
      <utterance>Bradley's Third Party Theory. Everything linked: Wilhite, Magdalena, the Ravine...I've got my own theories...and the one that sticks is the one I pray I'm wrong about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I hear rasp on the other end, hyperventilating, unhinged.</context>
      <utterance>Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MOTHERFUCKER -- you better meet me! That Cooze you threw everything away for is still cooked! I got the knife. I got Ainge- Junior. Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get this number Junior?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got everything on you! AND I'M</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The knife for MY file on Bradley. I know you already burned that Whore's but don't think I can't re- do investigations.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You snitch to Noonan, then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Noonan. I got stronger Allies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? The Soviets?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me in one hour with that file, Fern Dell Park-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Where you used to snag fruits for Vice? A volunteer gig I'm guessing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be there with Bradley's file or I scratch your scabby Bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone on the other end seems to break-in half. Hang up, it rings a beat later. Junior still wanting to spar. Snag the receiver, rip his shit:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, did the Feds dig your pad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-I see anybody near there Junior, the deals off and I gift that file to Bradley to fuck you with-</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Dave?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's got her. Junior. Sick. Evil. My mind cannibalizes itself with "where-is-she-how-do-I-get-her-back" when:</context>
      <utterance>Glenda?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA BLEDSOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't have her. A sigh so big, it steals all my air...</context>
      <utterance>Sorry...you gave me this number...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who were you talking-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Glenda in a chaise lounge on a small deck overlooking the canyon. She sits up.</context>
      <utterance>-no, no. It's nothing. I had a phone call, just before yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it him? The Cop you were telling me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to worry. I'm handling it. But I might send my friend Pete out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think it's safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just rather have someone there with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you would've woken me up this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs. Makes me smile despite my world caving-in...</context>
      <utterance>I'm better-looking in low light, I didn't want to blow it for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay by the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And I melt. Love-struck at possibly the worst fucking moment of my life. Hang up before your voice breaks. Grab a pen, scrawl for Pete, post it on the fridge magnet: `PETE: 655</context>
      <utterance>I miss you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior, this evil little curl. He turns. Follow him over a small knoll: that Gray Packard, waiting. A silhouette behind the wheel. As we near it the lights come on, blind me.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause in the car, Junior looks at me like I'm Rasputin, divining answers from the marine-layer moving-in over LA. The lights pop off and I hear a tired laugh coming from the car that we've all heard before.</context>
      <utterance>Turn your lights off...and just come out and talk to me...Fritz.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Fritz Koenig steps out of the Packard.</context>
      <utterance>Third Party Confirmed...I fucking knew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much with these sub-rosa things...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was Noonan tailing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior, jumpy in my periphery. I don't like it.</context>
      <utterance>Bradley's greatest stroke was enlisting you to his side.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilhite ran Magdalena for you, not Narco.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't. I had a feeling. I smelled cover-up all over Hector's disappearance and Wilhite wouldn't have the muscle or the mind-set to kingpin something that big by himself...you knew about Bradley trying to buy him out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was offering to exonerate Hector and clear his criminal record. Hector met with Wilhite and I to inform us of his decision...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Koenig pets Hector's twin Doberman guard dogs.</context>
      <utterance>...to accept Bradley's deal...</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Koenig draws a silenced pistol and shoots both dogs before shooting a shocked Hector twice in the chest. Wilhite staggers to his feet as Koenig steps over and delivers the coup de grace head-shot to Hector.</context>
      <utterance>...and although the terms of that deal worked well for him. I found them less than favorable...</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darktown. Chavez Ravine. Hot Spots for Human Vice. These are slums I run &amp; profit from. If these slums suddenly become Stadiums, that profit goes elsewhere...that crime goes elsewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig grins. Junior keeps shifting. Dying to shoot him dead.</context>
      <utterance>Bradley...you two got greed in common.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's how you were operating him.</context>
      <utterance>You knew about Wilhite and Lucille.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was aware of his sexual predilections.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and someone else's...</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We share an eye for human frailty and we're both born blackmailers Dave.  I knew young Stemmons here had a fondness for Lads, stretching back to his days at the academy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And like he was waiting for those words: Junior lunges. I twist to deflect but he's too fast -- feel something sink and drag in my side. I go down, gouge/groping for my gun. Instant trauma zaps nerves numb up the arm, fingers failing. Then a pain like boiling oil moves through my blood.</context>
      <utterance>And now you're his only ally.  This sad queer who fell out with cops and flunked out with the Feds.  So you get this file to battle Bradley with. What's Junior get in return?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Junior, his own .45 pulled, put to my head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to watch...I'm sorry it came to this, Dave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNIOR STEMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Koenig reads the file's first page, lifts it...a blank page behind...and behind that one...</context>
      <utterance>I hope the Bledsoe whore was worth it...'cuz she's still fucked. For a crooked cop, you think small.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Koenig spins back, more blank pages spilling from the file.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever moves I had left...I just made.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-Junior looks: that's all I need. Pull the pig-sticker off my ankle and corkscrew it into his calf, twisting. Junior bleats slaughtered-lamb as I reach up a wrench his gun free. Grab his tie, pull him down as I jut his gun up under his chin and fire two shots through the top of his head. Haul him down dead by his tie, turn -- Koenig's gun-hand flashes to his shoulder. Shoot him twice. He goes down gargling `fuck'. Stand-up on me sea-legs, bad wobble/weave as I slowly pull the knife from my side, pocket it. Feel blood flow saturate my pant leg. This weird wooze overcomes me as I approach Koenig. He pulls himself into a sitting position, shaking his head. This bemused, beaten, half-grin as he flicks blood from his hand like his fingers had just brushed something sticky.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't it!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Say nothing. Keep Junior's .45 out. My intention crystal clear: endgame. Koenig looks up, this odd squint, like a bum about to beg for change.</context>
      <utterance>Poorly played Dave...poorly played...</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut you in on something?</context>
      <utterance>Could I talk you into something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>119.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him no hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, remorse, resignation...it at all looks the same now.</context>
      <utterance>Won't work for me Fritz.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I do. Watch his hands as he removes his shoes, waiting for an ankle grab, his back-up piece...none comes. He sets his shoes aside, gazing up at the starless sky before issuing this short, gruff laugh...some inside joke that will die untold.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a minute then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOENIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and he holds his last breath and seems completely content as I shoot him. Cross to Junior now, rifle his clothes, retrieve a hotel key, Room 16, read it: MOTEL COMMODORE - 1195 Centinela Ave. Inglewood, CA 90302</context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fritz Koenig.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead. Along with Wilhite, Junior...and Hector Magdalena.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley, prim, proper, even this early. He sits down across from me like some fucking Duke.</context>
      <utterance>To collect. I have the things you need to destroy Noonan's play. These same things can be used to destroy you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things like?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stemmons files...and Wilhite's body. He committed suicide after you subpoenaed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just nod.</context>
      <utterance>This body is in your possession?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's what you need to burn Narco to the ground...but if those files and his body were to be given to Noonan and the Feds, with me providing the cherry-on-top testimony of a rogue cop. Well. The word `Cataclysmic' comes to mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will this cost?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley scoffs, pithy smile.</context>
      <utterance>A percentage of your Dodger Stadium stake in perpetuity. You buy my silence for a fourth of Hurwitz Holdings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doubtful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bradley: an actual, full-blown facial tic. His Adam's apple bobs as he realizes that he's finally been beaten.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you expect? A stick-up? Empty your safe? I'm about to disappear for good, and you're gonna fund my new life. You can't counter-punch out of this. Arrest me and I snitch the world.  I'll hold that over your head for the rest of your life. Renege on our deal and it won't matter if it's tomorrow or ten years from now...I'll fry you with that file.  I'm officially outta time now Chief. Call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilhite's body...Bury it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shaking to see her, touch her...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer as I follow him into the house.</context>
      <utterance>You go to bed drunk, or just been up all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Glenda, is she asle-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Instant-drop, moan. Glenda screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Seen Pete do this a dozen times and every time the same thought: God help me if he ever hits me like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pete looks to Milteer, wipes blurred eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pete bludgeons me. I try to get closer to Glenda. Feel my nose shatter. Another swing: right cheek detonates. A left hook to take advantage of my momentum: left eye explodes. Glenda's crying/screaming gets me madder than anything.</context>
      <utterance>The harder you hit him the quicker I say `stop' -- and cease that absurd crying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-touch me and he dies. Pete knocks me down again. My face in pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Pete hesitates, puts his boot into my guts: 1, 2, 3-</context>
      <utterance>Kick him-kick him-kick him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Milteer produces a Polaroid, takes a snapshot of my shattered husk, hands the camera to Pete on his way out:</context>
      <utterance>-you may stop.  Howard determined that this was the price for your time together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MILTEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milteer gone. I spit volumes of blood. I'll talk with a slur for the next year. Pete reaches for me, blotto, sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>You still have a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pushing out words past shattered teeth.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm sorry Dave...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I put you here...that Powerhawk-</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-there's a body in the trunk-</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big drunk nod from Pete. Glenda panicking, trying to stanch blood that keeps rushing. Pete, reeling drunk, leans down, stuffs something in my jacket.</context>
      <utterance>-burn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me take you to a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd never make it inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She frames my face with her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm through the worst of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lies will only leak, expose. The silence makes me just as guilty. She lets me off the hook, her head on my arm, leaning in. I kiss her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was I worth this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever the cost.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like that then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod. An understanding. Another kiss, the last one I'll remember.</context>
      <utterance>Just like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cop-killings clear the way for Bradley's "Redeem The Ravine' mandate. Dodger Stadium construction moves forward.  Captain Dan Wilhite and Hector Magdalena. Missing. APB's issued. Bradley's press fodder cast them as `outlaw cop and drug dealer' who most likely fled to Mexico. Narco under a full-blown, Bradley-led investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRADLEY</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...police unit run amok, who's long tradition of graft, does not extend to other divisions of the LAPD...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Gillette knife, fold it in a kerchief, gift-wrap it to Glenda. Place a letter under it on the night stand:</context>
      <utterance>I haven't loved you long enough to leave it all behind...Too many enemies. Too many ways for you to get hurt. Too close to me...a decision that will haunt me the rest of my days...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"My Heaven: the hours I had with you. My Hell: the years ahead, without. Someday I'll see you before you even know I'm looking."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Up to the TWA counter: glance up at the departures board-</context>
      <utterance>Pete's penance beating built me a brand new face...nobody gives me a second glance...not even the cops I recognize.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Legend: Recife, Brazil, 1978</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>127.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look back down at HER picture.</context>
      <utterance>ME   Me: gringo exile rich off funds from Stadium Parking lots. Meg and Pete: still married. Three boys. Boyce Bradley: Lt. Governor, then a Gubernatorial primary loser to some chump who acted in Chimp movies. Welles Noonan, convicted of jury tampering in `64. Prison suicide in `66. Howard Hughes: a shut-in shitting in coffee-cans at the Vegas Hilton.  George Ainge: body found, murder unsolved. Madge Magdalena, liver failure in `68. Lucille Magdalena: Mother of five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Put her photo in my chest pocket. Push the week-old Times into a waste-basket: a Pan-Am ticket to LA underneath.</context>
      <utterance>Glenda: twenty-five years avoiding her name. Only a photograph, yellowed with years-passed, reminding me of everything I never was.  Then a week-old Times at the place I buy coffee. Her picture sees me before I realize she's looking. Her Face eternal-beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>ME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I stand, shatter the mirror that reminds me of how long. And as I step out, an old man twenty-five years too late, and my MGM-handsome, 1958 face smiles back at me through the shards.</context>
      <utterance>...and it asked me to revoke our time apart, redeem it...tell her anything...tell her everything...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
