<movie id="597" title="Who Framed Roger Rabbit">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"WHO SHOT ROGER RABBIT?"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Written by Jeffrey Price and Peter S. Seaman</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD DRAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>September 2, 1986</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>FOOTSTEPS recede and a DOOR SLAM. Roger turns confidently back to his charge. But the little tyke is already squeezing through the playpen bars.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy's going to the beauty parlor, darling. But I'm leaving you with your favorite friend, Roger. He's going to take very, very good care of you...  ... cause if he doesn't, he's going back to the science lab! Roger gulps as he watches the legs disappear. We HEAR</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger makes a dive for him, misses, and gets his head stuck between the bars. He pleads with the Baby in a voice that resonates of Huntz Hall in "The Bowery Boys".</context>
      <utterance>Baby bye-bye...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, come back! You heard what your mother said!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The cartoon action stops abruptly, but the goofy CARTOON MUSIC PLAYS ON. We begin a slow PULL BACK TO REVEAL that this cartoon is being filmed LIVE ON A SOUND STAGE. The title card sits on an easle. The female legs are paper mache' props manipulated by two HUMAN CREW MEMBERS. Wearily, they lean the legs up against the stage wall. A human DIRECTOR, wearing a tweed jacket and baggy pleated pants, steps onto the set. From the equipment and the dress of the crew, we can tell it's the 1940's. Baby Herman throws his cookie down in disgust. He talks in a gravelly voice an octave lower than Wallace Beery's.</context>
      <utterance>Cut, cut, cut!</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was wrong with</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tweeting bird?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, a tweeting bird. But what does the script say? 'Rabbit gets conked. Rabbit sees</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Raoul. I can give you stars, I know I can. Just drop the safe on my head one more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've already dropped it on you twenty-three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about me. I can take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried about you. I'm worried about the safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Assistants dutifully record his thoughts, Maroon sees a GUY taking a nap in the shade of a palm tree.</context>
      <utterance>Starting tomorrow there'll be no more roast beef lunches. What happened to cheese sandwiches? I was raised on cheese sandwiches.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell that guy sleepin' over there he's fired!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your wife's brother, R.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Assistants disperse, Maroon approaches Valiant.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... tell him he's promoted. But get him out of my sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valiant, did you see the rabbit?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So what?</context>
      <utterance>He was blowin' his lines, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now an EDITH HEAD-TYPE hustles up to show Maroon several costume designs.</context>
      <utterance>So what? He's already put me three weeks behind on the shooting schedule!</utterance>
   <speaker>COSTUMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon quickly checks out the drawing.</context>
      <utterance>Your reaction, R.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! That's not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She flips another drawing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the pad back to the designer, who departs.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, I hope what you have ain't contagious or I'll be out of business.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you know about show business, Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant watches an ALLIGATOR in a rebel uniform dragging a brace of cannons and several TOADSTOOLS parade by.</context>
      <utterance>Only there's no business like it, no business I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you know why?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and there's no business as expensive. I'm twenty-five grand over budget on the latest Bunnysitter cartoon and it's all because that rabbit can't keep his mind on his work.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One too many safes dropped on his head?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon takes a copy of the "Hollywood Tattler" out of his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, that goes with the territory. He's a stunt bunny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the problem...  "Seen cooing over calamari with notsonew Sugar Daddy was Jessica Rabbit... wife of Maroon star, Roger".  His wife's a tramp, but he thinks she's Betty Crocker. The doubt's eatin' him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me a couple juicy pictures. Somethin' I can wise the rabbit up with.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't work in Toontown.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to. The rabbit's wife sings at an underground Toon revue joint called The Ink &amp; Paint Club. You can catch her in action there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The job's gonna cost you a hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred bucks? That's ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>So's the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon turns, snaps his fingers. His Assistant appears out of nowhere with Maroon's checkbook and a pen. The Assistant turns and stoops so that Maroon can write the check on his back.</context>
      <utterance>All right, all right... You got your hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda jumpy aren't you, Valiant? It's just Dumbo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got him on loan from Disney.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant grabs the check from Maroon and starts for the gate.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the lucky one...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will I hear from you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We FOLLOW Valiant out the gate under a wrought iron sign that reads "Maroon Cartoon Studios". As he starts across the road he's almost run over by a Toon roadster that ROARS out of the gates. When it BLASTS ITS HORN, it's the FIRST FIVE NOTES from the WOODY WOODPECKER SONG: "HA-HA-HA-HA-HA". Valiant jumps back as the roadster passes. WOODY THE WOODPECKER'S behind the wheel with a self-important smile on his face. Valiant angrily waves the cloud of Toon dust away.</context>
      <utterance>As soon as is humanly possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn Toons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>hops off his freeloader's seat on the back,</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant waves laconically.</context>
      <utterance>So long, mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We FOLLOW Valiant as he crosses the street to a seedy bungalow. A note is push-pinned to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - NOTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says: "Tomorrow's Friday... Well? Dolores".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, fellas, what's the good word?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ARTHRITIC COWBOY pipes up.</context>
      <utterance>Lost my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>COWBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DEAF-MUTE scribbles a note on a pad hanging around his neck. He hands the note to Valiant. It says "My girl dumped me". Valiant pats him on the back, consoling.</context>
      <utterance>Mule died.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Valiant mouths the rest of it for Augie's benefit only. Augie reads his lips, then starts to roar silently, slapping his thigh. Now Dolores makes her way down the bar. She grabs the Midget by the suspenders and slides him out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know what they say about dames, Augie...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, lemme remind ya pal, it was a</context>
      <utterance>So, makin' dame jokes, huh, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is fifty bucks. I need seventy-five before they check the books tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have it in the morning. Now be a sport and lemme have twenty bucks to put in my pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this paper even good?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check the scrawl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now ANGELO, a Neanderthal sitting a few stools down, is tapping the shell of a hardboiled egg.</context>
      <utterance>R.K. Maroon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo chuckles at his own joke and goes to eat his egg. Suddenly Valiant darkens. He grabs Angelo by the shirt and pulls him up to his face.</context>
      <utterance>Maroon? Valiant, don't tell me you're workin' for a Toon? Who's your client? Chilly Willy or Screwy Squirrel?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this straight, greaseball. I'm not workin' for a Toon! I'd never work for a</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant knocks on the door of, a non-descript building in a run-down factory area. A speakeasy style peephole slides open REVEALING the face of a TOON GORILLA. Valiant offers the password.</context>
      <utterance>Toon killed his brother. EXT. INK &amp; PAINT CLUB - NIGHT</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The peephole slides closed and after a beat the door swings open.</context>
      <utterance>Walt sent me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like your monkey suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We FOLLOW Valiant down the hall toward the main room. We can HEAR LAUGHTER and ZANY MUSIC from within.</context>
      <utterance>Wise ass...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant reaches under himself and comes up holding a deflated rubber bladder. The Geezer retrieves it from him.</context>
      <utterance>Will you listen to that? It's a pip! I'm thinking of callin' it a Whoopee Cushion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant rolls his eyes and grabs a Penguin as it glides by.</context>
      <utterance>Hand buzzer... real gasser.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scotch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENGUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a two drink minimum.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as long as there's no maximum.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Penguin puts a bill down on the Geezer's table and zips off. The Geezer takes a fountain pen out of his jacket and writes on the bill. But there doesn't seem to be any ink coming out. He shakes and shakes the pen to get it flowing. It flows all right. Ink splatters all over Valiant's shirt and pants. Valiant looks down at the stain, doing a slow burn. The Geezer starts laughing. Valiant jumps up and grabs him by the lapels.</context>
      <utterance>Waiter, I'll sign my check now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it for you, pops!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down, son. Look, the ink is gone. Valiant looks down at his shirt. The stain is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? It disappears.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant drops him into his chair and returns to his seat. The Penguin glides up with his drinks. Valiant swallows the first one with one quick jerk of the head.</context>
      <utterance>Well, why don't you make like the ink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CIGARETTE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant turns to see BETTY BOOP standing with a box of tobacco wares strapped around her neck. In contrast to all the other Toons, Betty's in black and white.</context>
      <utterance>Cigars... cigarettes... Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY BOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, it's swell to see you, Eddie. We miss you in Toontown.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish I could say the same. What're you doin' here, Betty?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY BOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work's been slow for me since the cartoons went to color. But I still got it, Eddie...  'Boop boop be-doop'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you still got it, Betty.  Who's Mr. Jocularity?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY BOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Marvin Acme, the gag king.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoulda guessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY BOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He comes here every night to see Jessica Rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big on the musical comedy, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY BOOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the lights dim and Betty moves on.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like you ve never seen her, Eddie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Jessica works her way over to Eddie. She stops at his table and sings tauntingly. Then with a flourish, she throws herself in his lap, and belts out the finale.</context>
      <utterance>'You ain't got no money Ain't got no use for you...'</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is RAUCOUS APPLAUSE when she finishes. Jessica looks deep into Eddie's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>'So get out of here... And get me the money toooo!'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GORILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, whaddaya think you're doin', chump?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gorilla smiles sadistically when he recognizes Valiant.</context>
      <utterance>Who're you callin' chump, chimp?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gorilla grabs Valiant by the belt and lifts him off the ground. He opens the fire door and heaves Valiant out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's da comedian...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GORILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't lemme catch your peepin' face around here again. Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gorilla slams the door. Valiant picks himself up out of the garbage. He brushes himself off, then starts down the alley toward the rear of the building. We FOLLOW him around the corner where he stops under Jessica's dressing room window. He drags over a milk crate to stand on, takes a small camera out of his pocket and opens the bellows. He stands on the crate and aims the camera through the corner of the window, as we HEAR the MUFFLED CONVERSATION from within.</context>
      <utterance>Ooga-booga.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACME</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we going to play pattycake tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode>0.5.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marvin, I have a headache...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACME</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you promised...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Valiant's eyes widen in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, all right. But this time take that hand buzzer off...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he starts CLICKING pictures...</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pattycake! Pattycake!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baker's man... but no use ruinin' a good pair of shoes over it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take comfort, son, you're not the first man whose wife played pattycake on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it. I won't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger takes another look at the pictures.</context>
      <utterance>The pictures don't lie. Mr. Valiant here took them himself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant eyes the booze longingly as he mutters to himself.</context>
      <utterance>But Jessy... she's the light of my life, the apple of my eye, the cream in my coffee...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you better start thinkin' about drinkin' it black.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon gestures out the window. We see a blinking neon sign on the roof of the building across the street -- "Acme - If It's Acme - It's A Gasser!"</context>
      <utterance>Frankly, I'm shocked. Marvin Acme's been my friend and neighbor for thirty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger takes the glass and shoots it down in one gulp.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the important thing now Roger, is to put all this behind you.  Drink this, son, you'll feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this all seems painful now, but you'll find someone new. Won't he, Mr, Valiant? Eddie has just picked up the decanter to pour one for himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dames'll be breakin' his door down.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Good lookin' guy like him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son-of-a-bitch...  Mr. Maroon, I think I'll be goin' now, so about the rest of my fee...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon sits at the desk and writes a check.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Valiant, sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant crosses to the desk and takes the check.</context>
      <utterance>Being experienced in these matrimonial matters, you have any advice for our friend here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My advice? Hop on over to Reno, get yourself a quickie divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Roger jumps onto Maroon's desk and grabs Valiant by the lapels.</context>
      <utterance>Divorce? Never!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're going to be</context>
      <utterance>Marriage is a two-way street and we're just experiencing a detour! Jessica and I are going to get back together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santino ignores the question and regards Valiant with a mixture of disgust and pity.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant Santino... how ya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me you didn't do a snoop job for a Toon named Roger the Rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santino flops open the morning paper. Valiant's eyes narrow as he reads it. The headline screams: "TOON KILLS MAN!" And underneath: "Marvin Acme Murdered at the Hands of Jealous Rabbit". Santino throws the paper on the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>That's what you woke me up for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got trouble, Eddie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just haven't been this close to Toontown for awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>walks back and takes Valiant's arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santino leads Valiant into the factory.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, somebody wants to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say the rabbit got the safe idea from a cartoon he was makin' the other day.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a gasser.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santino walks to Acme's glassed office where a sobbing Jessica Rabbit is being interrogated. We can only see her, not the person doing the interrogating. Valiant sidles over to where the Forensic Guys are dusting the photographs he had taken for prints. One of the Forensic Guys looks up from his work.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORENSIC #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant ignores the slings and arrows and surveys the scene of the crime. The door of the safe is ajar. Valiant tries to look inside. Forensic 2 closes the door with his knee. Now we HEAR the VOICE of Jessica Rabbit from behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Say, didn't you used to be Eddie Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant turns to the voice. WHAP! Jessica slaps him hard enough across the face to make his head turn.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORENSIC #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes you, Valiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes you wonder what in the world she was doin' with a guy who didn't clean his fingernails.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the end of a cane comes down on Valiant's hand, pinning it to the floor. Valiant follows the cane UP to it's gavel-shaped head -- past black pants, a black robe, to a cadaver-like complected face, and a large hooked proboscis. The head is shaved. Rimless tinted glasses obscure the eyes. Although he's human, the total appearance is frighteningly vulture-like. JUDGE DOOM is accompanied by Santino.</context>
      <utterance>It's not blood, it's paint.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this man removing evidence from the scene of a crime?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... no, Judge Doom. Valiant here was just about to hand it over, weren't you, Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom takes his cane off Eddie's hand and reaches out for the paint chip. Valiant palms a piece and drops a smaller piece into Doom's hand. Doom examines it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant stands to face the Judge, who towers over him.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like the deceased grabbed a handful of your client's pantaloons, Mr. Valiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not my client. I was workin' for R.K. Maroon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, we talked to Mr. Maroon. He told us the rabbit became quite agitated when you showed him the pictures, and said nothing would stand in the way of him getting his wife back. Is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, pal, do I look like a stenographer?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom smiles thinly at Valiant, tarns and walks with purpose towards the door. Santino and Valiant follow.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your mouth, Eddie, he's a judge.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rabbit's movements are fairly clear after leaving the Maroon Studios. He ran across the street, jimmied this door open, hoisted the safe on a block and tackle...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom nods his head toward a group of sinister WEASLES (a la Disney's "Wind In The Willows"). They're loitering by a dogcatcher's wagon with "Toontown Control" on the side, cleaning their fingernails with switchblades and polishing Toon revolvers.</context>
      <utterance>... then stood out here waiting for his prey. After he cold-bloodedly accomplished his task, he went home. He was almost apprehended there by my men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Men? They look more like weasles to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I find that weasles have a special gift for the work.  The rabbit didn't contact you by any chance, did he?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would he contact me? I just took some lousy pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you wouldn't have any idea where he might be?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom steps into Valiant's face.</context>
      <utterance>Have you tried Walla Walla? Kokomo's very nice this time of year.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a "YA-HA-HOOEY" interrupts his pontification, as a scruffy little TOON GOPHER comes hurtling over the wall from the Toontown side. He's holding his blackened rear end... apparently the result of a run-in with a stick of dynamite. BONK! The Gopher hits Doom in the back of the head, sending them both sprawling. The Gopher picks himself up and shakes off the effects of the concusion. When he sees who he's knocked down, he panics.</context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised you aren't more cooperative, Mr. Valiant. A human has been murdered by a Toon. Don't you appreciate the magnitude of that? My goal as Judge of Toontown, has been to rein in the insanity. To bring a semblance of law and order to a place where no civilized person has ever been able to step foot. The only way to do that is to make the Toons respect the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, you filthy little vagrant, you've soiled my robe!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cleanin' up real good. Judge.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Doom carries the Gopher to the "Toontown Control" wagon, Valiant shoots a look to Santino.</context>
      <utterance>You've defiled a symbol of justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd this gargoyle come from anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Doom gets to the wagon, the Weasles open up the back. In place of steel bars is a stream of fluid. A Weasle turns a key and the flow of liquid stops. The Gopher starts kicking furiously, trying to avoid the lock-up.</context>
      <utterance>No one knows. He bought the election a few years back. He's been rulin' Toontown ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, the Gopher breaks free and makes a desperate dash for the wall. Doom watches him run and calmly turns to where his car is parked. It's a black Lincoln touring car with an ugly bird-like hood ornament.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, Judge, please, please, lemme go. I think I hear my mother callin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly. the hood ornament SQUAWKS to life. It's a hideous TOON VULTURE. The Vulture flaps into flight. Just as the Gopher is about to make it over the top of the wall the Vulture's talons sink into his rear end and lift him airborne. The Vulture drops the Gopher off with the Weasles. They pin him down.</context>
      <utterance>Voltaire... the Gopher!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't I have any rights?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the Weasles retrieves a briefcase from the sedan, puts it on the hood and snaps it open. Twelve TOON KANGAROOS pop up, arranged in a jury box.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you do... to a swift and speedy trial.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raps the Gopher on the head with the gavel end of his cane.</context>
      <utterance>Court is now in session.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hereby sentence you to the dip!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Judge pulls on a black rubber glove, the Weasles take out a stainless steel tub WHEEZING with sadistic glee. They fill it from a spigot on the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, not the dip! Anything but the dip! I'm too young to die...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the dip?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He calls it the... Final Solution.</context>
      <utterance>That's how he gets rid of the troublemakers. It's a combination of acetone, turpentine and paint remover.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GOPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gopher's gone. All that's left of him is a paint slick on the surface of the liquid.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Help! He...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom pulls off the black rubber gloves finger by finger and hands them to a Weasle. He turns to Valiant.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets into his car, he pauses and looks back at Valiant.</context>
      <utterance>They're not kid gloves, Mr. Valiant. but that's how we handle things in Toontown. I would think you'd appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After all, didn't a Toon kill your brother?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Eddie, looks like you really stepped in it this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant slides the check across the bar.</context>
      <utterance>What are you complaining about? Here's your fifty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROLLEYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-five years and all I got to show for it is a ticket punch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with Earl?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new outfit bought the Red Car. Some big company called Cloverleaf Industries.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kiddin'? Bought the Red Cars, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant picks up his glass. lifts it in toast to the Trolleyman.</context>
      <utterance>Bastards put him on notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the Trolleyman unsteadily climbs up on his stool to get close to the Holy Grail... the Red Car route map over the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to the pencil pushers. May they all get lead poisoning.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROLLEYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old Number Six Line... who'da thought they'd close that one down?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie grabs Earl around the legs and throws him over his shoulder like a sack of potatoes. He carries him over to a booth and puts him down carefully, covering him with a tablecloth.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie, get him down from there. He's gonna break his neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROLLEYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Took you right to Toontown, it did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant walks back to his drink at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know... poor S.O.B.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think the rabbit did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna think. I wanna drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Valiant and Dolores look down the bar, but there's no one there. Finally the familiar cowlick of Baby Herman rises to the top of the bar as he clambers up a barstool.</context>
      <utterance>Make that a round.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't serve formula. Snookums.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You serve martinis, doncha?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Herman slides his baby bottle down the bar to Dolores.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it dry. Baby doesn't like to be wet.  You're Valiant, right? The name's Baby Herman.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are. Kinda out of your neighborhood, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I had to go slummin'. See, a friend of mine's bein' framed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the rabbit? They got him cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolores brings Baby Herman his baby bottle cocktail.</context>
      <utterance>You don't believe that. I mean. the guy's an idiot, a moron, a complete fool... but he'd never kill anyone. I know the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Dolores turns around, Baby Herman pats her on the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, doll.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, a ladies man, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My problem is I got a fifty-year-old lust and a three-year-old dinkie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My problem is I come here to drink in peace. So if you don't mind...</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Valiant, doesn't this whole thing smell a bit funny to you? I mean, no offense, but how did a mucky-muck like R.K. Maroon find you in the first place?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Eddie, it's not like you got an ad in the Yellow Pages.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the vote of confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And another thing, the paper said no will was found. But every Toon knows Acme had a will and, in it he promised to leave Toontown to the Toons.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where is it then?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody took it from him. That's what this whole thing's about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The papers said the safe door was opened, Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick to stuffin' the olives, willya, Dolores?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hunch is it was Maroon. He always was after Acme's property.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant takes the paint chip out of his pocket and dangles it in front of Baby Herman.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Does he wear pants this color?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But neither does Roger. That's Diablo Red. Roger's pants are Sunrise Orange.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be...</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your next move, Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant stands.</context>
      <utterance>My next move? That's easy. I'm gettin' up, and I'm walkin' out the door, and I'm goin' home to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're not even gonna bother to find out if the rabbit's gettin' framed?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Herman shakes his head sorrowfully. As Valiant heads for the door, Dolores whaps her towel down on the bar.</context>
      <utterance>He's a Toon... who cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant ignores her and walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you used to care, Eddie. And it didn t matter if a client's skin was black, white, or painted!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both jump out of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Aah!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I needed a place to hide. I'm in trouble, Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I hear. Even talkin' to you could get me a rap for aiding and abetting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Eddie, no one knows I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? Then how'd you find my house?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I asked the newsboy on the corner. He didn't know. Then I asked a janitor, the fireman and finally the green grocer down the way. He was very helpful.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie tries to open the door, but Roger blocks it spider-like, arms and legs extended.</context>
      <utterance>In other words, the whole goddamn world knows you're here! Out! Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant gives up trying to open the door and grabs Roger. He pulls and he pulls. Finally Roger snaps off like a broken rubber band. The two of them go tumbling backward. Valiant makes a grab for Roger but he slips out of his grasp like quicksilver.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Eddie, don't put me out. I didn't do it, I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant lunges again. Roger dodges.</context>
      <utterance>Sure I wanted to win Jessy back, but not that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant picks himself up and tries to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>After I left you, I went to see her at the Ink &amp; Paint Club.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dear Jessy. How do I love thee? Let me count the ways. 1-1000, 2-1000,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He retrieves the love letter, straightens it and puts it back in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that wasn't very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, pal, if you're still here when I finish this drink, I'm callin' the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that! I'm innocent I tell ya. The police'll just dip me. They were waitin' for me when I got home last night. I ran.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're so innocent, why'd you run?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant shoots the drink down and holds up the empty glass.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, Eddie, I'm a rabbit. We always run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to the phone on the counter. He lifts the receiver and starts to dial.</context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Valiant finishes dialing, he idly puts the empty shot glass down on a photograph on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this is the moment of truth! And I've spoken the truth, but you won't believe the truth. So I guess the truth is my goose is cooked, my hash is slung. my fait is accompli.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The goddamn will.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.A.P.D.?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valiant slowly returns the phone to the cradle,</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now outside we HEAR TIRES SCREECHING to a stop. Roger runs to the window and pulls back the drapes. His eyes bug out of his head.</context>
      <utterance>You mean you believe me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant comes to the window and looks out, too.</context>
      <utterance>It's Toon Control!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDDIE AND ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valiant jerks Roger back behind the curtain.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger, elated, jumps into Valiant's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from that window.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plants a big wet Toon kiss on Valiant's lips.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna help me? How can I ever thank you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For starters... don't ever kiss me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WEASLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger zips to the closet door and goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to 'em. Find a place to hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just kidding...</context>
      <utterance>Eddie Valiant... you're under arrest!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOOM! BOOM! BOOM! The KNOCKING is more impatient. Valiant looks to the door.</context>
      <utterance>You idiot. I lost the key for those cuffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEASLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What do you think you're doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Eddie, I forgot you're not a Toon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ever forget that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEASLE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scent's cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEASLE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points toward the trolley car pulling into the Terminal Station. They fall all over themselves scurrying over to the trolley. They surround it and jump aboard, tommy-gun at the ready.</context>
      <utterance>Pssst.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolores turns just as Roger's grinning face appears in the window.</context>
      <utterance>News flash... Hollywood. Citywide Toonhunt for Roger Rabbit, suspect in Acme slaying. Police describe him as short, cuddly... and psychotic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Eddie's face comes into view. He motions for her to open the window.</context>
      <utterance>Mother Mary...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Eddie, is this who I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger bows at the waist, takes her hand and kisses it like Charles Boyer</context>
      <utterance>Dolores, meet Roger Rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charmed, enchanted, pleasure's all mined.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Roger spots a plate of freshly shucked corn.</context>
      <utterance>The Toon Fairy left him under my pillow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before she can answer, he grabs an ear, presses it to his lips and applies the typewriter method to it. When he gets to the end of a row, we even HEAR the BING!</context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a riot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? Well, you're not handcuffed to him.  Anybody in the back room?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We FOLLOW Dolores as she leads Valiant and Roger across the hall. She stops at a door, unlocks it, and leads them in.</context>
      <utterance>It's all yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you decided to help him after all?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger quiets like a child for a moment as Valiant saws feverishly. Then Roger slips his hand</context>
      <utterance>I oughta have my head examined.  Will you hold still?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant saws a couple more strokes before the realization of what Roger's done hits him. His face darkens. Roger sees the look and sheepishly tries to recover by sticking his hand back in the cuff.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean to tell me you coulda taken your hand outta that cuff at any time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no, not</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My philosophy is if you don't have a sense of humor, you're better off dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well you just might get your wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get him out of it, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant throws the pattycake picture down on the table. Dolores and Roger both examine it closely.</context>
      <utterance>If I can find whoever wanted to kill Acme bad enough to get this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acme's will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's what this little drama is all about.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I think Maroon plays the part of the sound mind, your wife the sound body.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I resent that innuendo! My wife is completely innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your wife may be a lot of things, pal, but innocent isn't one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the scam, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Baby Herman was right. Somebody wants Acme's property. Cack the old man, pin it on Roger, and destroy the will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The habeus corpus is thickening.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Except they screwed up. I don't think they got the will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Acme had the will in his pocket that night at the club. It was gone in the morning when the cops found the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they just took it out of his pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why'd they bother to crack the safe? You can drop a Mosler 90 from Mount Baldy and it won't open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mr. Smarty-Pants Detective, your logic is specious. What prevented Mr. Acme from putting the will back in the safe before they killed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolores whistles over his deductions.</context>
      <utterance>Because he's not forty feet tall. The safe was up on the ceiling, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddie, you still got it. Hey, tomorrow maybe I'll go down to probate court and see who's sniffin' around Acme's estate?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant finishes sawing the cuffs. He stands and throws the cuffs aside. Valiant and Dolores go to the door. Roger follows them eagerly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, do that. I'm gonna go rattle Maroon's cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant turns.</context>
      <utterance>What should I do? Who should I see? Where should I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin', no one, nowhere, He slams the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDEN THE SHOT to REVEAL that Maroon's sharing a booth with BUGS BUNNY and his AGENT. Bugs is chewing on a carrot.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe money grows on trees in Toontown, but not at the Maroon Studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUGS BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Doc, fiduciary considerations aside, Roger Rabbit may have been willing to play second banana to an ankle-biter, but I ain't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augie nods his head. They sit and pick up the menus. Augie takes one peek and looks at Valiant, alarmed. He scribbles a note. Valiant reads it.</context>
      <utterance>This'll be fine, huh, Augie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant gets up from the table and starts across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Forget about the prices, pal. If you want the shrimp cocktail, you have a shrimp cocktail.  Excuse me, Augie, I've got a little table-hopping to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you should know, R.K., we're in negotiations for Bugs to star in his own series at Warner Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying to scare up a bidding war between me and Jack Warner, eh? Well, it won't work. I'll call William Morris and I'll have 'em put out a rabbit call the likes of which this town's never seen!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUGS BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your dime, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And stop callin' me Doc!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUGS BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Valiant arrives, pulls up a chair from next table and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Eh, sure, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mr. Maroon. Remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valiant? What're you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I Just thought I'd drop by and show you a photograph.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've already seen your photographs.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant takes an enlargement of the pattycake shot and puts it on the table in front of Maroon. We can clearly see the will sticking out of Acme's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I enlarged this one. Thought you might be interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant stands and departs. But his visit has done it's trick. Maroon looks l'ike he's seen a ghost. We FOLLOW Valiant across the room to his table where Augie is blissfully attacking a shrimp cocktail.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway... enjoy your lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augie nods enthusiastically. Valiant keeps an eye on Maroon's booth. Now he nudges Augie as Maroon excuses himself and goes into the phone booth just outside the door. Augie puts his shrimp fork down and picks up his pencil.</context>
      <utterance>How is that, Augie, pretty good?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augie stops writing as Maroon hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>The old man had it at the club that night. That's right. Yeah, I'm sure. I'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augie shrugs his shoulders. Disappointed, Valiant lights a cigarette. Now Augie elbows him and gestures across at Maroon, who's making another call. Augie starts writing again.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant drops a twenty on the table and pats Augie on the back.</context>
      <utterance>You did great, Augie. Have another shrimp cocktail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOGHORN LEGHORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foghorn Leghorn dramatically points skyward.</context>
      <utterance>Today we commit the body of brother Acme to the cold, I say cold, cold ground. We shed no tears for we know that Marvin is going to a better place. That high, high, I say that high-larious place up in the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A-men!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOGHORN LEGHORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Much to the funeral Director's amazement, the crank starts PLINKING Out the tune to "POP GOES THE WEASLE". Now the Toon mourners pick up on it and join in.</context>
      <utterance>Give us a sign, brother Herman, that you've arrived...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crank and SONG start going FASTER AND FASTER.</context>
      <utterance>Round and round the mullberry bush, The monkey chased the weasle...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica turns, startled. She stands and faces Maroon.</context>
      <utterance>So... trying to pull a fast one on me, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GARDENER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin' you want, mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EXT. INK &amp; PAINT CLUB - ALLEY - NIGHT A Steinway piano truck is parked next to the stage door. TWO husky PIANO MOVERS are rolling a baby grand up the ramp to the stage door. They knock on the door. The Gorilla opens it and they muscle the piano inside. After a moment, they reemerge. We FOLLOW them back to the truck where a second baby grand stands ready to be moved.</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOVER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Struggling, they push this second piano into the club.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about you, but it makes me sick to think of these beautiful pianos gettin' chopped into match sticks every night by those screwy ducks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DONALD DUCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>exasperated</utterance>
   <speaker>QUACK)</speaker>
      <mode> QUACK)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phooey! Out of tune again!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAFFY DUCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to worry, Donald. We can fix that with my sledgehammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONALD DUCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Valiant's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind, Daffy. I've got an axe in my dressing room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can't see anything in the darkness. But we hear the SOUND of A FISTFIGHT. There's the CRASHING of lamps and furniture breaking. Now the door opens for a second as the assailant escapes. Light floods in the room, illuminating Valiant on the floor with a curtain wrapped around his head. As he struggles free the door closes. The room is dark again. Valiant scrambles to the door. When he whips it open, REVEAL the Gorilla framed in the doorway. Valiant is frozen. The Gorilla flicks on the light. He smiles wickedly.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch...</utterance>
   <speaker>GORILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant tries to make a break for it. WHAM! The Gorilla lays him out cold with a right cross.</context>
      <utterance>And here I tought we had mice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GORILLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I caught him rummagin' around in here. Then I called you, Judge, on a counta you be da one we pay juice to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did the right thing, Bongo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being caught breaking and entering is not very good advertising for a detective. What were you looking for, Mr. Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant nods toward Jessica, who stands coolly smoking a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Ask her...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last week some heavy breather wanted one of my nylons as a souvenir. Maybe that's what he was after?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, doll, if I wanted underwear, I woulda broken into Frederick's of Hollywood. I was lookin' for Marvin Acme's will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marvin Acme had no will. I should know, the probate is in my court.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had a will, all right. She took it off Acme the night she and R.K. Maroon knocked him off. Then she set up her loving husband to take the fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, Mr. Valiant, are either drunk or punch drunk. Probably both.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant. I hope you have some proof?</context>
      <utterance>These are bold accusations, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant reaches into his pocket. But the blue envelope is gone.</context>
      <utterance>I found the cover the will came in behind the dressing table.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must've taken it off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gorilla makes a move for Valiant. Doom stops him.</context>
      <utterance>The other people who were in here lookin' for the will. I woulda caught 'em if Cheetah here hadn't interrupted me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant our own way... downtown.</context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, Bongo. We'll handle Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downtown? Fine. Get a hold of Santino, I'd be more than glad to talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, not</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't tellin' you nothin'! Get me Santino.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Weasles drag Valiant out of the room...</context>
      <utterance>You're a very stubborn man, Mr. Valiant. Very pig-headed. Boys, show Mr. Valiant how we handle pig-headed men at the Toontown station...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... you bastards! Leggo of me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEASLE #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soo-eey! Soo-eey!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEASLE #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>After a beat, Valiant comes staggering out of the tunnel. He's got a burlap sack over his head tied around his waist. Behind him, the Weasles emerge holding paint cans and brushes. They watch as he trips and falls by the side of the road. The Weasles GIGGLE victoriously and head back inside. Valiant lies there for a moment, catching his breath. Then he struggles to free his hands. Finally he rips the sack off his head and sits up.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go, boys. I think he's got the message.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's one for the books... a Toon wearin' human clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Earl... it's me, Valiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddie? Jesus, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toon cops worked me over.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I'll say. They gave you a real Toon-a-Roo.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl breaks the news to Valiant soberly.</context>
      <utterance>What am I, Earl?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a pig... a happy-go-lucky pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much. It's hard to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant tries to pull the brim of his hat down. But it's comically small on the huge head. He makes his way down the aisle past a veritable gauntlet of RAZZING, poking, tripping PASSENGERS. Finally he finds an empty seat in the back as the Red Car starts up.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Eddie, do me a favor. Could you sit in the back so you won't cause as much of a commotion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I, Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid takes his baseball bat and approaches Valiant innocently.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, darling. Take your bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid starts to take a swing with the bat.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mr. Pig. If I hit you on the head, will you make me a cuckoo bird?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid's eyes widen in terror. This is not a typical Toon response.</context>
      <utterance>Kid, if you hit me on the head, I'm gonna throw you out this window.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Valiant. I rang the doorbell, but I guess you couldn't hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica, caught in her lie, flutters her eyelids nervously.</context>
      <utterance>That's because I don't have a doorbell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... well, I... I just had to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she hands him a towel, she stares down at his anatomy.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you've seen me. Now give me a towel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toons aren't given imperfections.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? I guess we're not counting lying, stealing and murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got the wrong idea about me. I'a a pawn in this just like poor Roger. Can you help me find him? I'll pay you anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'll bet you would. You gotta have the rabbit to make the scam work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no... I love my husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. I can just feature you standin' outside your little hutch, holdin' a carrot cake waitin' for hubby to come home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please don't make fun of me, Mr, Valiant. You don't know how hard it is being a woman looking the way I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you don't know how hard it is bein' a man looking at a woman looking the way you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not bad, I'm just drawn that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica takes a cigarette out of her purse. She lights it and blows a cloud of Toon smoke. It forms a recreation of what she describes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not complainin'. But give me credit. I'm the guy who took the pictures of you and Acme playin' pattycake, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant waves at the smoke scene, dispelling it.</context>
      <utterance>Maroon came to me. He told me he'd fire Roger if I didn't do it. I went along with him for Roger's sake. It was only pattycake, after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So altruistic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the truth. Why won't you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause I don't take Acme Dumb Pills. I don't know what you're up to, lady, but I'm gonna nail you for the Acme murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant reaches behind him and picks up a small cup on the sink.</context>
      <utterance>If I'm as bad as you think, what's stopping me from just killing you right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica breaks down and starts sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>This cup of turpentine right here. Go for that gun in your purse and I'm gonna let you have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes to Eddie and hugs him, burying her head in his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mr, Valiant, please... you're my only hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant looks down at the luscious creature in his arms, considering the request. The moment is interrupted by the CLEARING of a VOICE.</context>
      <utterance>I'm weak... you're strong. Can't you find a place somewhere in your heart to help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Valiant, still in just a towel, sheepishly turns to face Dolores, who's standing in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Dabblin' in watercolors, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolores regards Jessica with undisguised contempt.</context>
      <utterance>Dolores...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica straightens her dress.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme guess... your cousin from Des Moines?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I should go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica blows Eddie a TOON KISS which flies across the room, landing on Eddie's cheek. She saunters past the smoldering Dolores and out the door. Dolores walks to Eddie and peels the kiss off his cheek. She crumples it up and throws it down in the wastebasket.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Eddie... don't hate me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably lookin' for a good place to stick a knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just stopped by to tell you that I checked out the Acme probate.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maroon, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. It's that Cloverleaf outfit again.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell would they want with a gag factory?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Valiant considers this new development, he cocks an ear. In the distance, we HEAR FAINT SINGING.</context>
      <utterance>Got me. But unless the will shows up by Friday midnight, it's theirs.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that comin' from the bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like singin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Valiant grabs his pants...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROGER RAB3IT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger grabs Augie's pad and pencil, scribbles some drawings lightning fast.</context>
      <utterance>'The merry-go-round broke down But you don't see me frown...'</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger flips through the pad which in crude animation, shows the story of Roger and Jessica getting back together, culminating in them kissing in a heart. Augie's delighted.</context>
      <utterance>'Things turned out fine And now she's mine...'</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger does backflips and acts like an escapee from the acute ward.</context>
      <utterance>'... Cause the merry-go-round Went round... Hoo-hoo, Hoo-hoo...'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't I get an encore?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, you crazy Toon... I've been out there riskin' my neck for you. I come back here and you're singin' and dancin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's my calling, my purpose, my raison d'etre. Toons are supposed to make people laugh... and believe me, those people needed a laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when they're done laughin' , they're gonna call the cops. That guy Angelo would rat on you for a nickel!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angelo? He's a pal, a chum...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An arsonist and a kidnapper. He just got outta prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I still don't think he'd turn me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because you got 'em to laugh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A laugh can be a powerful thing, Eddie. Sometimes it's the only weapon we have in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I prefer the Smith and Wesson variety.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've met some cynical and miserable humans in my time. But you, Edward Valiant, are positively funereal!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant takes his fist back to belt Roger. Roger stands stoicly, jaw thrust forward, eyes closed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, right now it's gonna be your funereal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead and throw that punch.  But you'd be more successful with a punch</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barflies avoid Doom's stare and shoot covered glances to one another. But nobody says a word. Doom pours a drink into his newly cleaned glass... then gently pours it down Voltaire's gullet.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for a rabbit. He was last seen in this neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom squashes the Midget's head down to approximate the size.</context>
      <utterance>You couldn't miss him. Buck teeth. Orange pants. About yea big.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom turns to Dolores.</context>
      <utterance>There's no rabbit here, so don't harass my customers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom walks around Dolores toward the back. But Doom stops next to the blackboard. On it is written: "Today's Special - French Dip - $ .50". Doom erases the "French" and the decimal point in front of the "50". Then he picks up the chalk and starts to write. The CHALK SQUEAKS excruciatingly on the blackboard. Everyone winces but watches anyway, as Doom writes "Rabbit" where the "French" was, and adds the zeroes to the "50". It now reads: "Rabbit Dip - $5000".</context>
      <utterance>I didn't come here to harass. I came here to reward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angelo looks defensively at all his cronies and back to Doom.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I seen a rabbit...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But instead of pointing to the back of the bar, he talks to the empty barstool beside him.</context>
      <utterance>He's right here in the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say 'ello,</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant plumps the pillow behind his head.</context>
      <utterance>Valiant? Why is it that whenever my men smell a rabbit, you're there?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be my cologne... Eau Dc Carrot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEASLE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest of the Weasles are arrayed behind Doom with Toon crowbars, picks, and a jackhammer.</context>
      <utterance>Youse want we should take the place apart?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom walks over to the locker.</context>
      <utterance>No, Sergeant. That won't be necessary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom just smiles and knocks the pattern out on the crate.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Doom, I don't know who's Toonier, you or the rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger bursts out of the can with the lid on his head. He responds con brio.</context>
      <utterance>Shave... and... a haircut...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PSSSHEW! Roger flies out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Two... bits!  Uh... oh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WEASLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant and Dolores are led out by a couple Weasles holding guns on them. As Doom snaps the briefcase open on the bar, the twelve Kangaroos pop up in their jury box. Doom raps on the bar with his gavel-headed cane. The regulars watch the bizarre scene in stunned silence.</context>
      <utterance>Oyez... oyez... oyez... court is now in session.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Weasles display photographs of Jessica and Acme playing pattycake, a blow-up of his fingerprints spelling RogerRabbitRogerRabbit in the whorls on the photographs, and a picture of Acme lying under the safe.</context>
      <utterance>Roger Rabbit is charged with the cold blooded murder of a human... Marvin Acme. The jury will direct their attention to exhibits A, B, and C.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For this heinous crime, I sentence you to the dip!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. not the dip! Eddie, tell him I didn't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sorry, pal, I tried.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think it's gonna matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom pulls on the rubber gloves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, and for that you're charged with aiding and abetting. But we'll let Santino handle that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, doesn't the rabbit even get a last request?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just kidding.</context>
      <utterance>A blindfold, cigarette, noseplugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you want a drink.  How about it, Judge?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why not? I'm feeling magnanimous tonight. The successful conclusion of this case draws the curtain on my career as a jurist. I'm retiring to take a new role in the private sector.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant pours a glass of whiskey filling it all the way to the rim. He holds it out to Roger.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well, don't expect the Toons to give you a gold watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go, kid... say hi to Casper for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Eddie, you know what happens when...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Roger's hand and forces the drink into it. Roger shrugs his shoulders and shoots the drink down. We've seen the reaction before. Suddenly Roger's head turns into a STEAM WHISTLE emitting such a PIERCING BLAST that is sends everyone into ear-grabbing agony. Glasses, bottles, mirrors, even Doom's glasses SHATTER. Valiant uses the distraction to punch the Weasles holding Roger. He grabs the rabbit by the scruff of the neck. He gets as assist from Augie, who couldn't hear the noise. Unfazed, Augie whacks a Weasle on the head with a barstool. The Midget crawls behind Doom, who's been momentarily blinded. The one-armed Soldier pushes him over. Angelo is turning one Weasle's head around and around like a cruller. Finally, Doom gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Drink it, jerk. All of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Weasles regroup, Valiant tips the stainless steel tub over sending the dip spilling toward them. The Weasles recoil from the liquid. Even Doom takes a step backward.</context>
      <utterance>After them you fools...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Eddie, that was quick thinkin'. Nothin' like usin' the old noggin, the noodle, the grey matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant opens the door of the Toon Control wagon, and flings Roger inside roughly.</context>
      <utterance>If I'm so smart, how come I'm runnin' from the law with a Toon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie and Roger turn. A snazzy TOON ROADSTER whose grill functions as it's mouth is talking from behind the liquid bars.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, gentlemen...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant sighs with resignation and slides out of the cab, Roger in tow.</context>
      <utterance>If you effect my extrication, I could offer you some carburetion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speeding rabbit, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I was afraid of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up ahead, an egg delivery truck is double-parked in their lane. Benny snaps around just as they're about to crash into the back of the truck. There's nowhere to go. But Benny's cool.</context>
      <utterance>Read all about it, Benny's back in town!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, just before impact, the Toon suspension on the car accordions up, giving it a clearance of about fifteen feet... just enough to get over the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Going up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roadster accordions back down to it's original height and speeds past TWO MOTORCYCLE COPS. The motorcycles ROAR after them.</context>
      <utterance>Next floor, sundries, knick knacks, escaped convicts. Watch your step.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Benny, what were you in for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckless driving. Do you believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny zig-zags through traffic, scooting between cars, but the Motorcycle Cops manage to stay on his tail. Up ahead, traffic is stopped in his lane. With nowhere to go, Benny passes a trolley car moving down the center of the street. Suddenly, he swerves in front of the trolley to elude the Cops... only to see another Red Car coming the other way.</context>
      <utterance>Hard to imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny sucks in his girth and gets on his tip-toes as the trollies pass on either side of them.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your breath, babies...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny hits the brakes. Smoke pours out as they burn up and the momentum is barely broken.</context>
      <utterance>The brakes! The brakes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roadster SMASHES through the wooden guard rail and sails out over the water. KERPLOP! It splashes down in the lake.</context>
      <utterance>Forget the brakes, who brought the water wings?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOOSH! Benny is gone. Valiant goes to the door and unlocks it. As he and Roger head up the back stairs...</context>
      <utterance>If you ever need me, just stick out your thumb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valiant and Valiant? Who's the other Valiant?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Roger into the office.</context>
      <utterance>My brother. Get inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's our plan, our scenario, our modus operandi?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant picks up some yellowed newspapers off the couch and dumps them on the floor. They leave a clean spot on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>We can't do anything till it's dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger walks over to the wall. He takes a framed picture off the wall which shows two guys clowning with Mickey Mouse.</context>
      <utterance>Guess you haven't been here in a while.  'Japs Bomb Pearl Harbor'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, who's this guy laughin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, I didn't recognize you... I've never seen you laugh before. That your brother makin' the rabbit ears?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant grabs the picture from Roger and re-hangs it.</context>
      <utterance>What is this, Twenty Questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get some sleep. I suggest you do the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You damn Toon! No wonder they picked you for the patsy. Always gotta play the fool. You make me sick!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, you shamuses are a tough audience, but what happened to you that was so dark, lurid, embittering?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna know? Well, since you're so goddamn curious, I'll tell ya. One of you Toons killed my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Toon? Noooo.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a Toon. It was the guy who killed Bambi's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him? Oh, he was vile, heinous, despicable... a smear on the drafting board.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He got the drop on us... literally.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, everybody thought so. But me and Teddy got a kick out of Toons. All Toons. We couldn't see the bad in 'em. And when this guy was accused of knockin' over the First National Bank of Toontown, we took his case. But when we looked into it, we found out he did do it after all. We went to his house to take him in. But he was wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Safe?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the PHONE on the desk RINGS. Roger makes a move to it.</context>
      <utterance>Piano. Guy got away, disappeared into Toontown. Nobody ever saw him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS TWO MORE TIMES and stops.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong number?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant goes to the phone anticipating a RING which comes after a moment. Valiant picks up the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dolores?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on the phone in the Terminal Bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hopin' you'd be there. Maroon's called here about four times. He says he's gotta talk to you tonight. He says he can help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you gonna call him, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What've I got to lose? You okay, Dolores?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... they closed me down for a coupla weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll work out just fine. When this thing is over, I'll take you to Catalina. How does that sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dolores hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Familiar. Be careful, Eddie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maroon? Whaddaya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got the will?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meet me at my studio at nine o'clock. If you've got the will maybe we can stop this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICK. Maroon has hung up. Valiant hangs up the phone and goes to a wall safe. He spins the combination.</context>
      <utterance>Stop what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, Eddie, you're not gonna go, are ya? Maroon'll be layin' for ya at nine o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I'll be there at 8:45.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you what, maybe I better come with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant reaches into the safe for a .38 revolver. He checks the cylinder. Then he takes out a wooden box about 8" X 12". He closes the safe, picks up a black doctor's bag and puts the box and the revolver into it.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Eddie, I'm not as much of a chump, and a patsy, a yokel as you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much is a shave and a haircut, Roger?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two bits.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant goes to the door, pauses.</context>
      <utterance>I rest my case.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't make it back here by ten...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant closes the door, leaving Roger alone. Roger paces back and forth manically.</context>
      <utterance>... I'd head for Cucamonga.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cucamonga? I don't know anybody in Cucamonga.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon jumps back as Valiant steps from behind the curtain, holding his black bag.</context>
      <utterance>Steady, R.K., that stuff's eighteen years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valiant! You surprised me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant takes over the pouring duties. He turns and carries Maroon's drink to him. Maroon goes and sits down in his chair. He looks to the pistol hiding place. Valiant casually sits on the desk, putting his legs over the drawer.</context>
      <utterance>That was the idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not too good at this, are you,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I'm not. I'm a cartoon maker, not a murderer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, everybody needs a hobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon gets up from his chair, highly agitated.</context>
      <utterance>No, you gotta understand, Valiant, I had nothin' to do with Acme gettin' killed. I just wanted to sell my studio. But they wouldn't buy my property unless Acme would sell his. And he wouldn't. So I was gonna blackmail Acme with pictures of him and the rabbit's wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maroon eyes Valiant's black bag.</context>
      <utterance>But then it all went to hell. I been around Toons all my life. I can't sit around and see them all destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got the will in there, don't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tricked me, damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAROON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no time to take it easy! You don't realize the diabolical mind we're dealing with!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUM-DUM #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What year is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DUM-DUM #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who won the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUM-DUM #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think, dummy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUM-DUM #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome back, Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUM-DUM #6</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you been the last five years?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the cylinder.</context>
      <utterance>Drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feelin' frisky tonight, boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUM-DUMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bullets eagerly dive into their respective chambers. He snaps the cylinder closed, reaches into his shoulder holster and takes out the pint bottle. He unscrews the cap and pours the rest of the booze onto the ground. When it's drained, he flings the bottle in the air and FIRES the Toon .38. KA-POW! It makes a SOUND like a CANNON.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RADIO ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... From the tippy tip top of Toontown's Tip Top Club, this is Mellow Melody Matinee. Here's our favorite cricket, Jimmy, with 'Give A Little Whistle'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMINY CRICKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'... Give a little whistle Give a little whistle...'</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jimmy croons on, Valiant emerges from the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>I hate Toontown...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he drives past a Toon building under construction. Like everything else in Toontown. the construction company sports the name "Acme". The sign out frontsays: WATCH OUR PROGRESS. Eddie looks up, and before he can drive by, the building gets built floor by floor with accompanying SFX in about two seconds. Up ahead, the street is clear for blocks. Then suddenly cars pour out of all side streets at once, clogging the boulevard like arteriosclerosis. There is mad HONKING in this cartoon traffic jam. Eddie shakes his head. He pulls over, parks and gets out. Valiant pulls out his Toon .38. Suddenly, the street empties in the blink of an eye. Shutters close, and the sidewalk rolls up like window shades. It's so quiet you could hear a pin drop. In fact, a PIN DROPS from a second story window, landing with the CLANG! of a manhole cover. All is quiet again. Valiant starts across the street -- there is a CREAK behind him. Valiant whirls around, levelling his pistol at the sound.</context>
      <utterance>Helloooo, cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant lowers the gun as Roger emerges.</context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot, Eddie. It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doin' in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant reaches into the black bag in the car. He comes out with a pair of TOON HANDCUFFS. He slaps one on Roger's wrist.</context>
      <utterance>I followed you to the Maroon Studios. When I heard those shots, I thought I'd help you and investigate the inside of this trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RA13BIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant drags Roger to the steering wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what're you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He locks the cuff to it, and heads across the street.</context>
      <utterance>I'm making sure you don't help me anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant turns slowly to see Jessica's got a bead on him with her revolver.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move, Valiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! She fires. But Valiant's still standing. We HEAR a CRASH behind Eddie as a figure falls into some boxes from a fire escape above.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I always figured I'd get it in Toontown.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica runs past Valiant to the figure. He follows, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>I think I got him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shot Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica moves the box aside and tugs on the rabbit ears. The rabbit head pops off. Underneath is a Weasle. In his hand is the Colt .45 Buntline.</context>
      <utterance>That's not Roger. It's one of Doom's men. He killed R.K. Maroon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady, I guess I had you pegged wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they run down the alley...</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, you're not the first. We better get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah... the open road.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Doom who killed Acme, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know who I could trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're even. By the way, I did find your husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant rounds the corner and points toward the spot where the car used to be. But all that remains is a crumpled bumper.</context>
      <utterance>He's right here in the...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head and looks around for signs of Roger.</context>
      <utterance>... car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get onto Doom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant sees a Weasle skulking at them with a tommygun. BLAM! Valiant fires at him. The Weasle ducks back around the corner. But Valiant's Dum-Dum SCREECHES to a stop and goes around the corner, too. We HEAR an EXPLOSION. The Weasle come staggering out and falls in the street.</context>
      <utterance>Marvin told me. Doom was after his land. Ne was afraid. That's why he brought me his will.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I opened up the blue envelope, all that was inside was a blank piece of paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Weasles are coming at them from every direction. Valiant aims the Toon .38 at a Toon tank rolling their way. But when he pulls the trigger, the gun just CLICKS. Empty.</context>
      <utterance>A joker to the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like our goose is cooked, our hash is slung, our fait is accompli...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme guess where you got that from. Tell me somethin', what'd you ever see in that guy anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant shakes his head. Now they are completely surrounded by Weasles. The situation looks bleak.</context>
      <utterance>He made me laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant jerks his thumb indicating the direction behind him. Suddenly, there's a rubber-burning SCREECH as Benny the Roadster arrives next to Valiant's hitchhiker-posed thumb.</context>
      <utterance>Well, do you prefer to die this way or that way?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant does a take.</context>
      <utterance>Need a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roadster looks back approvingly as Jessica climbs in with Eddie.</context>
      <utterance>Benny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>improvement in the company you keep. Benny blasts through a couple of Weasles. They swing back and forth like tavern doors, then topple. He takes a hard right into the next block which is the Toon Arctic. His tires turn into skis. He slaloms back and forth between trees. The Weasles pursue on dogsled. Benny grabs a striped barber's pole -- the North Pole -- and slides down it. They land in the Toon Sahara. Benny crawls up a large sand dune, his tongue hanging out of his radiator. He glances back at the Weasles who are mounted on camels, waving scimitars. When they reach the top of the sand dune, we see they're on the precipice of a bottomless chasm.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Valiant, you've made a vast</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, the drawbridge -- we're gonna make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see any bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because you gotta</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Valiant stands facing the Weasles, who are charging at him, swords raised. With a sly smile, Valiant holds up the eraser end of the pencil. This freezes the Weasles. But as Valiant starts to erase a rope support, the eraser breaks off the pencil and falls down into the chasm. The Weasles WHEEZE with relief and advance for the kill. At the last second, Valiant takes the business end of the pencil and scribbles a handsaw. He grabs it by the handle and saws the rope. The bridge swings away, smacking the Weasles into the opposite canyon wall. One by one, they slide off and disappear into the abyss.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie, come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His tires smoke, then disappear. It's a dip slick. Without tires, Benny spins out of control, finally ending up in the bushes roadside. Before Eddie and Jessica can make a move, they are surrounded by a horde of Weasles pointing what looks like a hundred guns at them.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh... whoaaa...! Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom opens one of the Roadster's doors and helps Jessica out. Valiant climbs out after her. The Weasles quickly relieve him of his Toon pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Are you two all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These roads can be very treacherous at night, especially in a maniacal Toon vehicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pot's callin' the kettle maniacal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Weasles prod Valiant and Jessica into Doom's Lincoln. A Weasle refers to Benny WHIMPERING in the bushes.</context>
      <utterance>I've had enough of your insolence!  Put him in my car. I think they'll enjoy attending our ribbon cutting at the Acme factory.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEASLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom climbs into the car and it zooms off, Weasles jumping onto the running boards.</context>
      <utterance>He's not going anywhere. We'll send the mobile unit after him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>crawls out of the bushes on his axles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes it down into the drainage ditch, dipping his tootsies one by one. There's a HISS as they hit the water and the chemicals from the dip are extinguished.</context>
      <utterance>The boinin', the boinin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Benny hears the SOUND of another VEHICLE COMING out of the Toontown Tunnel. He ducks down and peeks over the ditch to see...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah... that's better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger sees him and slams on the brakes, skidding the Packard into the Toontown sign.</context>
      <utterance>Roger!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny hobbles over to the Packard. He pops his trunk and rummages around. He comes out with Toon boltcutters. He clips Roger's cuffs off.</context>
      <utterance>Benny?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doom's got your wife and Valiant. He took them to the Acme factory,</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benny nudges Roger to the passenger side.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the Toon Roadster gingerly gets behind the wheel of the Packard. He hits the gas and the Packard lurches down the road.</context>
      <utterance>Slide over, son. It looks like you've done enough drivin' for tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several Weasles rush for the opportunity to frisk Jessica. The head Weasle slaps the others away. Then WHEEZING laciviously, he turns to the task. He starts to move his hands over her body when Jessica stomps her heel on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Frisk them. See if they have the will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Weasle hops away angrily and quickly frisks Valiant. He turns to Doom and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Get your hands off me, you little rodent!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter.  I don't expect the will to show up in the next fifteen minutes. By then Cloverleaf will own Toontown quite legally.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're Cloverleaf?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>gasoline, tires, automobiles.</context>
      <utterance>No one person is Cloverleaf. We're a vast company with diverse interests...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Doom. What would a company like that want with Toontown?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom goes to the truck and starts turning on valves and starting compressors.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't Toontown they wanted. It was my idea of how to put the land to better use.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, they thought my concept so brilliant, that they offered me the Directorship of Transportation. I've accepted.  Bring me Mr. Valiant's gun. The Weasle trots over and delivers Valiant's Toon .38. Doom inspects it. He reads an engraving on the frame.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Thanks for getting me out of the hoosegow. Yosemite Sam'.  How sweet. Doom throws the gun on the ground. He pushes back a long lever on the truck, letting loose a tiny spurt of fluid from the discharge valve. The gun disappears.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dip?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Enough to dip Toontown off the face of the earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BENNY/ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dip Toontown?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger scurries back to the Packard hidden outside the gates. He opens Valiant's black bag and comes out holding Eddie's real pistol. Benny comes tenderfooting up.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, what're you gonna do with that gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna save them, of course. You go for help. Find Dolores at the Terminal Bar. She'll know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROADSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Benny gets behind the wheel of the Packard.</context>
      <utterance>Well... all right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sick, Doom. Where do people like you come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind where I come from. Just watch where I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think anyone's gonna notice that Toontown's gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't care. Who's going to miss some ridiculous talking mice when they can have the future?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger starts to climb out of the toilet. He reaches for something to grab onto. Unwittingly, he gets the toilet chain hanging from the tank above. As he pulls himself out, the toilet flushes. Roger has only a moment to register a dumbfounded expression before he is sucked down the john.</context>
      <utterance>It's time to make my move.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here where we're standing, will be the cornerstone of my idea... the cloverleaf -- an elegant cement structure that intertwines freeways.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's a freeway?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A freeway, Mr. Valiant, is eight lanes of asphalt running uninterrupted from L.A. to Pasadena. Pasadena to Hollywood. Hollywood to Santa Monica. Someday everyone will be in cars driving happily, non-stop from one end of the L.A. Basin to another.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what this is all about? Tell me, who's gonna use your lousy freeway? We got the Red Cars, the best public transportation in the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for long. We're retiring the Red Cars. People will drive, Mr. Valiant, because they'll have to. And when they drive, they'll have to buy our cars, our tires, our gasoline.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you bother to call it a</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get 'em up. All of you! Or I let the Judge have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, darling!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's me, my dearest. I'd embrace you but first I have to take care of some unfinished business.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put that gun down, you buck-toothed fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Give me an excuse to fill you full of holes, pump you full of lead.  How'm I doin', Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real good, Rog... but maybe you better let me take over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milking the moment, he shifts the gun from one hand to another. He circles Doom, poking and prodding him with the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Not before I satisfy my sense of moral outrage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you could get away with this? Hah! We Toons may be idiotic, but we're not stupid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom picks the gun up. The Weasles drag Roger out from under the bricks. Big bright stars are circling his head.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this is turning out better than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant shakes his head, but Jessica starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Look, stars! Ready when you are, Raoul.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have missed you, Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Weasles twirl Toon rope around Roger and Jessica like a cocoon. They hook them on a power winch. Then hit a button and raise Roger and Jessica until they're suspended fifteen feet above the floor... right in the path of the Dipmobile. Doom hands Valiant's gun to the head Weasle.</context>
      <utterance>Tie the lovebirds together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom turns and starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Let him watch his Toon friends get dipped... then shoot him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Weasle turns at the last second, sticking the barrel up against Valiant's nose. Doom gets to his feet. He glowers at the Weasle and knocks him on the head with the gavel head of his cane. Doom stalks out of the room. The Weasles scramble to positions on the Dipmobile. One FIRES UP the ENGINE. The streetcleaner brushes start to turn. The vehicle starts to creep forward. Another Weasle climbs into the turret. He puts Roger and Jessica in the crosshairs of the cannon. Beads of sweat break out on Valiant's face. The Weasle, WHEEZING with evil glee, starts to press his finger to the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out, you idiot... he's going for the gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the last second, Eddie shouts at the Weasle.</context>
      <utterance>You guys think this is real funny, doncha?  Eddie, do somethin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Weasle turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant starts skulking across the floor. It's a cross between Groucho Marx and a Chuck Berry Duck Walk.</context>
      <utterance>'His name is Roger Rabbit He's got a crazy habit...'</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Now</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie takes a bite out of the Toon dynamite and acts like he's savoring it. The spectacle of this human doing this is too much to bear. Now the Weasles are rolling on the ground, holding their sides.</context>
      <utterance>'I think dynamite Is swell to eat'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's lost his mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger means it. The Weasles are laughing so hard they're giving themselves heart attacks. Valiant spins around on the floor like a clock dial gone berserk.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, isn't it great? Keep it up, Eddie... you're killing 'em, you're slayin' 'em, you're knockin' 'em dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One by one, the Weasles keel over... dead. Opaque WEASLE SPIRITS leave their bodies with wings and harps, and float heavenward, still laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, I want you to know I love you. I loved you more than any woman has ever loved a rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>we face the Grim Dipper, our paint will be comingled for eternity. They both close their eyes, waiting for the end. But it never cames. The truck runs up on some boxes and the sprayer arm swings back the other way. Doom grabs an Acme slingshot, loads an Acme boulder and fires it at Valiant. BLAM! It whacks Valiant on the head, laying him out cold in front of the Cloverleaf steamroller, Doom climbs into the steamroller and starts it up. He puts it into gear and starts it rolling toward Valiant. Valiant comes around to see the huge roller bearing down on him. At the last second, Valiant rolls out of the way and grabs an Acme boxing glove. It accordians out and smashes Doom in the face. He goes flying out of the driver's seat, turning the wheel as he falls. The steamroller starts to turn in circles. Valiant jumps Doom. But Doom is stronger. He throws Valiant off and starts whacking him with his fist. He pummels Valiant backward toward the drum of the steamroller. Valiant grabs the nearest thing for defense. It's a can of Acme Stay-Put Adhesive. He whips it up in front of his face. Doom puts his fist right through it, covering his hand with glue. He smiles at Valiant and hauls off again. Valiant ducks. Doom's fist strikes the top of the drum of the steamroller. Frantically he tries to pull it off. But it "Stays-Put". The roller starts to suck his fist down and under.</context>
      <utterance>Be comforted in the knowledge that as</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica and Roger avert their eyes as the steamroller crushes Doom. Valiant breathes a sigh of relief. He starts for the dip truck as the cannon swings back toward Roger and Jessica. But neither of them are watching the cannon. Their eyes are fixed on the ground behind the steamroller.</context>
      <utterance>Nooooo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit, he's a Toon!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surprised?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doom takes the black rubber gloves off, REVEALING red hands with long fingernails. He makes his fist into an anvil and advances on Valiant.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. Only a Toon could think of something as goofy as that freeway idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! From ten feet away, he smashes Valiant with a bone-crushing punch. Valiant staggers backwards.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so? Well, we'll see who's the goofy one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! Doom hammers Valiant again. He's defenseless against Doom's super human strength. BLAM! Valiant goes sprawling to the ground. Now Doom's hand turns into a buzzsaw. He goes to administer the coup de grace.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doom.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. SANTINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant looks down at the stain.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie, we better get you to hospital. You're bleedin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not blood. That's ink. That goof Acme squirted me with some the other day. Why it's comin' 'through now, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because it's Disappearing-Reappearing Ink. Shows up three days later. Gives you enough time to get away from the victim so he doesn't punch you in the nose. Great gag.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll treat you to a new shirt. After all, you did save Toontown.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem is without Marvin's will, the land still goes to Cloverleaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant looks up from his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. If only we knew what happened to that will...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say Roger, remember that love letter you wrote your wife at the Ink &amp; Paint Club?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you oughta read it to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches in his pocket, pulls out the paper and clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Jessy... How do I love thee? Let me count the... I, Marvin Acme, of sound mind and body... Hey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie wipes the spit off his face.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Eddie, you still think I'm a patsy, a simp, a chump?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, kid, you're a real hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger holds out a large stogie.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I am at that. Cigar?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger lights Eddie's and one for himself.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, Roger, you were right about your wife. She's a good lady. I'm glad you got her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm glad you got your sense of humor back. Think you'll keep it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant puffs on the cigar.</context>
      <utterance>Only time will tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALIANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good cigar. Where'd you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valiant glances down. The box says, "Acme Exploding Cigars". He looks to Roger, but it's too late. KABOOM! KABOOM! Their cigars blow up in classic Toon tradition, blackening both their faces. Roger starts laughing. Eddie stares at Roger for a moment, then he starts laughing too. They throw their heads back in a HOWL. The other Toons join in. Pretty soon the whole factory is shaking with LAUGHTER.</context>
      <utterance>From this box here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PORKY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(turns to</context>
      <utterance>O-k-k-k, mmmove along. There's nnnothin' else to see. T-t-that's it. T-t-that's all, folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERA)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, savoring the phrase, Porky stutters out the famous sign-off.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm, I l-l-like the sound of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORKY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eee-ba-da, eee-ba-da... t-t-that's all, folks!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
