<movie id="609" title="X Men">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRECKLED KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His friend is on the toilet with his head in his hands. He seems to be in some pain. He is SCOTT SUMMERS - AGE</context>
      <utterance>Man, what's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>17.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You just gotta-</context>
      <utterance>FRECKLED KID  Dude. Lighten up. She's just a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Freckled kid offers a small plastic bottle.</context>
      <utterance>No, my eyes... my eyes are killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRECKLED KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some Visine, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The freckled kid looks and sees that Scott's eyes are watering so badly that tears are literally streaming through his fingers. He goes back to the mirror to look at his own.</context>
      <utterance>My... eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The freckled kid turns back to him.</context>
      <utterance>... they're burning...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRECKLED KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, how much did you smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott looks up, taking his hands away, revealing for an instant that his eyes are merely bright red embers in his head. Featureless but for the color. Freckles takes a step back.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't smoke anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In every organism on Earth there exists a mutator gene - the X-factor, as it has come to be known. It is the basic building block of evolution - the reason we have evolved from homo habilus...</utterance>
   <speaker>PULL BACK WIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the room, the reactions, and on JEAN herself. A strong, attractive woman in her early 30's. A simple placard before her:</context>
      <utterance>JEAN   Until now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're avoiding the question I posed to you at the beginning of the hearing, Ms. Grey. Three words: Are mutants dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another SENATOR (LUCINDA ROWEE) speaks into her microphone:</context>
      <utterance>I am avoiding a question that is decidedly loaded, Senator. The wrong person behind the wheel of a car can be dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR ROWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we do license people to drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly raises a hand, continuing his tirade.</context>
      <utterance>But not to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Grey -- you work at a school for mutants in Westchester, New York. Can you tell the members of this committee what exactly you are teaching these mutants?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athletics --</context>
      <utterance>Math. History. Science. English.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't happen to be teaching them how to use their powers to --</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly raises a blown-up photograph: a grainy, super- zoomed, somewhat obscured image of a CAR ON A FREEWAY which appears to have "melted." Now he's really playing to the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Control, Senator... we teach them control.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was taken by a state police officer in Secaucus, New Jersey. A man in a minor altercation literally melted the car in front of him. I don't know where you come from, Ms. Grey, but where I come from, you don't go melting people's cars when they cut you off. You do it the old fashioned way -- you give 'em the finger.  But what you presume to tell this committee -</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I presume nothing, I am here to tell you that in time, the mutator gene will activate in every living human being on this planet. Perhaps even your children, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room LAUGHS. Kelly mistaken thinks it is for him, until the double meaning occurs to him. He is momentarily embarrassed, but he quickly recovers. KELLY (contd..) Ms. Grey, we are not here to weed out mutants. The Registration Act is designed merely to assess their potential threat - if any - to national security. The crowd reacts loudly in support of the Senator. Some cheer, some roar, some yell obscenities at Jean. Jean stands and walks out, pushing her way through reporters now moving in for her response. All the while, Kelly is delivering his last words. KELLY (contd.) Mutants are very real. They are among us. We must know who they are. And above all, we must know what they can do.</context>
      <utterance>I can assure you, there is no such creature in my genes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A SUDDEN FLASH OF LIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabretooth looks around, puzzled, then down at Logan's motionless body. Then to his feet where a hole in the ice sprouts bubbling water. The wind blows so violently now that he nearly misses two figures standing only a few yards away - mere silhouettes in the icy haze. A closer look tells us it is a man and a woman, THEY WEAR STRANGE UNIFORMS of form-fitting material - the man wears a reflective visor that hides his eyes. The woman's face is care revealing dark skin, penetrating eyes and unusual white hair. ANOTHER FLASH - one that seems to come from the man's visor itself. An intense beam of red light. Sabretooth looks down and sees the ice at his feet has broken away. He plunges through the ice like a mark in a carnival dunking tank. His massive weight and hairy coat quickly suck him down. The TWO FIGURES - CYCLOPS (Scott Summers) AND STORM (Ororo Munroe) - obviously two of the children we saw earlier now grown - move over the hole and calmly watch Sabretooth gather himself and swim back to the surface. Storm looks down at the hole, concentrating her intense gaze. The wind whips further and the water in the hole begins to freeze over.</context>
      <utterance>Lightning. No. Lightning is not red.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDER THE ICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one last look at the two mysterious figures now nearly obscured by the ice, he turns his body and swims away with the same agility he had on land.</context>
      <utterance>Sabretooth wisely concedes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toad, both hands occupied, flicks his long tongue and grabs a pair of pliers which he rests in Pyro's hand, leaving them slicked with SLIME. The flame in his finger goes out. The slimy coat over the pliers quickly HARDENS, freezing their action. PYRO (cont'd) I asked you not to do that. Blob laughs. Toad shrugs. In the background, almost ignored by them, something is on the television. The news.</context>
      <utterance>Hand me the dykes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The image in the screen is a helicopter shot of ELLIS ISLAND, with Liberty Island and the famous Statue in the background. NEWSCASTER (cont'd) Ellis Island, once an arrival point for thousands of immigrants crossing the Atlantic with the hopes of a better life, will open its doors again. Only this time it will be to leaders and their families from over 200 nations. Blob belches his skepticism deafeningly. TRACK FURTHER THROUGH THE LAIR AND OUT THE DOOR as the Newscast drones on.</context>
      <utterance>Preparations are nearly completed for the upcoming anniversary gala celebrating the formation of the United Nations. With nearly every invitation confirmed, the occasion promises to be the largest single gathering of world leaders in history.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Kelly is on the screen. Magneto shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>...and the leading voice in the call for Mutant registration is Senator Scott Frank Kelly, of Florida, who claims to support the constitutional rights of the genetically enhanced, but whose crusade to register mutants is gaining popularity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Sabretooth clears his throat, the clicking balls instantly freeze and hover there. The volume on the television drops, though no remote is in sight. Magneto notices Sabretooth's apparent exhaustion, his torn clothing, including the slashes in his side. His look asks  Sabretooth crosses the room and places the shining dog tag on the table. The one he ripped from Logan's neck. He sits at the desk, puzzling over it. MAGNETO (cont'd) Your expression tells me the news is not good, brother.</context>
      <utterance>Not this one again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Xavier's people. They knew. Frustrated. Magneto inspects the dog tag.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing odd about the tag at a glance, military dog tag, weathered and beaten, but certainly plain, Canadian Military, Logan's name, rank, and a faded serial number. His thumb feels the indention of the word at the bottom of the tag that does not seem to fit here.</context>
      <utterance>I want him. That is all they know because that is all you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>watching this. He begins speaking over Kelly's diatribe.</context>
      <utterance>I think the President's pre-occupation with international affairs has drawn his attention away from this problem. American's deserve the right to decide whether they want their children to be in school with mutants. To be taught by mutants. They also have the right to know the dangers. That's the purpose of registration. And mark my words, if the President isn't strong enough to do what needs to be done... As the Senator continues we PULL BACK and see Magneto</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Magneto turns Logan's dog tag between his fingers, we can't help but notice FADED PURPLE SERIAL NUMBERS</context>
      <utterance>And you may mark my words, Senator Kelly. All your plotting, all your hatred. I have plans for you. I've seen you come, and I will see you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you're looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A piece. Only a piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Magneto looks up at Kelly on the television we: PAN OVER TO A BULLETIN BOARD on the wall beside him. To a periodic table, smaller than the first. But still with that red square and added letter .</context>
      <utterance>Enough for a test.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GUYRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you thought of a demonstration of some kind? Maybe use the UN Summit to our advantage. The whole world will be watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in the whole world, Henry... I'm interested in America. Let the rest of the world deal with mutants their own way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUYRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly rubs his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guyrich leans to address the driver.</context>
      <utterance>Home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUYRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dulles Airport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Logan, still clutching his stolen clothes, opens his eyes and sees a man sitting behind a large mahogany desk -- PROFESSOR CHARLES XAVIER, an intense and intelligent man just to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Logan.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan, who was prepared for anything but this, just stares. XAVIER (cont'd) I'm sorry, allow me to formally introduce myself -- I am Professor Charles Xavier. This is my school.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like some breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier taps the side of his head with his finger.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he speaks, his lips do not move. We realize Logan  the voice in his head. In addition, the voice is accompanied by the FAMILIAR SOUND OF FOOT STEPS indicating that perhaps Xavier had herded Logan through the mansion with his mind. He does not like it. Xavier comes out from behind his desk. We see that he is in a MOTORED WHEELCHAIR. Realizing that he is safe for the moment, Logan begins putting on his stolen clothes.</context>
      <utterance>You're not the only one with gifts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought you here so that you would be safe from Magneto.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan looks Xavier over. He is obviously a kind man who is offering his help. Logan is silent for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>A very powerful mutant who for some reason has taken an interest in you. I'm not sure why, but until we find out, I must ask you to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier, disappointed, just watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks. Logan goes to the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guyrich looks out the window and looks at Kelly, puzzled. He stands and goes to the door to the cabin of the helicopter.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUYRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Guyrich tries to open the door. It's locked. GUYRICH (cont'd) Pilot? Kelly looks out the window now and sees the helicopter is closing in on an island - where, is anyone's guess. What is known is that the place is no pleasure resort. It is in fact some sort of refurbished island fortress, complete with turrets, built right into the side of the cliffs.</context>
      <utterance>Pilot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Pilot removes his helmet to REVEAL: Pyro, smiling. KELLY (cont'd) What the hell is this? Kelly is utterly confused. As Magneto nears, Guyrich steps forward to greet him, putting arms around Magneto's neck and kissing him deeply. Then Magneto looks deep and lovingly into Guyrich's eyes. And with that GUY SHAPE SHIFTS into a beautiful woman who herefore will be known as MYSTIQUE. Her body is covered in iridescent blue scales, which complement her lovely, solid yellow eyes. Kelly, of course, is shocked. Mystique shows a little hip, raising the scales at her mid-section mockingly, as the last of what we thought was Guyrich slips underneath.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God... Dear... God.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... wha... Who are you... Where is Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Guyrich has been dead for some time Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pyro grabs the Senator as he runs back for the helicopter in vain.</context>
      <utterance>You mutant bastards...</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you do to me... no matter what you'll make me right. Every word I have spoken will be confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Kelly struggles against all hope.</context>
      <utterance>Gosh, I hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Mystique walks up.</context>
      <utterance>People like you are the reason people like me exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTIQUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Mystique punches Kelly. Knocking him out cold.</context>
      <utterance>And people like you are the reason I was afraid to go to school as a child.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a  Senator? Kelly's reaction tells him he is certainly afraid of something right now. MAGNETO  That term always confused me. As if there were something to fear. Kelly looks around wildly, terrified. MAGNETO  God after all, is often defined as all- forgiving. A description I rather like. I think what you really are afraid of... Magneto uses his mind to move Kelly's chair a little closer. Kelly nearly loses it. MAGNETO  ...Is me and my kind. The Brotherhood of Mutants. He touches Kelly's face and Kelly recoils. MAGNETO  And this law. Your mutant registration act is only the beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The intention of registration act -</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shakes his head. There is nothing he can say to sway this man. Magneto turns and admires his machine. MAGNETO (cont'd) Well, we're much more giving than that. We simply want to share with you... To help you understand.</context>
      <utterance>INTENTION? Intention, Senator? We are talking about mankind here. His fear. It is only a matter of time before mutants will be herded into camps. Studied for weaknesses. And eventually wiped off the face of the Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you intend to do to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've found him. Magneto puts the phone to his ear. He smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Kelly, his skin glistening slightly, almost luminescent. Pinker (healthier?) then it was when he came in.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto hangs up the phone. He crosses to Kelly, leans in and whispers in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... Oh God... what have you done to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto stands, looks at his machine, then back at Kelly. MAGNETO (cont'd) Now if you'll excuse me... I have a train to catch.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the future... brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRAD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue looks at him, then quickly looks away. BRAD 1 (cont'd) Hey... Hey I'm talking to you. The Brads laugh amongst themselves at her reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awww... look guys she's shy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRAD 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue is silent and turns her back on him, trying to ignore him. BRAD 4 (cont'd) Hey... I'm talking to you. Rogue continues to ignore him. This gets Brad 4 angry. The other Brads watch his failure and laugh. BRAD 4 (cont'd) (louder) I said I'm talking to you! ANGLE ON: Logan, his ears picking up everything. Rogue looks down trying not to look at them. Brad 4 will not be ignored. He reaches out to the one place which is not covered by clothing that he can reach - - Rogue's hand lying at her side. BRAD 4 (cont'd) (louder still) I said...! He grabs her hand. Suddenly, Brad 4's eyes open wide as if he's in shock, an instant later, he COLLAPSES. Rogue reels back. Brad's 1, 2, and 3 stand up, they are angry.</context>
      <utterance>I'll keep you company.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue stands, frightened and confused. Brad blocks her in.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue moves to get away, but Brad 1 shoves Rogue. Rogue falls to the floor of the train, right next to Logan's feet. Brad 1 moves toward her. Suddenly, Logan steps in front of Brad 1.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Brad, she's a mutant!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you sit down and leave the kid alone, alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a mutant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Rogue, she gets up and huddles toward the rear of the train.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, nobody's perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen -- I don't want any trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brad 1 slams his fist into Logan's stomach. Logan grabs the man's fist and lifts him up and over, slamming him into the train floor. Brad 2 grabs a commuter's briefcase and smashes it on Logan's head. Bursting open, its contents fly everywhere. Logan turns. Brad 2 stares wide-eyed as the gash on Logan's head starts to heal. Suddenly, Brad 1 is up. He grabs Logan around the neck from behind. He holds Logan in his head lock while Brad 2 and 3 start punching him in the stomach and face. Logan is taking quite a beating and naturally the entire train of people are doing nothing. ANGLE ON: Logan's eyes, his pupils are getting smaller. His brow furrows like a wolf. A low guttural GROWL. Suddenly rage -- PRIMAL RAGE Logan's feet kick out, his left foot strikes Brad 1 in the face knocking him backward, while his right foot hooks around Brad 2's head dragging him forward. With his left hand Logan grabs Brad 2 by the throat, squeezing the esophagus. Brad 2 is paralyzed. His eyes roll up as the oxygen is cut off. Brad 2 collapses. ANGLE ON: Brad 3 running out of the car with the other passengers. A TRANSIT COP pushes past the fleeing passengers, into the car. Brad 1 still bear hugs Logan from behind. Logan reaches pushing his knuckles against Brad 1's leg. Suddenly: SHOOK -- the sound of metal extending. Brad 1 howls in pain. SHOOK -- the sound of metal retracting. Brad 1 releases Logan and stares down at three punctured holes in his leg. Logan wheels around, kicks him to the floor, and punches him. All eyes in the train are on Logan, as he raises his fist. SHOOK -- Logan extends his claws. Logan is at the peak of his rage. The passengers stare in disbelief. Even Rogue is astonished.</context>
      <utterance>Well you got trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSIT COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan pauses, only for a second. Brad 1 is wailing for his life. But rage has taken over. Logan raises his blades to finish what he started. Suddenly, THE TRAIN LURCHES VIOLENTLY. Logan goes flying backward.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze... transit police. Drop your weapon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The transit cop rises to his feet, brandishing his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>You can come out now, Logan. You're among friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSIT COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a turn of his finger, Magneto draws the pistol to him. The cop holds tight and is yanked off the train, onto the ground. With another twist of his hand, Magneto makes the gun leap from the cop's grasp and HOVER, pointing at the cop's head.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gun cocks.</context>
      <utterance>You Homo Sapiens and your guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>All turn to see Xavier, seated in his wheelchair -- flanked by Cyclops, Jean and Storm. All, save Xavier, are in uniform.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough, Max!</utterance>
   <speaker>THUNDER RUMBLES ACROSS THE SKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ANGLE ON: Storm, a GUST OF WIND.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never understand your regard for them, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll never understand terrorists.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You should do the same.</context>
      <utterance>I am trying to save our kind, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier's metal chair is gripped by magnetic forces. It shakes and begins to inch towards Magneto.</context>
      <utterance>Not at the cost of lives, Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chair is pulled closer to Magneto. Cyclops steps forward. Xavier need not turn to know help is coming. Magneto sees and respects Cyclops's power. The chair stops moving.</context>
      <utterance>Magneto.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto glances at Storm, then Cyclops.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright... it's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two in Alaska. Just how do you people manage to be in the right place at the right time? Still tinkering with Cerebro?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want with him? Magneto smiles now, tapping his METAL HELMET.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier's expression falters. It appears as if the helmet has been made to block Xavier from doing just that. MAGNETO (cont'd) I'll tell you something, Charles, we are more alike now than we were when we started.</context>
      <utterance>Can't read my mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still trying to make the world safe for our kind. Still trying to find a way to introduce ourselves -- definitively.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is it like these days?</context>
      <utterance>You definition of definitive was always a bit extreme for me, Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan slowly rises from the huddled passengers. Sabretooth fighting the urge to move on him. Logan glares back at Sabretooth. MAGNETO (cont'd) Ahh... there you are brother. I believe you possess something I am very much in need of. Just then, SABRETOOTH ROARS UNCONTROLLABLY and punches Toad in the stomach, doubling him over. Oddly - Toad is laughing. He stands upright.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just say that I am out to make some radical changes. Now come on Charles. For old times sake, for your sake... Leave him to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another roar and another punch. Toad is crying and laughing at the same time. TOAD (cont'd) Oh God it hurts. Do it again. Magneto watches this, momentarily stunned. Suddenly, Pyro grabs hold of his face.</context>
      <utterance>Do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PYRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Mystique MORPHS into a small child and begins tugging at Magneto's pant leg.</context>
      <utterance>I'M BLIND.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTIQUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto looks at the cause of it all: XAVIER, HIS EYES CONCENTRATING, HAS ALL OF MAGNETO'S MINIONS UNDER HIS</context>
      <utterance>I have to go to the bathroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could make you understand. If you could just be made to see it the way I do. The way it's going to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way what is going to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to change the world with or without you as a witness, Charles.  And this one gets a front row seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Magneto steps back a little further. His oddly behaving consorts follow.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This checkmate goes to you. I didn't want to hurt anyone. But you leave me no choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier indicates the wreckage of the train.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I appreciate your concern. But, I do better on my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll make you a deal. Two days. If we haven't figured out what Magneto wants with you by then... I'll bring you back myself. Logan looks up at Xavier suspiciously, hating that he is making sense. Xavier moves closer. Logan looks over at Rogue, covered in her layers of clothes. Storm is helping her off the train, yet taking care not to touch her skin.</context>
      <utterance>You got less than sixty miles today.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier looks to Rogue. A warmth comes over his face. An look of understanding. At a glance he has read her mind. He knows her pain -- her struggle. Rogue looks to Xavier. Their eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>her own family isn't able to accept. She's been on her own for weeks now, searching for a home. A place to belong. Xavier turns to Logan. XAVIER (cont'd) -- We're going to give her that. Logan looks at rogue, contemplating this. Then to Xavier.</context>
      <utterance>Rogue is a beautiful girl, with an extraordinary power. One that even</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-eight hours, old man. But if you cross me, I won't feel any guilt about what I do to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan eyes the rest of the gang until he settles his gaze on Jean. He offers a faint seductive smile. This is not lost on Cyclops. INT. MAGNETO'S LAIR - CELL - LATER - NIGHT A cell with bars, but no visible door. Kelly is hunched over his toilet, heaving. His suit is rumpled and dirty, showing signs that time has passed. There is a television just outside the door: We see SEVERAL NEWS HELICOPTERS circling a platform built against the backdrop of the main entrance to Ellis Island. We see massive security measures, the likes of which have never been attempted, being prepared. (Voice plays over the rest of the scene)</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He walks towards the cell and tries to look down the hall, pressing his face to the bars. NEWSCASTER (V.O. CONT'D) While the Secret Service has never had difficulty handling one or even several world leaders, it has never had to handle the daunting task of watching over all of them. It is only then that he hears a slight crack and his head squeezes between the bars like a soft-shelled egg. He gasps in pain, but more from shock. He pulls his head back with some difficulty and POP, it squeezes right back through.</context>
      <utterance>Is there such a thing as too much security? A possible complication adding to the United Nations Anniversary is the sheer number of security personnel for what will be the largest single summit in the history of the planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is horrified. Disgusted. He paces the cell, unable to comprehend what has happened to himself. It is only when he hears the sound of a HELICOPTER IN THE DISTANCE that he reacts. He starts to panic, then collects himself. Then he goes over to the bars again. He pauses, afraid... then: He pops his head through again. He turns his shoulder toward the bars and begins to push. His feet slip in the floor and his fingers stretch and crack inside, then his ribs begin to pop one by one with the brittleness of undercooked spaghetti. It is agonizing, but Kelly finally manages to pull his horribly-altered body through the bars.</context>
      <utterance>What have you bastards done to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he freezes when he actually enters the room. First, he sees that Blob is laying on the floor with a purple, welt-like hand print across his face. It is blistered and hideous. Blob is gasping for air. Magneto looks and sees the cell is empty. He looks at Sabretooth. MAGNETO (cont'd) I want him alive.</context>
      <utterance>How are we feeling today, Senator? Advanced, I hope...</utterance>
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll find him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ALIVE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly hits the fresh air, looking around wildly. He runs for the edge of a cliff high over the ocean. He raises his hands, we see his palms are covered with those wicked spines and they are dripping a venomous fluid not too different in color from the wound on Blob's face. But then suddenly, something is wrong. Kelly buckles, clutching his stomach again. He squelches what would have been a scream of agony. He looks at his palms and the spikes are gone. Kelly hears footsteps. Suddenly out of the darkness Sabretooth barrels toward him. Kelly turns and LEAPS. Sabretooth comes to the edge of the cliff. When he looks over, Kelly's body has vanished. Swallowed by the sea. Only his clothes remain on the rocks below. INT. LOGAN'S ROOM - NIGHT Jean shows Logan the simple dorm cube with a bed and a small desk. Jean opens the door for Logan and he inspects the sparse surroundings grimly. Cyclops stands just outside the door - eavesdropping.</context>
      <utterance>And Sabretooth bolts back from where they came. EXT. MAGNETO'S LAIR - NIGHT</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else I can get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some cigars. Case of beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no smoking or drinking on the school grounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't light the cigars - how about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see what I can do -- You should get some sleep. Even with your healing ability, you're going to be hurting for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean doesn't know what to make of that. She is about to leave, then pauses.</context>
      <utterance>What if I like the pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Professor said you were a solider. Actually, I believe he used the word mercenary.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well I don't like to talk about my past.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, the Professor could help you with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By reading my thoughts?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean smiles politely at his knowing glance.</context>
      <utterance>What if they're naughty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Get some shut-eye, slick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott.. I -</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like him being here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw what happened tonight. You think Magneto won't come after him again. You think he won't come here if necessary. This is a school, for God's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>for some terrible purpose it's our responsibility to do something. Cyclops shakes his head. JEAN (cont'd) What's wrong? There's something else bothering you. Cyclops gets closer to Jean. She puts her hand on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>If Magneto is planning to use Logan</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean leans in slowly and kisses Cyclops just beside his mouth</context>
      <utterance>I have a bad feeling about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cyclops pulls her close. The hold each other. INT. LOGAN'S ROOM - NIGHT E.C.U. Logan's ear. His super-sensitive hearing has picked up the whole conversation. Logan looks over on the bed and sees a new sketchbook and several pencils. A small note is attached. I hope you don't mind. I understand this helps you relax.</context>
      <utterance>You know I love you, Scott.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beast points to the x-ray.</context>
      <utterance>Adamantium. Until today I thought it to be a myth. Impenetrable, unbendable, resistant to the most extreme heat, cold, indestructible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been grafted to his entire skeleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He also has accelerated healing abilities - uncharted regenerative capability, making his age impossible to determine. He could very well be older than I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the Adamantium part of his mutation?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Someone put it there, relying on his healing abilities to keep him alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier wheels himself to the window, starring out, deep in thought.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think Magneto wants with him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCREAMING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan's eyes FLASH OPEN. He looks up and sees a figure looming over him. In a flash he reacts. THUD. Nothing more. Then silence. The door bursts open and Cyclops stands in the doorway shocked. Frozen. Jean is next and finally Storm. They can only stare. Logan sits upright in bed, CLAWS EXTENDED, INTO ROGUE'S CHEST. She is literally frozen at the end of his arm. Finally, Cyclops breaks the silence and moves to grab her.</context>
      <utterance>Logan's screaming as he comes to.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan finally pulls his claws free and retracts them. Rogue staggers, she pitches forward and touches his face gently with her hands, as though she would like him to be the last thing she sees on this Earth. Logan and Rogue, locked in a fatal moment of tenderness snaring a look of loneliness that only they can understand. But suddenly, Logan seems to change. And before he can say another word, he begins to tremble, then he starts to howl in pain. Rogue SNAPS BACK, mouth open in a gaping, silent scream. What sound comes out does not match the expression at all. Merely a gasp, like steam escaping. Through the huge slash in her clothes, we see the wound on her chest slowly vanish. Before long, she transforms back into a healthy young girl with no sign of injury. Then, her escaping breath begins to accelerate, much in the way Logan's did - too much like Logan's did. It is as if she has taken in his trait of berserker rage. Soon she is smashing things all around her. One hand rakes the wallpaper like claws. Finally, she gets a hold of herself, becoming the introverted Rogue we all know so well. Then she stands slowly, looks at the others. And she runs from the room. Storm runs after her. The rest turn to Logan, who lays on the floor, convulsing. Jean goes to help him. She looks back at Cyclops. His expression makes it clear that his worst fears about Logan have come to pass.</context>
      <utterance>DON'T TOUCH HER. Cyclops freezes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is everybody up at sunrise?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sun is setting, Logan. You've been asleep for nineteen hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she do to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She borrowed your power to save her life. When she touches someone, she absorbs their strengths -- their gifts. In your case -- your ability to heal. That's why she keeps her body covered.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt like she almost killed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she held on any longer she could have.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Storm shakes her head, but remains patient.</context>
      <utterance>And you think it helps calling her Rogue?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've learned to embrace what we are rather than hide it like an affliction. For some, it has become their identity. You mock the names these people choose but they wear them as badges of pride. They arrive at the door to the gym.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspiring -- Now what am I doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to talk to you. Logan turns and sees Cyclops. CYCLOPS  Storm, would you excuse us please?</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cyclops begins to walk away in the other direction. Logan just watches him go. After a moment, he decides it might be more interesting to see where this is going. He follows. They walk across the hall to:</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you been in Alaska?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan is barely through the door when Cyclops whips around on Logan and thumps his finger into his chest.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember. Is that what you wanted to ask me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to make you clear on something. Personally, I don't care what Magneto wants with you. He can take those claws of yours and use them for Barbecue skewers. What I do care about is the safety of this group. The Professor is in charge, and after the Professor, there's me. So, for the remainder of your time here, you're going to keep that killer instinct of yours locked down so no one else gets hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've served with men like you before. Methodical. Systematic -- Naive. You know what happens to those men in a real fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And I don't think this has anything to do with my  You just don't like the way I'm looking at your girl -- Or maybe you don't like the way she's looking back. And maybe you think you're man enough to do something about it. Cyclops is enraged. A red light begins to glow around the edge of his visor and the ruby-quartz lens brightens. We can faintly hear the low hum of immense power that is now barely contained. Before Cyclops can even react, Logan puts his fist against Cyclops' throat. SHOOK! Logan extends one claw up one side of Cyclops' neck. He smiles. LOGAN (cont'd) C'mon sport. You think you can blow the meat off my bones before I gut you? Let's find out. The air is now charged with tension. The two men are about to attack when-</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I got no interest in you, Xavier,  or your... X-Men. Logan takes him in for a moment. LOGAN</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Logan whirls and sees Xavier regarding them sternly. Logan turns his building anger on Xavier.</context>
      <utterance>Cyclops!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier sits calmly as Logan, claws still extended, marches over to him.</context>
      <utterance>I have a question for you, Chuck. What's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context> of super-powered freaks. Teaching wayward mutants about classical literature. For what? Logan continues to advance on Xavier. Cyclops moves to stop Logan, but Xavier waves him off.</context>
      <utterance>This. This whole God damn thing.  Making yourselves into some sort of</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point is to step into a more evolved position of social responsibility. To recognize that there is a world out there and that we mutants are as much a part of it as normal human beings.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>they're so afraid of us that we become the enemy? -- This place is gonna be one giant cemetery. Xavier has heard this argument before.</context>
      <utterance>What if it never happens? What if</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's Magneto talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's me talking. And you know what? It's only been thirty-two hours and you still have no idea what this guy wants with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan raises his hand to his chest grasping for something that no longer hangs from his neck. XAVIER (cont'd) You're thinking of your dog tag. It was made of Adamantium wasn't it?</context>
      <utterance>I believe he wants you for your Adamantium.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Logan turns and sees Jean walking towards them.</context>
      <utterance>Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan looks at Jean with concern.</context>
      <utterance>Rogue's missing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To find Rogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At Xavier's eye level is a black screen with a chin-rest like you see at the eye doctor. Xavier rests his head in it and the screen lights up. XAVIER (cont'd) Cerebro amplifies my power. It allows me to browse the world's consciousness and find the genetically enhanced. A vertical beam scans across his eye and a picture of Xavier's retina appears on the screen next to a computerized image of the same. The two images overlap and match perfectly. XAVIER (cont'd) This is how I found you. A small beep and a loud KNOCK of tumblers rolling and the vault door opens. They walk inside.</context>
      <utterance>The brainwaves of mutants are quite different than those of the average human being.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You designed this yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Magneto helped me put it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He helped you?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean, Logan, Cyclops and Storm watch as Xavier fits his wheelchair into the huge machine, and the chrome skull cap lowers onto the Professor's head, fitting like a second skin. It comes to life. What was dark and menacing is now a brilliant explosion of colored lights.</context>
      <utterance>We were friends once... But that was a long time ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't belong... I don't belong... I'm sorry... so sorry... there's nowhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've found her, Westchester Mall.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan looks over to Jean.</context>
      <utterance>No... I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. sport... you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue looks up and sees Storm standing right in front of her. Her eyes dart around, looking for a way out. STORM (cont'd) You don't have to run. Finally, Rogue surrenders.</context>
      <utterance>Rogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm not like the rest of you -- I'm tired of hurting people. She starts to cry now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And when Rogue looks up, she sees another figure - this one filling the frame behind Storm. A huge clawed hand grabs Storm around the throat and lifts her up as she struggles in vain.</context>
      <utterance>Why did I have to be like this? What purpose does it serve?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Cyclops tries to find a way up, but he trips over all the debris, helpless.</context>
      <utterance>HELP ME. STORM ISN'T BREATHING.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YOU HAVE TO COME AND GET ME. I CAN'T</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should always work with a spotter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan cannot help but glance at her left hand, still clinging to the bar. The shimmering diamond on the third finger.</context>
      <utterance>He's busy right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking maybe you and me could go into town.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan shrugs, starts to take his hands away. Jean is not ready to take the weight of the bar. It almost comes down on her when he catches it again.</context>
      <utterance>Not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he does. And so does Jean at the same time. She gets up and faces Logan - the bar simply hovers in mid- air. Logan smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Suit yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's uptight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He takes his work seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He takes himself seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you're failing to get at? Are you interested in me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding out her left hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Logan, do you see this ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen a lot of rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can reply, Rogue is standing in the doorway looking at them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'll bet you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rogue, where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>E.C.U. on Logan's nose. His nostrils flare... sensing... Logan squints the tiniest bit. We know he knows something is wrong, but he is hiding it.</context>
      <utterance>Logan. The Professor wants you to come with me right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue pauses. Confused.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Rogue, tell Jean what you were telling me last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Professor-- Logan walks towards her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves closer.</context>
      <utterance>You remember. About women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Logan--</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Rogue by the throat.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say about them being the same... SHOOK. The claws are out. HE LUNGES. LOGAN  No two women smell alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean, seeing Logan threaten Rogue with his claws for the second time, RAISES A VAULTING HORSE INTO THE AIR.</context>
      <utterance>Logan, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE TIGHT: Logan's left hand is wrapped around Rogue's throat but part of it is TOUCHING THE EXPOSED SKIN OF HER</context>
      <utterance>This ain't Rogue! He keeps his claws pointed at her face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jean spins around and sees MAGNETO. Without hesitation, the vaulting horse FLIES AT MAGNETO. Simultaneously, one of the thousand-pound weights flies from the weight set and smashes the vaulting horse aside. MAGNETO (cont'd) Fascinating. What I wouldn't give for that. Alas, metal is all I'm good for. But it seems to serve me well enough. Jean is completely unaware of the huge set of lockers rising behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Telekinesis.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do love a good check mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come with me and I'll let her live.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I care about her? I'm the only one who's sure to walk out of here. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>quicker than I will. Maybe I'll just cripple her. The lockers now stand upright, hovering over Jean's knees. MAGNETO (cont'd) So do her the favor. Show her mercy. Logan thinks for a moment -- looks at Jean still unconscious on the floor. Then: Logan retracts his claws. Mystique has morphed back into her natural state with the exception of ONE OF ROGUE'S POCKETS, which still clings to her hip. Mystique produces a large syringe from the pocket and sticks it in Logan's neck. Logan's legs weaken instantly. MAGNETO (cont'd) (to Mystique) Call the others and tell them we have what we came for.</context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you kill her. This catches Logan a little off guard. MAGNETO  Go on. Kill her. You can do it</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier shuts his eyes furious.</context>
      <utterance>When Rogue left the mansion, they must have followed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier opens his eyes and sees Rogue sitting on a chair in the corner. She is visibly upset. Xavier wheels over to Rogue. Xavier reaches out and softly touches her clothing covered shoulder. XAVIER (cont'd) This was not your fault. I knew there was a danger, I should have never left the school. And with that he turns his wheelchair to the door. XAVIER (cont'd) I am going to find Logan. Xavier leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... they wanted me out of the way. If I had been here... I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His vital signs are weak and getting weaker.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All are silent. Rogue looks to Beast with desperate eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in the process of running more tests. But it seems that every minute that goes by he gets weaker.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you help him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier lies in bed, motionless.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gone. The neuro-filter, someone removed it. Jean stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the Professor's mind. It's what keeps him from being crushed by the consciousness of millions. Cyclops steps away, pondering Beast's words. He understands the ramifications -- the damage that has been done to Xavier.</context>
      <utterance>The neuro-filter acts like a surge protector, regulating the infinite flow of information from Cerebro to</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can the Professor repair his own mind?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's already losing control of his vitals. Respiratory. Cardiovascular. Unless we manage to replace the filter by tomorrow morning, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. Jean follows him.</context>
      <utterance>We have to find Magneto.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm... I don't know if we can do this without Charles. Jean puts her hand lovingly to his face. Cyclops takes her hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to kiss him.</context>
      <utterance>He put you in charge for a reason, Scott.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMALL GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small girl stands alone in the hallway. SMALL GIRL (cont'd) Someone is here to see you. Jean's eyes widen -- and around the corner steps Senator Kelly, wearing the clothing he had taken from the beach. He trembles as though from a high fever. His body is covered with a layer of sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grey?...</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly makes a hole with his hands that is not much larger then that of a coffee can. KELLY (cont'd) ... I squeezed through. Kelly buckles in pain, but then catches himself. Jean and Cyclops rush to help him. Beast crutches himself out to see what's happening. Kelly notices Beast. KELLY (cont'd) What in God's name are you?</context>
      <utterance>Your front door was damaged... there was a hole...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to come here, Ms. Grey. I was afraid if I went to a hospital, they would...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Treat you like a mutant? We are not what you think. Not all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean looks closer at his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Tell it to the ones that did this to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean and Kelly both look as the cotton swab ignites like flash paper in her hand. Everyone is shocked. Jean pauses and takes the bottle of alcohol from the shelf. She pours a small amount on Kelly's arm and it instantly catches fire.</context>
      <utterance>I don't see these spikes you're talking about. I'm going to give you an antibiotic for the - Oh my God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue almost jumps out of her chair with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Rogue?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogue exits. Xavier slowly looks over to Kelly lying in the bed next to him. Both men are weak and getting weaker.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, I'll get the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator... Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly tries to speak, but his strength is waning. The two men are a pitiful sight, both slowly coming apart. XAVIER (cont'd) Can you tell me what happened to you? Kelly is in pain. It's a struggle to speak.</context>
      <utterance>I am Charles Xavier. This is my school.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to PROBE KELLY'S MIND.</context>
      <utterance>I was kidnapped... They killed GUYRICH... mutants... There was a light... a bright... light. Xavier turns to Kelly, looking deep into his eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>what -- you'll make me right. Every word I have spoken will be confirmed. He looks up and sees Mystique wheeling the gurney, smiling down at the Senator.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you do to me... no matter</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTIQUE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And people like you are the reason I was afraid to go to school as a child.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mutant gene tells the body when it needs to change.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can assure you, there is no such creature in my genes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The DOG TAG as it is elevated into the machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>SLOWLY BUILDING LIGHT, growing brighter and brighter.</context>
      <utterance>In every organism on Earth there exits a mutator gene -- The X-factor. The beginnings of another stage of evolution.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Pull back as if the camera is pulling back through his eye, into his head -- A MICROSCOPE'S VIEW OF HIS CELLS, suddenly and violently disturbed.</context>
      <utterance>God works too slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Kelly's reflection in the metal of the sink in his prison.</context>
      <utterance>What have you bastards done to me? CHILD'S VOICE  Mom, is that a mutant?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Blob's face, burned by Kelly's hands. Over the cliff.</context>
      <utterance>You're a leader Senator Kelly, you set an example...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUYRICH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The venomous spike emerging from Kelly's hands.</context>
      <utterance>... A Demonstration of some kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if more of you... were like more of us... like more of us...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUYRICH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... the UN summit... the whole world will be watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The woman staring up at him on the beach.</context>
      <utterance>What is it you intend to do to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The boy on the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... Oh God... what have you done to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God.... dear... God.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... the largest single summit in the history of the planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... the mutator gene will activate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The brotherhood of mutants.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the future... brother...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It appears as though Magneto has built a machine which somehow triggers the mutator gene in normal human beings. And he is using Adamantium as its core.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beast grabs a wax pen and draws a lightbulb on a glass drawing board.</context>
      <utterance>Its core?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thomas Edison knew how to make the light bulb. He had the energy source. He had the vacuum. But he didn't have the filament. He tried metal after metal but nothing would hold to power.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beast finishes his lightbulb by drawing the filament.</context>
      <utterance>... until he found tungsten.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>used the Adamantium in Logan's dog tag to test it on the Senator. And I assume now he plans to use the rest of Logan's skeleton for a larger demonstration.</context>
      <utterance>Correct... Apparently, Adamantium is the only metal strong enough to hold the energy this machine produces. He</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what purpose?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>nature. It's forcing the body's cells to replicate thousands of times faster than they're accustomed to. The Senator's body is literally burning itself out. Scott -- this machine kills people and I don't think Magneto realizes it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- Only there's a problem. The mutator gene is not responding to the radiation the way it would in mother</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean looks down and sees Xavier pointing with a trembling hand, trying to speak. Xavier is pointing to the television.</context>
      <utterance>So where do you think he's planning this larger demonstration?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is looking at yet another report on Ellis Island. Cyclops and Jean walk over. All they see on the TV is an aerial shot of Manhattan, slowly coming around toward the harbor. The television image is from the P.O.V. of a helicopter circling Ellis Island, taking in all the security and construction. The grand main hall to Ellis Island and finally, what the helicopter sees as it comes around for one more pass. SUDDENLY - The sound of Kelly's heart monitor begins to PICK UP SPEED. Jean rushes to Kelly and touches his pale neck. She draws her hand back quickly as if burned. The heart monitor keeps speeding up until it is racing faster than a human heart could possibly produce. Jean backs away helplessly. The sheet that covers Kelly's body begins to flatten out. The sweat covering the hapless Senator's body thickens into a viscous, clear liquid and begins to run off the table. Kelly is literally melting away. Cyclops holds Jean as she turns away. ANGLE ON: THE TV -- the gathering leaders of the world, the water clogged with boats, and the thousands of onlookers on Manhattan Island. All well within range.</context>
      <utterance>There...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could go.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Storm. Try to look for the highest vantage point. From what I can figure, he'll need to gain as much altitude as possible to blanket the island. It is my feeling that Magneto has to--</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beast. Beast looks at her. STORM  We'll be fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can still hear me... can't you. Xavier lies still. CYCLOPS  I want to thank you for taking me in. Taking us in... You have taught me everything in my life that is worth knowing. Cyclops grimly regards Xavier. CYCLOPS  And I want you to know that I'll take care of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'm sorry. About Logan. I was jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think that's perfectly understandable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you one thing though.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He calls me sport one more time, and I'll blow a watermelon-sized hole through him. She smiles and kisses him. CYCLOPS  Now let's go get him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>right, there'll be less security north of the George Washington Bridge. I'm taking her down.</context>
      <utterance>Radar Stealth Mode checks out. All</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Into the Hudson?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're backstage at the encore of creation. He looks at his watch. MAGNETO  Three minutes to curtain.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps out of the hatch and closes it.</context>
      <utterance>In the road to survival, there is always sacrifice Logan. We are the future... not them. We must protect ourselves. After tonight, when the leaders of the world return home -- They will return as brothers, as mutants... and our cause will be theirs. This is survival, I know you understand that, Logan... or is it Wolverine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lights on the Statue of Liberty are off.</utterance>
   <speaker>STORM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cyclops, motioning to an open area of water next to Liberty Island.</context>
      <utterance>Beast said that he would have to take a high vantage point.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cyclops pulls a lever. The X-Jet begins to surface. CYCLOPS (cont'd) Storm, give us some cover.</context>
      <utterance>Let's dock over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OPERATION COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She MORPHS back into her full self and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Roger Liberty one. Horizon out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTIQUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling... We're clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to assume that means that the Secret Service is out of commission. Jean, can you raise me up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too far.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Storm, Rogue, -- you take the south entrance.  Jean and I will go in here. Storm and Rogue start for the south entrance. CYCLOPS   I'll see you both soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE TORCH EXPLODES.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cyclops and Jean duck behind the marble map pedestal as fire whips around them. Move up through the CEILING OF FIRE to reveal Pyro at the center of the old torch. His eyes wide, manipulating the fire like an orchestra conductor.</context>
      <utterance>A RING OF FIRE wipes across the room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to scare you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan looks around to make sure it's clear.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God. Logan... we have to help Storm we have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Over Logan's shoulder. On the back of his neck we see some BLUE SCALES. Logan is not Logan, Logan is</context>
      <utterance>I'll go back, but first let me find you a safe place. Logan extends his hand. LOGAN  Here, take my hand. Rogue looks at Logan confused. Logan grows impatient. LOGAN  Take it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magneto. I've seen the results of your machine. I've seen Senator Kelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh, so the good Senator survived his fall? And the swim to shore? He is stronger than I ever could have imagined.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The experiment was a failure. Kelly didn't make it. Yes, you were successful in activating his mutator gene, but you failed to take into account the rest of his body -- it wasn't ready for the strain. Kelly was dead within hours. Your machine kills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto pauses. Shock registering on his face that he could be wrong. Thinking. Considering what Jean is telling him. His mind races and calculates the possibility. Then: MAGNETO (cont'd) I don't believe you.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto gets angry -- squeezing the metal surrounding Jean's head. Jean gasps. This drives Cyclops crazy, but he is helpless to stop it.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THUD -- the sound of footsteps, then another and another. The faces around the room look at the stairs as the footsteps get closer and louder. MAGNETO (cont'd) Check and mate.</context>
      <utterance>Why can't you see what I am trying to do? Why do you stand in my way? Magneto's anger is boiling over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mystique walks slowly toward magneto. Storm and Jean watch the torch in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh, there you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTIQUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to her... it's a trap. Magneto turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTIQUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she grabs the sides of his face and kisses him deeply. There is an awkward moment. Until: MAGNETO CONVULSES. Once, then again. Then he struggles to be set free. And MYSTIQUE TRANSFORMS INTO ROGUE. It has been her all along, using SHAPE SHIFTING powers borrowed from the real Mystique. Magneto fights to get free, but his power is being drained from him.</context>
      <utterance>This is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabretooth backhands Storm across the jaw, knocking her out. As her head drops, he draws his claws and slashes it down. It STOPS, just before tearing open Storm's throat, HELD BY AN UNSEEN FORCE. He turns and sees that Jean has focused her power in his arm. He smiles. He walks to Jean and tears off her bonds. He reaches out to grab her neck but his claw is stopped again in mid- air. Sabretooth just smiles wider and forces his hand forward. The outcome never really in doubt, the claw wraps around Jean's neck. She begins to choke.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabretooth lifts Jean by the neck and walks away from Cyclops as he chokes her.</context>
      <utterance>Jean!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean struggles desperately against Sabretooth's unbreakable grip, the life draining from her. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about this sweetheart, but I made Logan a promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sabretooth whips around, still clutching Jean to see -</context>
      <utterance>Hey, ya big pussy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SABRETOOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan grins.</context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that: he extends ONE CLAW from his right hand, squats down, and cuts the piece of metal holding Cyclops' visor to Magneto's belt. He lifts it up and it slides down his claw to his hand. He casually throws it in the air. LOGAN (cont'd) Jean? Logan looks at the visor and it freezes in the air. It flies across the room, right past Sabretooth's head. He lunges at it with his free claw but just misses it. The visor lands square on Cyclops' eyes, and attaches itself to Cyclops' face. He turns.</context>
      <utterance>Not just me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROGUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... There you are.  Is it really you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's really me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan stands. He takes a couple of steps before collapsing in Cyclops' arms.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm o.k. I'm o.k.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you are, sport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A LOUD CHEER as the room erupts into celebration.</context>
      <utterance>Even after last weeks terrorist vandalization of the Statue of Liberty by an unidentified mutant organization, the outcome of the vote was 51 to 49 in opposition to the Mutant Registration Act.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet. Quiet everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TV cuts to a shot of Kelly being grilled by reporters as he walks down the Capitol steps.</context>
      <utterance>This narrow defeat was probably due in large part to the surprising last- minute reversal by Senator Scott  Kelly, who until today provided the loudest voice in the cry for Mutant Registration. Earlier today, Kelly had this to say:</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he is speaking, we cut to:</context>
      <utterance>If we can not go into the future together, the divisions of fear and prejudice will tear this country apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>E.C.U. The back of Kelly's neck as he passes. A BLUE SCALE is visible above his collar. INT. LOGAN'S ROOM - DAY The FAINT CHEERS are heard through the walls. HAZY THEN FOCUS INTO -- light pushes through blinds. A gentle breeze moves them slightly. Logan sits up in his bed, his chest bandaged. VRRRIP -- the sound of blinds being pulled open. Bright sunshine fills the room, washing across a box and a card sitting on a bureau. ANGLE ON: the card as Logan reads it. LOGAN -- WELCOME HOME. It is signed simply, X. Logan reaches in the box, pulling out -- a UNIFORM. He lays it on the bed. He pulls on one of the gloves, stretching his fingers in it. Perfect fit. SHOOK -- He pops his claws through THREE METAL RINGLETS on the back of the glove -- clearly it was made specifically for him. Logan looks down into the box for him. INT. LOGAN'S ROOM - LATER - DAY From behind Logan we see him finish putting something on over his head. Logan turns into frame, he is wearing a dark blue MASK. It fits his head neatly. The sides arch up shadowing his ears, giving him a wolf or fox-like appearance. The shape is reminiscent of Logan's sketch -- the wolverine. Logan stands facing a mirror. The mask looks good on him and he seems to know it. Xavier is in the doorway. Logan pulls off the mask, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>No more questions. Please, no more questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you knock?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all asking how you're doing. Are you feeling up to saying hello to everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You have a home here now, if you want it. Everyone will...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?... miss me? Charley, I'm gonna walk out the front door and trust me, it won't be soon enough for everyone here. Logan pulls a duffle bag out of the closet. LOGAN  Can I, umm?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Everything in this room is for you. Logan seems genuinely touched by the gesture.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan shoves some clothes into the bag, but not all.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, I'll pay you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan smirks. He picks up his bag. They exit the room together.</context>
      <utterance>Well if you're going to leave then you at least owe them a goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Xavier is in the doorway. XAVIER (cont'd) Everyone, Logan would like to say... Logan steps into the doorway. Everyone can see him now. Before Xavier can finish his sentence he is interrupted by -- APPLAUSE -- simple, genuine, applause. Students slowly stand up. Proud of Logan. For he is one of them. He is a mutant. And he is a hero. As the unconditional applause echoes around him, Logan seems sincerely touched by their spontaneous outpouring. He is almost choked up -- almost. The applause quiet. XAVIER (cont'd) Well, Logan. All eyes are on Logan. Logan pauses. He looks to Xavier, then back to the room.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.  Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Logan puts his duffle bag down. He walks over to the table with Storm, Cyclops and Jean. Jean smiles at him, so does Cyclops -- his arm around the back of her chair. Logan sees them together, they are happy, and finally he offers a smile. Xavier holds for a moment at the door. A look of pride on his face, the pride a father has for his children.</context>
      <utterance>What's a guy gotta do to get a beer around here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't really have let you die, you know. I just needed...</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Magneto thinks for a while; then:</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't it ever wake you in the middle of the night? The feeling that some day, some day very soon, they will pass that foolish law - or one just like it - and they will come for you and your children? Take you all away?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does indeed, Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you do when you wake up to that?</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier makes a move, Magneto counters. Xavier moves again.</context>
      <utterance>I feel a great swell of pity for the poor soul who comes to that school again looking for trouble. He stares right at Magneto.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Xavier's white pieces slowly surrounding Magneto's Black King. MAGNETO (cont'd) - I will always find an escape.</context>
      <utterance>But you know that it is a war, old friend. And to win a war it takes the will to fight it at all costs, by any means necessary. And for that reason, I will always have the advantage. No matter how you trap me, how I am contained - Chess pieces seem to visually mimic their conversation</utterance>
   <speaker>XAVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Xavier places his queen gently down, taking away a knight. XAVIER (cont'd) Check. Just then, the door to the cell opens. A Guard waits. Magneto and Xavier stare at one another before Xavier turns and wheels himself out of the room. The door closes behind him, leaving Magneto alone with his plastic chess set in his plastic cell. And Magneto looks at the pieces before him. Something occurs to him. He smiles a wicked smile. And his rook LEVITATES, despite its properties, moving across the board and toppling Xavier's king.</context>
      <utterance>And I will always be there, old friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGNETO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And mate.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
