<movie id="610" title="Year One">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DRUMS get hotter as he closes his eyes and leans in to kiss her, but she turns and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should we eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you actually meant you were hungry. I thought-- forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm, these are so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she turns away he spits them out in disgust. Maya smiles and puts her face very close to his, their lips almost touching.</context>
      <utterance>Mmrrunm, they really are .</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'd really like?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>HOPEFULLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some fruit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>THINKS</mode>
      <context>He scans the nearby trees.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts darting from tree to tree, hopefully pointing out various options. She follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Orange? Tangerine?  Umm, mango? Kiwi? Peach? She shakes her head coyly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>COQUETTISHLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuh-uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kumquat? Uh, cock? Cockfruit?</context>
      <utterance>Okay, don't tell me-- papaya? Pomegranate? Lemon? Lime?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starfruit, casaba-- tangelo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>he doesn't even like her</utterance>
   <speaker>ANYMORE)</speaker>
      <mode> ANYMORE)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I give up. Which fruit do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>POINTS</mode>
      <context>Zed looks. It's a beautiful tree with lush, apple-like red fruit hanging from it.</context>
      <utterance>That one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SCOFFS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that's the fruit we don't eat! It's forbidden.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because we don't! It's a rule! That's the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil. You don't eat from that one. Nobody ever has.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop saying why not! I told you-- it's a rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do you always follow the rules?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No-- yeah-- I don't know. We don't have that many rules. In fact, we only have one rule-- DON'T EAT THAT</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fine. We won't. Forget I mentioned it. I understand if you're afraid--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not "afraid"--</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glares defiantly at Zed, then starts to walk away. It's not Paradise anymore. Then like every man that ever lived and will ever live, he caves.</context>
      <utterance>No, really, it's all right. I just thought you might be curious why we can eat everything else that walks, crawls, swims, flies, or grows in the ground, but not that particular fruit. And I thought you might be the kind of man who's willing to take a chance and start thinking for himself, but I guess I was wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips two ripe fruits from a low-hanging bough and hands her one. They both stare at the fruit.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! Fine! You want to try the Good and Evil fruit, you got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way! It was your idea. You go first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed considers for a long moment then decides.</context>
      <utterance>We both bite at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed chomps down hard and takes a big bite, but Maya fakes him out and stops before her teeth break the skin. ZED (cont'd) (with his mouth full) Got me. That's a good move. I'm going to steal it. He starts chewing and she watches as he gets his first taste of Good and Evil. Then his face contorts in disgust and he spits it out. ZED (cont'd) (gagging and spitting) Yuchh! That's horrible. Yecch, ptui! Ughh. He frantically wipes the inside of his mouth with his fingers, trying to get the terrible taste out.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Ready? One-- two-- three!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're saying it's not good?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his belly as his stomach starts to cramp. Then a loud bowel sound and his eyebrows shoot up. ZED (cont'd) Oh, no--</context>
      <utterance>Yes! I'm saying it's not good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>6.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs for the bushes. Maya's attention gets diverted.</context>
      <utterance>Official White</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, banana!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Marlak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor. Just kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you eat that fruit? It's forbidden. Everybody knows that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed notices a VILLAGER squatting in the bushes right behind his dwelling. ZED (cont'd) (shouts testily) Hey! Squanto! Give me a break, would ya'! You got the whole forest! (to Oh) Why does everyone have to crap right behind my hut?</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help myself! Maya was just staring at me with those pouty eyes-- and those perky breasts-- opposable thumbs. And how about the name? "The Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil"? You don't think that sounds tempting? They should've just called it "The Tree with the Fruit that Tastes Like Shit." Then for sure nobody would eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh notices a very pretty young woman, EEMA, standing near the communal fire with TWO HUNTERS. His heart leaps. OH (cont'd) (calls out eagerly) Hi, Eema! Eema turns, sees it's him and gives him a perfunctory wave, then turns back to the hunters and says something about Oh that makes them laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I think, and I could be wrong, that all the poop makes the ground more fertile, which in turn, gives the leaves in the area a softer feel. It's a vicious circle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see it. I mean she's cute, but I don't think I'd lay with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not! She's your sister! It'd be like sleeping with your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>which was a big mistake. I see that now. You think it won't be awkward the next morning but-- trust me, you just want to rip your eyeballs out.  Listen, if you want to impress Eema, tonight at the feast, do the fertility dance with her, then drag her back to your hut.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hut's a mess. And what if she struggles?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you give her a little tap on the head. Women respond to that--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SIGHS</mode>
      <context>They look over at Eema, who is now slowly stroking the shaft of a hunter's spear.</context>
      <utterance>No. She only likes hunters-- not gatherers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hunter Marlak walks by and stops. He's clearly half a rung lower on the human evolutionary scale.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't read too much into that. She kisses, then tongues the spear tip. ZED  Okay, that might mean something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't hunt today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak grunts and examines the primitive line drawings on the walls of Zed's hut.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Marlak. Very observant. I was indisposed. Got that intestinal thing that's been going around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not a bear. That's just some lines on a skin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SIGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a real bear. It's a "representation" of a bear. You know, a "picture."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Like you'd know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a skin with another of Zed's drawings on it, this one of a big-breasted naked girl. Zed quickly grabs it and holds it upside down.</context>
      <utterance>And what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That-- would be an antelope-- or a deer-- a deerpalope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like Maya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could it be Maya? It's just some lines on a skin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from my woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak cuffs him hard on the side of the head.</context>
      <utterance>Your woman? I'm not sure dragging her into the bushes kicking and screaming means you have an actual "thing" going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Nice supra-orbital ridge, fartface!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Oh? Did it ever occur to you that there may be more to life than this?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I think somebody's had enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm serious.We're born into thisworld, we hunt, we gather, we eat,we sleep, we make babies--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make babies--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--but why? What's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh takes a big toke on the pipe, chokes, and starts coughing uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>You always get like this when you smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Last night I couldn't sleep, so I just laid there looking up at the sky, counting the stars. There were over seventy. Kinda makes you think, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I've been thinking about it ever since I ate that fruit. Don't you ever wonder what's on the other side of the mountains?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(makes a sharp gesture)</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing on the other side of the mountains. Everybody knows that. The world just ends. You'd fall right off the edge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he picks up a round</context>
      <utterance>But what if it doesn't? What if it just goes on and on forever? Or what if it's round?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCK))</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He traces the circumference with his finger.</context>
      <utterance>And if you keep walking you eventually come right back to where you started?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SCOFFS</mode>
      <context>Zed flings the rock away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, that's plausible.</utterance>
   <speaker>A VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oww!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it, man! Go dance for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think? They're playing the Jackal Dance. I don't do that one so well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh summons his courage, gets up and crosses to where the girls are sitting. Zed makes subtle eye contact with Maya, waggles his eyebrows and licks his lips. She laughs and looks away. Oh starts dancing timidly right in front of Eema, subtly jerking his pelvis, trying to be cool. Eema just stares at him for a moment, then goes back to talking to her friends. Oh looks over at Zed for help. Zed mimes clonking her on the head. Oh picks up a wooden club and hits Eema right on the noggin. However, instead of submitting, she gets really pissed, stands up and decks him with one punch.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Go! Jackal Dance!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, hunter coming through.</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Wait your turn! There's a line here, buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a SPEAR is thrust inches from his face, stopping him. It's Marlak, who towers over Zed. His cohort, ENMEBARAGESI, short and stout, stands beside him.</context>
      <utterance>For your information I was in line and I just stepped out to chew some food for an elderly lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enmebaragesi said he saw you in the garden with Maya.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really? And what if I called Enmebaragesi a liar?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENMEBARAGESI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak gets right in Zed's face.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down. I said "what if"-- it was a hypothetical.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Villagers gather around them, Maya and Eema among them. Marlak puts his spear point to Zed's throat. MARLAK (cont'd) The truth!</context>
      <utterance>Enmebaragesi doesn't lie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zed, just admit it. You're just making it harder on yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(gingerly moves the spear</context>
      <utterance>No, you just made it harder on myself!  Okay, fine, you got me.</utterance>
   <speaker>POINT)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maya looks shocked, and tries to signal Zed to shut up.</context>
      <utterance>Maya and I lay together on occasion. We're consenting adults and we have an adventurous sexual relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode>STUNNED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You laid with my woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maya rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that what we're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENMEBARAGESI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I saw you eat the Forbidden Fruit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak knocks Zed to the ground. The DRUMMING stops. Oh comes running over and gets between Marlak and Zed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that! Yeah! I did eat the fruit. I was just kidding about humping Maya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed starts to walk away but quickly pivots and throws a WILD HAYMAKER at Marlak who easily ducks it, and it hits an unsuspecting Enmebaragesi squarely in the nose. Zed (cont'd) (to Enmebaragesi) And let that be a lesson to your big friend- Marlak grabs Zed, lands two solid punches to Zed's mid- section, and then clocks him with a vicious right that sends him sprawling to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Marlak, this is crazy. You're two of me. I'm not gonna fight you over a girl, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hunters laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Your father was a great hunter, but you're like-- a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENMEBARAGESI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good one, Marlak.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's about to spear Zed when suddenly the Shaman screams and jumps between them. The villagers step back as the Shaman howls an incantation and shakes his magic rattle at Zed.</context>
      <utterance>Now I kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really ate the fruit?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One bite! What's the big deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>halfheartedly shakes a chicken-foot rattle at</utterance>
   <speaker>HIM)</speaker>
      <mode> HIM)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't eat the fruit! That's been the number one rule from the beginning of time. Since the Great Turtle climbed from the sea with the Earth on his back, drank the ocean, pooped out the mountains and the first man fell from the stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always had trouble with the Great Turtle Theory-- too many unexplained gaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. You're screwed now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? How screwed? Like I knew it was a rule but I'm a little fuzzy on the exact details.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're cursed, man, and if you stay here then we'll all be cursed. You have to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I supposed to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to you. From now on you're completely on your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>DEFIANT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An arrow zips in and sticks in the post next to his head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to seem ungrateful or anything, but you wouldn't happen to have any arrows, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed looks around at his fellow villagers, trying to summon what dignity he has left.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better get moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>DEFIANT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but before I go I just want to say something. I know I'm not the greatest hunter--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Or gatherer--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hunters keep the insistent beat, their gaze fixed on Zed. ZED (cont'd) (rolls his eyes; "these guys are hopeless") Anyways, I'm going away, not because you're forcing me to-- which you are-- but because I choose to. Yes, I ate from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil-- major misunderstanding on my part-- and believe me I'm not recommending it unless you're interested in a very powerful laxative-- but it got me thinking about some pretty heavy stuff -- life questions, you know. So I'm out of here, and anyone who wants to join me is welcome. He looks around the circle and sees Maya. She sees Marlak staring at her and averts her eyes. ZED (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Yes, or gatherer-- but there's got to be more to life than this--  Kinda hard to concentrate with that rhythmic drumming, fellas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you see me if I'm not here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trying to trick me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, then tell me this-- who's standing right behind you?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it my speech?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the fire. I lost everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the speech was pretty good, right? I mean, even I was moved and I was the one speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh pulls Zed to his feet, and they sneak off into the deep woods.</context>
      <utterance>Can we talk about this later?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is nice, out here, the two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SULLEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, those hunters are idiots. In an hour they'll forget the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think they'll forget the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what we should do? You and me should kill the biggest boar ever-- just huge!-- and take it back to the village. Just to show them. And we won't let anyone else eat it. They'll have to watch us eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's that huge how would we carry it back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>CONSIDERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, we'll just start with something small. A squirrel or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we'll make everyone watch us eat a squirrel. Will you get real? There's no going back! There's, nothing to go back to! It's just ashes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SCOFFS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like it's so hard to build a new hut. It's just a pile of sticks and dung--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SCOWLS</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Zed stops and stands perfectly still.</context>
      <utterance>You're a pile of sticks and dung.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed makes a minimal gesture with his head. Oh looks up. A COUGAR crouches on a tree limb above them, poised to leap. Oh freezes. They talk like ventriloquists.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move a muscle.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will that work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some say run, some say don't.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. There's two different opinions on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sprints off and the cougar pounces right on oh.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to-- RUN!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really should put some maggots on those scratches. They look pretty deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>BITTER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to know why you told me not to move, and you ran.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I honestly thought he'd go for me. I thought I was doing you a favor. Apparently not appreciated.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, big favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to come with me, you know. I didn't ask you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you did! You looked right at me-- twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's a technique of public speaking, but I didn't ask you specifically. You chose to come. You gotta take some responsibility for that. And there's no point coming if you're just gonna keep whining about every little-- cougar that attacks you.  You want some or not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>HUFFY</mode>
      <context>He turns his back to Zed, and starts sorting through the pile of sticks.</context>
      <utterance>No, eat your weasel. You deserve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You making your own fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, arrows. We're going to need them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>RESIGNED</mode>
      <context>Zed claps him on the back and hugs him exuberantly. Oh winces in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a step forward, the rock shelf gives way beneath his feet and he falls a great distance, screaming all the way down, bouncing painfully off the big boulders, then a long, tumbling slide over sharp rocks and gravel to the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>Incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>WINCES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh. -  I'll go around! Wait for me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what you want, but that was no accident. You don't see a pattern here?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see a pattern. Every time something terrible can happen to me, it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but why? Why'd the cougar go for you and not me? Why did you fall and I didn't? Hard to believe it's all just random. Think about</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops to one knee and examines something in the bushes. Zed (cont'd) They stopped here to poop. Look.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! There!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four men, maybe five. And a child-- or a small women maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they had some nuts-- dried fruit-- some kind of green leafy vegetable--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe we can find where they peed. 14 Then Zed sees light through the trees and creeps 14 stealthily to the tree line. Oh creeps up beside him and they peer through the bushes. THREE COWS are grazing in a green pasture. Beyond it, well- tended fields of growing grain. Zed snaps into stalking mode, ducks down and silently signals Oh to be quiet and stay put.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! Enough! Can we just go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context>He takes his bow, pulls an arrow from his quiver, and slowly draws the bow, taking deadly aim at one of the cows. He shoots. The blunt, pointless arrow hits the cow in the side and bounces off. The cow looks up.</context>
      <utterance>This one's mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FIRST YOUNG FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just shoot my cow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>getting painfully to his</utterance>
   <speaker>FEET)</speaker>
      <mode> FEET)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well-- we're hunters.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a hunter. I'm more of a "maker." I made this loincloth, I do arrows-- I made a shelf unit for my hut--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you guys do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND YOUNG FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it look like? We're farmers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUNG FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a farmer; I'm a herdsman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND YOUNG FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a suck, is what you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST YOUNG FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother, Cain. I am called Abel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are called suck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother is angry because God looked on my sacrifice with favor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"God looked on my sacrifice with</utterance>
   <speaker>FAVOR--"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, is he a total suck or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's hard to say-- we just</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you dragging them into this? What do they know? They're morons.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>OFFENDED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Easy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you're so superior to everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Superior-er than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(shoves him)</context>
      <utterance>Really? Let's see how good you are at getting your ass kicked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(shoves him back)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Bring it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, boys, that's enough. We just want to--</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! This smug asshole insulted you and I want him to take it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not really that insulted--</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed steps between them, trying to make peace.</context>
      <utterance>Make me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain uses the distraction to sneak-punch Abel and the fight is on. They start throwing wild punches, then clinch and wrestle each other to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Boys, boys! You're brothers! Let's just relax and--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't we do something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain picks up a good-size rock and strikes Abel on the head with all his might. Abel falls heavily to the ground and lies there, not moving. Cain stands over him, breathing hard. ZED (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Just let them settle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SHOCKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that settles it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turns on him sharply, still holding the bloody</utterance>
   <speaker>ROCK)</speaker>
      <mode> ROCK)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain stares at Abel, still inert on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's all right. Probably just</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably just tuckered out from the fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What do you mean "we"? I don't want to play the blame game, but you're the one who hit him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could've stopped me! There's two of you and only one of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't know you were going to kill him--</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he clutches the rock)</context>
      <utterance>You calling me a murderer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an accident!  Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right! You were holding the rock and he-- accidentally ran into it-- really hard-- with his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay-- yeah-- good. But it might be better if we don't mention the "accident" to anyone. People might get the wrong idea. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, people could so easily misinterpret that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SHRUGS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why even bring it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>NODS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you guys. You're all right. Why don't you come with me? Have supper with the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately we already have dinner plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you should come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>why don't we go with you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the big round things for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're wheels, numbskull. They make the cart roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh screams as the HEAVY WHEELS ROLL OVER HIS FEET.</context>
      <utterance>Wow! That is like the greatest invention since the vagina. Cain whips the oxen and they lumber forward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cain, my son!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain stops the cart and dismounts with Zed and Oh. CAIN (cont'd) Can these guys stay for supper? (off Adam's questioning</context>
      <utterance>Hail, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOK)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain turns to Zed and Oh and furtively mimes an elaborate lip- sewing gesture, ancient precursor to the modern lip-zipper.</context>
      <utterance>I bring strangers who would sojourn with us this night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings, strangers. I am called Adam and you are welcome to share the fruits of our toil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed gives Cain a subtle, acquiescent nod as Adam ushers them into his crude dwelling.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, but I'm kind of staying away from fruit for the time being.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is thy brother, Abel?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake their heads and cough nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Abel? Haven't seen him. I thought he was with you.  You guys see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED AND OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nape. Not that I remember. Never seen anybody-- anywhere-- anytime -- ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your sister Lilith said she saw him in the field with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that was yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this day. She said you both made offerings.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That might've been Boaz---</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you and Abel. She said it looked like you were arguing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we're brothers, we argue sometimes- it's not that big a deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>EXPLODES</mode>
      <context>He smashes his plate against the wall and storms out. An awkward silence as Zed and Oh exchange guilty looks.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! What am I-- his keeper? Get off my back, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fear the worst for Abel. I am sorely vexed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Bergmanesque gloom fills the hovel as Adam muses sullenly on his sorry circumstances.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's got to be pretty vexing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For my sin the ground is cursed. Thorns and thistles does it sprout for us, and we are doomed to toil all the days of our lives. For as the Lord has commanded, by the sweat of your brow shall you get bread to eat until you return to the ground from which you were taken. For dust you are, and to dust shall you return.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. That's kind of a downer isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the way of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I hope not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed looks at the luscious Lilith, then back at Adam.</context>
      <utterance>You are welcome to stay the night and lay with my daughter Lilith.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm waiting for the punchline.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilith nods demurely and exits through a curtain. Zed starts to follow her out.</context>
      <utterance>She is without a husband, and as the Lord has said, thou shalt be fruitful and multiply.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may share the bed of my son Seth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, there you go.  Oh looks at Seth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I multiplied with a sheep.  My thingie smells like lamb chops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LILITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My bed is small but you're welcome to share it. It's the way of my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's a good way to be. In fact, I'm kind of surprised a pretty girl like you is sleeping alone anyway. I would've thought guys would be lined up at the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you just haven't met the right one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SUAVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we have that in common--</utterance>
   <speaker>LILITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm attracted to women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What does that mean?</context>
      <utterance>I don't even know what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like to have sex with other women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stares at her for a long</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMENT)</speaker>
      <mode> MOMENT)</mode>
      <context>Lilith shakes her head, turns away from him, and pulls up her blanket. Zed shrugs and rolls over to sleep. They lie there quietly in the dark for a long beat. Then-- Zed (cont'd) You're kidding! Whoa! That's amazing!</context>
      <utterance>I'm really not getting this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth lifts his knees to his chest and farts a surprisingly long cadenza.</context>
      <utterance>Oooh, listen to this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's really good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to see a trick?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been the same damn thing my whole life.  "Why can't you be more like Abel?"  "Oh, your sacrifice was good, too, but Abel's was-- wow!"</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>trying to change the</utterance>
   <speaker>SUBJECT)</speaker>
      <mode> SUBJECT)</mode>
      <context>KINSMEN from other dwellings start gathering.</context>
      <utterance>Your brother Seth is an interesting guy. Did you know he can put his penis in his mouth? Adam and Zed come out of his dwelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cain!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, hey-- where's everybody going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To look for Abel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>MUTTERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns aside and makes a goofy sarcastic face for Oh's benefit.</context>
      <utterance>I said good luck. I'm really worried about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adam and the others hurry off, and as soon as they're gone, Cain rushes over and starts harnessing the oxen to the cart. CAIN (cont'd) (to Zed and Oh) Now listen, I'm getting out of here, and you better come with me. I have a feeling they're going to try and blame this whole "Abel- killing-thing" on you.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I am. I just have to finish toiling over here, then I'm right behind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would they blame us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He urgently whips the oxen and they climb aboard as the cart lumbers forward.</context>
      <utterance>Because when they find him and his head is all bashed in, they're going to start pointing fingers, and you guys are drifters, so they'll put two and two together and that makes-- He stares expectantly at Zed and Oh. CAIN  Four! It makes four! Now stop asking so many questions and hop on. We gotta get out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh approaches a bakery stand and stares hungrily at the bread.</context>
      <utterance>Look at all these people! And this stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for a loaf but the MERCHANT strikes his hand with a cane. OH (cont'd) Ow!</context>
      <utterance>Can I have one of those?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two silver pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>HUNGRY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna need some money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They see a crowd at the center of the market gathered around a raised platform. SLAVES IN SHACKLES are lined up on the raised wooden platform while CUSTOMERS examine those waiting to be auctioned. The AUCTIONEER brings up a fnuscular male slave in a loincloth. ZED (cont'd) It's Marlak! Marlak's hands are bound and he's restrained by a chain attached to a thick leather collar around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we're gonna need money.  What's money?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUCTIONEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the bidding starts, Zed spots Maya, his sister Eema, and Enmebaragesi among the chained-up slaves waiting to be sold. Zed and Oh push their way through the crowd and go to them.</context>
      <utterance>Next up, an unusual item-- looks like a Caucasian-- he's big, he's strong, he's a good breeder, so I'm going to start at 100 gold minas. Do I hear 100?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women embrace him with relief and excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Eema! Maya!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SHEEPISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Eema.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened? How did you get here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right? Did they-- rape you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode>SHRUGS</mode>
      <context>The SLAVE TRADER sees them talking to Eema and approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little. Zed and Oh look at her curiously.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You interested in some slaves?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have money?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>CAGEY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that depends on what you mean by money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, pal, money talks and bullshit walks. I don't have time for looky- loos.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>GRANDLY</mode>
      <context>(confidentially to Zed and</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I can help.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an amazing coincidence-- running into you and Maya and them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still think it's all just a coincidence? All of us here right now, at this particular place, at this particular time?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>THINKS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Why do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure yet, but I'm starting to believe that everything happens for a reason. Like, why did I eat the forbidden fruit?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To get laid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>which omnipotent force?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean "which" omnipotent force? How many omnipotent forces could there be?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! What's "omnipotent" mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work with me-- I'm just speculating here. Let's call this force "God"; and let's say this "God" is controlling everything. Maybe God wanted me to have the knowledge of good and evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would he want that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know God's a "He?" Zed rolls his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What if we've been chosen?</context>
      <utterance>Don't you get what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think we've been chosen by God?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no offense, but it's possible that I was chosen and you all just happened to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would God choose you? Why wouldn't he choose Marlak? He's stronger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(points to his temples)</context>
      <utterance>A chosen doesn't need to be strong. I'm big this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do have a fat face.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not my face, my brain. It's enormous. I'm the smartest guy in the village.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SCOFFS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not even-- I'm smarter than you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!  Which one of us is smarter?</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're both idiots!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, then why are we free and you're chained up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Come here. I think we worked something out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit tight. I'm going to get you out of here. Do you trust me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>HEDGING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to trust you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him an encouraging hug, then Zed and Oh cross to Cain and the slave trader.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never trusted that guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SARCASTIC                                                     </mode>
      <context>They are pushed to the front of the platform.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Just 'cause he murdered his brother and got hit by lightning?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right! Next up is a twofer-- I'm selling them as a pair-- I know they don't look like much-- but I'm starting the bidding at sixty gold minas. Do I hear sixty?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode>NOTHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, it's two for one here. Do I hear fifty? Anyone? That's only twenty-five apiece, folks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-five? Thirty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, people! We're a steal at thirty!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, a Bedouin SHEIK raises his giraffe-tail fly whisk and waves it at the slave trader.</context>
      <utterance>They probably don't know how smart you think you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE TRADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Sold to Sheikh Hassan for 30 gold minas!  Have a good time in the salt mines, boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For you maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I want you to know I blame myself for everything that happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So does everybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from my woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>IRRITATED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's going to be possible. And I told you before, she's not "your woman."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak starts muscling and squirming his way through the body pile trying to get to Zed.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OTHER SLAVES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Watch it, jerk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>MUFFLED</mode>
      <context>Oh is vaguely aware of the fight going on but can't move.</context>
      <utterance>Ecchhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh tries to maneuver to Zed, but can't move an inch. OH (CONT'D) (cont'd) If everyone could just move to the right. Please? Thank you in advance for your cooperation. (then, giving up hope) You can do it, Zed! Use his weight against him! Marlak now has Zed locked in a lethal choke hold.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on! I'm coming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEDOUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off! Don't make me come in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>MASHED</mode>
      <context>The Bedouin is just about to respond when suddenly A METAL TIPPED ARROW FLIES IN AND PIERCES HIS THROAT. He drops to the sand, dead.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see you try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak starts for Zed but two soldiers ride up and throw a heavy restraining net over him. Zed grabs oh and takes off running over the nearest sand dune. Sargon watches them flee.</context>
      <utterance>Take the slaves!</utterance>
   <speaker>A SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, shall I pursue them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They won't get far.</context>
      <utterance>No. Let the desert have them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tend to the slaves. We leave for Sodom before daybreak.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder who they are. Their hats are really great, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their hats? I'm sorry, but when that one guy cut the other guy's head off, my first thought wasn't, "Gee, what a great hat."</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't my very first thought, but I'd be lying if I said it wasn't up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>WATCHFUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we just need to figure out a way to rescue Maya and Eema.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're killers!</context>
      <utterance>How are we going to rescue anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>WILY</mode>
      <context>He keeps a sharp, wakeful eye on the enemy camp.</context>
      <utterance>Patience, my friend. Even killers have to sleep sometime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SCRATCHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that was refreshing. How'd you sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>YAWNS</mode>
      <context>Then Zed suddenly remembers Maya. He looks and sees that the soldiers and slaves are long gone.</context>
      <utterance>Not that well. I think I was over- tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps to his feet, looks around desperately, and sees nothing but a vast wasteland in every direction.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed sniffs the air, puts his ear to the ground, and tastes the sand.</context>
      <utterance>Now where do we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I listen to you? Now we're going to starve to death or die of thirst.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you stop being so negative? I got your back, man. Who saved you from those lions when you were a baby? They were going to pounce, had you surrounded. Took the mama lion-- BAM!-- kneed her right in the face. Papa lion comes flying at me-- BAM!-- dropped an elbow, knocked his ass out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I've asked people about that and no one else seems to remember it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, because nobody else was there. You're lucky I was walking by.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>THEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, it's possible I dreamed that-- but who practically raised you after your father was dragged off by those raccoons? Not a dignified death.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pull back to reveal that they are surrounded by hungry jackals, vultures and hyenas.</context>
      <utterance>He was a small man. Oh collapses face down in the sand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts Oh over his shoulder and stumbles on.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to keep moving.  I've got you, buddy-- just like always.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dad? We making a burnt offering?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Isaac. As God has commanded me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see the sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abraham takes a cord and starts tying Isaac's hands together.</context>
      <utterance>The Lord will provide the sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode>NERVOUSLY</mode>
      <context>Without another word Abraham takes strong hold of Isaac and lifts him up onto the firewood. ISAAC (cont'd) (really scared now) Okay, if this is because I didn't clean up my tent, you can stop now. I get it. Then Abraham pulls a long slaughtering knife from beneath his robe. ISAAC (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Uh-- is this like a magic trick?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, nothing? You were just going to kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a difference.</context>
      <utterance>No, I was going to sacrifice him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac nods gratefully.</context>
      <utterance>Not to him, I'm guessing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Art thou an angel of the Lord?</context>
      <utterance>By what right do you interfere?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Verily, thou wast sent to stay my hand by the Eternal one, blessed be He.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>NODS</mode>
      <context>Oh helps Isaac off the altar stone and unties him.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you just said.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's nuts! I'm telling you-- he's totally lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Abraham, son of Terah of the house of Nahor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Zed and this is Oh, sons of-- people you wouldn't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brothers, let us give thanks unto God for staying my hand on the mountain this day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best dad in all the land, everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KINSMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a ritual response, in</utterance>
   <speaker>UNISON)</speaker>
      <mode> UNISON)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praise be to God, hallowed be His name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for the bounty which He hath bestowed unto us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE KINSMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed and Oh mutter along, trying to fit in.</context>
      <utterance>He hath increased our wealth and blessed us with His loving kindness.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED AND OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abraham looks at them.</context>
      <utterance>--mumble mumble mumble loving kindness.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed and Oh look at each other blankly.</context>
      <utterance>Friends, whence comest thou?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode>HELPFULLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to know where you're from.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode>SUSPICIOUS</mode>
      <context>Zed perks up at the mention of Sodom, recalling the destination of the soldiers who took Maya and the others.</context>
      <utterance>Thou comest not from the cities of the plain? From Sodom or Gomorrah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sodom and Gomorrah? Never been there. But I've heard of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lord has cursed them for their abomination.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>i didn't know that. What kind of abomination are we talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They bow down before false Gods and worship graven images.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abominable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The men of the city are weak and soft, fat with rich food, intoxicated by strong drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Tell me more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their women are whores; their shameless lust knows no bounds. They flaunt their flesh without shame and any man may have knowledge of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where exactly are those cities?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just want to know so we can avoid them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode>FIERCELY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk not the path of Sodom! For surely will the Lord send his holy fire to destroy the city and all who dwell within, to smite them and all their seed for their iniquity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>CONCERNED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you think all this smiting is going to go down? We may have some friends there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abraham sweeps out of the tent. Zed and Oh jump to their feet and follow. Isaac tags along.</context>
      <utterance>Accompany me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abraham, I'm a little worried about the city being destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his arms and spreads them wide.</context>
      <utterance>Their fate is sealed. But for my faith and devotion, the self-same God has given unto me the whole of this land, from the Jordan to the Negev, from the river of Egypt to the great Euphrates. This did He grant to me and my seed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>IMPRESSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is all your land?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For eternity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode>SCOFFS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, God just forgot to tell anyone else. we're having a war with someone like every five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed and Oh fake their way through a ritual response.</context>
      <utterance>I and my kinsmen have vanquished our enemies by the mighty hand of the Lord, praised be He.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is praise and love his whole graciousness--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abraham gets a strange faraway look in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>--of his wealthy bounty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Therefore, to signify my Covenant with the One True God, on this night will I circumcise the flesh of my foreskin, and of you and every male who dwells hereby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go again--</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>we will grasp the foreskins of our penises and cut therefrom the extra flesh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>AGHAST</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I have any extra.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't we could just get our ears pierced?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what did I tell you-- nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Abe, it's late, and we've all had a lot to drink, and I know this whole foreskin thing sounds like a good idea now, but you may just want to sleep on it. we could always cut 'em off in the morning, but if we do it now, there's just no putting it back on later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed and Oh both reflexively cover their crotches.</context>
      <utterance>No. So it shall be written, so it shall be done.  Get my big knife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have any idea where we're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the city. I have to find Maya.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The city! He said God's going to smite them with holy fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You think he's more chosen than me?</context>
      <utterance>And you're going to listen to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seemed to know what he was talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and he also wanted to give his dick a little trim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even know where we're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to Sodom, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Your dad specifically said Sodom and Gomorrah were evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, whatever. If I show you how to get there, will you buy me a bottle of wine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I told you, that's not where we're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Then we'll just stand here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there for less than a beat. ZED (cont'd) Okay, you win. Take us to Sodom. Isaac takes a couple of steps to the top of a rise and points off in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it was right around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and my friends sneak in on the weekends. We hang around, pick up on the babes, drink some wine, get wasted on killer hash--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be smoking either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start down toward the city.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Grandpa, but I've been smoking for four harvests, so I think I'm okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, they're not open. We should probably come back later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just have to knock. They always let me in.  Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Why do I have to knock? What if we're waking somebody up? Let's just get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac impatiently grabs a big rock and starts banging on the door.</context>
      <utterance>Where? Back to the penis-cutter? Besides, Eema and Maya might be in there. You want to get them out before the city's destroyed, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTING</mode>
      <context>Suddenly Zed and Oh are yanked off their feet from behind and slammed into the wall by helmeted sentries. Isaac quickly runs away.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Anybody there? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac stops a safe distance away and turns back to taunt the guards.</context>
      <utterance>Halt!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna make me?  You and what army?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get help! Tell your father!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FIRST GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hebrews, from the look of them.</context>
      <utterance>They were banging on the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not really Hebrews-- The guard smacks him in the mouth. ZED  Okay. Lesson learned. No talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we wake the Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to do that. He gets pretty mean when you wake him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sentry grabs Oh's nipple and twists. Oh SCREAMS loudly. The guards freeze at the sound of his scream and look nervously to a closed door at one end of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Meaner than this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have to wait 'til morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Why don't you pick on someone your own size? The sergeant drops Oh and turns to Zed. ZED   Which would be difficult since there are probably very few people around who actually are your size-- He smacks Zed hard on the side of the head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get my big stick. I'll deal with the fat one first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>INSULTED</mode>
      <context>The sergeant rips open Zed's shirt exposing his back, then steps up behind Oh and does the same. A guard hands him a lethal-looking bat studded with sharp spikes.</context>
      <utterance>Relatively fat one. I wouldn't be talking about fat, if I were you. Another blow from the sergeant. ZED  Right. Enough said.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he takes a big backswing, Zed and Oh shut their eyes and prepare for the worst.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Sodom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! I know these guys!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED AND OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cain?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He embraces them. They look confused and doubtful, but relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Brothers!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you guys are lucky that sergeant is a friend of mine. I let him sodomize me once right after I got here and he's been real nice to me ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SARCASTIC</mode>
      <context>Cain stops and looks at them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, thanks for saving us. What are you going to do to us now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>wait a second. Do I detect a tone here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, honestly? You did sell us into slavery.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa whoa whoa! Hold a grudge much? That was like a fortnight ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half a fortnight, maybe.</context>
      <utterance>That was way less than a fortnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He embraces them.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a break! I was dealing with the death of a close family member and I needed some space. But now I realize that you guys are like my brothers. And it's so rare to find a brother that you love. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED AND OH</speaker>
      <mode>UNEASILY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>EXUBERANT</mode>
      <context>Cain walks up to a food vendor's stall and stares menacingly at the VENDOR. He raises his fist. The vendor cowers.</context>
      <utterance>Now, you guys hungry? Watch this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prostitute smiles at them as she sensuously peels a banana, then slides the whole thing unbroken into her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Check out that woman across the street! She's looking at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are so in! She's eye-knowing us like crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna love Sodom. Trust me. It's crazy. This morning, I almost got a handie behind that pita stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I kind of have a girlfriend-- not a girlfriend, yet, but a girl I like, so I shouldn't--</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a jug of wine from the stall of a WINE MERCHANT. The merchant just bows obsequiously and keeps his mouth shut. CAIN (cont'd) You know, if you guys are staying you should join the guards. The pay's not great, but there's tons of perks. I'm telling you, it's the only way to go. Cain grabs a piece of candy from a SMALL CHILD and stuffs it in his mouth. The child starts crying, Cain kicks her in the ass and she runs away.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what happens in Sodom, stays in Sodom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, I'll introduce you to the captain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is great! How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer pops him on the head with a truncheon.</context>
      <utterance>You look good, but I think my hat's too big. They notice an OFFICER staring at them. OH   Do you happen to know where I could get a smaller hat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So is this it? We just walk around?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much. We just look for troublemakers and kick the living shit out of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's death for sure.</context>
      <utterance>If we see a thief or a pickpocket, we just slap him around-- maybe cut off a finger or an ear, or the tip of his nose, lower lip-- anything you can just grab and slice in one fluid motion-- then we take our share of the loot and let him go. Mostly what we worry about are activist types, rabble rousers, getting people all riled up against the King or the Temple Priests.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty harsh, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harsh times, brother. We're in the middle of a famine. People are starving. If we don't get some rain soon, it could get ugly.  Then we'll get to start kicking ass big time. He stops to flog a BEGGAR with his hand out. CAIN  Beat it, you filthy beggar!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't blame people for being hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, just remember, it's the palace that pays you, not the people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that girl? I think she liked me! She looked right at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The royal guard takes his foot off Zed's neck and they all get back to their feet.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, I wonder why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was she?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Princess Inanna. She's totally hot, but don't even think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire crowd starts moving in the same direction as the royal entourage.</context>
      <utterance>Because she's royalty and you're scum?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's everybody going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the temple. Let's go.  You have to see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>FOLLOWING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she be there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody will be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Princess isn't eating?</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find it hard to eat when so many are hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your concern is enviable.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode>POUTY</mode>
      <context>The Queen, 40's, still beautiful, reacts.</context>
      <utterance>And besides, I'm so fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not fat--</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am, mother! Those new linen pants you got me from Egypt make my ass look just huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you can't keep starving yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Everybody else is starving-- present company excluded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful, Princess. You may be my step-daughter, but these are dangerous times and those are dangerous words. I weep for the suffering of my people, but the spirit of rebellion is alive in the city and if necessary I will crush it with every means at my disposal.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode>SARCASTIC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the good of the people.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the good of everyone who enjoys the favor of the throne.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. I'm just so incredibly bored.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The High Priest continues.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that the idiot who was standing up in the street? Maya sees him, too, and starts fuming.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We come before you in humble supplication, invoking your blessing, the sweet rain which waters our fields, enriches the harvest, fills our storehouses, makes mighty the house of Ish-ka-bi- baal and the city of Sodom-- The King nods graciously. HIGH PRIEST  --and feeds us, your children, with the bounty of your grace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's picking a virgin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>LASCIVIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Uh huh. Uh huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZED AND OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>watching curiously.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they want a virgin for?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To throw into the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SHOCKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Offering to the Gods. There's a famine going on. If we don't make a good sacrifice, it won't rain. No rain, no harvest. No harvest, no food. Get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pretty self-explanatory.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You throw the virgin in the fire so it'll rain?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like a waste of a perfectly good virgin to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another great cheer from the crowd as they throw her into the fire.</context>
      <utterance>For the love of the Gods and the glory of their Creation, the great dome of Heaven, the green growing Earth, we commit this maiden to your Holy Fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>APPALLED</mode>
      <context>Maya approaches them but Zed and Oh still don't recognize her.</context>
      <utterance>This is just crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Princess wishes to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her wish is my command.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(points at Zed)</context>
      <utterance>Not you. Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Cool.  We're kind of a package deal. Can he come with?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain squeezes both their shoulders and gives Maya an artificial smile.</context>
      <utterance>The three of us are inseparable. We're like brothers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two of you follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain fumes as Zed and Oh head off with Maya.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try to put in a good word for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't I go with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>EUNUCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Is he your lover?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah! No? That would be weird.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EUNUCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I serve the royal family-- little of this, little of that. I've been a palace eunuch since I was nine years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been living here since you were nine?  I should look into that. How do you get to be a eunuch?</utterance>
   <speaker>EUNUCH</speaker>
      <mode>MATTER-OF-FACT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They cut off your testicles.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>HORRIFIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What's up with all the genital mutilation?</utterance>
   <speaker>EUNUCH</speaker>
      <mode>SHRUGS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, after a while you don't even miss them.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>EMPHATIC</mode>
      <context>The Eunuch leads him down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'd miss them-- I'm sure. I hardly got to use them yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the liver is streaked with gray-- that's not a favorable sign-- but the heart looks good. See how nice and red it is here. That's always a good omen.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usually it means that the sheep took very good care of itself, probably sticking to a high-fiber diet of grass and hay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it mean for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wouldn't that be fun?</context>
      <utterance>Well, it could mean either a surprise visit from a former friend or sweetheart-- or that you're going on a long sea voyage!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>SCORNFUL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you become High Priest?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIME MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it's time for a new High Priest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRIME MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty, there's talk of revolution in the streets. Grain and oil are scarce, prices are high, starving peasants are pouring into the city looking for food--</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Queen and Princess Inanna are lounging on cushioned divans, listening.</context>
      <utterance>Poverty has a bitter taste, but it's the flavor they were born to. It's the will of the Gods.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode>BLASE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can the Gods really be so cruel?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maya approaches and whispers something to the Princess.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's cruel. It's just practical. If everybody was rich, who'd wait on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. See that he's bathed and dressed, then bring him to me. Maya frowns and exits. INANNA   This should be amusing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>POINTED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know.- I'm just a guard because my "brother" didn't pull any strings with his friends in the royal court.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, first of all, we're not actually brothers---</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like Abel. I oughta just bash your head in--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You didn't let me finish. As soon as I get in there I'm going to talk to somebody and get you invited, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>UNCONVINCED</mode>
      <context>Cain pulls open the big doors and Zed steps through the portal. Cain tries to steal peeks inside as the heavy doors slam shut.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. Have a nice orgy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maya?! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no choice. I'm a slave, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In fact, we came here to find you.</context>
      <utterance>I was going to rescue you! Really!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait here until you're sent for.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wasn't my idea, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed shakes his head, looks around the room, then STARTS walking past a row of "LIVING STATUES," semi-nude men and women on pedestals covered head to toe in gold body paint, frozen in heroic postures that show off their beautiful bodies. Zed looks closely at one beautiful nude "GODDESS", then furtively reaches out and fondles her breast. The goddess slaps his hand, then resumes her pose.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. You were just chosen again. Maybe after you and the Princess get together you can start thinking about someone beside yourself. She walks off before he can answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GODDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>watch it, jerk!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You're a real girl! That is so cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not supposed to talk. I'm a statue.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you look so-- gold. How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going? I just had my whole body painted by a fat guy with no balls, and believe me, he was very thorough, if you know what I mean. How's it going with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. Had a little rub and a scrub, now I'm up for some grub.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds nice-- for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh scans the great hall looking for her and spots Zed's sister Eema, his crush, come into the room carrying a tray of food.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You'll never guess who's here- - Maya! She's working here-- and she looks great! But she's kinda mad at me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eema has been beautifully groomed and is now dressed as a household slave. She stops to serve some rowdy OFFICERS who take the opportunity to tease and fondle her. She tries to pull away but Sargon, the general, grabs her arm.</context>
      <utterance>There's Eema!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he starts to lift her hem, she drops the whole tray of food on him. His cohorts laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Stand still, wench! I want to see what's under that skirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! It was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sargon grabs her and raises his hand to hit her. Zed steps in quickly.</context>
      <utterance>That was no accident!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he pulls her away from</context>
      <utterance>You! Slave girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apologize to this officer--- now!</context>
      <utterance>I told you to fetch me more wine!</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Eema exits, Zed turns to the officers and shrugs. ZED (cont'd) Slaves-- what are you gonna do?</context>
      <utterance>Now go-- fetch! Wait by that-- skinny statue. I'll deal with you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try using a hot poker. That they understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch. Helpful hint. I will keep that in mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were sold to the palace. But I won't serve these people! I'd rather die!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep that up and you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?  Have you joined them?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look accusingly at Zed.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't joined anything.  Does this look like fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I know what you're thinking, but I'm just checking it out. We kept hearing that this place was so evil, but now that I look around I'm thinking maybe it's not all bad. There's a lot to learn here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Like human sacrifice?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Like the wheel, for instance! That's pretty awesome-- the way it just goes around in a circle. And farming! And metal-- writing, money, pottery-- hot baths. Come on! Back in the village we thought sharpening a stick was a big breakthrough.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I think I've been chosen to do something great with my life--</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go again--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maya returns for Zed.</context>
      <utterance>--and I don't think it's hunting wild pigs and weaving baskets.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>COOLLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wants to see you-- now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't think I'm interested in her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>MIFFED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I think that? Just because you couldn't take your eyes off her--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just using her, Maya! It's part of my plan. I'm going to get you all out of here as soon as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode>SKEPTICAL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maya sees A GUARD watching them and reverts to her slave attitude. MAYA (cont'd) (bowing to Zed) The Princess awaits you.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits with Maya.</context>
      <utterance>And I await her.  You two await me.  Stay out of trouble. I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has no idea what he's doing, does he?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. So much has happened. Sometimes I think-- She walks away. OH   I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather not, if you don't mind. I'm not really a slave. I'm a guard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then maybe you'd rather I speak to your commander and have you whipped to within an inch of your life. Or perhaps I whip you myself? How would you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are those my choices?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The High Priest lies back down. Oh looks around, finds a pitcher filled with precious oil and dribbles some on the High Priest's hairy chest.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh pours oil liberally over his chest, back, and shoulders. HIGH PRIEST (cont'd) That's good. Now rub it in.</context>
      <utterance>No! More oil! Much more, you insolent dolt!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>APPALLED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With my hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh grimaces and starts gingerly massaging the oil into his hairy chest and shoulders. HIGH PRIEST (cont'd) (in ecstasy) Mmmmm, I love it. The sweet scent of precious oil. The oily-- oiliness. Eema walks by with a pitcher of wine and sees Oh massaging the High Priest. She gasps.</context>
      <utterance>Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>EMBARRASSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eema! This isn't what you think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode>FLUSTERED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's fine. I understand. This really explains a lot about you that I didn't get before.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits.</context>
      <utterance>No, really! I'm just-- rubbing oil on this man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mnum imam. I have an idea. Why don't we go back to my place and see what's under all that paint?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>DISGUSTED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ughh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it was so close.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're called the "twin cities."</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks pretty from up here, but some people think God is going to wipe them out because they're so evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you think? Am I evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really know you. But you don't look evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you find me attractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah. I think you're-- incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have body issues.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're perfect. Your face, your hair--  Your eyes are like the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My eyes are brown.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's kinda dark. I took a shot. I know they're big, though-- and wet-- She pulls him close. ZED  Can I ask you one thing? What would a girl like you want with a guy like me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, finally a man who has the courage to question the order of things--- a man chosen by the Gods to do something great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>EXHILARATED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what I've been thinking! You wouldn't believe the things that have been happening to me lately. I just didn't know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know why. To bring you here-- to this place-- to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SMITTEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't agree more. I'm trying to agree more, but I can't. That's how much I agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand and leads him away. A SHADOWY FIGURE watches them from behind a curtain.</context>
      <utterance>Come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has a huge gold ring set with precious gems on every finger, and a gold tiara on his head studded with rubies and emeralds.</context>
      <utterance>My life is devoted to the service of the Gods and the good of the people. I take nothing for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's so-- unselfish of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is. It's just so-- lonely. Sometimes i hunger for the touch of another human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>COY</mode>
      <context>(pointing thumbs at</context>
      <utterance>Here's a riddle: what has two thumbs and wants another oil rub?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIMSELF)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ohquickly changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>This-guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where does that hall lead to?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Oh's arm and leads him down the hail toward a set of incredibly impressive doors covered with cuneiform writing and arcane religious symbols. HIGH PRIEST (cont'd) Behind those doors is the Holy of Holies-- the earthly domain of the</context>
      <utterance>Come, I'll show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>94.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Official White HIGH PRIEST  Gods-- a place so ineffably sacred, so powerful, that to enter is instant death for any mortal.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.  So who cleans it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>it needs no cleaning.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, of course not.  Kind of makes you wonder though-- the guys who built it, did they just die the minute they finished, or did the Gods give them a second to get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume they finished it, then the Gods descended.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's probably it.  So you're saying we can't go in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just told you! To enter is instant death! Only I can go in and only once a year after very elaborate purification rituals and days of special prayers and offerings.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>QUICKLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoos him down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Fine! Enough! I'm sorry I brought it up. Let's go.  Move. Move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to enter the Holy of Holies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Finally. Now you're talking! Should I enter it right here or should we go back to your bedroom? Does the Holy of Holies like to be entered from behind or--?</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode>POINTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the Holy of Holies-- you have to go in there and talk to the Gods.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Gods are in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they say, but the only one who ever goes in is the High Priest. They say it's instant death for anyone else to enter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why am I going in?</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode>IMPATIENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you were chosen? If the Gods wanted you dead they would have killed you already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right-- right. Then again, if the rules say--</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you always follow the rules?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with chicks always wanting guys to break the rules? You-all have this bad boy complex---- She kisses him fiercely on the lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do this for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He enters the Holy of Holies. A FIGURE darts between the columns and hides in the shadows. A beam of moonlight reveals the mark of Cain on his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just looking for the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode>INNOCENTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him not to go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>SHRIEKS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seize them!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards arrest Oh as Cain steps up and takes hold of Zed.</context>
      <utterance>Seize him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>SMIRKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should've invited me to the party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you done for me? I've been attacked by a cougar, I've fallen down a mountain, I almost had the tip of my thingy cut off, I've been greasing up the High Priest all night, and now I'm hanging upside down in a dungeon. And I have to pee real bad. All because of you. You call yourself a friend? Name one good thing you've done for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've helped you come out of your shell.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really have to pee--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I know I'm not perfect, and I may have made a few wrong turns, but you have to understand-- I'm a chosen. That's a lot of responsibility -- you can't even imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>ANGRY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only one who thinks you're chosen is you, so shut up already!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>STUNG</mode>
      <context>Zed starts frantically yanking on his shackles to no avail. ZED (cont'd) That was just my first idea-- and I'm also accepting ideas.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, be mad, but I'm going to get us out of here, if it's the last thing I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guard! I have to pee! Now! Seriously!  Oh, no--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd roars as GUARDS stationed around the square pull canvas covers off big baskets of rocks and the people rush to grab stones to throw. Zed and Oh instinctively move closer to each other.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! For these and other crimes they may not actually have done yet but we're pretty sure they were thinking about, the prisoners will be stoned to death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reluctantly turns and looks at Zed.</context>
      <utterance>Observe, my dear. It seems the least you could do, since it was you who lured him to his death.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't intend for this to happen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything to say before the sentence is carried out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to say this is really messed up--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I make a suggestion?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>IRKED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd thinks that's not a bad idea and murmurs agreement. ZED (cont'd) (pressing the advantage) In fact, don't you think it would be fair for us to get to pick the person who stones us? Cain looks doubtful, but the crowd thinks this is eminently fair.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just pick one person to throw?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Ooh, me! Pick me! Me!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that idiot doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain points at a BIG GUY, heavily muscled, eagerly waving his hand.</context>
      <utterance>We pick him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at a BOY, about nine years old and not very big.</context>
      <utterance>No, next to him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a kid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed plays the crowd which starts booing in disapproval. ZED (cont'd) This guy hates kids!</context>
      <utterance>So? You got something against kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the balcony, the King shifts uncomfortably, intimidated by the power of the mob. He nods to Sargon who signals to Cain.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! What's he got against kids? Children are the future! Give the kid a shot! The kid! The kid!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed turns to Oh.</context>
      <utterance>All right! All right! We'll try it. Kid! Grab a rock. The boy picks up a good-size rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to face the boy, ready to dodge when he throws. The boy winds up and fires a major league fastball that smacks Oh right on the forehead. The crowd cheers. ZED (cont'd) Holy shit! That kid's got an arm!</context>
      <utterance>Good thinking, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>DAZED</mode>
      <context>Oh spins and tries to duck but takes the rock right on the head. OH (cont'd) Hey! There's two of us! The crowd cheers and pats the kid on the back.</context>
      <utterance>I think he hit me. The boy fires again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the count of three! One-- two--</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everybody on this side now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd goes silent. All eyes turn and look up to the palace balcony. ZED (cont'd) (shouts to the King) Why didn't I die in the Holy of Holies? On the balcony, everyone is totally stopped by his question. One by one they all look to the High Priest who seems to be stumped. In the square, the crowd starts muttering. Zed seizes the initiative. ZED (cont'd) I entered the Holy of Holies and, lo, I did not die! Why? Because I am chosen by the Gods!</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I have a question for the King!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEOPLE IN THE CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed gives Oh a look: "See? I told you."</context>
      <utterance>He is chosen! He is the Chosen One. The Chosen One!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spare the Chosen One! Spare the Chosen One! Spare the Chosen One!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the balcony, the King and his ministers hastily confer with the High Priest.</context>
      <utterance>And his friend! Don't forget his friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could it be? Is he truly chosen?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't-- I suppose it's possible- I'd have to examine some new</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>62</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>addressing the crowd in the square.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers. Zed and Oh exchange hopeful looks.</context>
      <utterance>By order of the King, the sentence has been commuted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>PLAINTIVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we just stone them a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the judgement of our most merciful King that the prisoners are to be enslaved to toil at hard labor until they die of exhaustion or starvation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you think that actually makes anybody work harder? It just makes them resent you. Is that what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faster!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh glowers at him and steps up the pace.</context>
      <utterance>Can I just ask when lunch is? The whip lashes out again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Boys! Long time no see. They glance up, but ignore him. ZED  Don't tell me you're still mad about Maya. That's so over. I have a thing going with the princess now-- well, almost had a thing. I'm a slave now-- just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You're not just like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another GUARD approaches and whacks Marlak with his stick.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. We do have our differences-- like about a cup and half of brain tissue-- but that doesn't mean we can't work together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take those bricks to the top. The masons are waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I'd like to, but I did something to my neck--  I must've slept on it funny-- those dungeon pillows are like rocks-- well, they are rocks-- so I should probably take it easy or I'll be no damn good for work tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said move!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guard draws his short sword and raises it over Zed.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! But I should tell you, this isn't really my area. I'm just on a break from the mud department--</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more word and you die--</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to Marlak and</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay. I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENMEBARAGESI)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak and Enmebaragesi lunge against the ropes, but Zed makes no effort to pull. They glare at him. ZED (cont'd) Learned that from Maya. Good trick, huh? Okay, together this time. Go!</context>
      <utterance>Okay, boys, on the count of three. One-- two-- three!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How high you guys think we're going with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to Heaven, I guess. That's how tall they usually build 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ambitious.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now that was a ziggurat.</context>
      <utterance>We worked on the Tower of Babel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed looks down at his crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Incredible erection.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>MODESTLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nothing. You should see it when I'm excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tower.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(snickers to himself)</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right, the tower. Incredible erection.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, the Egyptians are working on an entirely different concept. Four sides, slanting walls, pointy top.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a pyramid?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRICKLAYER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SLAVE CHILD approaches with a water bucket.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Far out. Yet timeless in a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVE CHILD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the child offers him the ladle, Zed recognizes her.</context>
      <utterance>Want some water?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak kicks Zed from behind, knocking him over.</context>
      <utterance>You're from the village, aren't you? The child nods. ZED  I bet you wish you were back there right now, don't you. The child nods again. ZED  Well, don't give up. You're going to get home someday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in line! Now! Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where're we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To watch the sacrifice. The King demands it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard's whip catches him across the back. OH (cont'd) Ow! Why don't you try using your words for a change?</context>
      <utterance>Is that compulsory? Because I saw one when I first got here and it made me a little sick--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At your service, my lady. Anytime, anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode>FLIRTATIOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a depraved thought. You're so delightfully low. Absolute filth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode>SUAVELY</mode>
      <context>He touches his tongue to the tip of his nose and waggles his eyebrows. The King arrives with Sargon to loud booing from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, your majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they booing me? How dare they!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King looks doubtfully at the hostile crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Your Highness, with all due respect, those were "Woos." They love you. They were "wooing" you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All is in readiness, Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now? More virgins to sacrifice?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cain bows to the King.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, two, followers of the Chosen One, discovered by this loyal soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just doing my duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King stands and makes a proclamation loud enough for everyone to hear. KING (cont'd) In supplication to the Gods, for the love of the People, we offer a humble sacrifice to the sacred temple fire-- our own step- daughter, the Princess Inanna! The crowd gasps. KING (cont'd) (to Inanna) For the good of the people.</context>
      <utterance>And one more to demonstrate our own faith and charity.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't dare!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sargon and Cain seize Inanna, but she shrugs them off and rises with dignity.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't I? If you like, I could arrange for you to join her. The Queen slowly sits back down. KING   How long did you think I'd tolerate your insolence?  Burn her.-</utterance>
   <speaker>INANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you all in Hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ENMEBARAGESI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're bringing out the women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>AMAZED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you seeing that far?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENMEBARAGESI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see your sister, Eema--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(turning to the other</context>
      <utterance>We have to do something! Somebody has to stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVES)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The slaves start to mutter. The guards draw their swords and heft their spears, now on high alert.</context>
      <utterance>We can't let them do this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to get down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2</speaker>
      <mode>SNORTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over my dead body.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without a moment's hesitation, Marlak grabs him and tosses him off the top of the ziggurat. He screams all the way down.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thanks, Marlak.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Who saw that coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed looks around quickly, grabs the end of a long coiled rope attached to a big pulley, and hands Marlak the other end.</context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without waiting for a response, Zed bravely jumps off the top of the ziggurat holding the rope.</context>
      <utterance>Lower me down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks shocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seizes the opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other slaves and people in the crowd pick up his excitement.</context>
      <utterance>A sign! It's a sign! The Chosen One comes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Maya and starts dragging her toward the gaping mouth of the idol and the raging fire within. She struggles but is too drugged to put up much resistance. He grabs the sacramental pitcher of oil and starts sloppily anointing her. HIGH PRIEST (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Burn them! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>RUSHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the balm of this healing oil soothe your journey through the sacred fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>DESPERATELY</mode>
      <context>Then, a voice from above.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fight it! It's the will of the Gods!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context>Zed is standing atop the idol's head, brandishing a sword and shield.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sees him and starts to revive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, 'I don't think so!'</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed rolls his eyes in frustration and starts tentatively climbing down from the top of the idol. He jumps the last few feet and lands right in front of the fire, blocking the High Priest's way.</context>
      <utterance>Still not getting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I Said, 'I don't think so.'</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever that last thing you said was.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>THINKS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abraham's small army of HEBREWS reveal themselves, draw their weapons and attack the reinforcements. The last Hebrew to unrobe is Isaac, who just stands there observing the growing chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Death to the idolators!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just fucking nuts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ministers all draw daggers from their robes and move in for the kill. KING (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>I knew I could depend on your loyalty.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode>MUTTERS</mode>
      <context>He falls to their flashing knives.</context>
      <utterance>Assholes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Eema.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her full red lips and big blue eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eema, you're my woman! You hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep away!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wrestles Maya even closer to the fire.</context>
      <utterance>No! The Gods demand a sacrifice! And you ruined it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just sacrifice something small-- a rabbit maybe. Or a duck. That'd be good, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>SCREAMS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! A duck would not be good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that the crowd explodes into rousing cheers. In the midst of the crowd, Abraham looks around and scowls.</context>
      <utterance>All hail the Chosen One!</utterance>
   <speaker>ABRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the altar, Maya, revived now, embraces Zed.</context>
      <utterance>What am I? Chopped liver?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're incredible, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed and Maya, Oh and Eema stand there basking in the gratitude of the people as Inanna looks on.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I've been trying to tell you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlak grunts at him and reaches for his knife. ISAAC (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Hey, babe. Ever made it with a circumcised guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode>BACKPEDALING</mode>
      <context>Marlak and Maya cross to Zed who is loading a packhorse. Marlak looks at him for a long moment then punches him hard on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Is she with you? I did not realize that. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode>GRUDGING</mode>
      <context>Zed waits for more, but nothing comes.</context>
      <utterance>You did good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clasp hands.</context>
      <utterance>Well said, Marlak. You really have a way with words.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll tell stories about you around the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh is at the front of the caravan, giving orders, but no one is listening to him. Zed joins him. ZED (cont'd) Everybody ready?</context>
      <utterance>Not much to tell, is there? Just an average guy who saw his destiny and had the courage to defy a powerful empire. No big deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OH</speaker>
      <mode>WORRIED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just about-- I guess so. The Hebrews are going to lead us to the sea and we can get boats from there. We can trade all this stuff everybody gave us for the trip home.</utterance>
   <speaker>EEMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh swells up with pride.</context>
      <utterance>I'll listen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where will you go now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might head down to Egypt. I hear it's a happening kinda place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily. You want to come?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures off and he sees a small train of camels and horses loaded with a ton of her personal possessions. MAYA (cont'd) The Princess gave me a few gifts when she freed us.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get my things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Traveling light, huh? Okay, here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>POINTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the west!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's west.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed grins and they start walking, passing a small herd of sheep and goats, tended by VEILED WOMEN, going in the opposite direction. As THE LAST OF THE SHEPHERD WOMEN passes, we notice something masculine about her build and posture. Zed nods politely to her, but she averts her eyes and turns away from him.</context>
      <utterance>I knew that. Just wanted to see if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>zed does a double take at the voice, shrugs, and walks off with Maya-- as a torrential rain begins to fall.</context>
      <utterance>Peace--- brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
