<movie id="613" title="Youth in Revolt">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick pulls up his trousers and leaps off the bed. He pulls the drawer under his mattress out.</context>
      <utterance>My last name, which I loath, is Twisp.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A view of the drawer reveals it to be filled with neatly filed issues of Penthouse and Hustler. He puts the most recently utilized magazine in its place.</context>
      <utterance>The next thing you should know about me is that I am obsessed with sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick posing in front of the mirror, pants around his ankles again. He looks at himself from various angles.</context>
      <utterance>Lately, I have become morbidly aware of my penis.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We PAN DOWN, and where Nick's crotch is supposed to be, there is a hole in the screen leading us to...</context>
      <utterance>Once a remote region accessed indifferently for micturition, it has developed overnight into a gaudy Las Vegas of the body.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A view of the books and CDs on his shelf.</context>
      <utterance>I am entering the tenth grade at St. Vitus Academy, which, I am told, is the most rigorous prep school in the East Bay. Hopefully I will be invited to join Miss Satron's English Literature class.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Follow the curser on the monitor as he types the words -</context>
      <utterance>I am a voracious reader and listen to Frank Sinatra. So needless to say, I am still a virgin.</utterance>
   <speaker>STILL A VIRGIN.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He pauses in thought, then continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have yet to hold hands with a girl, let alone have my winkie up her wendell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>JERRY, early 40's, saunters in wearing a TRUCKERS DO IT IN OVERDRIVE shirt and boxers. His gut hangs over the elastic, but he is completely devoid of an ass.</context>
      <utterance>She used to keep Dad up to date on all the motor statutes he was violating. This is one of the reasons they got divorced.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jerry absently smacks Estelle's butt. Waddles over to the breakfast table. He snatches the Funnies from the paper in Nick's hands.</context>
      <utterance>Mom's boyfriend, Jerry is a long distance trucker, though his ultimate ambition is to be on state disability.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jerry gives an asinine chuckle at the cartoon. Nick glares.</context>
      <utterance>I've been struggling to think of a commendable thing to say about Jerry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No luck. His grey matter registers at cretin and the needle doesn't budge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>In the drive, Nick slaves over the duty of washing the rims of his dad's BMW 325i.</context>
      <utterance>Dad is a copywriter for agricultural magazines.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd like to own a more prestigious model of BMW, but, as he often reminds me, he is burdened with crippling child support payments.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick closes his eyes, his right arm moving rhythmically.</context>
      <utterance>My mother is the one who painted my room to look like Dolly Parton's boudoir. She read this color was used in hospitals to calm mental patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BLACKNESS. The masturbation reaches its feverous climax. Then the long moan and sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what I told her. I am not mentally ill.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And as Frank Sinatra's UNTIL THE REAL THING COMES ALONG begins, we go to OPENING CREDITS.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just a teenager.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry looks over his shoulder and they all take a moment to appreciate the slab-sided Lincoln in the drive.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry? Where did that car come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like the one Kennedy was shot in.</context>
      <utterance>It's a '62 Lincoln convertible.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except his was black and yours is white. And dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that. I was going to take you and your mom for a spin after breakfast. But now I guess it'll just be her and me. You have your smart mouth to thank for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it. I guess I'll just have to hang out all alone at the book depository.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerry, I don't understand. What happened to the Chevy-Nova?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry smiles with cretin pride. Nick looks to his mother and disturbingly enough, she seems turned on by his car-owner savvy.</context>
      <utterance>Sold it to a sailor on the Alameda Naval Air Base. A man should never own a car for more than three months, Estelle. That way he always gets the thrill of owning a new automobile!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jerry fails to notice Estelle waiting and instead just climbs in and chugs his beer. Estelle appears mildly disappointed before opening the door herself.</context>
      <utterance>After spending twelve years with Dad, Mom has had a string of lovers, none of whom she has asked me to approve.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Jerry pulls out, he tosses his beer bottle in the direction of the trash can at the end of the drive.</context>
      <utterance>I'm starting to think her boyfriends are like U.S. Presidents.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He misses and the bottle shatters on the pavement, but Jerry drives off anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Just when you think they can't get any worse...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...she manages to find God's Perfect Asshole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Jerry here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just left. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up is that hunk of shit Chevy he sold us made it seventeen miles before the engine blew up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second sailor holds aloft the banana peel sealed in a plastic bag. Nick glances to drive and regards the smoking Chevy-Nova with its camouflage paint job. A THIRD SAILOR is rummaging through the boxes in the open garage. He finds some spray-paint and shakes the can. Nick turns back to the sailors on the stoop.</context>
      <utterance>And we found evidence of a banana in the transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he owes us nine hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think he used that nine hundred dollars to buy his Lincoln. He's giving my mom a joyride in it now. But he'll be back this afternoon, so I would come back then. He's pretty stubborn. You might have to beat it out of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks one more time to the Chevy as the third sailor finishes painting the hood with the words: PAY UP OR DIE.</context>
      <utterance>That can be arranged. In the meantime we're leaving the piece of shit in the driveway. With a note.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sailors nod, somewhat perplexed by this kid's demeanor. As they turn to go and Nick closes the door...</context>
      <utterance>I like it. Very to the point. Well... See you guys this afternoon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Reveal Nick and his friend LEFTY, 16, belly down in the grass overlooking the clearing. Lefty watches the copulating couple with a pair of binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you have a good reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sister said she saw Millie Filbert holding hands with some college guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, Lefty. I think your sister is just waging psychological warfare.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's working. What am I gonna do, Nick? I'm obsessed. I think about Millie so much my balls ache.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in response, Lefty passes the binoculars off to Nick and then turns over onto his back and unzips his pants. As Lefty jerks it, Nick looks with nonchalance...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe your just not wacking off enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I've been taping my pecker to my right leg at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case you haven't heard, Lefty's erect member takes a dramatic turn midway up the shaft.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just have your parents take you to the dick doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? It would kill them to know that I even get hard-ons.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, you might want to get it fixed before asking Millie out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick gives a dubious glance in Lefty's direction.</context>
      <utterance>True. What if I shove it up the wrong hole?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lefty's grasp of the female anatomy is somewhat tenuous; he imagines there are orifices galore down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry hollers from the kitchen where Estelle gapes out the window. Nick calmly joins them from upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, you little shit, get down here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points out the window and they all take in the Chevy and the sailors' oh-so-subtle note on the hood.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, do you know anything about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Those sailors came by. They want their money back. I guess there was a banana in the transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell them when I was coming back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry seeths inwardly at Nick's mock innocence.</context>
      <utterance>Now why would I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, Jerry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll go get the Lincoln washed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're leaving? What happens when the sailor comes back for his nine- hundred dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on cue comes the ring of the doorbell and the simultaneous pounding of angry Navy fists on the back door. They peer out the window and find the fleet on the front steps.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell him he bought the car with my standard guarantee. Thirty days or thirty feet. Whichever comes first. I'm in the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry first starts to dart one way and then another, searching for a hiding space as he hisses.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, look. The sailors are here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then the front door gets kicked open and a mob of sailors pour in. Jerry flees. A HANDHELD CAM chase as he heads for the back and is cut off by the sailors coming in. Jerry bolts up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Get rid of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerry, where are you going? Just tell them you are in the right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty-three lousy dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the sailors pokes Jerry in the gut hard and he whimpers.</context>
      <utterance>That's my life savings!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt him! Nick, call 911!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick raises his hands. "You don't have to tell me twice."</context>
      <utterance>Touch that phone, kid, and you lose your left nut.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Please don't hurt me. It's all I got, guys. I swear. Take the Lincoln!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want the Lincoln. I want my nine-hundred dollars. I'm taking the sixty-three, which means you owe me another eight hundred and thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight hundred and thirty seven, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that they release him and Jerry crumples to the floor like an abandoned marionette.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Have it by tomorrow or you'll be found in the trunk of your new used piece of shit at the bottom of the Bay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We need to call the police!</context>
      <utterance>Jerry, what are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not some tattle-tale like your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then for God's sake, Jerry, just sell the Lincoln and pay them!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. It's in The Code.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What code? The vehicular code?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Code of the streets, Babe. Code of the streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry takes a seat at the kitchen table and adopts The Thinker pose. He strokes his chin as Nick and Estelle await his brilliant solution with breathless anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>Then what are you planning to do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jerry's got on a hat made from Coors beer cans. He's behind the wheel of his Lincoln convertible.</context>
      <utterance>We are going to Ukiah for a last minute vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Estelle dumps in the cooking gear and closes the trunk. Her halter top looks like an advertisement for Droop City. Nick's in the back. Estelle waves at the neighbors like she's Miss Corn Dog of 1954.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry says we'll be staying in a cabin on Clear Lake that's owned by a friend of his.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, everyone! We're going on vacation!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's blow!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back, Nick removes his sunglasses to regard the long, green, turd of a trailer. Some concrete dwarves in the grass. A dusty canvas awning over a small cement patio. A decrepit picket fence with a sign that reads: MY GREEN HAVEN. Estelle looks as if she's about to cry. Jerry puts his arm around her.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry...? You said it was a cabin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Estelle. It's real cute on the inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry pushes out and disappears into the back. Nick watches him with loathing. Estelle smiles apologetically.</context>
      <utterance>I say the kid does the dishes and we retire to the master bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>Mom? Do you really like Jerry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that she excuses herself, leaving Nick to ponder.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, how many men do you think there are who'd be interested in a forty-one year old woman with two brats, no money, and stretch marks?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Except her age. She's forty-three.</context>
      <utterance>Mom is a realist about everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>My mind races. I get an instant</context>
      <utterance>The moment I see her I know the Gods, while having cruelly endowed me with imperfect posture and pussy postponing pimples, had put me here for a purpose. My heart palpitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>T.E.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni glances up from her book and looks over her shoulder at him. Nick just stares. She gives an amused smile, almost flirtatious. Nick grins back.</context>
      <utterance>Super:</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks down. He pulls the robe closed, scowls, and goes into a flustered march down the path.</context>
      <utterance>Your robe is open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hel-lo, Excitable Boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, honey, meet Sheeni Saunders.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick regards Sheeni and her mischievous smirk.</context>
      <utterance>Sheeni needs to go to the grocery store. I've offered her your help in carrying her bags.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to go to services?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Much to the consternation of my fanatical parents I have converted to atheism. Fortunately my brother, Paul, paved the way for such transgressions.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul is an atheist too?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddhist, I believe, though we have not seen him in some time. I myself am looking forward to being free of parental bondage.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likewise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, your mother seems very nice, though your father I think might be rather dim.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they pass the meeting hall there comes a surge of HYMNS in chorus.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry and I share no blood links of any kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds rather zealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, even though I am no longer a believer I always found the services wonderfully aerobic.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni stops. She looks at Nick intently.</context>
      <utterance>You could say the same thing about sex.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, are you going to turn out like all the other young men and have nothing on your mind except carnal pleasures?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hardly ever think about sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She resumes walking. Nick follows her with confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Really? I think about it all the time. It's the hormones at work, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. A second floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni relieves him of the watermelon.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Father bought it so that he could look down upon the world. For him, Christian humility has always been a struggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was nice to meet you, Nick. She trudges down the slate path to the home.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns around. Gives a little smirk.</context>
      <utterance>Sheeni? Do you want to come to the beach with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a thoughtful invitation. I'd love to, Nick. Wait for me in the living room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick spins around to see MR. SAUNDERS reclining in his armchair. He is an immense, florid-faced, verdant eye-browed ogre in a rumpled blue suit.</context>
      <utterance>I understand you have invited my daughter to the beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, yes, Mr. Saunders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aha! Then I trust, sir, you are aware that in doing so you have entered into an oral contract to perform in loco parentis, i.e. to provide for the safety and well- being of aforementioned minor female.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sheeni descends the stairs. Jean cut-offs over a knockout yellow swimsuit that shows off her flowing nubility. Mr. Saunders grumbles. Sheeni grabs up a straw beach bag and pushes Nick out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Father, do shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Nick. Bye, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vaya con Dios!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind applying this to my exposed areas?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick's hands freeze.</context>
      <utterance>My, you get turned on easily.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't stop, Nick. We all have our hormones to deal with. Girls are fortunate in that it doesn't show. For all the world knows, my vagina could be moist with desire as we speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's none of your business, I'm sure. Shall you do my front too?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls over onto her back, her young breasts straining up against the yellow spandex.</context>
      <utterance>I'm up for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't find it too stimulating, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts in on her flawless legs, gliding on the oil all the way within a finger's reach of her sweet apex. With each daring pass, he comes closer to that final split. Finally the hand swerves too late, and lightly grazes the softly yielding vee.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coping.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick moves up, lubricating her arms, shoulders and neck. He smooths the oil on the soft undulating foothills.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Nick. Maybe you better do the top now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Nick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods, and for a beat they trek on in silence. He glances down at her hand and fumbles for it with his own.</context>
      <utterance>Breathless is one of my favorite films, though it might be eclipsed by Rebel Without a Cause. I often wonder what American cinema would be like today had Dean done more than three.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick becomes sickeningly pale.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Nick. You seem very nice. But in fairness, I should tell you that I have a boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trent Preston.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen years of age, six-two, fluent in French, plays the piano, a champion swimmer, and writes Futurist Percussive poetry. They stop at the gate to the Saunders' home.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not familiar with Futurist Percussive poems.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could recite one of Trent's if you'd like.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a dramatic pause.</context>
      <utterance>Please do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives a slightly amused smile at Nick's blank expression.</context>
      <utterance>RamDam 12/ Sizzle mop/ Crunch down/ Safety net/ Hot! Hot! Hot!/ Void.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's poetry, I'm a turkey scrotum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick flipping through a Penthouse under the covers.</context>
      <utterance>Here is an hour by hour account of the worst night of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1 AM. I decide it is just a case of puppy love and look forward to the interesting women I shall meet in the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>2 AM. I conclude the only way out is suicide. I begin to pen a poignant suicide note. Sheeni will see Trent for the shallow pedant he is and always treasure my memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn off the damn light!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>3 AM. I decide I am too chicken for any of the manly, violent means of suicide. I shall swallow sleeping pills. Where to get them, though?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4 AM. I can not die an inviolate virgin. Either I find a way to get laid soon or suicide gets postponed until after high school.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna beat your meat, go outside!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>5 AM. It will be too painful to see Sheeni again. I shall ask Mom if we can cut our vacation short and return to Oakland.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick? God what time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven o'clock. How about breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come back in two hours. I'm going on a hike. You can join me if you'd like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, where are your hiking boots, water bottle, provisions, survey maps and compass?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like John Muir I enter the wilderness with nothing more than my journal and a childlike sense of wonder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but I have no plans to baby any slackers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Not to be morbid, but this sight has been the chosen means of at least three teen suicides.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh. Quite a hike just to end your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni backs away. Nick stays, staring over the edge.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there is a road. But I agree. Adolescents have a tendency toward the over-dramatic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my journal!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get so upset Nick. Though your handwriting is egregious, you have a fairly decent vocabulary. Although, Trent is not an "affected twit." Nick snatches the journal out of her hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my private thoughts and are none of your business!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick can only stare at her sprawled out on her back as if posing for a centerfold.</context>
      <utterance>The lengths you say you are willing to go to to win my heart, the contemplation of suicide at the thought of not having me...  It all evokes a strong emotional warmth in my breast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as he is lost in the ocean of her gaze before he manages to gain his senses.</context>
      <utterance>Did you mean it, Nickie?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you like it if I read your journal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can read it if you'd like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's in French.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A necessity for a child in a household with prying Christian parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick leaps on top of her, grabbing her thin wrists. She squeals and giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't you like to know. That last passage would be of particular interest to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spill it! I demand full disclosure!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wrestle, perspiring, squirming bodies brushing together. Flashing super: Thundering Erection They pause. He's got her arms pinned. She's on her back. He hovers above her.</context>
      <utterance>Never!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick considers her expression.</context>
      <utterance>Nickie's got a hard-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. She looks at him expectantly. Nick is at a loss.</context>
      <utterance>You're still a virgin, I can tell. Maybe that's why I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick tentatively approaches her luscious mouth. Their noses dodge successfully and their lips meet. After a long moment, they break it off. Staring into each other's eyes. Sheeni jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss me, you wienie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When can I see you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick grins with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Get up early tomorrow and you can shower with me in the ladies room. Five minutes to six. If you dare.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's this Sheeni girl like?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the Encyclopedia Britannica.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got a nice rack.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry chuckles. Nick stares at him, perhaps resolving to murder the trucker in his sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I go to the sheriff's now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I managed to convince Mother you were retarded and couldn't read the sign.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, where were you anyway? We said five minutes to six.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. But, Nick, women are always discreetly late. It's expected of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swell. And the punctual guy fries in the chair for rape.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't complain. At least you got to shower with a naked woman.  What are your plans today?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents want to go to Middletown. Jerry has the moronic notion of buying a trailer there before we leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods glumly. Clearly a devastating thought.</context>
      <utterance>I should like to come with you, Nick. The more time we spend together the better. I fear when you leave we might never see each other again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your cash price?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said in the ad. Thousand dollars firm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thousand, huh? That must be with a guarantee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As is, where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The geezer ponders the bad news. Estelle shakes her head and goes inside the RV to inspect.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Those rusty propane tanks are a fire hazard. The roof probably needs work. I couldn't go above eight hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are mouse droppings in all the closets, Jerry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might take nine fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni lets out a squeal of delight. They all turn their attention to where she has discovered a box full of squirming</context>
      <utterance>Nine hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUPPIES.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She brings one of them over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shows him the ugly little pug. Short droopy ears, a tiny, batlike face.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni turns to Nick pleadingly. Nick fishes through his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Ten dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I have is a Subway card with four stickers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sold.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt close to the dog's actual value.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She plants a kiss on his lips and promptly turns her attention to the dog, who licks her face affectionately. Nick looks on with appropriate jealousy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you, Nickie!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pronounced Al-bear)</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to name him Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't sound like any kind of name for a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The geezer looks to Nick with an expression of "I stand corrected." Nick returns with a nod that says "You have no idea."</context>
      <utterance>I'll have you know I've named him after the deceased French writer, Albert Camus. Author of L'Etranger and other works of existential brilliance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni, I think I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, your hormones certainly do. And oddly enough, my hormones like you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni? It's... It's okay. We can visit each other when I get a drivers license.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope that's true, but.. It's not that. It's...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my parents. They're... I fear they will never allow me to keep Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick tries to hide his hurt. Picks up the paper with annoyance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>SNIFFLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, honey. Why don't you take Albert? He could be our love child.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you could consider it, honey. For me. I've never asked you for anything before.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I could take him, but I'd have certain conditions. I would have to be the only dad on the scene.  Trent would have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's asking a lot. Trent worships the ground I walk on.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your choice. Life with me and the dog you love. Or a pet-free existence with a shallow, egotistical poet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, Nick, I guess I don't have any choice. I'll break up with Trent. But if he kills himself it's on your conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I accept full responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, good, that's settled.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite, darling. I want one more thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Sheeni looks pensive. It fades to amusement.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick lifts his eyebrows. Now we're getting somewhere!</context>
      <utterance>Do you have a condom?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be in a safe place. A nice comfortable bed. With no threat of interruptions. And for relaxation and mood setting some good red wine, preferably French. I want a new condom. Not one that's been riding around in your wallet for years. Consumers rated them a while back. I suggest you get their top-rated brand. This may take some research in the library. I'd appreciate a photocopy of the article. Plus, for supplementary protection, I want a name brand spermicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about I have a quick vasectomy just to be on the safe side?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Nick, that, of course, is up to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fires up the Lincoln and they kick up dust. Albert slobbers all over Nick. Nick sets him down and watches Sheeni in the side-mirror, waving in the road.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Back to civilization!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sheeni watches the Lincoln and trailer recede toward the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>I have a tall mountain to climb, with many treacherous glaciers still to cross, but finally, I have obtained a stamped entry visa to the paradise that lay beyond.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In short... I have a very real prospect for getting laid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry pops the hood and lets out a whistle.</context>
      <utterance>I guess they didn't cave after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, everything's complete. There's even water in the windshield washer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did they ever get it in here? My front door can't be more than three feet wide.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they brought it in piece by piece and then reassembled it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry slams down the hood.</context>
      <utterance>But it would take an army of mechanics to do all that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or a navy, Babe. Or a navy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick and Joanie meet eyes. She lifts a quizzical eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, your sister came all the way from LA for a weekend visit!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stellar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The family dines over take-out fried chicken. Jerry kicks Albert and the puppy goes tumbling across the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Can someone do something about the mutt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Jerry. Can someone do something about the monstrosity dripping oil in my living room?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I noticed that. What's the story?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry contemplates smacking Nick upside the head, but decides against it when he discerns Estelle is probably in her son's corner.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry tried to outsmart a few sailors. It's been an amusing saga.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, Babe, I guess when I come back from my next haul I'll just have to take it apart piece by piece.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to anything scandalous these days, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going to ask you the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick puffs out his chest. Joanie looks down at her boob-job.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Not that it's any of your business, but I've taken a class to improve my posture.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Joanie looks very nice. And she has a new boyfriend too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you meet him in posture class?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick met a nice girl in Ukiah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really now? Are you on each others' Myspace pages?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly. Sheeni believes the internet will be the end of literacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's to be a torturous snail mail exchange, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More like the occassional collect call.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry kicks the dog away from his sock. Albert growls and prepares for another charge.</context>
      <utterance>Collect calls? And just who do you expect to pay for that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Nick. Want to learn how a car is put together?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks. Auto mechanics doesn't interest me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry lurches backward in the chair and lands on the floor, revealing that Albert's teeth have a firm grasp on Jerry's sack. The dog shakes the scrotum in his jaws.</context>
      <utterance>See, Estelle, I told you the kid was queer-eeAAAAHHHHH!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to swipe Albert with his beer bottle, but the dog retreats into the house, leaving Jerry rolling around on the floor. Joanie and Nick exchange a smile. The phone rings. Estelle gets up to answer it.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it! The dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, put the dog in the basement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, that was your father on the phone. He lost his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How unlike him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch your smart mouth. This means the end of child support.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to start going to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>DISTORTED</mode>
      <context>In Nick's eyes the fear of a sentence worse than death.</context>
      <utterance>Oakland Public School.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you accept a collect call from Sheeni Saunders?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks around, opens the door to the linen closet and darts inside.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni? How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm well, Nickie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how is Trent? Not too suicidal I hope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, he was disconsolate, but we talked all day and he's come to see this as an opportunity for growth. Oh, and Nick, Trent wanted me to tell you that he bears you no ill will.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nor I him. I wish him all the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His parents are sending him to a French speaking boarding school this year. He's sure to get along there. So how is my darling Albert?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, though he's taken a disliking to Jerry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you, Nickie? How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I regret, Love of My Life, my father has lost his job and I will now be forced to go to public school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How unfortunate. What did he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a writer - sort of. He writes advertising copy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?  Nick, I suggest we look at your father's firing as a blessing in disguise.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I propose we get your father a job here in Ukiah and you can come and live with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. Not that I'm fond of Ukiah, but I'd live in a drainage culvert to be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick furrows his brow with skepticism.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Nickie. Now, I happen to know Progressive Plywood is looking for an assistant editor. It would be perfect for your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no idea you had knowledge of the employment opportunities of trade magazines.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The owner is the father of a friend of mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, it's Trent's father. So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why would Trent want to help my father move to Ukiah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, darling. Trent harbors you no ill will. I will have him call your father up pretending to be a head hunter.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well, but I don't see how I am to live with him. My mother values my indentured servitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must influence her to send you away. I feel this will require being in a constant state of open revolt on your part.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON her GLOSSY LIPS.</context>
      <utterance>I propose you rent the film Rebel Without a Cause as soon as possible. You must emulate James Dean...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A glint of resolve in Nick's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...You must be bad, Nickie. Be very, very bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in pre-lap comes the DING DONG of the doorbell.</context>
      <utterance>I will, darling. I will!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a beat, Nick rolls down the window.</context>
      <utterance>Kids? This is Officer Lance Wescott. He has some bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estelle sobs, but isn't joined by her children. She turns to Lance.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother's friend Jerry had a heart attack in a bar in Dallas. He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will they be sending his belongings?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Nick looks to Joanie. They both look to their mother.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... I'm afraid they've already been sent. To his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bursts into tears and collapses into Officer Lance Wescott's arms.</context>
      <utterance>His... His wife?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick watches his mother sobbing against the cop's chest for a beat before he rolls up the window and he and Joanie resume watching the movie. Estelle's cries of despair become...</context>
      <utterance>There, there, Ma'am. It's going to be okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PUSH IN on his reflection, as a moustache appears. Then a beret and black and white striped shirt. Then a cigarette holder and Thompson machine-gun. And FRANOIS is born.</context>
      <utterance>Like a Parisian James Dean, he will be bold, reckless, contemptuous of authority, and irresistible to women.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Franois. I think you'll do nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui, I am ze perfect match pour une Francophile for ze likes of Sheeni Saunders. I have ze calculating intelligence...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Franois cocks the machine-gun.</context>
      <utterance>...the itchy trigger finger...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Joanie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's sleeping in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance looks at him, seething inwardly. He glances to Estelle.</context>
      <utterance>No doubt. I don't think anyone got a wink last night with all that racket.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought there were laws in this city against illicit cohabitation. Or are they just another big policeman's joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, you are asking for trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance lunges across the table.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do? Shoot me with your gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick flings down his napkin and heads for the front door.</context>
      <utterance>No, Lance! Nickie, go to your room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen door slams behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the in God's name has gotten into you?!? Jerry paid good money for that trailer!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just what makes you so sure it was me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estelle gestures to the trailer, which we can see has been defaced with the words GOD'S PERFECT ASSHOLE.</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell else would write such a thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up a semi-nude Polaroid of Lacey.</context>
      <utterance>And just how do you explain this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Lacey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just who the hell is Lacey?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estelle stares at the photo, face contorted by revulsion and envy.</context>
      <utterance>Dad's girlfriend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His girlfriend? What are you doing with a picture like this of your father's girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Mom, all boys his age have pictures like that to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to Nick; morbidly</context>
      <utterance>When I want your opinion on raising my child, I'll ask for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURIOUS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's this Lacey tart like?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Super: (True)</context>
      <utterance>Well, she likes fast cars and takes a lot of naps with dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Super: (Not true)</context>
      <utterance>She likes to sit on Dad's lap while he eats and blow in his ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she calls him "Thunder Rod" and he calls her "Sugar Puss." Super:  At this point Estelle has turned bright red.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stalks off. Joanie glances over at Nick with amusement.</context>
      <utterance>You are confined to your room until school starts, you sick pervert.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I was leaving with you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your day will come. I never thought mine would, but it did. Was all that stuff about Lacey and Dad made up?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish. Did you really take a posture class?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lefty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with your mom, Nick? She gave me the third degree just to come up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I vandalized Jerry's trailer and she found my picture of Lacey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lefty unzips his backpack and produces a large hardbound volume titled Lovemaking for Advanced Gourmets.</context>
      <utterance>Well, good thing I stole this from the bookstore then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was reading it all last night. Boy, having sex is a lot more complicated than I thought. Did you know you were supposed to stick your pinkie in her bumhole?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lefty flops down on the sofa next to Nick and the two of them flip through the manual.</context>
      <utterance>No way, man. Here, I got the page marked.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They regard the illustrated figures of men and women in various states of foreplay.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I'm not sure I should try this on Sheeni. I think this book is for people who've been married so long they're disgusted by the sight of each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we really supposed to be that... uh... big?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think these illustrations are disproportionate for emphasis.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should compare.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick and Lefty get to their feet and stand opposite each other like a pair of duelists. They simultaneously undo their belts and pull their pants and underwear to their feet. They straighten. Lefty's eyes fall to Nick's crotch. He gets a hint of concern in his expression. Nick stares at Lefty's, tilting his head to compensate for the curvature. The door behind them opens and Estelle appears toting Nick's lunch. She lets out a scream. The boys turn to face her, pants around their ankles.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we should. Just for the sake of research.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick bursts from the room, desperately trying to buckle his pants. Estelle is hot on his heels, wielding the hardbound sex manual as they round the bannister.</context>
      <utterance>You won't get away! I'm calling your parents! PERVERTS!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She catches up to Nick at the top of the stairs and cracks him upside the head.</context>
      <utterance>In my house! How dare you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, I just want you to know that I've thought about it, and I've accepted that you are gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him dubiously and hands out the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks a pantsful, but I'm not gay. If you're really concerned though, I suggest you get me a room at the Ukiah Motel 6. If anyone can straighten me out, it's Sheeni.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick takes the phone from her hands and she closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds more like a job for your father. Here, he wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this I hear about you being unemployed?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but my condition is only temporary. I can change it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you do. We need the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, there are more important things in life than money.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Dad. Like getting a good education. And being able to respect your parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got two words for you. Safe sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FEMALE CASEWORKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Office of Child Welfare.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, uh... My name is Nick. Nick Twisp. My father's name is George Twisp.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CASEWORKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he hit you, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not lately. But he's missed several child support payments, and is not looking for work. So now I'm going to public school in Oakland.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CASEWORKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the Oakland schools!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And he's had an offer from a respectable publication in Ukiah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CASEWORKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you worry, young man. I'll get right on this. Don't worry. We'll light a fire under that deadbeat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lefty. How's it hangin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never believe who called me, Nick. Millie Filbert!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert squats to poop in someone's yard. The boys pause to wait for him.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno. She just called and asked if I wanted to hang out tonight. I didn't want to ask why. I need to find someplace for us to get it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can use my house if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. My Mom and Lance are going to a movie and I'm planning on stealing Jerry's trailer and torching it in a parking lot, so you'll have the whole house to yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert finishes his business and they resume walking.</context>
      <utterance>Right on.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where you headed anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Browerly's office. My parents are making me see a shrink now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asking lots of weird questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet your left nut he is! He asked if I had any lustful thoughts toward my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you tell him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him about beating off once with her brassiere.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you tell him that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what it's like. I think they release chemicals in their office to make you tell the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a professional. He must be very expensive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know. The bill goes to your house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom is paying for your therapy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so. It was your cyclops I was staring at.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but it was your idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true. Gee, maybe I am gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be retarded. We were doing research for our girlfriends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. I forgot. That's a relief. So you'll leave the door open?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just don't blow your load on my sheets.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks a pantsful, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it. See ya, Lefty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lance and I are walking down to the movie theater. There's TV dinners in the freezer. Oh, and Nick - your father got a job in Ukiah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom? Do you think it might be a good idea if I moved in with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, that just wouldn't work. I depend on that child support money to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But shouldn't you depend on the child support money for, you know... child support?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your smart mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The hitch ball grinds under the trailer socket.</context>
      <utterance>Tow Jerry's trailer to a remote parking lot in Berkeley and burn it to the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick fires up the V-8 engine and shifts into drive, pulling forward. He cuts across the lawn.</context>
      <utterance>Thus evicting myself from my mother's clutches and into the arms of My One And Only Love.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The trailer clips the corner of the house. Chunks of stucco fall and the galvanized downspout shudders and writhes, collapsing the long rain gutter running across the front of the home. Nick guns it, and with a lurch the trailer splinters free. He dodges the birch tree, but plows over the smaller Asian pear. The Lincoln bounces the curb and catapults into the street, the trailer weaving back and forth, smashing parked cars.</context>
      <utterance>Franois wanted to torch the trailer where it sits, but I've convinced him a parking lot will reduce the risk of collateral damage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mom! How was the movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You little shit. You stole your mother's dead ex-boyfriend's trailer and set a five million dollar fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I refuse to stand for such allegations!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance flips through his notebook and reads.</context>
      <utterance>Nick! They have a description of the arsonist!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A white teenage male, about five- seven. A hundred and twenty five pounds, dark hair, spotted complexion...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That could be anyone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick glances down at the lettering on his shirt. Oops. Estelle bursts into tears.</context>
      <utterance>He was also wearing a tee shirt with the words: I'm single, let's mingle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance takes Estelle in his arms and smirks at Nick.</context>
      <utterance>What am I going to do? My only son will be sent to prison!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lance, can't something be done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, Estelle. I'll make out that Nick reported the car and trailer stolen before the fire. It'll be less suspicious. But I could take some serious heat for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lance! You're wonderful! How can I possibly repay you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her ass a playful squeeze. She lets out a giggle.</context>
      <utterance>I'll think of something, Estelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the kid better not be here when the detectives start coming around. I'd send him away for a while. A long while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick suddenly brightens.</context>
      <utterance>He can go make his father's life miserable!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I like it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She snatches up the phone and dials. George's groggy voice can be heard answering. Estelle screams into the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You're going, buster!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're son just burned down half of Berkeley! Come and get the little brat!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, Estelle, aren't you going to punish him? I'd say he deserves a good hiding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>cupping the squawking</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE)</speaker>
      <mode> PHONE)</mode>
      <context>Lance gives Nick another smirk.</context>
      <utterance>He's too much for me anymore. Can you do it, Lance, darling?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>With the final blow the tree limb cracks in half. Nick looks over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I don't scream much. I am making a painful sacrifice for The Woman Of My Dreams. My suffering possesses a beauty which elevates it above this sordid scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance looks around the room. Picks up an umbrella and considers it in his hand. Nick hangs his head.</context>
      <utterance>Are you through?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick finds Lefty lurking in the shrubs that divide his mother's lawn from the neighbor's. He limps to his friend.</context>
      <utterance>Psst. Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering what happened to you. Did you get to blow your wad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I did not get to blow my wad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get interrupted?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's worse than being interrupted?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Millie is a lesbian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only reason she wanted to hang out with me is because she heard that I showed you my slinky and thought I was gay too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, man. I didn't have a great night either.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I dunno what you're gonna do, but I'm giving suicide serious consideration this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or you could just fake it and then hide out in Ukiah with me. Then later come back and maybe Millie Filbert will boink you out of pity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pair of headlights swing into the drive and Lefty ducks out of sight. The headlights turn out to belong to George Twisp's</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's not a bad idea. Thanks a pantsful, Nick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trunk pops open.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Lacey. Hi, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any way I could sit up front with Lacey, Dad? Mom's boyfriend beat me pretty badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Nick. In this car, faggots get the back seat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick watches longingly as George leads Lacey into the home. As he places his hand on Lacey's ass, he looks back over his shoulder and throws a smug look in Nick's direction.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead and bring your stuff inside. Lacey and I need a nap. C'mon, Sugar Puss.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a competitive asshole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm, hello. Is Sheeni available?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She most certainly is not. As a matter of fact, we've banned you from her life, Nick Twisp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trent Preston informed us that not only were you moving here to pursue my daughter, but that you're not even mentally-handicapped, and thus molested my wife in the shower of sound mind and body.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That rat-fink-fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watch your language. This is a Christian home. We're sending Sheeni to Les cole des Arts and Literatures in Santa Cruz.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ogre snorts in condescending amusement.</context>
      <utterance>Santa Cruz! But she'll be miserable without me. We're in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Mr. Saunders slams the door so hard in Nick's face that the entire two story mobile home rocks back and forth.</context>
      <utterance>Then I guess it's a good thing Trent is going there too. She'll have someone to console her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick lights up at the sight of her and they embrace. They kiss passionately. He works his way to her neck and starts to reach under the sweatshirt.</context>
      <utterance>Nick! Oh, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to sneak away just to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. I had to burn down half of Berkley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was you? Nick, are you out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni's expression indicates that she is touched, but it turns to troubled.</context>
      <utterance>I felt a grand gesture was required, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, Trent betrayed us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Franois will kill him later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Franois?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni takes a step back at the notion.</context>
      <utterance>Nevermind. The point is we must elope.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Nick. I do love you, but I don't want to spend the rest of our lives on the run.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes another step back.</context>
      <utterance>It's a small price to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I can't, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!? But, Sheeni. I just don't get it. I'm here. Albert's here too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods glumly and Sheeni seems overcome with remorse.</context>
      <utterance>I know, Nick, and I've been longing for you so. But we'll just have to find another way. The car is already packed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick Twisp, I will not allow you to accept defeat so easily!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or we could consummate here in the woods.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick just blinks blankly.</context>
      <utterance>Did you bring the consumer reports?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I really must go now, darling.</context>
      <utterance>Then it will have to be Santa Cruz.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... Goodbye, Sheeni. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls her hood over her head. Nick watches wistfully as she slips away into the forest.</context>
      <utterance>I love you too. Squeeze darling Albert for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have endured a five million dollar beating for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been stabbed. Stabbed in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>WE TRACK down the row of other students, starting with a THREE HUNDRED POUND BEHEMOTH. The row seems to descend in weight class, until we reach Nick at the very end.</context>
      <utterance>I do not have a friend within a hundred miles. This is a daunting thought if you think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry `bout wompin' ya. I'm Dwayne.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick. Nick Twisp.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Nick? Why do you suppose guys got only two testicles when we got ten fingers and toes?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick turns off his shower and slinks away.</context>
      <utterance>I could not begin to speculate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick comes up the path to meet him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Nick. I'm Paul, Sheeni's brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Paul. How did you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've met.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a previous life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul begins rolling a joint.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice fire in Berkeley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Sheeni tell you that was me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Was I an arsonist in a previous life?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But Sheeni was.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God. What did she burn?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hands the joint out to Nick. He regards it dubiously.</context>
      <utterance>Men. Men and boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, Franois! What was Paul smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick shrugs and opens the top dresser drawer, revealing Lacey's lingerie. Nick starts dancing, doing a strip tease for himself. WE PAN AROUND the room, and when we reach Nick again, he's wearing nothing but a pair of Lacey's thongs. He models in front of the mirror, regarding his bulging T.E. He removes a C-cup bra and holds it high. He uses the elastic straps to fasten the bra onto his head. He starts dancing up a storm to the cheesy Vengaboys rendition of BRAZIL in his head. Waving arms. Bicycling leg movements.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and go with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick gives a startled jump.</context>
      <utterance>What the... What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is..? Is that my bra?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods. The front door opens and MRS. CRAMPTON enters with Safeway bags of her own. Dwayne follows close behind her.</context>
      <utterance>We're calling that fruitcake display strike one. Two more strikes and it's back to Oakland.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Albert barks and jumps at Dwayne's feet.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Hi, Dwayne. What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks to his father in horror as Dwayne goes chasing after the dog.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't ya heard. We're gonna be roommates! Ain't that zinky?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't serve two shifts.</context>
      <utterance>Dwayne, get yer dumb ass back here and take yer sleepin' pill. You must be Nick. Wash yer hands, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Dad? What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Crampton's our new housekeeper. I'm renting out the spare room to her seeing as her camper has been deemed unfit for human habitation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Dwayne?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bunking with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick leans back and glares in silent protest as everyone takes their seats at the table.</context>
      <utterance>You working on strike two?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Nick. You wanna sleep in bed with me? It'll be tons warmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A knock at the door. Lacey enters.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you, Dwayne.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick sits up in bed to receive the letter. As Lacey leaves, he tears through the wax seal and unfolds its contents.</context>
      <utterance>This came for you, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a love letter, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, it's in French. Say, why does your mother give you sleeping pills?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`Cuz otherwise I'd stay up all night playin' Nintendo Wii. Say, Nick, can I walk Albert?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Dogs don't grow on trees.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleeease, Nick?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. But it will cost you one sleeping pill per walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatchu want them pills for, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never know when sedatives will come in handy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lefty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Hey, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lefty, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I live here. The guy's only charging me fifty in cash a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, what are you doing in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did what you told me, Nick. I threw my backpack off the pier and reported my own suicide. I even left a note.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lefty joins Nick in his walk down the road.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, Lefty, I'm kinda impressed. Faking your suicide is pretty ballsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where you headed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Redwood High School.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you want to go to school if you didn't have to?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's weird, Nick, but school seems like a pretty fun place to hang out once you get rid of classes and homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see this stunt really has liberated your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, Nick: killing myself was the best thing that ever happened to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I sit at your table?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'm Lefty and this is Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vijay sits and shakes their hands.</context>
      <utterance>I am Vijay Joshi.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you both have been rejected by the socially elite of our school. Ukiah is a cultural wasteland compared to India. Though some of the girls are very attractive.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at the moment. But I am optimistic. How about you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but she transferred.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mean Sheeni Saunders. I heard she was interested in some brilliant fellow in the Bay Area.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's you, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick narrows his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised. You are not at all what I imagined.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how is Sheeni?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. She sent me this letter. But it's in French.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I translate it for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak French?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I speak French, English, Hindi, Marathi, and Urdu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick hands over the letter and Vijay starts reading it silently. He chuckles as he reads and Nick squints his eyes at him in annoyance. Vijay picks up on it, clears his throat and reads aloud.</context>
      <utterance>That must come in handy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear, Nick...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sheeni slips into a nightgown as other GIRLS walk around scantily clad behind her.</context>
      <utterance>...a stimulating experience which I am now not so quick to change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you should consider learning French and enrolling. That said...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>TAGGARTY, short dark hair, intense green eyes, Manhattan sophistication cloaked in fragile ripeness, snaps a Polaroid of a sleepy BOY.</context>
      <utterance>I have an interesting roommate from New York named Taggarty...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Taggarty tacks the picture to a wall covered with Polaroids. She writes the boy's grade (C-) beneath his image.</context>
      <utterance>She has already slept with seventeen boys and hopes to rack up fifty before leaving here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode>READING</mode>
      <context>Vijay sets down the letter. Nick waits a beat, staring in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>All in all, I'm happy and look forward to further growth in this rich, intellectual environment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vijay picks up the letter again.</context>
      <utterance>That's it? Nothing else about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes... Love to you and Albert.  Who's Albert?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert is our dog. This is a disaster. What the hell does she mean Trent wants to mend the relationship?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but this Taggarty girl sounds very uninhibited. I wonder if she's made it with a Hindu yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather sounds like a babe. You think if I grew a beard I'd pass for college age?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to get to Sheeni as soon as possible. If I don't Trent Preston is going to mindfuck her into thinking she doesn't like me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then he'll probably fuck her in other ways. Did you know you're supposed to put your pinkie in a girl's bumhole, Vijay?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you shut up and help me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Nick. What should we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suggest we steal my father's BMW and take a trip to Santa Cruz. Vijay, you'll have to be our translator.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what will we tell our parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can tell your father you are staying at Nick's house for the weekend. And visa versa.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what if we are caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THREE CUTS. The JINGLE as Nick removes his Dad's keys from the bureau. The trunk SLAMMING closed with the sleeping bags inside. The ROAR of the engine as Vijay's hand turns the key in the ignition.</context>
      <utterance>To hell with it, Vijay. It's time to take action!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this music, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Dave Brubeck.  I thought a person as cultured as yourself would appreciate it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick, Vijay, and Lefty are noticeably shorter than the older boys around them.</context>
      <utterance>Nickie?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Sheeni.  Hi, I'm Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. So you're Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've heard so much about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is Vijay. And this is Lefty. Lefty goes to USC.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni glances over at the disapproving MATRON. She leans in close.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, I knew you'd come!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods in understanding.</context>
      <utterance>...but you must wait in the car until we can sneak you in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lefty, should maybe sleep in my room. It's pretty crowded in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your roommate won't mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lefty gulps and picks up his grip. He pauses in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Darlene went home for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes and Vijay and Nick exchange a knowing glance.</context>
      <utterance>Well, see you guys in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni steps into the tiny closet to change. Vijay and Nick regard the...</context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, everyone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's your competition.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two boys turn around and watch in hot-blooded bliss as Taggarty searches for her misplaced nightie.</context>
      <utterance>A distinguished group I would be happy to join.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is your plan?</context>
      <utterance>I am in a state of sexual frenzy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We drape a blanket over the lower bunk for Sheeni and me. You tackle Taggarty on the top bunk. Here's a condom. I slipped two to Lefty, leaving us with four.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if they don't go for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll go for it. You can cut the sexual tension in that room with a knife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick tries to appear unconcerned. She gives him a kiss and climbs into her narrow bed. As Nick and Vijay prepare their sleeping bags on the floor, they watch Taggarty climb up to her bunk in the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly, darling. Not with others in the room.  We must wait until everyone falls asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGERTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight boys. Do you need the light on to take off your clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  We can find our zippers in the dark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that the matron?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>It was Trent.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you say it was Trent?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He came to discuss our friendship. I told him now was not the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where is Trent now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Though silence follows, we take a moment to allow Nick's mind to race in the dark. He stands and looks at the mirror above the dresser. Franois can be made out sitting by the window in the moonlight, stroking the Thompson.</context>
      <utterance>I assume he went back to the boys' dorm. Now really, Nickie, you are keeping everyone awake with your inquiries.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now is our chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chance for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To confront our nemesis. We must go to the boys' dorm and kill Trent where he sleeps.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose we should at least get a look at him. To see what we're dealing with.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(stubbing out his</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIGARETTE)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that he cocks the Thompson for dramatic flare.</context>
      <utterance>You see what we are dealing with... and zen I wll deal wiz it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trent?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Who the hell are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Nick Twisp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you're Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Trent here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just missed him, Nick. He just grabbed a couple condoms and left.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say where he was going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he said he was going to Heather's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's where Lefty is. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed. Ed Solomon. Trent's roommate.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you're Ed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick takes off running and Ed stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. It's just that Sheeni mentioned Trent has a thing for a guy named Ed, and that he touches the guy when he falls asleep. But obviously if that were you, you'd know about it. Must be a different Ed Solomon. Take care now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Trent in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Lefty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick peers past Heather where he finds Lefty standing naked in the moonlight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm right here, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trent was here, but he left. He only dropped by to lend us a couple more condoms.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I gave Lefty two already.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and that was very generous of you, but the night is young.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what is Trent, the fucking condom faerie!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fact that Nick doesn't yet raises his temperament even further.</context>
      <utterance>You can have one of ours, Nick. If you need one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where did he say he was going?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't say, but I'm pretty sure I just saw him go into our bathroom down the hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sheeni's friend, Nick. Sorry to disturb you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's OK. It was something I ate. So wait, are you Sheeni's boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not that you asked.</context>
      <utterance>My name's Bernice. Bernice Lynch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you Bernice. Actually, I think Trent Preston mentioned you. He said you were frumpy, but now that I've met you, I can see Trent is a lying bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. And Trent can go to hell for all I care. Sheeni too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like Sheeni?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personally, I hate her guts. Well, pardon me, Nick. I feel like throwing up some more now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves him away as she bends over the sink to hurl again. Then lifts her face and smiles through the dripping bile.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't happen to see Trent Preston did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick's eyes widen in alarm.</context>
      <utterance>I did actually. I think he was on his way to Sheeni's room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was Trent here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick hangs his head.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick stares into her eyes to discern her honesty, but he finds nothing but adoration.</context>
      <utterance>But I sent him away again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I want you, darling. Not even Trent can match the industriousness and tenacity with which you have pursued me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>I/E. BMW 325I  - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>MOVING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lefty lets out a holler of joy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did it three times! Two long ones and a quickie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Just great. How about you, Vijay?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was difficult to tell with that condom, Nick. Why did you buy such thick ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That brand was top-rated by Consumers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's safe. No organism could penetrate those walls.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think the girls are in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will likely notify their parents. Perhaps even expel them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car sputters. Nick's eyes go to the gas gauge.</context>
      <utterance>That's it! Expel them. Then Sheeni will have to come back to Ukiah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we can't stay in the car. Sooner or later Highway Patrol is going to come by and ask for our non-existent driver's license.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we have no money!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no shoes! I'll catch pneumonia and die a indeterminate proto-quasi-virgin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>Mom? It's Nick. I'm sorry to wake you, but I'm hoping you'll help your only son. Especially seeing as it would really piss off Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two other boys exchange confused glances, not entirely if this is how people go missing.</context>
      <utterance>Pardon me. But is one of you Nick Twisp?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods, not yet sure whether or not this gentle giant is actually blushing with shyness or red with agitation at being sent on a midnight mission.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Wally. I'm a friend of your mom's.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick breaks into a smile. Finally the Gods have cut him a break.</context>
      <utterance>So, uhm, uh... Your mom says you need a ride. Did I mention I'm a friend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estelle's face registers "none of your business," but a kind look from Wally and she softens.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to Lance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick nods and goes back to eating.</context>
      <utterance>Lance is busy training to be a detective. He isn't around as much as he used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Rumpkin is very smart. Ask him a question, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Mr. Rumpkin, what famous actress was married to Frank Sinatra, Artie Shaw, and Mickey Rooney?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever she is, she sure gets around.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estelle smiles with pride. Nick and the other boys regard the gentle giant with admiration. He bashfully averts his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Ava Gardner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nothing. You should see what he did with the living room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK, LEFTY, VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wally flips another switch and the car's radio turns on.</context>
      <utterance>Ooooooh.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK, LEFTY, VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wally makes a slightly embarrassed gesture of scratching his head before lumbering over to the couch and taking a seat next to Estelle. Nick watches as Wally puts his arm around his mother and they listen to the Chevy play them Elvis' LOVE ME TENDER. The two adults snuggle in the glow of the tail lights and it brings an unexpected rush of caring in his expression.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaaaaah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uhm... It was nice meeting you, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wally blushes even more. He closes the door and starts to turn the truck around. Nick watches him go. Wally waves goodbye. Nick turns and the three boys make their way down the dusty road.</context>
      <utterance>You too, Mr. Rumpkin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lacey gives Nick an amused smile.</context>
      <utterance>In the bedroom. I wouldn't bother him, Nick. He's in a foul mood. He's on with the police. Apparently someone broke in and stole his Beamer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lacey! Get in here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, you got a girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you asked your girlfriend as a favor, would she do it with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys don't share their girlfriends.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick seethes inwardly. There comes a ruckus from the back bedroom and Lacey emerges.</context>
      <utterance>I get ya. You're worried `cause your girlfriend might get knocked up. What if I pull out, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not my fault, you tight-assed, critical, nonfeeling, sexist drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sticks and stones. It doesn't bother me if you sleep on the couch from now on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it bother you that you're a selfish, uptight, boring lover?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George appears in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>You forgot lousy driver!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick hangs his head. George moves about the kitchen chugging from a jug of zin. Lacey picks up the ringing phone.</context>
      <utterance>That's strike two, jerkoff!</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Lacey hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found your car in Davenport, George. Go pick it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lacey takes a seat next to Nick and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Look who's wearing the pants this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, I feel for you. It must be tough being a teenager in this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother wasn't any better.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom has had a difficult time. She has had a great deal to put up with. I'm starting to appreciate that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you by any chance referring to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George swills some zin and mumbles ominously.</context>
      <utterance>If the shoe fits, suck on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see who's sucking on what soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks up glumly from his lunch. Lefty has his feet up on the table, his facial growth is almost respectable.</context>
      <utterance>I spoke with Taggarty this morning. She requested a wallet sized photo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick narrows his eyes at the two non-virgins.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Vijay. That makes it official. Welcome to the club.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What grade did you receive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A C+. Which I feel is perfectly satisfactory given the conditions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess this means they're not being expelled.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, apparently they convinced the matron it was all quite innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Lefty and Vijay seem taken aback by the outburst.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? She had her flashlight trained on your Hindi boner!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick stands and collects his lunch tray.</context>
      <utterance>No need to be jealous, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm to get Sheeni expelled and sent back to me I will need a partner in crime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick begins typing and speaking out loud.</context>
      <utterance>Luckily, Franois has a girl on the inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Bernice, it was nice meeting you this weekend in the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want you to know I now see why you loath Sheeni Saunders so strongly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bernice sits next to Sheeni, despite the fact she's being ignored. Bernice drops a pill into Sheeni's coffee nonchalantly.</context>
      <utterance>You must introduce one of these into her breakfast beverage each day.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sheeni's head slips off her hand as she drifts off. We MOVE across the classroom to where Bernice scribbles in her notebook.</context>
      <utterance>She may be intelligent, but she is not likely to pass her courses when she's falling asleep in class.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A view of the notebook shows her to be scribbling Nick's name with hearts. She flips through pages of obsession.</context>
      <utterance>Since meeting you, I have come to realize my interest in Sheeni was only a transient adolescent infatuation. I like you more than I can say. Take courage. Together we will outsmart these cake eaters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode>DREAMILY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy is in Davenport. Where you left his car.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick watches the sensual foot message. He picks up the bag full of mushrooms and considers them.</context>
      <utterance>We saved you some mushrooms, Nick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick picks up the phone and Paul takes his place at Lacey's feet.</context>
      <utterance>Nick? Get the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>I/E. BMW 325I  - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode>MOVING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George cradles the cell phone. WE INTERCUT.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Nick Twisp. I am alive. I am a breathing organism.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit fooling around, Nick. This is your dad. Is everything okay there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid, Dad. Everything will be okay. You deserve to be loved.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that supposed to mean? Is Lacey there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lacey is here. Paul is caressing her toes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul! Who the hell is Paul?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're naked.</context>
      <utterance>Paul is our friend. He makes beautiful music for the acrobats.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's naked? Is Lacey naked?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone and pulls out the cord. He joins Paul in working Lacey's feet.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid, Dad. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad is afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is on the wrong path. I have felt that for some time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LIVING ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>where Paul stands between George and Lacey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George lunges and Paul socks him in the eye, dropping him to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, George, just calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You are in serious trouble. You've assaulted me and I know for a fact that you two were having naked orgies with my son. That child is only twelve years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sixteen, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(turning to Lacey and</context>
      <utterance>Shut your pie hole!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy is an underaged minor. I'm going to have you arrested and charged with child molesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be an idiot, George. No one was naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you get out of prison, you will both have to register as sex offenders. You will never be able to get a decent job again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never had a decent job. I don't think I'd want one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Paul. George, I'll pick up the rest of my things tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until you pay me the rest of the money you owe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I paid you all your money!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Not the extra charges.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lacey and Paul depart, Nick turns and dreamily wanders back toward his room.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck-your-stinking-extra-charges.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick gets back into his room and closes the door behind him. SWISH TO... Dwayne playing Nintendo naked. He looks over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Using bad language in front of a minor. The judge will hear about that too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's all the ruckus about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dwayne! Please cover yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna play Nintendo all night?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick unplugs the Nintendo and climbs into bed. Dwayne just sits there on the floor, naked as a clam.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. I'm tired. Let's go to sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A pillow whacks across a blubbery face.</context>
      <utterance>There is only one explanation: I have been Dwayned.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wake up! I know what you were doing last night, you disgusting beast!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dwayne throws off his sheets. Nick shudders at the sight. ...which is when Mrs. Crampton barges in..</context>
      <utterance>Don't be mad, Nick. I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's yer pajamas?</context>
      <utterance>Boys, time to get-- AHH! Dwayne!</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick made me take them off, Mom. He took off his too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You leave my son alone. Don't go co'rupt him with yer nastiness!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We weren't doing anything, Mrs. Crampton. It was just hot last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you get hot, boys, open a window. Don't go takin' off yer pajamas. That's nasty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonjour.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taggarty? It's Nick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Nick. I suppose you want to talk to Sheeni.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taggarty crosses to the bunks, where Sheeni is curled up among the sheets as if in some Renaissance portrait.</context>
      <utterance>If you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni sleepily takes the phone.</context>
      <utterance>It's your would-be-lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, My Beloved. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so well. I have been afflicted with some kind of chronic fatigue.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you are home sick. You do sound rather blue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not home sick, Nick. In fact, I'm not very happy with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? What did I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he doesn't deserve it.</context>
      <utterance>You know damn well, Nick. You've been spreading rumors about Trent.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't deserve it!?! I'd have to claim he has genital warts to sink to his level.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whatever you said to Ed Solomon, it was enough to get him to give Trent a black eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni, I just don't get it. This guy has cock-blocked at every turn and you're taking his side?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cock-blocked?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>SIGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have to resume this another time, Nick. It's been an emotionally exhausting weekend. My parents are in an uproar over Paul. He's moved some floozie in with him up in the studio over the garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lacey's not a floozie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lacey? You know her?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. She's my father's ex- girlfriend. I think that might make you my stepmother-in-law.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick. Don't be gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. At any rate, I'll let you go. We'll have plenty of time to settle this tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sheeni, Thanksgiving. I'll be coming for dinner, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even think it, Nick. You know my parents don't approve of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm confident they will learn to love me. After all, I'm practically family.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICK. Nick regards the phone defensively. He puts it down and takes a seat at the table. He glares at Dwayne as they eat breakfast. There comes a knock at the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, you must dismiss this Thanksgiving notion from your mind. I remain firm on this issue. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move, blubber boy, I'll get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is George Twisp in?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I'm pretty sure he's sleeping off a hangover, Officer. Is he under arrest?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under arrest? No, I'm the officer working the case of his stolen car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can tell your pop that the CD he found in his car is Ravi Shankar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indian music. So we're a checkin' the INS files, see if we can get some prints that match. You wouldn't know anyone who might have stolen the car who listens to this crap, would ya, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, and I'm not sure I like the implication. Ravi Shankar is beloved by many Caucasian...</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick stands stiff as a board. The officer peers around him at Dwayne sitting inside.</context>
      <utterance>What about Vijay Joshi?</utterance>
   <speaker>DWAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer makes a note.</context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty sure he's Injun.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick gives a weak smile and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Vijay Joshi. We'll look into it. Thank you, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Crampton complained to Dad that I tried to corrupt the fat pervert cohabitating with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twisp residence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Hey, Mom. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Nickie, I have some bad news!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'm ready. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid Lance and Wally got into a terrible row. He tried to arrest Wally and Wally broke Lance's jaw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the bad news?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick glances up and sees the black and white patrol car pulling up outside.</context>
      <utterance>The Berkeley police know you started the fire. Lance told them where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He slams down the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, they're coming to arrest you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick turns to find Lefty coming up the path with two bags of groceries under his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lefty, have you seen Vijay, today?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, haven't you heard? Vijay's been arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arrested?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For grand theft auto. They found his prints in your father's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's terrible. Did he go quietly?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We linger a beat on Nick's blank expression. Then -</context>
      <utterance>No. He said you were his accomplice and now the Ukiah police are looking for you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that or risk incarceration to keep my dinner date.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously the answer is clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Nick. Right on time. Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spots the sad flowers in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Thanksgiving, Lacey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What interesting flowers, Nick. Who are they for?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lacey leads him by the hand into the chintz-bedecked parlor. Sheeni's larger-than-life father and 5,000 year old mother sit cross-legged on the floor, running their hands over the hooked rug.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Mrs. Saunders.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Saunders coos and takes the flowers. Her husband squints up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. and Mrs. Saunders, you remember Nick Twisp, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are very, very tall.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No he's not, Dad. He just appears tall because you are on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick glances over at Mrs. Saunders who is now eating the flowers.</context>
      <utterance>I can feel the floor pushing against me. Can you feel it too, tall youth?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul served an appetizer earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick smiles with amusement.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's a recipe I picked up in the Southwest. Stuffed mushrooms.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGERTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Taggarty makes her entrance down the stairs, cloaked in a green cape.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGERTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She greets him with a casually intimate kiss.</context>
      <utterance>How is the star-crossed persistent lover?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I guess. Where's Sheeni?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGERTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upstairs, Nick. She saw you coming and hid in her room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner is almost ready, My Love.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not intend to be party to my brother's absurdities. He has allowed you in and drugged my parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni finally looks up from her book.</context>
      <utterance>I think they are deriving some good from the experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, Nick? I expressly asked you not to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hell with that. What do I have to do to prove my love to you? My friends have gotten laid and I'm pretty sure neither one of them was beaten with a tree trunk, raped by a walrus, or had to contend with the likes of Trent Preston!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were raped by a walrus?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni, I have shown restraint, I have committed crimes, I have traveled to the lengths of the state and still you won't give me this one little thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sex, Nick. Why don't you just say it? That's what you want. You want me to have sex with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>A beat as Nick's open admissions makes her consider his point. She sighs and shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Well... YEAH!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is my dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses the book at him, but he dodges it successfully.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent. He should be coming out of the oven right about now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands up and tries to slap him. He grabs her wrists and pulls her to him.</context>
      <utterance>I hate you, Nickie!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They break away and she smiles in spite of herself.</context>
      <utterance>I hate you too. They share a long, intense kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Saunders emits a long, low, fog horn of a fart that ends badly. The others exchange glances but he and his wife still have their heads solemnly bowed.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Lord...</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Lord, thank you for this bounty. Help us to be tolerant of others - especially the boyfriends and girlfriends of our immediate relations. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MRS. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Your father looks rather strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, mother, he is sitting in his own bowel movement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another helicopter passes overhead.</context>
      <utterance>That's no excuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The food is delicious, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sister, darling, how long has it been since we all observed the rituals of Thanksgiving?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not long enough, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat as they all dine in silence. Then- Mrs. Saunders croaks out in song.</context>
      <utterance>I hope it's the first of many such occasions for me. Sheeni narrows her eyes at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul begins humming approvingly and one by one the others accompany her as Mr. Saunders pretends to conduct them with a drumstick.</context>
      <utterance>Siiiilent night, Hooooly night/ Aaaall in calm, aaall is bright...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Round yon virgin Mother and Child/ Holy infant so tender and mild/ Sleep in heavenly peace... Sle-eep in heavenly pee-eace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick glances up with a start as TRENT PRESTON makes his entrance. He's not quite the deity Nick's expected, but rather a fairly plain, blond with slightly androgenous features and a certain flamboyance. His black eye, courtesy of Ed Solomon, still remains.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Trent, you made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Saunders grunts his acknowledgement as he takes the pitcher and pours water into his own lap.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Taggarty. Hello, Everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trent swivels slowly around and they lock eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Trent, darling, this is Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, at last we meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Trent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a seat, Trent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I have bad news.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Taggarty, I can't stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni and Taggarty gasp. Nick swallows hard.</context>
      <utterance>Bernice Lynch has tried to commit suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She swallowed a number of sleeping pills, and is now in a coma.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The poor girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more. Before I left school, I searched her room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you obtain proper authorization from the officials?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dramatically extracts the letter from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>No, Nick, I acted on my own initiative. In Bernice's closet, I found this letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the letter, the writer instructed Bernice to begin sedating Sheeni with drugs he himself supplied.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAGGARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, you didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you see...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick! You could have killed me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SAUNDERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who died?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Saunders points a liver spotted finger in his direction.</context>
      <utterance>No one yet, Mr. Saunders.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick places his napkin next to his plate and stands.</context>
      <utterance>I can't arrest him. But I have called the Santa Cruz Police. They are on their way here now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I shall be going now. Please continue without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick stops in front of Trent.</context>
      <utterance>Nick, I suggest you remain here and face the consequences like a man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other guests murmur their shock. Nick stops in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for that unsolicited counsel, Trent. And please, do drop dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Sheeni. I did it all for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the dreadful proclamation ringing in his ears, Nick leaves.</context>
      <utterance>You are completely contemptible, Nick Twisp. I never wish to see you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick stops at the edge of the woods to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Here I am, reviled by friends and family. Relentlessly pursued by three police jurisdictions.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He looks up the road which has been blocked off by flashing squad cars.</context>
      <utterance>Fronois suggests we flee the country. But where to go? Mexico? Canada? India, perhaps?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Hi, Joanie. How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Joanie listens gravely, shaking her head at the most gruesome parts of the story. Nick finishes, flopping into a chair.</context>
      <utterance>Since my sister can see through me, I'm obliged to give a relatively candid and thorough review of the events.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What happened?</context>
      <utterance>Nick, six months ago you were just another brownnosing honor student.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not really sure. I fell in love with Sheeni. All I want is to be with her. The rest is all a big misunderstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, you've stolen, vandalized, trespassed, and burned down Berkeley. All for one girl. If there's a misunderstanding, it's with your insight into females.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... But where did I go wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, boys your age are always looking for the path of least resistance to becoming a man. A boy's whole self-esteem rests on how fast he can get a girl into bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far, I agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick furrows his brow. Clearly that had not occurred to him.</context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later what those boys realize, is that the girls you're chasing base their self-esteem on how many hoops they can get the boy to jump through before going to bed with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I guess what you should ask yourself is: How far are you willing to go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joanie nods in amusement.</context>
      <utterance>All the way, Joanie. I'm willing to go all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick takes the wad of cash, clearly moved.</context>
      <utterance>You can stay here a couple days, but eventually they'll come looking for you. I don't have much money to give you, but here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Joanie. I... Uh... I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too, you little brat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, bacon boy, it's Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, ya little prick, where are ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter, they'll get you eventually.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick slams down the phone before Lance can respond.</context>
      <utterance>Let me make it easy. I'll be at Redwood High School tomorrow morning. Round up your donut dipping friends. I'm turning myself in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lefty lifts his eyes and sees his friend.</context>
      <utterance>Lefty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick? What are you doing here? Everyone and their mother's mother is looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have me soon enough. Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home. I'm done being dead, Nick. Heather and I are going back to Oakland for Christmas. You should have heard how glad my parents were that I didn't kill myself. They were even happier when they found out I'm not gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great, Lefty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEFTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, being in love is pretty great. So what's your plan, Nick?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There comes a murmur from the crowd and Tina directs the student camera-man to the road on the ridge where... George's BMW pulls to a stop overlooking the school.</context>
      <utterance>This is Tina Manion reporting live at Redwood High in Ukiah where local law enforcement as well as the FBI awaits the promised arrival of Nick Twisp.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd hushes as the door opens and Nick emerges.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. That's my car!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and thus completely compatible with Lefty's otherwise incongruent penis.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little to the right... a little... RIGHT THERE! RIGHT THERE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Taggarty at her wall. Ed Solomon lounges in the bed behind her.</context>
      <utterance>...never would find her perfect A.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>With a quick stroke of her pen, she changes Ed's grade from a B minus to a B plus.</context>
      <utterance>And would therefore start grading on a curve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joanie of course would get to continue to travel the world...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The CELEBRITY she is serving looks from her cleavage to her eyes. She gives a little smile.</context>
      <utterance>...and she and her breasts would probably go on to have the wonderful life that they deserve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlotta looks up, startled. She composes herself and shakes Sheeni's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Are you a friend of Nick's?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A terribly old friend. Carlotta Ulanksy. I'm sorry for your loss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be, Carlotta. I am no doubt culpable for Nick's actions.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, love does compel us to desperate acts. People cannot always act rationally.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Carlotta. Nick had wonderful a way of making me feel worthy of the pursuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni gives a pensive nod.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, if there's one thing the demise of Nick Twisp has taught me, it's that self worth comes from within.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to stay the night, Carlotta? We can reminisce of our departed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my. A kind offer, but I really must...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlotta does her best not to look conflicted, but it shows.</context>
      <utterance>It's just... I don't think I could bear to be alone tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodness. What an attractive negligee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like it? I bought it in Santa Rosa last fall. I had hoped to wear it for Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni crawls into bed. She cuddles close.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, darling, I'm sure he would have found it most... Appealing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like lying here with you, Carlotta.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlotta furrows her brow.</context>
      <utterance>I can't think of anyone I'd rather lie here with.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except maybe Nick. If Nick were here, what do you suppose he would do to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make love to you I would think.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK/CARLOTTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni tugs off the wig and tosses it across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Take off that silly wig and make love to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheeni! You knew!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick swoons, grasping her gauze-glazed nakedness.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, Nick. Did you really expect to fool your soul mate with such a disguise?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as they engage in a feverish kiss, ROUSING HYMNS surge. The church chorus' joyful song rings Hallelujah. The two lovers are entwined before an abstract RED</context>
      <utterance>Take me darling!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents are at services. They won't be back for hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we have breakfast, my love?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni hauls herself out of bed and grabs the phone off the cradle.</context>
      <utterance>What a lovely notion, darling. You go ahead downstairs and get things started.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calling Taggarty to report that you are not completely incompetent in the bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I get to stay and hear my grade?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at him and he smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>Not a chance, Mr. Twisp. Such things are reserved for girl talk only. And for good reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well, Sheeni. Don't be long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick lowers his arms and furrows his brow.</context>
      <utterance>What do I sink? I sink now's are chance to run for ze hills.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, we are young, yes? Is the world not our oyster? Beaucoup des filles. Do you not want to know what it is like to make love to another girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What about Sheeni?</context>
      <utterance>I do, but... We've come so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the reflection we can see behind Nick as Albert leaps onto the love seat and barks at the sound of approaching sirens. Nick runs to the window just in time to see half a dozen law enforcement vehicles pull up.</context>
      <utterance>Forget Sheeni. Yes, she will always be ze first conquest, but all zis time you saught zis was ze end, ze one and only, when in fact it is only ze beginning. Nick lifts his eyebrows with dawning epiphany.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ducks down from the window as a chopper buzzes overhead.</context>
      <utterance>Sheeni, the police are here!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quick! Maybe I can sneak out the back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. How do they even know I'm alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick spins to face her. She's standing in the doorway and there's not a hint of wrong-doing in her face.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I called them of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks a pantsful!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Nickie, it had to be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks to Franois in disbelief. But the Frenchman just rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I can't very well marry a wanted man, honey. Look at it this way, in a few months you'll be a free man and we can be together in Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pensive beat as Nick contemplates telling her he may never see her again. But behind Sheeni's air of control, Nick finally sees the vulnerability he's had in his hands all along.</context>
      <utterance>You might as well break it to her now, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Franois is right of course, but on the other hand, why be cruel? After all, Sheeni had managed to give me hope every step of the way. And if hope is what Sheeni would now need to go on, well then...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheeni beams. Franois smacks his forehead with hand.</context>
      <utterance>As always, you are right, my love.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Frenchman in the mirror sticks the barrel of the Thompson in his mouth and blows himself OUT OF FRAME just as... ...the front door bursts open and the FBI AGENTS surround Nick.</context>
      <utterance>Merd.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Write often, Nickie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't worry about Albert. He'll be waiting for you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The FBI agents shove Nick into the back of their black Saturn.</context>
      <utterance>As Franois would remind me, I'm intelligent, healthy, virile, not violently ugly... On the whole I am splendidly equipped for this great adventure we call the human existence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick turns to face the front while behind him the waving figure gets ever more distant. A pensive moment as he actually questions...</context>
      <utterance>Besides, what jury would convict a teenager who acted out of love? And even if I do get to spend the next few months of my youth getting Dwayned by the inmates of the California Juvenile Correctional System, I did get my thirty two minutes of lovemaking with one of the most outstanding girls of this or any other epoch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Nick revisits those thirty two minutes in his mind and it brings a smirk to his face.</context>
      <utterance>But was it all worth it?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
